<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 71—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES INTERNATIONAL BROADCASTING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6201.</num>
<heading> Congressional findings and declaration of purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress makes the following findings and declarations:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> It is the policy of the United States to promote the right of freedom of opinion and expression, including the freedom “to seek, receive, and impart information and ideas through any media and regardless of frontiers,” in accordance with Article 19 of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Open communication of information and ideas among the peoples of the world contributes to international peace and stability and the promotion of such communication is in the interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> It is in the interest of the United States to support broadcasting to other nations consistent with the requirements of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The continuation of existing United States international broadcasting, and the creation of a new broadcasting service to the people of the People’s Republic of China and other countries of Asia which lack adequate sources of free information, would enhance the promotion of information and ideas, while advancing the goals of United States foreign policy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The reorganization and consolidation of United States international broadcasting will achieve important economies and strengthen the capability of the United States to use broadcasting to support freedom and democracy in a rapidly changing international environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 432</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6202.</num>
<heading> Standards and principles</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Broadcasting standards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">United States international broadcasting shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> be consistent with the broad foreign policy objectives of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be consistent with the international telecommunications policies and treaty obligations of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> not duplicate the activities of private United States broadcasters;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> not duplicate the activities of government supported broadcasting entities of other democratic nations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> be conducted in accordance with the highest professional standards of broadcast journalism;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> be based on reliable information about its potential audience;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> be designed so as to effectively reach a significant audience; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> promote respect for human rights, including freedom of religion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Broadcasting principles</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">United States international broadcasting shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> news which is consistently reliable and authoritative, accurate, objective, and comprehensive;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a balanced and comprehensive projection of United States thought and institutions, reflecting the diversity of United States culture and society;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> clear and effective presentation of the policies of the United States Government and responsible discussion and opinion on those policies, including editorials, broadcast by the Voice of America, which present the views of the United States Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the capability to provide a surge capacity to support United States foreign policy objectives during crises abroad;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> programming to meet needs which remain unserved by the totality of media voices available to the people of certain nations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> information about developments in each significant region of the world;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> a variety of opinions and voices from within particular nations and regions prevented by censorship or repression from speaking to their fellow countrymen;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> reliable research capacity to meet the criteria under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> adequate transmitter and relay capacity to support the activities described in this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> training and technical support for independent indigenous media through government agencies or private United States entities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voice of America broadcasts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The long-range interests of the United States are served by communicating directly with the peoples of the world by radio. To be effective, the Voice of America must win the attention and respect of listeners. These principles will therefore govern Voice of America (VOA) broadcasts:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> VOA will serve as a consistently reliable and authoritative source of news. VOA news will be accurate, objective, and comprehensive.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> VOA will represent America, not any single segment of American society, and will therefore present a balanced and comprehensive projection of significant American thought and institutions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> VOA will present the policies of the United States clearly and effectively, and will also present responsible discussions and opinion on these policies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 433</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–415, § 1(p)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4301</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1323(d), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–778</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–292, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2811</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299Q(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4021</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6203.</num>
<heading> Establishment of the Chief Executive Officer of the United States Agency for Global Media</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continued existence within Executive branch</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Agency for Global Media shall continue to exist within the Executive branch of Government as an entity described in <ref>section 104 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chief Executive Officer</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The head of the United States Agency for Global Media shall be a Chief Executive Officer, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, until such time as a Chief Executive Officer is appointed and has qualified, the current or acting Chief Executive Officer appointed by the Board may continue to serve and exercise the authorities and powers under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The first Chief Executive Officer appointed pursuant to paragraph (1) shall serve for an initial term of three years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A Chief Executive Officer appointed pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be compensated at the annual rate of basic pay for level III of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5314 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of Director of International Broadcasting Bureau</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective on <date date="2016-12-23">December 23, 2016</date>, the position of the Director of the International Broadcasting Bureau shall be terminated, and all of the responsibilities, offices, authorities, and immunities of the Director or the Agency under this chapter or any other Act or authority before such date shall be transferred or available to, assumed by, or overseen by the Chief Executive Officer, as head of the Agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Immunity from civil liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, all limitations on liability that apply to the Chief Executive Officer shall also apply to members of the boards of directors of RFE/RL, Inc., Radio Free Asia, the Open Technology Fund, the Middle East Broadcasting Networks, or any organization that consolidates such entities when such members are acting in their official capacities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 434</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, §§ 1322, 1323(b), (c), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–777</ref>, 2681–778; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. A, title V, §§ 502, 504]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–451; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1288(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2548</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII</ref>, §§ 1299P(c)(1), 1299Q(e)(1), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4020</ref>, 4024.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6204.</num>
<heading> Authorities of Chief Executive Officer</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Chief Executive Officer shall have the following authorities:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To supervise all broadcasting activities conducted pursuant to this chapter, the Radio Broadcasting to Cuba Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1465</ref> et seq.],,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002332">1</ref> the Television Broadcasting to Cuba Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1465aa</ref> et seq.], and Worldnet Television, except as provided in <ref>section 6205(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To review and evaluate the mission and operation of, and to assess the quality, effectiveness, and professional integrity of, all such activities within the context of the broad foreign policy objectives of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To ensure that United States international broadcasting is conducted in accordance with the standards and principles contained in <ref>section 6202 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To review, evaluate, and determine, at least annually, after consultation with the Secretary of State, the addition or deletion of language services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> To make and supervise grants and cooperative agreements for broadcasting and related activities in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter and on behalf of other agencies, accordingly.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> To allocate funds appropriated for international broadcasting activities among the various elements of the Agency and grantees, subject to reprogramming notification requirements in law for the reallocation of funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> To review engineering activities to ensure that all broadcasting elements receive the highest quality and cost-effective delivery services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> To undertake such studies as may be necessary to identify areas in which broadcasting activities under its authority could be made more efficient and economical.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> To submit to the President and the Congress an annual report which summarizes and evaluates activities under this chapter, the Radio Broadcasting to Cuba Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1465</ref> et seq.], and the Television Broadcasting to Cuba Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1465aa</ref> et seq.]. Each annual report shall place special emphasis on the assessment described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> To the extent considered necessary to carry out the functions of the Chief Executive Officer, procure, rent, or lease supplies, services, and other property for journalism, media, production, and broadcasting, and related support services, notwithstanding any other provision of law relating to such acquisition, rental, or lease, and under the same terms and conditions as authorized under section 501(b) of the United States Information and Educational Exchange Act of 1948 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 1461(b)</ref>), and for multiyear contracts and leases for periods of up to 20 years subject to the requirements of subsections (b) through (f) of <ref>section 3903 of title 41</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> To appoint such personnel for the Chief Executive Officer as the Chief Executive Officer may determine to be necessary, which shall not be subject to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service, and to fix their compensation in accordance with the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> To obligate and expend, for official reception and representation expenses, such amount as may be made available through appropriations (which for each of the fiscal years 1998 and 1999 may not exceed the amount made available to the Chief Executive Officer and the International Broadcasting Bureau for such purposes for fiscal year 1997).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> To make available in the annual report required by paragraph (9) information on funds expended on administrative and managerial services by the Agency and by grantees and the steps the Chief Executive Officer has taken to reduce unnecessary overhead costs for each of the broadcasting services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> The Chief Executive Officer may provide for the use of United States Government transmitter capacity for transmission or relay of Radio Free Asia or any other grantee authorized under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To procure personal services at rates not to exceed the daily equivalent of the rate provided for positions classified above grade GS–15 of the General Schedule under <ref>section 5108 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To allow those providing such services, while away from their homes or their regular places of business, travel expenses (including per diem in lieu of subsistence) as authorized by <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref> for persons in the Government service employed intermittently, while so employed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> To procure, pursuant to <ref>section 1535 of title 31</ref> (commonly known as the “Economy Act”), such goods and services from other departments or agencies for the Chief Executive Officer and the International Broadcasting Bureau as the Chief Executive Officer determines are appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> To utilize the provisions of titles III, IV, V, VII, VIII, IX, and X of the United States Information and Educational Exchange Act of 1948 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1431</ref> et seq.], and section 6 of Reorganization Plan Number 2 of 1977, as in effect on the day before the effective date of title XIII of the Foreign Affairs Agencies Consolidation Act of 1998, to the extent the Chief Executive Officer considers necessary in carrying out the provisions and purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> To utilize the authorities of any other statute, reorganization plan, Executive order, regulation, agreement, determination, or other official document or proceeding that had been available to the Director of the United States Information Agency, the Chief Executive Officer, or the Chief Executive Officer <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002333">2</ref> before the effective date of title XIII of the Foreign Affairs Consolidation Act of 1998 for carrying out the broadcasting activities covered by this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To provide for the payment of primary and secondary school expenses for dependents of personnel stationed in the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands (CNMI) at a cost not to exceed expenses authorized by the Department of Defense for such schooling for dependents of members of the Armed Forces stationed in the Commonwealth, if the Chief Executive Officer determines that schools available in the Commonwealth are unable to provide adequately for the education of the dependents of such personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> To provide transportation for dependents of such personnel between their places of residence and those schools for which expenses are provided under subparagraph (A), if the Chief Executive Officer determines that such schools are not accessible by public means of transportation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<content> To redirect or reprogram funds within the scope of any grant or cooperative agreement, or between grantees, as necessary (and not later than 15 days before any such redirection of funds between language services, to notify the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate regarding such redirection),.<sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<content> To change the name of the Agency pursuant to congressional notification 60 days prior to any such change.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<chapeau> To—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> require annual content reviews of each language service of Voice of America, The Office of Cuba Broadcasting, and each grantee network, consisting of a review of at least 10 percent of available unique weekly content from any selected week from the previous year, which shall be conducted, to the extent practicable, by fluent language speakers and experts without direct affiliation to the language service being reviewed, who are seeking any evidence of inappropriate or unprofessional content, which shall be submitted to the Office of Policy Research, the head and Board of the respective language service, and the Chief Executive Officer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> submit to the appropriate congressional committees a list of anomalous reports, including status updates on anomalous services during the 3-year period commencing on the date of receipt of the first report of biased, unprofessional, or otherwise problematic content.”; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002334">3</ref> and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> launch a review, using external, native-language and regional experts, the results of which are to be reported to the appropriate congressional committees, if a widespread pattern of violations of the principles, standards, or journalistic code of ethics of a language service or grantee network has been identified.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Professional independence of broadcasters</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State and the Chief Executive Officer, in carrying out their functions, shall respect the professional independence and integrity of the Agency, its broadcasting services, and the grantees of the Agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on corporate leadership of grantees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chief Executive Officer may not award any grant under subsection (a) to RFE/RL, Inc., Radio Free Asia, the Middle East Broadcasting Networks, the Open Technology Fund, or any other grantee authorized under this chapter (collectively referred to as “Agency Grantee Networks”) unless the incorporation documents of any such grantee require that the corporate leadership and Board of Directors of such grantee be selected in accordance with this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conflicts of interest</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chief Executive Officer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Chief Executive Officer may not serve on any of the corporate boards of any grantee under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A full-time employee of a Federal agency may not serve on a corporate board of any grantee under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifications of grantee board members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Individuals appointed under subsection (a) to the Board of Directors of any of the Agency Grantee Networks shall have requisite expertise in journalism, technology, broadcasting, or diplomacy, or appropriate language or cultural understanding relevant to the grantee’s mission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 435</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–415, § 1(s)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4302</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1323(e)–(i), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–778</ref>, 2681–779; <ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. A, title V, § 507(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1394</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–140, § 8</ref>, <date date="2005-12-22">Dec. 22, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2652</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1288(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2549</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII</ref>, §§ 1299P(c)(2), 1299Q(c), (e)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4020</ref>, 4021, 4025; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. I, title XCVII, § 9706</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3915</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6205.</num>
<heading> Establishment of the International Broadcasting Advisory Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The International Broadcasting Advisory Board (referred to in this section as the “Advisory Board”) shall advise the Chief Executive Officer of the United States Agency for Global Media, as appropriate. The Advisory Board as established shall exist within the executive branch as an entity described in <ref>section 104 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition of the Advisory Board</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Advisory Board shall consist of seven members, of whom—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> six shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, in accordance with subsection (c); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> one shall be the Secretary of State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chair</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President shall designate, with the advice and consent of the Senate, one of the members appointed under paragraph (1)(A) as Chair of the Advisory Board.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Party limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not more than three members of the Advisory Board appointed under paragraph (1)(A) may be affiliated with the same political party.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Terms of office</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), members of the Advisory Board shall serve for a single term of 4 years, except that, of the first group of members appointed under paragraph (1)(A)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> two members who are not affiliated with the same political party, shall be appointed for terms ending on the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of the U.S. Agency for Global Media Reform Act;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> two members who are not affiliated with the same political party, shall be appointed for terms ending on the date that is 4 years after the date of the enactment of the U.S. Agency for Global Media Reform Act; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> two members who are not affiliated with the same political party, shall be appointed for terms ending on the date that is 6 years after the date of the enactment of the U.S. Agency for Global Media Reform Act.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary of State shall serve as a member of the Advisory Board for the duration of his or her tenure as Secretary of State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The President shall appoint, with the advice and consent of the Senate, additional members to fill vacancies on the Advisory Board occurring before the expiration of a term.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Term</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any members appointed pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall serve for the remainder of such term.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service beyond term</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any member whose term has expired shall continue to serve as a member of the Advisory Board until a qualified successor has been appointed and confirmed by the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">When there is a vacancy in the office of Secretary of State, the Acting Secretary of State shall serve as a member of the Advisory Board until a new Secretary of State is appointed.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Selection of the Advisory Board</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In identifying individuals for appointment to the Advisory Board under subsection (a), the President shall appoint United States citizens—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> who, with the exception of the Secretary of State, are not regular, full-time employees of the United States Government; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> who are distinguished in the fields of public diplomacy, mass communications, print, broadcast or digital media, or foreign affairs, of whom—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> one individual should be appointed from among a list of at least three individuals submitted by the Chair of the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> one individual should be appointed from among a list of at least three individuals submitted by the Ranking Member of the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> one individual should be appointed from among a list of at least three individuals submitted by the Chair of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> one individual should be appointed from among a list of at least three individuals submitted by the Ranking Member of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions of the Advisory Board</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The members of the Advisory Board shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide the Chief Executive Officer of the United States Agency for Global Media with advice and recommendations for improving the effectiveness and efficiency of the Agency and its programming;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> meet with the Chief Executive Officer at least four times annually, including twice in person as practicable, and at additional meetings at the request of the Chief Executive Officer or the Chair of the Advisory Board;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> report periodically, or upon request, to the congressional committees specified in subsection (c)(2) regarding its advice and recommendations for improving the effectiveness and efficiency of the United States Agency for Global Media and its programming;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> obtain information from the Chief Executive Officer, as needed, for the purposes of fulfilling the functions described in this subsection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> consult with the Chief Executive Officer regarding budget submissions and strategic plans before they are submitted to the Office of Management and Budget or to Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> advise the Chief Executive Officer to ensure that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Chief Executive Officer fully respects the professional integrity and editorial independence of United States Agency for Global Media broadcasters, networks, and grantees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> agency networks, broadcasters, and grantees adhere to the highest professional standards and ethics of journalism, including taking necessary actions to uphold professional standards to produce consistently reliable and authoritative, accurate, objective, and comprehensive news and information; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> provide other strategic input to the Chief Executive Officer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appointment of heads of networks</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The heads of Voice of America, the Office of Cuba Broadcasting, RFE/RL, Inc., Radio Free Asia, the Middle East Broadcasting Networks, the Open Technology Fund, or of any other grantee authorized under this chapter may only be appointed or removed if such action has been approved by a majority vote of the Advisory Board.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">After consulting with the Chief Executive Officer, five or more members of the Advisory Board may unilaterally remove any such head of network or grantee network described in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quorum</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A quorum shall consist of four members of the Advisory Board (excluding the Secretary of State).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Decisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in paragraph (2), decisions of the Advisory Board shall be made by majority vote, a quorum being present.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Closed sessions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Advisory Board may meet in closed sessions in accordance with <ref>section 552b of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension and debarment of grantees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), a grantee may not be debarred or suspended without consultation with the Chief Executive Officer and a three-fourths majority vote of the Advisory Board in support of such action.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria for suspension</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A grantee may not be suspended unless the Advisory Board determines that the criteria described in section 513.405 of title 22, Code of Federal Regulations, have been met.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspending official</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Advisory Board shall collectively serve as the suspending official (as described in section 513.105 of title 22, Code of Federal Regulations).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Debarment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria for debarment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A grantee may not be debarred unless the Advisory Board determines that one or more of the causes described in section 513.305 of title 22, Code of Federal Regulations, has been established.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Debarring official</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Advisory Board shall collectively serve as the debarring official (as described in section 513.105 of title 22, Code of Federal Regulations).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Members of the Advisory Board, while attending meetings of the Advisory Board or while engaged in duties relating to such meetings or in other activities of the Advisory Board under this section (including travel time) shall be entitled to receive compensation equal to the daily equivalent of the compensation prescribed for level IV of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5315 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Travel expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">While away from their homes or regular places of business, members of the Board may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized under section 5703 of such title for persons in the Government service employed intermittently.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretary of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of State is not entitled to any compensation under this chapter, but may be allowed travel expenses in accordance with paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Support staff</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Chief Executive Officer shall, from within existing United States Agency for Global Media personnel, provide the Advisory Board with an Executive Secretary and such administrative staff and support as may be necessary to enable the Advisory Board to carry out subsections (d) and (e).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 436</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1323(j), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–780</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1288(3)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2551</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299Q(d)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4022</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. G, title LXXIV, § 7401</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2543</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6206.</num>
<heading> Grantee corporate boards of directors</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The corporate board of directors of each grantee under this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be bipartisan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall, except as otherwise provided in this Act, have the sole responsibility to operate their respective grantees within the jurisdiction of their respective States of incorporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall be composed of not fewer than 5 members, who shall be qualified individuals who are not employed in the public sector; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> shall appoint successors in the event of vacancies on their respective boards, in accordance with applicable bylaws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Not Federal employees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No employee of any grantee under this chapter may be a Federal employee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 307</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. I, title XCVII, § 9704</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3914</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6207.</num>
<heading> Limits on grants for Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board of RFE/RL, Incorporated</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Agency may not make any grant to RFE/RL, Incorporated, unless the certificate of incorporation of RFE/RL, Incorporated, has been amended to provide that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Board of Directors of RFE/RL, Incorporated, shall consist of the members authorized under section 6204(a)(20) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002335">1</ref> of this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such Board of Directors shall make all major policy determinations governing the operation of RFE/RL, Incorporated, and shall appoint and fix the compensation of such managerial officers and employees of RFE/RL, Incorporated, as it considers necessary to carry out the purposes of the grant provided under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Location of principal place of business</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Agency may not make any grant to RFE/RL, Incorporated unless the headquarters of RFE/RL, Incorporated and its senior administrative and managerial staff are in a location which ensures economy, operational effectiveness, and accountability to the Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Not later than 90 days after confirmation of all members of the Agency, the Agency shall provide a report to Congress on the number of administrative, managerial, and technical staff of RFE/RL, Incorporated who will be located within the metropolitan area of Washington, D.C., and the number of employees whose principal place of business will be located outside the metropolitan area of Washington, D.C.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on grant amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The total amount of grants made for the operating costs of RFE/RL, Incorporated, may not exceed $85,000,000 in fiscal year 2003.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alternative grantee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Chief Executive Officer determines at any time that RFE/RL, Incorporated is not carrying out the functions described in this section in an effective and economical manner, the Agency may award the grant to carry out such functions to another entity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Not a Federal agency or instrumentality</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter may be construed to make RFE/RL, Incorporated a Federal agency or instrumentality.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Grants authorized under <ref>section 6204 of this title</ref> for RFE/RL, Incorporated, shall be available to make annual grants for the purpose of carrying out similar functions as were carried out by RFE/RL, Incorporated, on the day before <date date="1994-04-30">April 30, 1994</date>, with respect to Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty, consistent with section 2 of the Board for International Broadcasting Act of 1973 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2871</ref>], as in effect on such date.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant agreement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Grants to RFE/RL, Incorporated, by the Agency shall only be made in compliance with a grant agreement. The grant agreement shall establish guidelines for such grants. The grant agreement shall include the following provisions—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that a grant be used only for activities which the Agency determines are consistent with the purposes of subsection (f);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that RFE/RL, Incorporated, shall otherwise comply with the requirements of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that failure to comply with the requirements of this section may result in suspension or termination of a grant without further obligation by the Agency or the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> that duplication of language services and technical operations between RFE/RL, Incorporated and the <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002336">2</ref> any other grantee of the Agency be reduced to the extent appropriate, as determined by the Chief Executive Officer; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> that RFE/RL, Incorporated, justify in detail each proposed expenditure of grant funds, and that such funds may not be used for any other purpose unless the Agency gives its prior written approval.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibited uses of grant funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No grant funds provided under this section may be used for the following purposes:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For any activity for the purpose of influencing the passage or defeat of legislation being considered by Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For first class travel for any employee of RFE/RL, Incorporated, or the relative of any employee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on management practices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Effective not later than March 31 and September 30 of each calendar year, the Inspector General of the Department of State and the Foreign Service shall submit to the Agency and the Congress a report on management practices of RFE/RL, Incorporated, under this section. The Inspector General of the Department of State and the Foreign Service shall establish a special unit within the Inspector General’s office to monitor and audit the activities of RFE/RL, Incorporated, and shall provide for on-site monitoring of such activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audit authority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Such financial transactions of RFE/RL, Incorporated, as relate to functions carried out under this section may be audited by the Government Accountability Office in accordance with such principles and procedures and under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the Comptroller General of the United States. Any such audit shall be conducted at the place or places where accounts of RFE/RL, Incorporated, are normally kept.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Representatives of the Government Accountability Office shall have access to all books, accounts, records, reports, files, papers, and property belonging to or in use by RFE/RL, Incorporated pertaining to such financial transactions and necessary to facilitate an audit. Such representatives shall be afforded full facilities for verifying transactions with any assets held by depositories, fiscal agents, and custodians. All such books, accounts, records, reports, files, papers, and property of RFE/RL, Incorporated, shall remain in the possession and custody of RFE/RL, Incorporated.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law and upon repeal of the Board for International Broadcasting Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2871</ref> et seq.], the Inspector General of the Department of State and the Foreign Service is authorized to exercise the authorities of chapter 4 of title 5 with respect to RFE/RL, Incorporated.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 437</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, §§ 1314(d), 1323(<i>l</i>)(1), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–777</ref>, 2681–780; <ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 501, 502, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1392</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1288(5)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2552</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299Q(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4025</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(45)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4348</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. F, title LXVI, § 6602</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 1011</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6208.</num>
<heading> Radio Free Asia</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Grants authorized under <ref>section 6204 of this title</ref> shall be available to make annual grants for the purpose of carrying out radio broadcasting to Asia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Such broadcasting service shall be referred to as “Radio Free Asia”.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Radio Free Asia shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide accurate and timely information, news, and commentary about events in Asia and elsewhere; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> be a forum for a variety of opinions and voices from within Asian nations whose people do not fully enjoy freedom of expression.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant agreement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any grant agreement or grants under this section shall be subject to the following limitations and restrictions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Agency may not make any grant to Radio Free Asia unless the headquarters of Radio Free Asia and its senior administrative and managerial staff are in a location which ensures economy, operational effectiveness, and accountability to the Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any grant agreement under this section shall require that any contract entered into by Radio Free Asia shall specify that all obligations are assumed by Radio Free Asia and not by the United States Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any grant agreement shall require that any lease agreements entered into by Radio Free Asia shall be, to the maximum extent possible, assignable to the United States Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Grants made for the operating costs of Radio Free Asia may not exceed $30,000,000 in each of the fiscal years 2000 and 2001.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Grants awarded under this section shall be made pursuant to a grant agreement which requires that grant funds be used only for activities consistent with this section, and that failure to comply with such requirements shall permit the grant to be terminated without fiscal obligation to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations on administrative and managerial costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that administrative and managerial costs for operation of Radio Free Asia should be kept to a minimum and, to the maximum extent feasible, should not exceed the costs that would have been incurred if Radio Free Asia had been operated as a Federal entity rather than as a grantee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessment of effectiveness of Radio Free Asia</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 3 years after the date on which initial funding is provided for the purpose of operating Radio Free Asia, the Agency shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> whether Radio Free Asia is technically sound and cost-effective,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> whether Radio Free Asia consistently meets the standards for quality and objectivity established by this chapter,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> whether Radio Free Asia is received by a sufficient audience to warrant its continuation,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the extent to which such broadcasting is already being received by the target audience from other credible sources; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the extent to which the interests of the United States are being served by maintaining broadcasting of Radio Free Asia.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification and consultation regarding displacement of Voice of America broadcasting</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Agency shall notify the appropriate congressional committees before—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> entering into any agreements for the utilization of Voice of America transmitters, equipment, or other resources that will significantly reduce the broadcasting activities of the Voice of America in Asia or any other region in order to accommodate the broadcasting activities of Radio Free Asia; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> entering into any agreements in regard to the utilization of Radio Free Asia transmitters, equipment, or other resources that will significantly reduce the broadcasting activities of Radio Free Asia.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chief Executive Officer of the Agency shall consult with such committees on the impact of any such reduction in Voice of America broadcasting activities or Radio Free Asia broadcasting activities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alternative grantee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Chief Executive Officer determines at any time that Radio Free Asia is not carrying out the functions described in this section in an effective and economical manner, the Agency may award the grant to carry out such functions to another entity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Not a Federal agency or instrumentality</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter may be construed to make Radio Free Asia a Federal agency or instrumentality.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 309</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 439</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–415, § 1(s)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4302</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. A, title V, § 501]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–450; <ref>Pub. L. 110–321, § 4</ref>, <date date="2008-09-19">Sept. 19, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3535</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–71, § 1</ref>, <date date="2009-10-09">Oct. 9, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2058</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–202, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-07-13">July 13, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1374</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–323, title VII, § 703(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 1941</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1288(6)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2553</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299Q(e)(4)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4025</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6208a.</num>
<heading> Open Technology Fund</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Grants authorized under <ref>section 6204 of this title</ref> shall be available to make annual grants for the purpose of promoting, consistent with United States law, unrestricted access to uncensored sources of information via the internet to enable journalists, including journalists employed by or affiliated with the Voice of America, Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, Radio Free Asia, the Middle East Broadcasting Networks, the Office of Cuba Broadcasting, or any entity funded by or partnering with the United States Agency for Global Media, to create and disseminate, and for their audiences to receive, news and information consistent with the purposes, standards, and principles specified in sections 6201 and 6202 of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is established a grantee entity to be known as the “Open Technology Fund”, which shall carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions of the grantee</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In furtherance of the mission set forth in subsection (a), the Open Technology Fund shall seek to advance freedom of the press and unrestricted access to the internet in repressive environments oversees, and shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> research, develop, implement, and maintain—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> technologies that circumvent techniques used by authoritarian governments, nonstate actors, and others to block or censor access to the internet, including circumvention tools that bypass internet blocking, filtering, and other censorship techniques used to limit or block legitimate access to content and information; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> secure communication tools and other forms of privacy and security technology that facilitate the creation and distribution of news and enable audiences to access media content on censored websites;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> advance internet freedom by supporting private and public sector research, development, implementation, and maintenance of technologies that provide secure and uncensored access to the internet to counter attempts by authoritarian governments, nonstate actors, and others to improperly restrict freedom online;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> research and analyze emerging technical threats and develop innovative solutions through collaboration with the private and public sectors to maintain the technological advantage of the United States Government over authoritarian governments, nonstate actors, and others;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> develop, acquire, and distribute requisite internet freedom technologies and techniques for the United States Agency for Global Media, including as set forth in paragraph (1), and digital security interventions, to fully enable the creation and distribution of digital content between and to all users and regional audiences;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> prioritize programs for countries the governments of which restrict freedom of expression on the internet, and that are important to the national interest of the United States, and are consistent with section 7050(b)(2)(C) of the Further Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2020 (<ref>Public Law 116–94</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> carry out any other effort consistent with the purposes of this chapter or press freedom overseas if requested or approved by the United States Agency for Global Media.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Methodology</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out subsection (b), the Open Technology Fund shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> support fully open-source tools, code, and components, to the extent practicable, to ensure such supported tools and technologies are as secure, transparent, and accessible as possible, and require that any such tools, components, code, or technology supported by the Open Technology Fund remain fully open-source, to the extent practicable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> support technologies that undergo comprehensive security audits to ensure that such technologies are secure and have not been compromised in a manner detrimental to the interest of the United States or to individuals and organizations benefitting from programs supported by the Open Technology Fund;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> review and update periodically as necessary security auditing procedures used by the Open Technology Fund to reflect current industry security standards;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> establish safeguards to mitigate the use of such supported technologies for illicit purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> solicit project proposals through an open, transparent, and competitive application process to attract innovative applications and reduce barriers to entry;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> seek input from technical, regional, and subject matter experts from a wide range of relevant disciplines, to review, provide feedback, and evaluate proposals to ensure the most competitive projects are funded;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> implement an independent review process, through which proposals are reviewed by such experts to ensure the highest degree of technical review and due diligence;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> maximize cooperation with the public and private sectors, as well as foreign allies and partner countries, to maximize efficiencies and eliminate duplication of efforts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> utilize any other methodology approved by the United States Agency for Global Media in furtherance of the mission of the Open Technology Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant agreement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any grant agreement with or grants made to the Open Technology Fund under this section shall be subject to the following limitations and restrictions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The headquarters of the Open Technology Fund and its senior administrative and managerial staff shall be located in a location which ensures economy, operational effectiveness, and accountability to the United States Agency for Global Media.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Grants awarded under this section shall be made pursuant to a grant agreement which requires that grant funds be used only for activities consistent with this section, and that failure to comply with such requirements shall permit the grant to be terminated without fiscal obligation to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any grant agreement under this section shall require that any contract entered into by the Open Technology Fund shall specify that all obligations are assumed by the grantee and not by the United States Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Any grant agreement under this section shall require that any lease agreements entered into by the Open Technology Fund shall be, to the maximum extent possible, assignable to the United States Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Administrative and managerial costs for operation of the Open Technology Fund should be kept to a minimum and, to the maximum extent feasible, should not exceed the costs that would have been incurred if the Open Technology Fund had been operated as a Federal entity rather than as a grantee.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Grant funds may not be used for any activity the purpose of which is influencing the passage or defeat of legislation considered by Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relationship to the United States Agency for Global Media</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Open Technology Fund shall be subject to the same oversight and governance by the United States Agency for Global Media as other grantees of the Agency as set forth in <ref>section 6204 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The United States Agency for Global Media, its broadcast entities, and the Open Technology Fund should render assistance to each other as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section or any other provision of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Not a Federal agency or instrumentality</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in this section may be construed to make the Open Technology Fund a Federal agency or instrumentality.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Detailees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Under the Intergovernmental Personnel Act [<ref>42 U.S.C. 4701</ref> et seq.], employees of a grantee of the United States Agency for Global Media may be detailed to the Agency, and Federal employees may be detailed to a grantee of the United States Agency for Global Media.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relationship to other United States Government-funded Internet freedom programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States Agency for Global Media shall ensure that internet freedom research and development projects of the Open Technology Fund are coordinated with internet freedom programs of the Department of State and other relevant United States Government departments, in order to share information and best-practices relating to the implementation of subsections (b) and (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Open Technology Fund shall highlight, in its annual report, internet freedom activities, including a comprehensive assessment of the Open Technology Fund’s activities relating to the implementation of subsections (b) and (c). Each such report shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An assessment of the current state of global internet freedom, including trends in censorship and surveillance technologies and internet shutdowns, and the threats such pose to journalists, citizens, and human rights and civil-society organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A description of the technology projects supported by the Open Technology Fund and the associated impact of such projects in the prior year, including the countries and regions in which such technologies were deployed, and any associated metrics indicating audience usage of such technologies, as well as future-year technology project initiatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessment of the effectiveness of the Open Technology Fund</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than two years after <date date="2021-01-01">January 1, 2021</date>, the Inspector General of the Department of State and the Foreign Service shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Whether the Open Technology Fund is technically sound and cost effective.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Whether the Open Technology Fund is satisfying the requirements of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The extent to which the interests of the United States are being served by maintaining the work of the Open Technology Fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audit authorities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Financial transactions of the Open Technology Fund, as such relate to functions carried out under this section, may be audited by the Government Accountability Office in accordance with such principles and procedures and under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the Comptroller General of the United States. Any such audit shall be conducted at the place or places at which accounts of the Open Technology Fund are normally kept.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access by GAO</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Government Accountability Office shall have access to all books, accounts, records, reports, files, papers, and property belonging to or in use by the Open Technology Fund pertaining to financial transactions as may be necessary to facilitate an audit. The Government Accountability Office shall be afforded full facilities for verifying transactions with any assets held by depositories, fiscal agents, and custodians. All such books, accounts, records, reports, files, papers, and property of the Open Technology Fund shall remain in the possession and custody of the Open Technology Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exercise of authorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Inspector General of the Department of State and the Foreign Service is authorized to exercise the authorities of the Inspector General Act of 1978 with respect to the Open Technology Fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 309A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299P(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4016</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6209.</num>
<heading> Incorporation and non-Federal status of broadcasting entities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Defined term</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “grant” includes agreements under <ref>section 6305 of title 31</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “grantee” includes recipients of an agreement described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Incorporation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Chief Executive Officer is authorized to incorporate grantees in accordance with the regular notification procedures of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal status</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter or in any other Act, and no action taken pursuant to this chapter or any other Act, may be construed to make a grantee incorporated pursuant to subsection (b), or any other grantee or entity provided funding by the Agency, a Federal agency or instrumentality.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Leadership of grantee organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The chief executive officer or the equivalent official of RFE/RL Inc., Radio Free Asia, the Open Technology Fund, and the Middle East Broadcasting Networks, and any other organization that is established or authorized under this chapter, shall serve at the pleasure of, and may be named by, the Chief Executive Officer of the Agency, with the concurrence of the Grantee Board and subject to the approval of the Advisory Board pursuant to <ref>section 6205 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 310</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1288(7)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2553</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII</ref>, §§ 1299P(c)(2), (3), 1299Q(e)(5), (f), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4020</ref>, 4025, 4026; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. I, title XCVII, § 9705</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3915</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6209a.</num>
<heading> Inspector General authorities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Inspector General of the Department of State and the Foreign Service shall exercise the same authorities with respect to the United States Agency for Global Media as the Inspector General exercises under the Inspector General Act of 1978 and <ref>section 3929 of this title</ref> with respect to the Department of State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Respect for journalistic integrity of broadcasters</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Inspector General of the Department of State and the Foreign Service shall respect the journalistic integrity of all the broadcasters covered by this chapter and may not evaluate the philosophical or political perspectives reflected in the content of broadcasts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 310A</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1288(7)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2554</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299Q(e)(6)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4025</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6209b.</num>
<heading> Role of the Secretary of State in foreign policy guidance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To assist the Agency in carrying out its functions, the Chief Executive Officer shall regularly consult with and seek from the Secretary of State guidance on foreign policy issues.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 310B</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1288(7)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2554</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299Q(e)(7)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4025</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6210.</num>
<heading> Preservation of American jobs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that the Director of the United States Information Agency and the Chairman of the Board for International Broadcasting should, in developing the plan for consolidation and reorganization of overseas international broadcasting services, limit, to the maximum extent feasible, consistent with the purposes of the consolidation, elimination of any United States-based positions and should affirmatively seek to transfer as many positions as possible to the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 444</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6211.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299Q(e)(8)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4025</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6212.</num>
<heading> Requirement for authorization of appropriations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on obligation and expenditure of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for the fiscal year 1994 and for each subsequent fiscal year, any funds appropriated for the purposes of broadcasting subject to supervision of the Agency shall not be available for obligation or expenditure—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> unless such funds are appropriated pursuant to an authorization of appropriations; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in excess of the authorized level of appropriations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent authorization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The limitation under subsection (a) shall not apply to the extent that an authorization of appropriations is enacted after such funds are appropriated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The provisions of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> may not be superseded, except by a provision of law which specifically repeals, modifies, or supersedes the provisions of this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall not apply to, or affect in any manner, permanent appropriations, trust funds, and other similar accounts which are authorized by law and administered under or pursuant to this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 313</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 444</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. A, title V, § 507(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1394</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299Q(e)(9)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4025</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6213.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the terms “Agency” and “Chief Executive Officer of the Agency” mean the United States Agency for Global Media and the Chief Executive Officer of the United States Agency for Global Media, respectively, and the position, respectively, authorized in accordance with this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “RFE/RL, Incorporated” means the corporation having the corporate title described in <ref>section 6207 of this title</ref> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002337">1</ref></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “salary or other compensation” includes any deferred compensation or pension payments, any payments for expenses for which the recipient is not obligated to itemize, and any payments for personnel services provided to an employee of RFE/RL, Incorporated.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 314</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 445</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1288(8)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 2554</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299Q(e)(10)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4025</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6214.</num>
<heading> Relocation costs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, funds derived from the sale of real property assets of RFE/RL in Munich, Germany, may be retained, obligated, and expended to meet one-time costs associated with the consolidation of United States Government broadcasting activities in accordance with this chapter, including the costs of relocating RFE/RL offices and operations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 315(d)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 103–415, § 1</ref>(<i>ll</i>), <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4303</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6215.</num>
<heading> Establishment of Radio Free Afghanistan</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement of a detailed plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 15 days after <date date="2002-03-11">March 11, 2002</date>, RFE/RL, Incorporated, shall submit to the Broadcasting Board of Governors a report setting forth a detailed plan for the provision by RFE/RL, Incorporated, of surrogate broadcasting services in the Dari and Pashto languages to Afghanistan. Such broadcasting services shall be known as “Radio Free Afghanistan”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grant authority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Effective 15 days after <date date="2002-03-11">March 11, 2002</date>, or the date on which the report required by subsection (a) is submitted, whichever is later, the Broadcasting Board of Governors is authorized to make grants to support Radio Free Afghanistan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supersedes existing limitation on total annual grant amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Grants made to RFE/RL, Incorporated, during the fiscal year 2002 for support of Radio Free Afghanistan may be made without regard to section 308(c) of the United States International Broadcasting Act of 1994 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 6207(c)</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Available authorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the authorities in this section, the authorities applicable to carry out United States Government broadcasting activities under the United States Information and Educational Exchange Act of 1948 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1431</ref> et seq.], the United States International Broadcasting Act of 1994 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 6201</ref> et seq.], the Foreign Affairs Reform and Restructuring Act of 1998, and other provisions of law consistent with such purpose may be used to carry out the grant authority of subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Standards; oversight</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Radio Free Afghanistan shall adhere to the same standards of professionalism and accountability, and shall be subject to the same oversight mechanisms, as other services of RFE/RL, Incorporated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–148, § 2</ref>, <date date="2002-03-11">Mar. 11, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 64</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6216.</num>
<heading> Special authority for surge capacity</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Emergency authority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Whenever the President determines it to be important to the national interests of the United States and so certifies to the appropriate congressional committees, the President, on such terms and conditions as the President may determine, is authorized to direct any department, agency, or other entity of the United States to furnish the United States Agency for Global Media with such assistance outside the United States as may be necessary to provide international broadcasting activities of the United States with a surge capacity to support United States foreign policy objectives during a crisis abroad.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supersedes existing law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The authority of paragraph (1) shall supersede any other provision of law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Surge capacity defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “surge capacity” means the financial and technical resources necessary to carry out broadcasting activities in a geographical area during a crisis abroad.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President is authorized to exercise the authority provided in subsection (a)(1) for a period of up to six months, which may be renewed for one additional six month period.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to the President such sums as may be necessary for the President to carry out this section, except that no such amount may be appropriated which, when added to amounts previously appropriated for such purpose but not yet obligated, would cause such amounts to exceed $25,000,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations in this subsection are authorized to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations in this subsection may be referred to as the “United States International Broadcasting Surge Capacity Fund”.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The annual report submitted to the President and Congress by the United States Agency for Global Media under <ref>section 6204(a)(9) of this title</ref> shall provide a detailed description of any activities carried out under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 316</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 110–53, title XX, § 2031(c)</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 516</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299Q(e)(11)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 4026</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6217.</num>
<heading> Global internet freedom</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statement of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States to promote internet freedom through programs of the Department and USAID that preserve and expand the internet as an open, global space for freedom of expression and association, which shall be prioritized for countries—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> whose governments restrict freedom of expression on the internet; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that are important to the national interest of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose and coordination with other programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Global internet freedom programming under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> shall be coordinated with other United States foreign assistance programs that promote democracy and support the efforts of civil society—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to counter the development of repressive internet-related laws and regulations, including countering threats to internet freedom at international organizations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to combat violence against bloggers and other civil society activists who utilize the internet; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to enhance digital security training and capacity building for democracy activists;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> shall seek to assist efforts—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to research key threats to internet freedom;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to continue the development of technologies that provide or enhance access to the internet, including circumvention tools that bypass internet blocking, filtering, and other censorship techniques used by authoritarian governments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to maintain the technological advantage of the Federal Government over the censorship techniques described in subparagraph (B); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall be incorporated into country assistance and democracy promotion strategies, as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2023—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> $75,000,000 to the Department and USAID, to continue efforts to promote internet freedom globally, and shall be matched, to the maximum extent practicable, by sources other than the Federal Government, including the private sector; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> $49,000,000 to the United States Agency for Global Media (referred to in this section as the “USAGM”) and its grantees, for internet freedom and circumvention technologies that are designed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for open-source tools and techniques to securely develop and distribute digital content produced by the USAGM and its grantees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to facilitate audience access to such digital content on websites that are censored;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to coordinate the distribution of such digital content to targeted regional audiences; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to promote and distribute such tools and techniques, including digital security techniques.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States Agency for Global Media activities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual certification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For any new tools or techniques authorized under subsection (c)(2), the Chief Executive Officer of the USAGM, in consultation with the President of the Open Technology Fund (referred to in this subsection as the “OTF”) and relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall submit an annual certification to the appropriate congressional committees that verifies they—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have evaluated the risks and benefits of such new tools or techniques; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> have established safeguards to minimize the use of such new tools or techniques for illicit purposes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information sharing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may not direct programs or policy of the USAGM or the OTF, but may share any research and development with relevant Federal departments and agencies for the exclusive purposes of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sharing information, technologies, and best practices; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> assessing the effectiveness of such technologies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States Agency for Global Media</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Chief Executive Officer of the USAGM, in consultation with the President of the OTF, shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> coordinate international broadcasting programs and incorporate such programs into country broadcasting strategies, as appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> solicit project proposals through an open, transparent, and competitive application process, including by seeking input from technical and subject matter experts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> support internet circumvention tools and techniques for audiences in countries that are strategic priorities for the OTF, in accordance with USAGM’s annual language service prioritization review.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> USAGM report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 120 days after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, the Chief Executive Office of the USAGM shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that describes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> as of the date of the report—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the full scope of internet freedom programs within the USAGM, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the efforts of the Office of Internet Freedom; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the efforts of the Open Technology Fund;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the capacity of internet censorship circumvention tools supported by the Office of Internet Freedom and grantees of the Open Technology Fund that are available for use by individuals in foreign countries seeking to counteract censors; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any barriers to the provision of the efforts described in clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (A), including access to surge funding; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> successful examples from the Office of Internet Freedom and Open Technology Fund involving—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> responding rapidly to internet shutdowns in closed societies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensuring uninterrupted circumvention services for USAGM entities to promote internet freedom within repressive regimes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, the Secretary and the Administrator of USAID shall jointly submit a report, which may include a classified annex, to the appropriate congressional committees that describes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> as of the date of the report—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the full scope of internet freedom programs within the Department and USAID, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Department circumvention efforts; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> USAID efforts to support internet infrastructure;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the capacity of internet censorship circumvention tools supported by the Federal Government that are available for use by individuals in foreign countries seeking to counteract censors; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any barriers to provision of the efforts enumerated in clauses (i) and (ii) of subsection (e)(1)(A), including access to surge funding; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> any new resources needed to provide the Federal Government with greater capacity to provide and boost internet access—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to respond rapidly to internet shutdowns in closed societies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to provide internet connectivity to foreign locations where the provision of additional internet access service would promote freedom from repressive regimes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Security audits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Before providing any support for open source technologies under this section, such technologies must undergo comprehensive security audits to ensure that such technologies are secure and have not been compromised in a manner that is detrimental to the interest of the United States or to the interests of individuals and organizations benefitting from programs supported by such funding.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Surge</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), there is authorized to be appropriated, in addition to amounts otherwise made available for such purposes, up to $2,500,000 to support internet freedom programs in closed societies, including programs that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> are carried out in crisis situations by vetted entities that are already engaged in internet freedom programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> involve circumvention tools; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> increase the overseas bandwidth for companies that received Federal funding during the previous fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts authorized to be appropriated pursuant to paragraph (1) may not be expended until the Secretary has certified to the appropriate congressional committees, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives that the use of such funds is in the national interest of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Defined term</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “internet censorship circumvention tool” means a software application or other tool that an individual can use to evade foreign government restrictions on internet access.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. I, title XCVII, § 9707</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3915</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>