<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 85—</num>
<heading>NORTH KOREAN HUMAN RIGHTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7801.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> According to the Department of State, the Government of North Korea is “a dictatorship under the absolute rule of Kim Jong Il” that continues to commit numerous, serious human rights abuses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Government of North Korea attempts to control all information, artistic expression, academic works, and media activity inside North Korea and strictly curtails freedom of speech and access to foreign broadcasts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Government of North Korea subjects all its citizens to systematic, intensive political and ideological indoctrination in support of the cult of personality glorifying Kim Jong Il and the late Kim Il Sung that approaches the level of a state religion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Government of North Korea divides its population into categories, based on perceived loyalty to the leadership, which determines access to food, employment, higher education, place of residence, medical facilities, and other resources.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> According to the Department of State, “[t]he [North Korean] Penal Code is [d]raconian, stipulating capital punishment and confiscation of assets for a wide variety of ‘crimes against the revolution,’ including defection, attempted defection, slander of the policies of the Party or State, listening to foreign broadcasts, writing ‘reactionary’ letters, and possessing reactionary printed matter”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Government of North Korea executes political prisoners, opponents of the regime, some repatriated defectors, some members of underground churches, and others, sometimes at public meetings attended by workers, students, and schoolchildren.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The Government of North Korea holds an estimated 200,000 political prisoners in camps that its State Security Agency manages through the use of forced labor, beatings, torture, and executions, and in which many prisoners also die from disease, starvation, and exposure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> According to eyewitness testimony provided to the United States Congress by North Korean camp survivors, camp inmates have been used as sources of slave labor for the production of export goods, as targets for martial arts practice, and as experimental victims in the testing of chemical and biological poisons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> According to credible reports, including eyewitness testimony provided to the United States Congress, North Korean Government officials prohibit live births in prison camps, and forced abortion and the killing of newborn babies are standard prison practices.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> According to the Department of State, “[g]enuine religious freedom does not exist in North Korea” and, according to the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom, “[t]he North Korean state severely represses public and private religious activities” with penalties that reportedly include arrest, imprisonment, torture, and sometimes execution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> More than 2,000,000 North Koreans are estimated to have died of starvation since the early 1990s because of the failure of the centralized agricultural and public distribution systems operated by the Government of North Korea.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> According to a 2002 United Nations-European Union survey, nearly one out of every ten children in North Korea suffers from acute malnutrition and four out of every ten children in North Korea are chronically malnourished.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> Since 1995, the United States has provided more than 2,000,000 tons of humanitarian food assistance to the people of North Korea, primarily through the World Food Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> Although United States food assistance has undoubtedly saved many North Korean lives and there have been minor improvements in transparency relating to the distribution of such assistance in North Korea, the Government of North Korea continues to deny the World Food Program forms of access necessary to properly monitor the delivery of food aid, including the ability to conduct random site visits, the use of native Korean-speaking employees, and travel access throughout North Korea.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> The risk of starvation, the threat of persecution, and the lack of freedom and opportunity in North Korea have caused large numbers, perhaps even hundreds of thousands, of North Koreans to flee their homeland, primarily into China.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> North Korean women and girls, particularly those who have fled into China, are at risk of being kidnapped, trafficked, and sexually exploited inside China, where many are sold as brides or concubines, or forced to work as prostitutes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> The Governments of China and North Korea have been conducting aggressive campaigns to locate North Koreans who are in China without permission and to forcibly return them to North Korea, where they routinely face torture and imprisonment, and sometimes execution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> Despite China’s obligations as a party to the 1951 United Nations Convention Relating to the Status of Refugees and the 1967 Protocol Relating to the Status of Refugees, China routinely classifies North Koreans seeking asylum in China as mere “economic migrants” and returns them to North Korea without regard to the serious threat of persecution they face upon their return.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> The Government of China does not provide North Koreans whose asylum requests are rejected a right to have the rejection reviewed prior to deportation despite its obligations under the 1951 United Nations Convention Relating to the Status of Refugees and the 1967 Protocol Relating to the Status of Refugees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<content> North Koreans who seek asylum while in China are routinely imprisoned and tortured, and in some cases killed, after they are returned to North Korea.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<content> The Government of China has detained, convicted, and imprisoned foreign aid workers attempting to assist North Korean refugees in proceedings that did not comply with Chinese law or international standards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<content> In January 2000, North Korean agents inside China allegedly abducted the Reverend Kim Dong-shik, a United States permanent resident and advocate for North Korean refugees, whose condition and whereabouts remain unknown.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(23)</num>
<content> Between 1994 and 2003, South Korea has admitted approximately 3,800 North Korean refugees for domestic resettlement, a number that is small in comparison with the total number of North Korean escapees but far greater than the number legally admitted in any other country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(24)</num>
<content> Although the principal responsibility for North Korean refugee resettlement naturally falls to the Government of South Korea, the United States should play a leadership role in focusing international attention on the plight of these refugees, and formulating international solutions to that profound humanitarian dilemma.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(25)</num>
<content> In addition to infringing the rights of its own citizens, the Government of North Korea has been responsible in years past for the abduction of numerous citizens of South Korea and Japan, whose condition and whereabouts remain unknown.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–333, § 3</ref>, <date date="2004-10-18">Oct. 18, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1287</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7802.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to promote respect for and protection of fundamental human rights in North Korea;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to promote a more durable humanitarian solution to the plight of North Korean refugees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to promote increased monitoring, access, and transparency in the provision of humanitarian assistance inside North Korea;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to promote the free flow of information into and out of North Korea; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to promote progress toward the peaceful reunification of the Korean peninsula under a democratic system of government.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–333, § 4</ref>, <date date="2004-10-18">Oct. 18, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1290</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7803.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> China</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “China” means the People’s Republic of China.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Humanitarian assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “humanitarian assistance” means assistance to meet humanitarian needs, including needs for food, medicine, medical supplies, clothing, and shelter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> North Korea</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “North Korea” means the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> North Koreans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “North Koreans” means persons who are citizens or nationals of North Korea.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> South Korea</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “South Korea” means the Republic of Korea.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–333, § 5</ref>, <date date="2004-10-18">Oct. 18, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1290</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–346, § 4</ref>, <date date="2008-10-07">Oct. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3941</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>PROMOTING THE HUMAN RIGHTS OF NORTH KOREANS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7811.</num>
<heading> Sense of Congress regarding negotiations with North Korea</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that the human rights of North Koreans should remain a key element in future negotiations between the United States, North Korea, and other concerned parties in Northeast Asia.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–333, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2004-10-18">Oct. 18, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1290</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7812.</num>
<heading> Support for human rights and democracy programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Support</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is authorized to provide grants to private, nonprofit organizations to support programs that promote human rights, democracy, rule of law, and the development of a market economy in North Korea. Such programs may include appropriate educational and cultural exchange programs with North Korean participants, to the extent not otherwise prohibited by law. The President is also authorized to provide grants to entities to undertake research on North Korea’s denial of human rights, including on the political and military chains of command responsible for authorizing and implementing systemic human rights abuses, including at prison camps and detention facilities where political prisoners are held.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to the President $2,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2005 through 2008 and $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2009 through 2022 to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under paragraph (1) are authorized to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–333, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2004-10-18">Oct. 18, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1290</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–346, § 5</ref>, <date date="2008-10-07">Oct. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3941</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–172, § 4</ref>, <date date="2012-08-16">Aug. 16, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1308</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–198, § 7(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-07-20">July 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1523</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7813.</num>
<heading> Radio broadcasting to North Korea</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that the United States should—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> facilitate the unhindered dissemination of information in North Korea by increasing its support for broadcasting, including news rebroadcasting, to North Korea, and that the Broadcasting Board of Governors should increase such broadcasts, including news rebroadcasts, to North Korea from current levels, with a goal of providing 12-hour-per-day broadcasting to North Korea, including broadcasts by Radio Free Asia and Voice of America; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> expand funding for nongovernmental organization broadcasting efforts, prioritizing organizations that engage North Korean defectors in programming and broadcast services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 120 days after <date date="2004-10-18">October 18, 2004</date>, the Broadcasting Board of Governors shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> describes the status of current United States broadcasting to North Korea; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> outlines a plan for increasing such broadcasts to 12 hours per day, including a detailed description of the technical and fiscal requirements necessary to implement the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–333, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2004-10-18">Oct. 18, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1291</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–198, § 4</ref>, <date date="2018-07-20">July 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1521</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7814.</num>
<heading> Actions to promote freedom of information</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President is authorized to take such actions as may be necessary to increase the availability of information inside North Korea by increasing the availability of sources of information not controlled by the Government of North Korea, including sources such as radios capable of receiving broadcasting from outside North Korea, USB drives, micro SD cards, audio players, video players, cell phones, wi-fi, wireless internet, web pages, internet, wireless telecommunications, and other electronic media that shares information.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In accordance with the sense of Congress described in <ref>section 7813 of this title</ref>, the President, acting through the Secretary of State, is authorized to distribute or provide grants to distribute information receiving devices, electronically readable devices, and other informational sources into North Korea, including devices and informational sources specified in paragraph (1). To carry out this paragraph, the President is authorized to issue regulations to facilitate the free-flow of information into North Korea.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Research and development grant program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In accordance with the authorization described in paragraphs (1) and (2) to increase the availability and distribution of sources of information inside North Korea, the President, acting through the Secretary of State, is authorized to establish a grant program to make grants to eligible entities to develop or distribute (or both) new products or methods to allow North Koreans easier access to outside information. Such program may involve public-private partnerships.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Culture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In accordance with the sense of Congress described in <ref>section 7813 of this title</ref>, the Broadcasting Board of Governors may broadcast American, Korean, Chinese, and other popular music, television, movies, and popular cultural references as part of its programming.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rights and laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In accordance with the sense of Congress described in <ref>section 7813 of this title</ref>, the Broadcasting Board of Governors should broadcast to North Korea in the Korean language information on rights, laws, and freedoms afforded through the North Korean Constitution, the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, the United Nations Commission of Inquiry on Human Rights in the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea, and any other applicable treaties or international agreements to which North Korea is bound.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Religious minorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Efforts to improve information access under this subsection should include religious communities and should be coordinated with the Office of International Religious Freedom to ensure maximum impact in improving the rights of religious persons in North Korea.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Broadcasting report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 180 days after <date date="2018-07-20">July 20, 2018</date>, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Broadcasting Board of Governors, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that sets forth a detailed plan for improving broadcasting content for the purpose of targeting new audiences and increasing listenership; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau><date date="2022-09-30">September 30, 2022</date>, and annually thereafter for each of the next 5 years, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Chief Executive Officer of the United States Agency for Global Media, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a description of the effectiveness of actions taken pursuant to this section and sections 5583 and 5584 of the Otto Warmbier Countering North Korean Censorship and Surveillance Act of 2022, including data reflecting audience and listenership, device distribution and usage, and technological development and advancement usage;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the amount of funds expended by the United States Government pursuant to section 403; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002391">1</ref> and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> other appropriate information necessary to fully inform Congress of efforts related to this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to the President $3,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2005 through 2022 to carry out subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under paragraph (1) are authorized to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2004-10-18">October 18, 2004</date>, and annually through 2022, the Secretary of State, after consultation with the heads of other appropriate Federal departments and agencies, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report, in classified form, on actions taken pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information technology study</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the North Korea Sanctions and Policy Enhancement Act of 2015,<sup>1</sup> the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a classified report that sets forth a detailed plan for making unrestricted, unmonitored, and inexpensive electronic mass communications available to the people of North Korea.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–333, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2004-10-18">Oct. 18, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1291</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–346, § 7</ref>, <date date="2008-10-07">Oct. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3941</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–172, § 6</ref>, <date date="2012-08-16">Aug. 16, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1309</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–122, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2016-02-18">Feb. 18, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 112</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–198</ref>, §§ 5, 7(b), <date date="2018-07-20">July 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1521</ref>, 1523; <ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LV, § 5584(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3373</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7815.</num>
<heading> United Nations Commission on Human Rights</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that the United Nations has a significant role to play in promoting and improving human rights in North Korea, and that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the United Nations Commission on Human Rights (UNCHR) has taken positive steps by adopting Resolution 2003/10 and Resolution 2004/13 on the situation of human rights in North Korea, and particularly by requesting the appointment of a Special Rapporteur on the situation of human rights in North Korea; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the severe human rights violations within North Korea warrant country-specific attention and reporting by the United Nations Working Group on Arbitrary Detention, the Working Group on Enforced and Involuntary Disappearances, the Special Rapporteur on Extrajudicial, Summary, or Arbitrary Executions, the Special Rapporteur on the Right to Food, the Special Rapporteur on the Promotion and Protection of the Right to Freedom of Opinion and Expression, the Special Rapporteur on Freedom of Religion or Belief, and the Special Rapporteur on Violence Against Women.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–333, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="2004-10-18">Oct. 18, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1291</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7816.</num>
<heading> Establishment of regional framework</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Congress finds that human rights initiatives can be undertaken on a multilateral basis, such as the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), which established a regional framework for discussing human rights, scientific and educational cooperation, and economic and trade issues.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that the United Sates <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002392">1</ref> should explore the possibility of a regional human rights dialogue with North Korea that is modeled on the Helsinki process, engaging all countries in the region in a common commitment to respect human rights and fundamental freedoms.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–333, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="2004-10-18">Oct. 18, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1292</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7817.</num>
<heading> Special Envoy on North Korean human rights issues</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special Envoy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall appoint a special envoy for North Korean human rights issues within the Department of State (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Special Envoy”), by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Special Envoy should be a person of recognized distinction in the field of human rights who shall have the rank of ambassador and shall hold the office at the pleasure of the President.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Central objective</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The central objective of the Special Envoy is to coordinate and promote efforts to improve respect for the fundamental human rights of the people of North Korea, including, in coordination with the Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration, the protection of those people who have fled as refugees.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duties and responsibilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Special Envoy shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> participate in the formulation and the implementation of activities carried out pursuant to this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> engage in discussions with North Korean officials regarding human rights;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> support international efforts to promote human rights and political freedoms in North Korea, including coordination and dialogue between the United States and the United Nations, the European Union, North Korea, and the other countries in Northeast Asia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> consult with non-governmental organizations who have attempted to address human rights in North Korea;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> make recommendations regarding the funding of activities authorized in sections 7812 and 7814 of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> review strategies for improving protection of human rights in North Korea, including technical training and exchange programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> develop an action plan for supporting implementation of the United Nations Commission on Human Rights Resolution 2004/13.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2004-10-18">October 18, 2004</date>, and annually thereafter through 2022, the Special Envoy shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the activities undertaken in the preceding 12 months under subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–333, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="2004-10-18">Oct. 18, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1292</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–346, § 8</ref>, <date date="2008-10-07">Oct. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3941</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–172, § 7</ref>, <date date="2012-08-16">Aug. 16, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1309</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–198, § 7(c)</ref>, <date date="2018-07-20">July 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1523</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>ASSISTING NORTH KOREANS IN NEED</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7831.</num>
<heading> Report on United States humanitarian assistance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2004-10-18">October 18, 2004</date>, and annually thereafter through 2022, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, in conjunction with the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that describes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> all activities to provide humanitarian assistance inside North Korea, and to North Koreans outside of North Korea, that receive United States funding;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any improvements in humanitarian transparency, monitoring, and access inside North Korea during the previous 1-year period, including progress toward meeting the conditions identified in subparagraphs (A) through (D) of <ref>section 7832(b)(1) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> specific efforts to secure improved humanitarian transparency, monitoring, and access inside North Korea made by the United States and United States grantees, including the World Food Program, during the previous 1-year period.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Needs assessment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The report shall include a needs assessment to inform the distribution of humanitarian assistance inside North Korea.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The information required by subsection (a)(1) may be provided in classified form if necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–333, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2004-10-18">Oct. 18, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1293</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. D, title V, § 534(j)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3007</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–346, § 9</ref>, <date date="2008-10-07">Oct. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3942</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–172, § 8</ref>, <date date="2012-08-16">Aug. 16, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1309</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–198, § 7(d)</ref>, <date date="2018-07-20">July 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1523</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7832.</num>
<heading> Assistance provided inside North Korea</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Humanitarian assistance through nongovernmental and international organizations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> at the same time that Congress supports the provision of humanitarian assistance to the people of North Korea on humanitarian grounds, such assistance also should be provided and monitored so as to minimize the possibility that such assistance could be diverted to political or military use, and to maximize the likelihood that it will reach the most vulnerable North Koreans;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> significant increases above current levels of United States support for humanitarian assistance provided inside North Korea should be conditioned upon substantial improvements in transparency, monitoring, and access to vulnerable populations throughout North Korea; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the United States should encourage other countries that provide food and other humanitarian assistance to North Korea to do so through monitored, transparent channels, rather than through direct, bilateral transfers to the Government of North Korea.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States assistance to the government of North Korea</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> United States humanitarian assistance to any department, agency, or entity of the Government of North Korea shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> be delivered, distributed, and monitored according to internationally recognized humanitarian standards;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be provided on a needs basis, and not used as a political reward or tool of coercion;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> reach the intended beneficiaries, who should be informed of the source of the assistance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> be made available to all vulnerable groups in North Korea, no matter where in the country they may be located; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> United States nonhumanitarian assistance to North Korea shall be contingent on North Korea’s substantial progress toward—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> respect for the basic human rights of the people of North Korea, including freedom of religion;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> providing for family reunification between North Koreans and their descendants and relatives in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> fully disclosing all information regarding citizens of Japan and the Republic of Korea abducted by the Government of North Korea;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> allowing such abductees, along with their families, complete and genuine freedom to leave North Korea and return to the abductees’ original home countries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> reforming the North Korean prison and labor camp system, and subjecting such reforms to independent international monitoring; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> decriminalizing political expression and activity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2004-10-18">October 18, 2004</date>, the Administrator of the Agency for International Development shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing compliance with this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–333, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2004-10-18">Oct. 18, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1293</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7833.</num>
<heading> Assistance provided outside of North Korea</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is authorized to provide assistance to support organizations or persons that provide humanitarian assistance to North Koreans who are outside of North Korea without the permission of the Government of North Korea.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Types of assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Assistance provided under subsection (a) should be used to provide—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> humanitarian assistance to North Korean refugees, defectors, migrants, and orphans outside of North Korea, which may include support for refugee camps or temporary settlements; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> humanitarian assistance to North Korean women outside of North Korea who are victims of trafficking, as defined in section 7102(15) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002393">1</ref> of this title, or are in danger of being trafficked.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to funds otherwise available for such purposes, there are authorized to be appropriated to the President $5,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2022 to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under paragraph (1) are authorized to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–333, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2004-10-18">Oct. 18, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1294</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–346, § 10</ref>, <date date="2008-10-07">Oct. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3942</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–172, § 9</ref>, <date date="2012-08-16">Aug. 16, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1309</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–4, title XII, § 1212(b)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref>127 Stat. 144</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–198, § 7(e)</ref>, <date date="2018-07-20">July 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1524</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7834.</num>
<heading> Briefings on the welfare of North Korean children</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall designate a representative to regularly brief the appropriate congressional committees in an unclassified setting on United States Government efforts to advocate for the best interests of North Korean children and children of one North Korean parent, including efforts to address, when appropriate, the adoption of such children living outside North Korea without parental care.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary’s designee shall be prepared to address in each briefing the following topics:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The analysis of the Department of State of the challenges facing North Korean children residing outside North Korea and challenges facing children of one North Korean parent in other countries who are fleeing persecution or are living as de jure or de facto stateless persons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Department of State efforts to advocate for the best interest of North Korean children residing outside North Korea or children of one North Korean parent living in other countries who are fleeing persecution or are living as de jure or de facto stateless persons, including, when possible, efforts to address the immediate care and family reunification of these children, and, in individual cases where appropriate, the adoption of eligible North Korean children living outside North Korea and children of one North Korean parent living outside North Korea.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Department of State efforts to develop a comprehensive strategy to address challenges that United States citizens would encounter in attempting to adopt, via intercountry adoption, North Korean-origin children residing in other countries or children of one North Korean parent residing outside North Korea who are fleeing persecution or are living as de jure or de facto stateless persons, including efforts to overcome the complexities involved in determining jurisdiction for best interest determinations and adoption processing, if appropriate, of those who habitually reside in a Hague country or a non-Hague country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Department of State diplomatic efforts to encourage countries in which North Korean children or children of one North Korean parent are fleeing persecution or reside as de jure or de facto stateless persons to resolve issues of statelessness of North Koreans residing in that country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Department of State efforts to work with the Government of the Republic of Korea to establish pilot programs that identify, provide for the immediate care of, and assist in the family reunification of North Korean children and children of one North Korean parent living within South Korea and other countries who are fleeing persecution or are living as de jure or de facto stateless persons.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 112–264, § 4</ref>, <date date="2013-01-14">Jan. 14, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2432</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>PROTECTING NORTH KOREAN REFUGEES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7841.</num>
<heading> United States policy toward refugees and defectors</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 120 days after <date date="2004-10-18">October 18, 2004</date>, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the heads of other appropriate Federal departments and agencies, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report that describes the situation of North Korean refugees and explains United States Government policy toward North Korean nationals outside of North Korea.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The report shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an assessment of the circumstances facing North Korean refugees and migrants in hiding, particularly in China, and of the circumstances they face if forcibly returned to North Korea;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an assessment of whether North Koreans in China have effective access to personnel of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees, and of whether the Government of China is fulfilling its obligations under the 1951 Convention Relating to the Status of Refugees, particularly Articles 31, 32, and 33 of such Convention;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an assessment of whether North Koreans presently have unobstructed access to United States refugee and asylum processing, and of United States policy toward North Koreans who may present themselves at United States embassies or consulates and request protection as refugees or asylum seekers and resettlement in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the total number of North Koreans who have been admitted into the United States as refugees or asylees in each of the past 5 years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> an estimate of the number of North Koreans with family connections to United States citizens; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a description of the measures that the Secretary of State is taking to carry out <ref>section 7843 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The information required by paragraphs (1) through (5) of subsection (b) shall be provided in unclassified form. All or part of the information required by subsection (b)(6) may be provided in classified form, if necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–333, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2004-10-18">Oct. 18, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1295</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7842.</num>
<heading> Eligibility for refugee or asylum consideration</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The purpose of this section is to clarify that North Koreans are not barred from eligibility for refugee status or asylum in the United States on account of any legal right to citizenship they may enjoy under the Constitution of the Republic of Korea. It is not intended in any way to prejudice whatever rights to citizenship North Koreans may enjoy under the Constitution of the Republic of Korea, or to apply to former North Korean nationals who have availed themselves of those rights.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of nationals of North Korea</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of eligibility for refugee status under <ref>section 1157 of title 8</ref>, or for asylum under <ref>section 1158 of title 8</ref>, a national of the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea shall not be considered a national of the Republic of Korea.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–333, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="2004-10-18">Oct. 18, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1295</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7843.</num>
<heading> Facilitating submission of applications for admission as a refugee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall undertake to facilitate the submission of applications under <ref>section 1157 of title 8</ref> by citizens of North Korea seeking protection as refugees (as defined in <ref>section 1101(a)(42) of title 8</ref>).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–333, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="2004-10-18">Oct. 18, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1296</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7844.</num>
<heading> United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actions in China</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Government of China has obligated itself to provide the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) with unimpeded access to North Koreans inside its borders to enable the UNHCR to determine whether they are refugees and whether they require assistance, pursuant to the 1951 United Nations Convention Relating to the Status of Refugees, the 1967 Protocol Relating to the Status of Refugees, and Article III, paragraph 5 of the 1995 Agreement on the Upgrading of the UNHCR Mission in the People’s Republic of China to UNHCR Branch Office in the People’s Republic of China (referred to in this section as the “UNHCR Mission Agreement”);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the United States, other UNHCR donor governments, and UNHCR should persistently and at the highest levels continue to urge the Government of China to abide by its previous commitments to allow UNHCR unimpeded access to North Korean refugees inside China;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the UNHCR, in order to effectively carry out its mandate to protect refugees, should liberally employ as professionals or Experts on Mission persons with significant experience in humanitarian assistance work among displaced North Koreans in China;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the UNHCR, in order to effectively carry out its mandate to protect refugees, should liberally contract with appropriate nongovernmental organizations that have a proven record of providing humanitarian assistance to displaced North Koreans in China;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the UNHCR should pursue a multilateral agreement to adopt an effective “first asylum” policy that guarantees safe haven and assistance to North Korean refugees; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> should the Government of China begin actively fulfilling its obligations toward North Korean refugees, all countries, including the United States, and relevant international organizations should increase levels of humanitarian assistance provided inside China to help defray costs associated with the North Korean refugee presence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Arbitration proceedings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is further the sense of Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> if the Government of China continues to refuse to provide the UNHCR with access to North Koreans within its borders, the UNHCR should initiate arbitration proceedings pursuant to Article XVI of the UNHCR Mission Agreement and appoint an arbitrator for the UNHCR; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> because access to refugees is essential to the UNHCR mandate and to the purpose of a UNHCR branch office, a failure to assert those arbitration rights in present circumstances would constitute a significant abdication by the UNHCR of one of its core responsibilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–333, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="2004-10-18">Oct. 18, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1296</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7845.</num>
<heading> Annual reports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Immigration and refugee information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2004-10-18">October 18, 2004</date>, and every 12 months thereafter through 2022, the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit a joint report to the appropriate congressional committees and the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate on the operation of this subchapter during the previous year, which shall include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The number of aliens who are nationals or citizens of North Korea who applied for political asylum and the number who were granted political asylum.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The number of aliens who are nationals or citizens of North Korea who applied for refugee status and the number who were granted refugee status.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A detailed description of the measures undertaken by the Secretary of State to carry out <ref>section 7843 of this title</ref>, including country-specific information with respect to United States efforts to secure the cooperation and permission of the governments of countries in East and Southeast Asia to facilitate United States processing of North Koreans seeking protection as refugees. The information required under this paragraph shall be provided in unclassified form, with a classified annex, if necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Countries of particular concern</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall include in each annual report on proposed refugee admission pursuant to <ref>section 1157(d) of title 8</ref>, information about specific measures taken to facilitate access to the United States refugee program for individuals who have fled countries of particular concern for violations of religious freedom, identified pursuant to <ref>section 6442(b) of this title</ref>. The report shall include, for each country of particular concern, a description of access of the nationals or former habitual residents of that country to a refugee determination on the basis of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> referrals by external agencies to a refugee adjudication;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> groups deemed to be of special humanitarian concern to the United States for purposes of refugee resettlement; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> family links to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–333, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="2004-10-18">Oct. 18, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1297</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–346, § 11</ref>, <date date="2008-10-07">Oct. 7, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3942</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–172, § 10</ref>, <date date="2012-08-16">Aug. 16, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1309</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–198, § 7(f)</ref>, <date date="2018-07-20">July 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1524</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7846.</num>
<heading> Sense of Congress on humanitarian coordination related to the Korean Peninsula</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any instability on the Korean Peninsula could have significant humanitarian and strategic impact on the region and for United States national interests; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> as such, the United States Government should work with countries sharing a land or maritime border with North Korea to develop long-term whole-of-government plans to coordinate efforts related to humanitarian assistance and human rights promotion and to effectively assimilate North Korean defectors.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–333, title III, § 306</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 115–198, § 6</ref>, <date date="2018-07-20">July 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1523</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>