<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 98—</num>
<heading>INTERNATIONAL CHILD ABDUCTION PREVENTION AND RETURN</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9101.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Abducted child</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “abducted child” means a child who is the victim of international child abduction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Abduction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “abduction” means the alleged wrongful removal of a child from the child’s country of habitual residence, or the wrongful retention of a child outside such country, in violation of a left-behind parent’s custodial rights, including the rights of a military parent.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Abduction case</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term abduction case <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002423">1</ref> means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> a case that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> has been reported to the Central Authority of the United States by a left-behind parent for the resolution of an abduction;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> meets the criteria for an international child abduction under the Hague Abduction Convention, regardless of whether the country at issue is a Convention country; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes any case reported involving an application filed with the Central Authority of the United States or directly with the foreign central authority by a parent seeking rights of access or return.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access case</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “access case” means a case involving an application filed with the Central Authority of the United States by a parent seeking rights of access.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Annual Report” means the Annual Report on International Child Abduction required under <ref>section 9111 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “application” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a Convention country, the application required pursuant to article 8 of the Hague Abduction Convention;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a bilateral procedures country, the formal document required, pursuant to the provisions of the applicable arrangement, to request the return of an abducted child or to request rights of access, as applicable; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of a non-Convention country, the formal request by the Central Authority of the United States to the Central Authority of such country requesting the return of an abducted child or for rights of contact with an abducted child.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bilateral procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “bilateral procedures” means any procedures established by, or pursuant to, a bilateral arrangement, including a Memorandum of Understanding between the United States and another country, to resolve abduction and access cases, including procedures to address interim contact matters.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bilateral procedures country</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “bilateral procedures country” means a country with which the United States has entered into bilateral procedures, including Memoranda of Understanding, with respect to child abductions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Central Authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Central Authority” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a Convention country, the meaning given such term in article 6 of the Hague Abduction Convention;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a bilateral procedures country, the official entity designated by the government of the bilateral procedures country within the applicable memorandum of understanding pursuant to <ref>section 9113(b)(1) of this title</ref> to discharge the duties imposed on the entity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of a non-Convention country, the foreign ministry or other appropriate authority of such country.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Child</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “child” means an individual who has not attained 18 years of age.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Convention country</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Convention country” means a country for which the Hague Abduction Convention has entered into force with respect to the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hague Abduction Convention</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Hague Abduction Convention” means the Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction, done at The Hague <date date="1980-10-25">October 25, 1980</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interim contact</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “interim contact” means the ability of a left-behind parent to communicate with or visit an abducted child during the pendency of an abduction case.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Left-behind parent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “left-behind parent” means an individual or legal custodian who alleges that an abduction has occurred that is in breach of rights of custody attributed to such individual.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(16)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-Convention country</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “non-Convention country” means a country in which the Hague Abduction Convention has not entered into force with respect to the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(17)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Overseas military dependent child</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “overseas military dependent child” means a child whose habitual residence is the United States according to United States law even though the child is residing outside the United States with a military parent.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(18)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Overseas military parent</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “overseas military parent” means an individual who—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has custodial rights with respect to a child; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is serving outside the United States as a member of the United States Armed Forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(19)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pattern of noncompliance</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “pattern of noncompliance” means the persistent failure—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> of a Convention country to implement and abide by provisions of the Hague Abduction Convention;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> of a non-Convention country to abide by bilateral procedures that have been established between the United States and such country; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> of a non-Convention country to work with the Central Authority of the United States to resolve abduction cases.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Persistent failure</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Persistent failure under subparagraph (A) may be evidenced in a given country by the presence of 1 or more of the following criteria:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> Thirty percent or more of the total abduction cases in such country are unresolved abduction cases.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> The Central Authority regularly fails to fulfill its responsibilities pursuant to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the Hague Abduction Convention; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> any bilateral procedures between the United States and such country.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The judicial or administrative branch, as applicable, of the national government of a Convention country or a bilateral procedures country fails to regularly implement and comply with the provisions of the Hague Abduction Convention or bilateral procedures, as applicable.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> Law enforcement authorities regularly fail to enforce return orders or determinations of rights of access rendered by the judicial or administrative authorities of the government of the country in abduction cases.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(20)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rights of access</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “rights of access” means the establishment of rights of contact between a child and a parent seeking access in Convention countries—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by operation of law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> through a judicial or administrative determination; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> through a legally enforceable arrangement between the parties.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(21)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rights of custody</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “rights of custody” means rights of care and custody of a child, including the right to determine the place of residence of a child, under the laws of the country in which the child is a habitual resident—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> attributed to an individual or legal custodian; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> arising—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> by operation of law; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> through a judicial or administrative decision; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> through a legally enforceable arrangement between the parties.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(22)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rights of interim contact</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “rights of interim contact” means the rights of contact between a child and a left-behind parent, which has been provided as a provisional measure while an abduction case is pending, under the laws of the country in which the child is located—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by operation of law; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> through a judicial or administrative determination; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> through a legally enforceable arrangement between the parties.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(23)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unresolved abduction case</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), the term “unresolved abduction case” means an abduction case that remains unresolved for a period that exceeds 12 months after the date on which the completed application for return of the child is submitted for determination to the judicial or administrative authority, as applicable, in the country in which the child is located.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Resolution of case</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">An abduction case shall be considered to be resolved if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the child is returned to the country of habitual residence, pursuant to the Hague Abduction Convention or other appropriate bilateral procedures, if applicable;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the judicial or administrative branch, as applicable, of the government of the country in which the child is located has implemented, and is complying with, the provisions of the Hague Abduction Convention or other bilateral procedures, as applicable;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the left-behind parent reaches a voluntary arrangement with the other parent;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the left-behind parent submits a written withdrawal of the application or the request for assistance to the Department of State;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the left-behind parent cannot be located for 1 year despite the documented efforts of the Department of State to locate the parent; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> the child or left-behind parent is deceased.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–150, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-08-08">Aug. 8, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1809</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. G, title LXXV, § 7509(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2550</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>DEPARTMENT OF STATE ACTIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9111.</num>
<heading> Annual Report</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than April 30 of each year, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an Annual Report on International Child Abduction. The Secretary shall post the Annual Report to the publicly accessible website of the Department of State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each Annual Report shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> a list of all countries in which there were 1 or more abduction cases, during the preceding calendar year, relating to a child whose habitual residence is the United States, including a description of whether each such country—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is a Convention country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is a bilateral procedures country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> has other procedures for resolving such abductions; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> adheres to no protocols with respect to child abduction;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> for each country with respect to which there were 5 or more pending abduction cases, during the preceding year, relating to a child whose habitual residence is the United States—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number of such new abduction and access cases, respectively, reported during the preceding year and the number of children involved;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> for Convention and bilateral procedures countries—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the number of abduction and access cases that the Central Authority of the United States transmitted to the Central Authority of such country; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the number of abduction and access cases that were not submitted by the Central Authority to the judicial or administrative authority, as applicable, of such country;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the reason for the delay in submission of each case identified in subparagraph (B)(ii) by the Central Authority of such country to the judicial or administrative authority of that country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the number of unresolved abduction and access cases, respectively, the number of children involved, and the length of time each case has been pending;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> the number and percentage of unresolved abduction cases in which law enforcement authorities have—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> not located the abducted child;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> failed to undertake serious efforts to locate the abducted child; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> failed to enforce a return order rendered by the judicial or administrative authorities of such country;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the total number and the percentage of the total number of abduction and access cases, respectively, resolved during the preceding year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> recommendations to improve the resolution of abduction and access cases; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the average time it takes to locate a child;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the number of abducted children whose habitual residence is in the United States and who were returned to the United States from—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Convention countries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> bilateral procedures countries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> countries having other procedures for resolving such abductions; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> countries adhering to no protocols with respect to child abduction;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a list of Convention countries and bilateral procedures countries that have failed to comply with any of their obligations under the Hague Abduction Convention or bilateral procedures, as applicable, with respect to the resolution of abduction and access cases;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a list of countries demonstrating a pattern of noncompliance and a description of the criteria on which the determination of a pattern of noncompliance for each country is based;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> information on efforts by the Secretary of State to encourage non-Convention countries—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to ratify or accede to the Hague Abduction Convention;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to enter into or implement other bilateral procedures, including memoranda of understanding, with the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to address pending abduction and access cases;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the number of cases resolved without abducted children being returned to the United States from Convention countries, bilateral procedures countries, or other non-Convention countries, and number of children involved in such cases;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> a list of countries that became Convention countries with respect to the United States during the preceding year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> information about efforts to seek resolution of abduction cases of children whose habitual residence is in the United States and whose abduction occurred before the Hague Abduction Convention entered into force with respect to the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> the total number of pending cases the Department of State has assigned to case officers and number of children involved for each country and as a total for all countries.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Unless a left-behind parent provides written permission to the Central Authority of the United States to include personally identifiable information about the parent or the child in the Annual Report, the Annual Report may not include any personally identifiable information about any such parent, child, or party to an abduction or access case involving such parent or child.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional sections</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each Annual Report shall also include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> information on the number of unresolved abduction cases affecting military parents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a description of the assistance offered to such military parents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> information on the use of airlines in abductions, voluntary airline practices to prevent abductions, and recommendations for best airline practices to prevent abductions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> information on actions taken by the Central Authority of the United States to train domestic judges in the application of the Hague Abduction Convention; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> information on actions taken by the Central Authority of the United States to train United States Armed Forces legal assistance personnel, military chaplains, and military family support center personnel about—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> abductions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the risk of loss of contact with children; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the legal means available to resolve such cases.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification to Congress on countries in noncompliance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of State shall include, in a separate section of the Annual Report, the Secretary’s determination, pursuant to the provisions under <ref>section 9122(b) of this title</ref>, of whether each country listed in the report has engaged in a pattern of noncompliance in cases of child abduction during the preceding 12 months.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The section described in paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall identify any action or actions described in <ref>section 9122(d) of this title</ref> (or commensurate action as provided in <ref>section 9122(e) of this title</ref>) that have been taken by the Secretary with respect to each country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall describe the basis for the Secretary’s determination of the pattern of noncompliance by each country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> shall indicate whether noneconomic policy options designed to resolve the pattern of noncompliance have reasonably been exhausted, including the consultations required under <ref>section 9123 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–150, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2014-08-08">Aug. 8, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1813</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–81, div. E, title LVII, § 5702</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 2381</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9112.</num>
<heading> Standards and assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> ensure that United States diplomatic and consular missions abroad—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> maintain a consistent reporting standard with respect to abduction and access cases;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> designate at least 1 senior official in each such mission, at the discretion of the Chief of Mission, to assist left-behind parents from the United States who are visiting such country or otherwise seeking to resolve abduction or access cases; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> monitor developments in abduction and access cases; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> develop and implement written strategic plans for engagement with any Convention or non-Convention country in which there are 5 or more cases of international child abduction.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–150, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2014-08-08">Aug. 8, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1815</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9113.</num>
<heading> Bilateral procedures, including memoranda of understanding</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2014-08-08">August 8, 2014</date>, the Secretary of State shall initiate a process to develop and enter into appropriate bilateral procedures, including memoranda of understanding, as appropriate, with non-Convention countries that are unlikely to become Convention countries in the foreseeable future, or with Convention countries that have unresolved abduction cases that occurred before the Hague Abduction Convention entered into force with respect to the United States or that country.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prioritization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary of State shall give priority to countries with significant abduction cases and related issues.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The bilateral procedures described in subsection (a) should include provisions relating to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the identification of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Central Authority;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the judicial or administrative authority that will promptly adjudicate abduction and access cases;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the law enforcement agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> the implementation of procedures to ensure the immediate enforcement of an order issued by the authority identified pursuant to subparagraph (B) to return an abducted child to a left-behind parent, including by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> conducting an investigation to ascertain the location of the abducted child;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> providing protection to the abducted child after such child is located; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> retrieving the abducted child and making the appropriate arrangements for such child to be returned to the child’s country of habitual residence;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the implementation of a protocol to effectuate the return of an abducted child identified in an abduction case not later than 6 weeks after the application with respect to the abduction case has been submitted to the judicial or administrative authority, as applicable, of the country in which the abducted child is located;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the implementation of a protocol for the establishment and protection of the rights of interim contact during pendency of abduction cases; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the implementation of a protocol to establish periodic visits between a United States embassy or consular official and an abducted child, in order to allow the official to ascertain the child’s location and welfare.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–150, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2014-08-08">Aug. 8, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1815</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9114.</num>
<heading> Report to congressional representatives</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall submit written notification to the Member of Congress and Senators, or Resident Commissioner or Delegate, as appropriate, representing the legal residence of a left-behind parent if such parent—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> reports an abduction to the Central Authority of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> consents to such notification.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">At the request of any person who is a left-behind parent, including a left-behind parent who previously reported an abduction to the Central Authority of the United States before <date date="2014-08-08">August 8, 2014</date>, the notification required under subsection (a) shall be provided as soon as is practicable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–150, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2014-08-08">Aug. 8, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1816</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>ACTIONS BY THE SECRETARY OF STATE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9121.</num>
<heading> Response to international child abductions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to promote the best interest of children wrongfully abducted from the United States by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establishing legal rights and procedures for their prompt return; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ensuring the enforcement of reciprocal international obligations under the Hague Abduction Convention or arrangements under bilateral procedures;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to promote the timely resolution of abduction cases through 1 or more of the actions described in <ref>section 9122 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to ensure appropriate coordination within the Federal Government and between Federal, State, and local agencies involved in abduction prevention, investigation, and resolution.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actions by the Secretary of State in response to unresolved cases</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of action by the Secretary of State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For each abduction or access case relating to a child whose habitual residence is in the United States that remains pending or is otherwise unresolved on the date that is 12 months after the date on which the Central Authority of the United States submits such case to a foreign country, the Secretary of State shall determine whether the government of such foreign country has failed to take appropriate steps to resolve the case. If the Secretary of State determines that such failure occurred, the Secretary should, as expeditiously as practicable—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> take 1 or more of the actions described in subsections (d) and (e) of <ref>section 9122 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> direct the Chief of Mission in that foreign country to directly address the resolution of the case with senior officials in the foreign government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority for delay of action by the Secretary of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of State may delay any action described in paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines that an additional period of time, not to exceed 1 year, will substantially assist in resolving the case.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Secretary of State delays any action pursuant to paragraph (2) or decides not to take an action described in subsection (d) or (e) of <ref>section 9122 of this title</ref> after making the determination described in paragraph (1), the Secretary, not later than 15 days after such delay or decision, shall provide a report to the appropriate congressional committees that details the reasons for delaying action or not taking action, as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional briefings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">At the request of the appropriate congressional committees, the Secretary of State shall provide a detailed briefing, including a written report, if requested, on actions taken to resolve a case or the cause for delay.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In carrying out subsection (b), the Secretary of State should—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> take 1 or more actions that most appropriately respond to the nature and severity of the governmental failure to resolve the unresolved abduction case; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> seek, to the fullest extent possible—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to initially respond by communicating with the Central Authority of the country; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> if clause (i) is unsuccessful, to target subsequent actions—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> as narrowly as practicable, with respect to the agencies or instrumentalities of the foreign government that are responsible for such failures; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> in ways that respect the separation of powers and independence of the judiciary of the country, as applicable.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidelines for actions by the Secretary of State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In addition to the guidelines under paragraph (1), the Secretary of State, in determining whether to take 1 or more actions under paragraphs (5) through (7) of <ref>section 9122(d) of this title</ref> or <ref>section 9122(e) of this title</ref>, shall seek to minimize any adverse impact on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the population of the country whose government is targeted by the action or actions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the humanitarian activities of United States and nongovernmental organizations in the country; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action in the case of abducted children who reach the age of 16</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When an individual who is an abducted child attains 16 years of age, a consular officer from a United States diplomatic mission in the country in which such individual resides shall, until either the left-behind parent seeking assistance or the individual (after attaining 18 years of age) requests the officer to cease, annually attempt to contact such individual, through welfare and whereabout visits and by engaging other agencies and foreign counterparts as necessary, to provide information, as relevant, on rights and privileges as a United States citizen, such as passports, and any eligible benefits from left-behind parent, such as G.I. educational and health benefits and to obtain a verified location of such individual.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–150, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2014-08-08">Aug. 8, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1817</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. G, title LXXV, § 7509(b)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2551</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9122.</num>
<heading> Actions by the Secretary of State in response to patterns of noncompliance in cases of international child abductions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Response to a pattern of noncompliance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to oppose institutional or other systemic failures of foreign governments to fulfill their obligations pursuant to the Hague Abduction Convention or bilateral procedures, as applicable, to resolve abduction and access cases;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to promote reciprocity pursuant to, and in compliance with, the Hague Abduction Convention or bilateral procedures, as appropriate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to directly engage with senior foreign government officials to most effectively address patterns of noncompliance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of countries with patterns of noncompliance in cases of international child abduction</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual review</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than April 30 of each year, the Secretary of State shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> review the status of abduction and access cases in each foreign country in order to determine whether the government of such country has engaged in a pattern of noncompliance during the preceding 12 months; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> report such determination pursuant to <ref>section 9111(f) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determinations of responsible parties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of State shall seek to determine the agencies or instrumentalities of the government of each country determined to have engaged in a pattern of noncompliance under paragraph (1)(A) that are responsible for such pattern of noncompliance—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to appropriately target actions in response to such noncompliance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to engage with senior foreign government officials to effectively address such noncompliance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actions by the Secretary of State with respect to a country with a pattern of noncompliance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 90 days (or 180 days in case of a delay under paragraph (2)) after a country is determined to have been engaged in a pattern of noncompliance under subsection (b)(1)(A), the Secretary of State shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> take 1 or more of the actions described in subsection (d);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> direct the Chief of Mission in that country to directly address the systemic problems that led to such determination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> inform senior officials in the foreign government of the potential repercussions related to such designation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority for delay of actions by the Secretary of State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall not be required to take action under paragraph (1) until the expiration of a single, additional period of up to 90 days if, on or before the date on which the Secretary of State is required to take such action, the Secretary determines and certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that such additional period is necessary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for a continuation of negotiations that have been commenced with the government of a country described in paragraph (1) in order to bring about a cessation of the pattern of noncompliance by such country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for a review of corrective action taken by a country after the designation of such country as being engaged in a pattern of noncompliance under subsection (b)(1)(A); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in anticipation that corrective action will be taken by such country during such 90-day period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for additional action by the Secretary of State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of State shall not be required to take additional action under paragraph (1) with respect to a country determined to have been engaged in a persistent pattern of noncompliance if the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has taken action pursuant to paragraph (5), (6), or (7) of subsection (d) with respect to such country in the preceding year and such action continues to be in effect;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> exercises the waiver under <ref>section 9124 of this title</ref> and briefs the appropriate congressional committees; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> submits a report to the appropriate congressional committees that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> indicates that such country is subject to multiple, broad-based sanctions; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> describes how such sanctions satisfy the requirements under this subsection.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after the submission of the Annual Report, the Secretary shall submit a report to Congress on the specific actions taken against countries determined to have been engaged in a pattern of noncompliance under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Description of actions by the Secretary of State in Hague Abduction Convention countries</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (f), the actions by the Secretary of State referred to in this subsection are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a demarche;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an official public statement detailing unresolved cases;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a public condemnation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a delay or cancellation of 1 or more bilateral working, official, or state visits;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of United States development assistance in accordance with section 116 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151n</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of United States security assistance in accordance with section 502B of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2304</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of assistance to the central government of a country pursuant to chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2346</ref> et seq.; relating to the Economic Support Fund); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> a formal request to the foreign country concerned to extradite an individual who is engaged in abduction and who has been formally accused of, charged with, or convicted of an extraditable offense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commensurate action</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as provided in subsection (f), the Secretary of State may substitute any other action authorized by law for any action described in subsection (d) if the Secretary determines that such action—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is commensurate in effect to the action substituted; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> would substantially further the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If commensurate action is taken pursuant to this subsection, the Secretary shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> describes such action;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> explains the reasons for taking such action; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> specifically describes the basis for the Secretary’s determination under paragraph (1) that such action—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is commensurate with the action substituted; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> substantially furthers the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Resolution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall seek to take all appropriate actions authorized by law to resolve the unresolved case or to obtain the cessation of such pattern of noncompliance, as applicable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Humanitarian exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any action taken pursuant to subsection (d) or (e) may not prohibit or restrict the provision of medicine, medical equipment or supplies, food, or other life-saving humanitarian assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study of international parental child abduction</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after the <date date="2024-12-23">December 23, 2024</date>, the Secretary of State, subject to the availability of funds, shall seek to enter into an agreement with an appropriate university, research institution, or nongovernmental organization to study and publish a report on the impact to abducted children and left-behind parents as a result of international parental child abduction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of State shall consult with the appropriate congressional committees on the goals of the study and report required under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 and 2026 to carry out the study required under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–150, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2014-08-08">Aug. 8, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1818</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. G, title LXXV, § 7509(c)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2551</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9123.</num>
<heading> Consultations with foreign governments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As soon as practicable after the Secretary of State makes a determination under <ref>section 9121 of this title</ref> in response to a failure to resolve unresolved abduction cases or the Secretary takes an action under subsection (d) or (e) of <ref>section 9122 of this title</ref>, based on a pattern of noncompliance, the Secretary shall request consultations with the government of such country regarding the situation giving rise to such determination.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–150, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2014-08-08">Aug. 8, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9124.</num>
<heading> Waiver by the Secretary of State</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to subsection (b), the Secretary of State may waive the application of any of the actions described in subsections (d) and (e) of <ref>section 9122 of this title</ref> with respect to a country if the Secretary determines and notifies the appropriate congressional committees that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the government of such country—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> has satisfactorily resolved the abduction cases giving rise to the application of any of such actions; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> has ended such country’s pattern of noncompliance; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the national security interest of the United States requires the exercise of such waiver authority.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional notification</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than the date on which the Secretary of State exercises the waiver authority under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> notify the appropriate congressional committees of such waiver; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> provide such committees with a detailed justification for such waiver, including an explanation of the steps the noncompliant government has taken—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to resolve abductions cases; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to end its pattern of noncompliance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication in Federal Register</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to subsection (d), the Secretary of State shall ensure that each waiver determination under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is published in the Federal Register; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is posted on the Department of State website.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limited disclosure of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State may limit the publication of information under subsection (c) in the same manner and to the same extent as the President may limit the publication of findings and determinations described in <ref>section 2414(c) of this title</ref>, if the Secretary determines that the publication of such information would be harmful to the national security of the United States and would not further the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–150, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="2014-08-08">Aug. 8, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1821</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9125.</num>
<heading> Termination of actions by the Secretary of State</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any specific action taken under this Act or any amendment made by this Act with respect to a foreign country shall terminate on the date on which the Secretary of State submits a written certification to Congress that the government of such country—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has resolved any unresolved abduction case that gave rise to such specific action; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has taken substantial and verifiable steps to correct such country’s persistent pattern of noncompliance that gave rise to such specific action, as applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–150, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2014-08-08">Aug. 8, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1821</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>PREVENTION OF INTERNATIONAL CHILD ABDUCTION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9141.</num>
<heading> Authorization for judicial training on international parental child abduction</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State, subject to the availability of appropriations, shall seek to provide training, directly or through another government agency or nongovernmental organizations, on the effective handling of parental abduction cases to the judicial and administrative authorities in countries—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in which a significant number of unresolved abduction cases are pending; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that have been designated as having a pattern of noncompliance under <ref>section 9122(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Strategy requirement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2014-08-08">August 8, 2014</date>, the President shall submit a strategy to carry out the activities described in subsection (a) to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of State $1,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2015 and 2016 to carry out subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts appropriated for the activities set forth in subsection (a) shall be used pursuant to the authorization and requirements under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 113–150, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="2014-08-08">Aug. 8, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1822</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>