<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 65—</num>
<heading>CONTROL AND ELIMINATION OF CHEMICAL AND BIOLOGICAL WEAPONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5601.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to mandate United States sanctions, and to encourage international sanctions, against countries that use chemical or biological weapons in violation of international law or use lethal chemical or biological weapons against their own nationals, and to impose sanctions against companies that aid in the proliferation of chemical and biological weapons;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to support multilaterally coordinated efforts to control the proliferation of chemical and biological weapons;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to urge continued close cooperation with the Australia Group and cooperation with other supplier nations to devise ever more effective controls on the transfer of materials, equipment, and technology applicable to chemical or biological weapons production; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to require Presidential reports on efforts that threaten United States interests or regional stability by Iran, Iraq, Syria, Libya, and others to acquire the materials and technology to develop, produce, stockpile, deliver, transfer, or use chemical or biological weapons.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–182, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1991-12-04">Dec. 4, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1245</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5602.</num>
<heading> Multilateral efforts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multilateral controls on proliferation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States to seek multilaterally coordinated efforts with other countries to control the proliferation of chemical and biological weapons. In furtherance of this policy, the United States shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> promote agreements banning the transfer of missiles suitable for armament with chemical or biological warheads;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> set as a top priority the early conclusion of a comprehensive global agreement banning the use, development, production, and stockpiling of chemical weapons;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> seek and support effective international means of monitoring and reporting regularly on commerce in equipment, materials, and technology applicable to the attainment of a chemical or biological weapons capability; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> pursue and give full support to multilateral sanctions pursuant to United Nations Security Council Resolution 620, which declared the intention of the Security Council to give immediate consideration to imposing “appropriate and effective” sanctions against any country which uses chemical weapons in violation of international law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multilateral controls on chemical agents, precursors, and equipment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is also the policy of the United States to strengthen efforts to control chemical agents, precursors, and equipment by taking all appropriate multilateral diplomatic measures—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to continue to seek a verifiable global ban on chemical weapons at the 40 nation Conference on Disarmament in Geneva;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to support the Australia Group’s objective to support the norms and restraints against the spread and the use of chemical warfare, to advance the negotiation of a comprehensive ban on chemical warfare by taking appropriate measures, and to protect the Australia Group’s domestic industries against inadvertent association with supply of feedstock chemical equipment that could be misused to produce chemical weapons;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> to implement paragraph (2) by proposing steps complementary to, and not mutually exclusive of, existing multilateral efforts seeking a verifiable ban on chemical weapons, such as the establishment of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a harmonized list of export control rules and regulations to prevent relative commercial advantage and disadvantages accruing to Australia Group members,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> liaison officers to the Australia Group’s coordinating entity from within the diplomatic missions,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a close working relationship between the Australia Group and industry,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a public unclassified warning list of controlled chemical agents, precursors, and equipment,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> information-exchange channels of suspected proliferants,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a “denial” list of firms and individuals who violate the Australia Group’s export control provisions, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> broader cooperation between the Australia Group and other countries whose political commitment to stem the proliferation of chemical weapons is similar to that of the Australia Group; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to adopt the imposition of stricter controls on the export of chemical agents, precursors, and equipment and to adopt tougher multilateral sanctions against firms and individuals who violate these controls or against countries that use chemical weapons.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–182, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1991-12-04">Dec. 4, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1245</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5603.</num>
<heading> United States export controls</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> use the authorities of the Arms Export Control Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.] to control the export of those defense articles and defense services, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> use the authorities of the Export Administration Act of 1979 to control the export of those goods and technology,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">that the President determines would assist the government of any foreign country in acquiring the capability to develop, produce, stockpile, deliver, or use chemical or biological weapons.</continuation>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–182, title III, § 304(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-04">Dec. 4, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1246</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5604.</num>
<heading> Determinations regarding use of chemical or biological weapons</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination by President</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> When determination required; nature of determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Whenever persuasive information becomes available to the executive branch indicating the substantial possibility that, on or after <date date="1991-10-28">October 28, 1991</date>, the government of a foreign country has made substantial preparation to use or has used chemical or biological weapons, the President shall, within 60 days after the receipt of such information by the executive branch, determine whether that government, on or after <date date="1991-10-28">October 28, 1991</date>, has used chemical or biological weapons in violation of international law or has used lethal chemical or biological weapons against its own nationals. <ref>Section 5605 of this title</ref> applies if the President determines that that government has so used chemical or biological weapons.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matters to be considered</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In making the determination under paragraph (1), the President shall consider the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> All physical and circumstantial evidence available bearing on the possible use of such weapons.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> All information provided by alleged victims, witnesses, and independent observers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The extent of the availability of the weapons in question to the purported user.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> All official and unofficial statements bearing on the possible use of such weapons.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Whether, and to what extent, the government in question is willing to honor a request from the Secretary General of the United Nations to grant timely access to a United Nations fact-finding team to investigate the possibility of chemical or biological weapons use or to grant such access to other legitimate outside parties.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination to be reported to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon making a determination under paragraph (1), the President shall promptly report that determination to the Congress. If the determination is that a foreign government had used chemical or biological weapons as described in that paragraph, the report shall specify the sanctions to be imposed pursuant to <ref>section 5605 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Congressional requests; report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Request</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chairman of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate (upon consultation with the ranking minority member of such committee) or the Chairman of the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives (upon consultation with the ranking minority member of such committee) may at any time request the President to consider whether a particular foreign government, on or after <date date="1991-12-04">December 4, 1991</date>, has used chemical or biological weapons in violation of international law or has used lethal chemical or biological weapons against its own nationals.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 60 days after receiving such a request, the President shall provide to the Chairman of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Chairman of the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a written report on the information held by the executive branch which is pertinent to the issue of whether the specified government, on or after <date date="1991-12-04">December 4, 1991</date>, has used chemical or biological weapons in violation of international law or has used lethal chemical or biological weapons against its own nationals. This report shall contain an analysis of each of the items enumerated in subsection (a)(2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–182, title III</ref>, §§ 306, 309(b)(3), <date date="1991-12-04">Dec. 4, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1252</ref>, 1259.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5605.</num>
<heading> Sanctions against use of chemical or biological weapons</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial sanctions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If, at any time, the President makes a determination pursuant to <ref>section 5604(a)(1) of this title</ref> with respect to the government of a foreign country, the President shall forthwith impose the following sanctions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The United States Government shall terminate assistance to that country under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.], except for urgent humanitarian assistance and food or other agricultural commodities or products.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Arms sales</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The United States Government shall terminate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sales to that country under the Arms Export Control Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.] of any defense articles, defense services, or design and construction services, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> licenses for the export to that country of any item on the United States Munitions List.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Arms sales financing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The United States Government shall terminate all foreign military financing for that country under the Arms Export Control Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Denial of United States Government credit or other financial assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The United States Government shall deny to that country any credit, credit guarantees, or other financial assistance by any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government, including the Export-Import Bank of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exports of national security-sensitive goods and technology</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The authorities of section 4605 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002321">1</ref> of title 50 shall be used to prohibit the export to that country of any goods or technology on that part of the control list established under section 4604(c)(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002321">1</ref> of title 50.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional sanctions if certain conditions not met</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential determination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Unless, within 3 months after making a determination pursuant to <ref>section 5604(a)(1) of this title</ref> with respect to a foreign government, the President determines and certifies in writing to the Congress that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that government is no longer using chemical or biological weapons in violation of international law or using lethal chemical or biological weapons against its own nationals,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that government has provided reliable assurances that it will not in the future engage in any such activities, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> that government is willing to allow on-site inspections by United Nations observers or other internationally recognized, impartial observers, or other reliable means exist, to ensure that that government is not using chemical or biological weapons in violation of international law and is not using lethal chemical or biological weapons against its own nationals,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">then the President, after consultation with the Congress, shall impose on that country the sanctions set forth in at least 3 of subparagraphs (A) through (F) of paragraph (2).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanctions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The sanctions referred to in paragraph (1) are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multilateral development bank assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The United States Government shall oppose, in accordance with <ref>section 262d of this title</ref>, the extension of any loan or financial or technical assistance to that country by international financial institutions.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bank loans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The United States Government shall prohibit any United States bank from making any loan or providing any credit to the government of that country, except for loans or credits for the purpose of purchasing food or other agricultural commodities or products.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Further export restrictions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The authorities of section 4605 <sup>1</sup> of title 50 shall be used to prohibit exports to that country of all other goods and technology (excluding food and other agricultural commodities and products).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Import restrictions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Restrictions shall be imposed on the importation into the United States of articles (which may include petroleum or any petroleum product) that are the growth, product, or manufacture of that country.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Diplomatic relations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The President shall use his constitutional authorities to downgrade or suspend diplomatic relations between the United States and the government of that country.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential action regarding aviation</heading>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The President is authorized to notify the government of a country with respect to which the President has made a determination pursuant to <ref>section 5604(a)(1) of this title</ref> of his intention to suspend the authority of foreign air carriers owned or controlled by the government of that country to engage in foreign air transportation to or from the United States.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> Within 10 days after the date of notification of a government under subclause (I), the Secretary of Transportation shall take all steps necessary to suspend at the earliest possible date the authority of any foreign air carrier owned or controlled, directly or indirectly, by that government to engage in foreign air transportation to or from the United States, notwithstanding any agreement relating to air services.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The President may direct the Secretary of State to terminate any air service agreement between the United States and a country with respect to which the President has made a determination pursuant to <ref>section 5604(a)(1) of this title</ref>, in accordance with the provisions of that agreement.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> Upon termination of an agreement under this clause, the Secretary of Transportation shall take such steps as may be necessary to revoke at the earliest possible date the right of any foreign air carrier owned, or controlled, directly or indirectly, by the government of that country to engage in foreign air transportation to or from the United States.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The Secretary of Transportation may provide for such exceptions from clauses (i) and (ii) as the Secretary considers necessary to provide for emergencies in which the safety of an aircraft or its crew or passengers is threatened.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subparagraph, the terms “air transportation”, “air carrier”, “foreign air carrier”, and “foreign air transportation” have the meanings such terms have under <ref>section 40102(a) of title 49</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal of sanctions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall remove the sanctions imposed with respect to a country pursuant to this section if the President determines and so certifies to the Congress, after the end of the 12-month period beginning on the date on which sanctions were initially imposed on that country pursuant to subsection (a), that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the government of that country has provided reliable assurances that it will not use chemical or biological weapons in violation of international law and will not use lethal chemical or biological weapons against its own nationals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> that government is not making preparations to use chemical or biological weapons in violation of international law or to use lethal chemical or biological weapons against its own nationals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> that government is willing to allow on-site inspections by United Nations observers or other internationally recognized, impartial observers to verify that it is not making preparations to use chemical or biological weapons in violation of international law or to use lethal chemical or biological weapons against its own nationals, or other reliable means exist to verify that it is not making such preparations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> that government is making restitution to those affected by any use of chemical or biological weapons in violation of international law or by any use of lethal chemical or biological weapons against its own nationals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria for waiver</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The President may waive the application of any sanction imposed with respect to a country pursuant to this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of any sanction other than a sanction specified in subsection (b)(2)(D) (relating to import restrictions) or (b)(2)(E) (relating to the downgrading or suspension of diplomatic relations), the President determines and certifies to the Congress that such waiver is essential to the national security interests of the United States, and if the President notifies the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives of his determination and certification at least 15 days before the waiver takes effect, in accordance with the procedures applicable to reprogramming notifications under section 634A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2394–1</ref>], or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of any sanction specified in subsection (b)(2)(D) (relating to import restrictions), the President determines and certifies to the Congress that such waiver is essential to the national security interest of the United States, and if the President notifies the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives of his determination and certification at least 15 days before the waiver takes effect; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the President determines and certifies to the Congress that there has been a fundamental change in the leadership and policies of the government of that country, and if the President notifies the Congress at least 20 days before the waiver takes effect.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the event that the President decides to exercise the waiver authority provided in paragraph (1) with respect to a country, the President’s notification to the Congress under such paragraph shall include a report fully articulating the rationale and circumstances which led the President to exercise that waiver authority, including a description of the steps which the government of that country has taken to satisfy the conditions set forth in paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contract sanctity</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanctions not applied to existing contracts</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A sanction described in paragraph (4) or (5) of subsection (a) or in any of subparagraphs (A) through (D) of subsection (b)(2) shall not apply to any activity pursuant to any contract or international agreement entered into before the date of the presidential determination under <ref>section 5604(a)(1) of this title</ref> unless the President determines, on a case-by-case basis, that to apply such sanction to that activity would prevent the performance of a contract or agreement that would have the effect of assisting a country in using chemical or biological weapons in violation of international law or in using lethal chemical or biological weapons against its own nationals.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The same restrictions of subsection (p) of section 4605 <sup>1</sup> of title 50, as that subsection is so redesignated by <ref>section 304(b) of this title</ref>, which are applicable to exports prohibited under section 4605 <sup>1</sup> of title 50, shall apply to exports prohibited under subsection (a)(5) or (b)(2)(C) of this section. For purposes of this subparagraph, any contract or agreement the performance of which (as determined by the President) would have the effect of assisting a foreign government in using chemical or biological weapons in violation of international law or in using lethal chemical or biological weapons against its own nationals shall be treated as constituting a breach of the peace that poses a serious and direct threat to the strategic interest of the United States, within the meaning of subparagraph (A) of section 4605(p) <sup>1</sup> of title 50.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanctions applied to existing contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The sanctions described in paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of subsection (a) shall apply to contracts, agreements, and licenses without regard to the date the contract or agreement was entered into or the license was issued (as the case may be), except that such sanctions shall not apply to any contract or agreement entered into or license issued before the date of the presidential determination under <ref>section 5604(a)(1) of this title</ref> if the President determines that the application of such sanction would be detrimental to the national security interests of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–182, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="1991-12-04">Dec. 4, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1254</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5606.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 107–228, div. B, title XIII, § 1308(g)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1441</ref></heading>
</section>
</chapter>