<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 64—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES RESPONSE TO TERRORISM AFFECTING AMERICANS ABROAD</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5501.</num>
<heading> International negotiations concerning aviation security</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to seek bilateral agreements to achieve United States aviation security objectives with foreign governments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to continue to press vigorously for security improvements through the Foreign Airport Security Act <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002319">1</ref> and the foreign airport assessment program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to continue to work through the International Civil Aviation Organization to improve aviation security internationally.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Negotiations for aviation security</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Department of State, in consultation with the Department of Transportation, shall be responsible for negotiating requisite aviation security agreements with foreign governments concerning the implementation of United States rules and regulations which affect the foreign operations of United States air carriers, foreign air carriers, and foreign international airports. The Secretary of State is directed to enter, expeditiously, into negotiations for bilateral and multilateral agreements—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for enhanced aviation security objectives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to implement the Foreign Airport Security Act <sup>1</sup> and the foreign airport assessment program to the fullest extent practicable; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to achieve improved availability of passenger manifest information.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A principal objective of bilateral and multilateral negotiations with foreign governments and the International Civil Aviation Organization shall be improved availability of passenger manifest information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–604, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3081</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5502.</num>
<heading> Coordinator for Counterterrorism</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Coordinator for Counterterrorism shall be responsible for the coordination of international aviation security for the Department of State.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–604, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3082</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5503.</num>
<heading> Department of State notification of families of victims</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department of State policy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the policy of the Department of State pursuant to <ref>section 2715 of this title</ref> to directly and promptly notify the families of victims of aviation disasters abroad concerning citizens of the United States directly affected by such a disaster, including timely written notice. The Secretary of State shall ensure that such notification by the Department of State is carried out notwithstanding notification by any other person.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department of State guidelines</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>, the Secretary of State shall issue such regulations, guidelines, and circulars as are necessary to ensure that the policy under subsection (a) is fully implemented.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–604, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3083</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5504.</num>
<heading> Designation of State Department-family liaison and toll-free family communications system</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation of State Department-family liaison</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>, the Secretary of State shall issue such rules and guidelines as are necessary to provide that in the event of an aviation disaster directly involving United States citizens abroad, if possible, the Department of State will assign a specific individual, and an alternate, as the Department of State liaison for the family of each such citizen.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Toll-free communications system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the establishment of the Department of State toll-free communications system to facilitate inquiries concerning the affect of any disaster abroad on United States citizens residing or traveling abroad, the Secretary of State shall ensure that a toll-free telephone number is reserved for the exclusive use of the families of citizens who have been determined to be directly involved in any such disaster.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–604, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3083</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5505.</num>
<heading> Disaster training for State Department personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional training</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall institute a supplemental program of training in disaster management for all consular officers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training improvements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In expanding the training program under subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall consult with death and bereavement counselors concerning the particular demands posed by aviation tragedies and terrorist activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In providing such additional training under subsection (a) the Secretary of State shall consider supplementing the current training program through—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> providing specialized training to create a team of “disaster specialists” to deploy immediately in a crisis; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> securing outside experts to be brought in during the initial phases to assist consular personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–604, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3084</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5506.</num>
<heading> Department of State responsibilities and procedures at international disaster site</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dispatch of senior State Department official to site</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>, the Secretary of State shall issue such rules and guidelines as are necessary to provide that in the event of an international disaster, particularly an aviation tragedy, directly involving significant numbers of United States citizens abroad not less than one senior officer from the Bureau of Consular Affairs of the Department of State shall be dispatched to the site of such disaster.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria for Department of State staffing at disaster site</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>, the Secretary of State shall promulgate criteria for Department of State staffing of disaster sites abroad. Such criteria shall define responsibility for staffing decisions and shall consider the deployment of crisis teams under subsection (d). The Secretary of State shall promptly issue such rules and guidelines as are necessary to implement criteria developed pursuant to this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State Department ombudsman</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>, the Secretary of State shall issue such rules and guidelines as are necessary to provide that in the event of an international aviation disaster involving significant numbers of United States citizens abroad not less than one officer or employee of the Department of State shall be dispatched to the disaster site to provide on-site assistance to families who may visit the site and to act as an ombudsman in matters involving the foreign local government authorities and social service agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Crisis teams</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>, the Secretary of State shall promulgate procedures for the deployment of a “crisis team”, which may include public affairs, forensic, and bereavement experts, to the site of any international disaster involving United States citizens abroad to augment in-country Embassy and consulate staff. The Secretary of State shall promptly issue such rules and guidelines as are necessary to implement procedures developed pursuant to this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–604, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3084</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5507.</num>
<heading> Recovery and disposition of remains and personal effects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the policy of the Department of State (pursuant to <ref>section 2715 of this title</ref>) to provide liaison with foreign governments and persons and with United States air carriers concerning arrangements for the preparation and transport to the United States of the remains of citizens who die abroad, as well as the disposition of personal effects. The Secretary of State shall ensure that regulations and guidelines of the Department of State reflect such policy and that such assistance is rendered to the families of United States citizens who are killed in terrorist incidents and disasters abroad.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–604, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3085</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5508.</num>
<heading> Assessment of Lockerbie experience</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall compile an assessment of the Department of State response to the Pan American Airways Flight 103 aviation disaster over Lockerbie, Scotland, on <date date="1988-12-21">December 21, 1988</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidelines</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall establish, based on the assessment compiled under subsection (a) and other relevant factors, guidelines for future Department of State responses to comparable disasters and shall distribute such guidelines to all United States diplomatic and consular posts abroad.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–604, title II, § 209</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3085</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5509.</num>
<heading> Official Department of State recognition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>, the Secretary of State shall promulgate guidelines for appropriate ceremonies or other official expressions of respect and support for the families of United States citizens who are killed through acts of terrorism abroad.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–604, title II, § 210</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3085</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5510.</num>
<heading> United States Government compensation for victims of terrorism</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall submit to the Congress, not later than one year after <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>, recommendations on whether or not legislation should be enacted to authorize the United States to provide monetary and tax relief as compensation to United States citizens who are victims of terrorism.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may establish a board to develop criteria for compensation and to recommend changes to existing laws to establish a single comprehensive approach to victim compensation for terrorist acts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Income tax benefit for victims of Lockerbie terrorism</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), in the case of any individual whose death was a direct result of the Pan American Airways Flight 103 terrorist disaster over Lockerbie, Scotland, on <date date="1988-12-21">December 21, 1988</date>, any tax imposed by subtitle A of title 26 shall not apply—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> with respect to the taxable year which includes <date date="1988-12-21">December 21, 1988</date>, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with respect to the prior taxable year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In no case may the tax benefit pursuant to paragraph (1) for any taxable year, for any individual, exceed an amount equal to 28 percent of the annual rate of basic pay at Level V of the Executive Schedule of the United States as of <date date="1988-12-21">December 21, 1988</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–604, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3085</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5511.</num>
<heading> Overseas Security Electronic Bulletin Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>, the Secretary of State shall issue such rules and regulations as may be necessary to establish, under the Bureau of Consular Affairs, an electronic bulletin board accessible to the general public. Such bulletin board shall contain all information, updated daily, which is available on the Overseas Security Electronic Bulletin Board of the Bureau of Diplomatic Security.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–604, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3086</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5512.</num>
<heading> Antiterrorism measures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidelines for international aviation travelers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of notifying the public, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation, shall develop and publish guidelines for thwarting efforts by international terrorists to enlist the unwitting assistance of international aviation travelers in terrorist activities. Notices concerning such guidelines shall be posted and prominently displayed domestically and abroad in international airports.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of international standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Transportation in all appropriate fora, particularly talks and meetings related to international civil aviation, shall enter into negotiations with other nations for the establishment of international standards regarding guidelines for thwarting efforts by international terrorists to enlist the unwitting assistance of international aviation travelers in terrorist activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of rewards for terrorism-related information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purpose of notifying the public, the Secretary of State shall publish the availability of United States Government rewards for information on international terrorist-related activities, including rewards available under section 2708(a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002320">1</ref> of this title and chapter 204 of title 18. To the extent appropriate and feasible, notices making such publication shall be posted and prominently displayed domestically and abroad in international airports.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Transportation should take appropriate measures to utilize and train properly the officers and employees of other United States Government agencies who have functions at international airports in the United States and abroad in the detection of explosives and firearms which could be a threat to international civil aviation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–604, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3087</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5513.</num>
<heading> Proposal for consideration by International Civil Aviation Organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation, shall propose to the International Civil Aviation Organization the establishment of a comprehensive aviation security program which shall include (1) training for airport security personnel, (2) grants for security equipment acquisition for certain nations, and (3) expansion of the appropriate utilization of canine teams in the detection of explosive devices in all airport areas, including use in passenger screening areas and nonpublic baggage assembly and processing areas.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 101–604, title II, § 215</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 3087</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>