<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 110—</num>
<heading>INFORMATION SECURITY AND CYBER DIPLOMACY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10301.</num>
<heading> United States international cyberspace policy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to work internationally to promote an open, interoperable, reliable, and secure internet governed by the multi-stakeholder model, which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> promotes democracy, the rule of law, and human rights, including freedom of expression;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> supports the ability to innovate, communicate, and promote economic prosperity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is designed to protect privacy and guard against deception, malign influence, incitement to violence, harassment and abuse, fraud, and theft;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to encourage and aid United States allies and partners in improving their own technological capabilities and resiliency to pursue, defend, and protect shared interests and values, free from coercion and external pressure; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> in furtherance of the efforts described in paragraphs (1) and (2)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to provide incentives to the private sector to accelerate the development of the technologies referred to in such paragraphs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to modernize and harmonize with allies and partners export controls and investment screening regimes and associated policies and regulations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to enhance United States leadership in technical standards-setting bodies and avenues for developing norms regarding the use of digital tools.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In implementing the policy described in subsection (a), the President, in consultation with outside actors, as appropriate, including private sector companies, nongovernmental organizations, security researchers, and other relevant stakeholders, in the conduct of bilateral and multilateral relations, shall strive—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to clarify the applicability of international laws and norms to the use of information and communications technology (referred to in this subsection as “ICT”);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to reduce and limit the risk of escalation and retaliation in cyberspace, damage to critical infrastructure, and other malicious cyber activity that impairs the use and operation of critical infrastructure that provides services to the public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to cooperate with like-minded countries that share common values and cyberspace policies with the United States, including respect for human rights, democracy, and the rule of law, to advance such values and policies internationally;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to encourage the responsible development of new, innovative technologies and ICT products that strengthen a secure internet architecture that is accessible to all;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> to secure and implement commitments on responsible country behavior in cyberspace, including commitments by countries—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not to conduct, or knowingly support, cyber-enabled theft of intellectual property, including trade secrets or other confidential business information, with the intent of providing competitive advantages to companies or commercial sectors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to take all appropriate and reasonable efforts to keep their territories clear of intentionally wrongful acts using ICT in violation of international commitments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> not to conduct or knowingly support ICT activity that intentionally damages or otherwise impairs the use and operation of critical infrastructure providing services to the public, in violation of international law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to take appropriate measures to protect the country’s critical infrastructure from ICT threats;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> not to conduct or knowingly support malicious international activity that harms the information systems of authorized international emergency response teams (also known as “computer emergency response teams” or “cybersecurity incident response teams”) of another country or authorize emergency response teams to engage in malicious international activity, in violation of international law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> to respond to appropriate requests for assistance to mitigate malicious ICT activity emanating from their territory and aimed at the critical infrastructure of another country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> not to restrict cross-border data flows or require local storage or processing of data; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> to protect the exercise of human rights and fundamental freedoms on the internet, while recognizing that the human rights that people have offline also need to be protected online; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to advance, encourage, and support the development and adoption of internationally recognized technical standards and best practices.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. I, title XCV, § 9501</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3897</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10302.</num>
<heading> International cyberspace and digital policy strategy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Strategy required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, the President, acting through the Secretary, and in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall develop an international cyberspace and digital policy strategy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The strategy required under subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a review of actions and activities undertaken to support the policy described in <ref>section 10301(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> a plan of action to guide the diplomacy of the Department with regard to foreign countries, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> conducting bilateral and multilateral activities—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to develop and support the implementation of norms of responsible country behavior in cyberspace consistent with the commitments listed in <ref>section 10301(b)(5) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to reduce the frequency and severity of cyberattacks on United States individuals, businesses, governmental agencies, and other organizations;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to reduce cybersecurity risks to United States and allied critical infrastructure;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> to improve allies’ and partners’ collaboration with the United States on cybersecurity issues, including information sharing, regulatory coordination and improvement, and joint investigatory and law enforcement operations related to cybercrime; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> to share best practices and advance proposals to strengthen civilian and private sector resiliency to threats and access to opportunities in cyberspace; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> reviewing the status of existing efforts in relevant multilateral fora, as appropriate, to obtain commitments on international norms regarding cyberspace;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a review of alternative concepts for international norms regarding cyberspace offered by foreign countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> a detailed description, in consultation with the Office of the National Cyber Director and relevant Federal agencies, of new and evolving threats regarding cyberspace from foreign adversaries, state-sponsored actors, and non-state actors to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> United States national security;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Federal and private sector cyberspace infrastructure of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> intellectual property in the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the privacy and security of citizens of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> a review of the policy tools available to the President to deter and de-escalate tensions with foreign countries, state-sponsored actors, and private actors regarding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> threats in cyberspace;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the degree to which such tools have been used; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> whether such tools have been effective deterrents;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a review of resources required to conduct activities to build responsible norms of international cyber behavior;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> a review, in coordination with the Office of the National Cyber Director and the Office of Management and Budget, to determine whether the budgetary resources, technical expertise, legal authorities, and personnel available to the Department are adequate to achieve the actions and activities undertaken by the Department to support the policy described in <ref>section 10301(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> a review to determine whether the Department is properly organized and coordinated with other Federal agencies to achieve the objectives described in <ref>section 10301(b) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> a plan of action, developed in coordination with the Department of Defense and in consultation with other relevant Federal departments and agencies as the President may direct, with respect to the inclusion of cyber issues in mutual defense agreements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form of strategy</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Public availability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The strategy required under subsection (a) shall be available to the public in unclassified form, including through publication in the Federal Register.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Classified annex</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The strategy required under subsection (a) may include a classified annex.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Briefing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 30 days after the completion of the strategy required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall brief the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate, the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives regarding the strategy, including any material contained in a classified annex.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Updates</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The strategy required under subsection (a) shall be updated—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> not later than 90 days after any material change to United States policy described in such strategy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> not later than 1 year after the inauguration of each new President.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. I, title XCV, § 9503</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3902</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10303.</num>
<heading> Cybersecurity recruitment and retention</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that improving computer programming language proficiency will improve—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the cybersecurity effectiveness of the Department; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the ability of foreign service officers to engage with foreign audiences on cybersecurity matters.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technology talent acquisition</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish positions within the Bureau of Global Talent Management that are solely dedicated to the recruitment and retention of Department personnel with backgrounds in cybersecurity, engineering, data science, application development, artificial intelligence, critical and emerging technology, and technology and digital policy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Goals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The goals of the positions described in paragraph (1) shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to fulfill the critical need of the Department to recruit and retain employees for cybersecurity, digital, and technology positions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to actively recruit relevant candidates from academic institutions, the private sector, and related industries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to work with the Office of Personnel Management and the United States Digital Service to develop and implement best strategies for recruiting and retaining technology talent; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to inform and train supervisors at the Department on the use of the authorities listed in subsection (c)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, the Secretary shall submit a plan to the appropriate congressional committees that describes how the objectives and goals set forth in paragraphs (1) and (2) will be implemented.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated $750,000 for each of the fiscal years 2023 through 2027 to carry out this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report on hiring authorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, and annually thereafter for the following 5 years, the Secretary shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a list of the hiring authorities available to the Department to recruit and retain personnel with backgrounds in cybersecurity, engineering, data science, application development, artificial intelligence, critical and emerging technology, and technology and digital policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a list of which hiring authorities described in paragraph (1) have been used during the previous 5 years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the number of employees in qualified positions hired, aggregated by position and grade level or pay band;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the number of employees who have been placed in qualified positions, aggregated by bureau and offices within the Department;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the rate of attrition of individuals who begin the hiring process and do not complete the process and a description of the reasons for such attrition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the number of individuals who are interviewed by subject matter experts and the number of individuals who are not interviewed by subject matter experts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> recommendations for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> reducing the attrition rate referred to in paragraph (5) by 5 percent each year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> additional hiring authorities needed to acquire needed technology talent;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> hiring personnel to hold public trust positions until such personnel can obtain the necessary security clearance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> informing and training supervisors within the Department on the use of the authorities listed in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Incentive pay for cybersecurity professionals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">To increase the number of qualified candidates available to fulfill the cybersecurity needs of the Department, the Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> include computer programming languages within the Recruitment Language Program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide appropriate language incentive pay.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, and annually thereafter for the following 5 years, the Secretary shall provide a list to the appropriate congressional committees that identifies—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the computer programming languages included within the Recruitment Language Program and the language incentive pay rate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the number of individuals benefitting from the inclusion of such computer programming languages in the Recruitment Language Program and language incentive pay.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. I, title XCV, § 9506</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3904</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10304.</num>
<heading> Short course on emerging technologies for senior officials</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, the Secretary shall develop and begin providing, for senior officials of the Department, a course addressing how the most recent and relevant technologies affect the activities of the Department.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Throughput objectives</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary should ensure that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> during the first year that the course developed pursuant to subsection (a) is offered, not fewer than 20 percent of senior officials are certified as having passed such course; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in each subsequent year, until the date on which 80 percent of senior officials are certified as having passed such course, an additional 10 percent of senior officials are certified as having passed such course.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. I, title XCV, § 9507</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3906</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10305.</num>
<heading> Establishment and expansion of Regional Technology Officer Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regional Technology Officer Program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish a program, which shall be known as the “Regional Technology Officer Program” (referred to in this section as the “Program”), and shall be administered by the Bureau for Cyberspace and Digital Policy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Goals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The goals of the Program shall include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Promoting United States leadership in technology abroad.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Working with partners to increase the deployment of critical and emerging technology in support of democratic values.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Shaping diplomatic agreements in regional and international fora with respect to critical and emerging technologies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Building diplomatic capacity for handling critical and emerging technology issues.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Facilitating the role of critical and emerging technology in advancing the foreign policy objectives of the United States through engagement with research labs, incubators, and venture capitalists.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Maintaining the advantages of the United States with respect to critical and emerging technologies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, the Secretary shall submit an implementation plan to the appropriate congressional committees that outlines strategies for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> advancing the goals described in subsection (a)(2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> hiring Regional Technology Officers and increasing the competitiveness of the Program within the Foreign Service bidding process;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> expanding the Program to include a minimum of 15 Regional Technology Officers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> assigning not fewer than 2 Regional Technology Officers to posts within—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> each regional bureau of the Department; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Bureau of International Organization Affairs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual briefing requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, and annually thereafter for the following 5 years, the Secretary shall brief the appropriate congressional committees regarding the status of the implementation plan required under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated up to $25,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2023 through 2027 to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. I, title XCV, § 9508</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3906</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–159, div. G, title LXXIII, § 7301</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 2541</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10306.</num>
<heading> Vulnerability disclosure policy and bug bounty program report</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bug bounty program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “bug bounty program” means a program under which an approved individual, organization, or company is temporarily authorized to identify and report vulnerabilities of internet-facing information technology of the Department in exchange for compensation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information technology</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “information technology” has the meaning given such term in <ref>section 11101 of title 40</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vulnerability Disclosure Policy</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, the Secretary shall design, establish, and make publicly known a Vulnerability Disclosure Policy (referred to in this section as the “VDP”) to improve Department cybersecurity by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> creating Department policy and infrastructure to receive reports of and remediate discovered vulnerabilities in line with existing policies of the Office of Management and Budget and the Department of Homeland Security Binding Operational Directive 20–01 or any subsequent directive; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> providing a report on such policy and infrastructure to Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after the establishment of the VDP pursuant to paragraph (1), and annually thereafter for the following 5 years, the Secretary shall submit a report on the VDP to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives that includes information relating to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the number and severity of all security vulnerabilities reported;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the number of previously unidentified security vulnerabilities remediated as a result;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the current number of outstanding previously unidentified security vulnerabilities and Department of State remediation plans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the average time between the reporting of security vulnerabilities and remediation of such vulnerabilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the resources, surge staffing, roles, and responsibilities within the Department used to implement the VDP and complete security vulnerability remediation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> how the VDP identified vulnerabilities are incorporated into existing Department vulnerability prioritization and management processes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> any challenges in implementing the VDP and plans for expansion or contraction in the scope of the VDP across Department information systems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> any other topic that the Secretary determines to be relevant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bug bounty program report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, the Secretary shall submit a report to Congress that describes any ongoing efforts by the Department or a third-party vendor under contract with the Department to establish or carry out a bug bounty program that identifies security vulnerabilities of internet-facing information technology of the Department.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after the date on which any bug bounty program is established, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives regarding such program, including information relating to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the number of approved individuals, organizations, or companies involved in such program, disaggregated by the number of approved individuals, organizations, or companies that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> registered;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> were approved;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> submitted security vulnerabilities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> received compensation;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the number and severity of all security vulnerabilities reported as part of such program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the number of previously unidentified security vulnerabilities remediated as a result of such program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the current number of outstanding previously unidentified security vulnerabilities and Department remediation plans for such outstanding vulnerabilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the average length of time between the reporting of security vulnerabilities and remediation of such vulnerabilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the types of compensation provided under such program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the lessons learned from such program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the public accessibility of contact information for the Department regarding the bug bounty program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the incorporation of bug bounty program identified vulnerabilities into existing Department vulnerability prioritization and management processes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> any challenges in implementing the bug bounty program and plans for expansion or contraction in the scope of the bug bounty program across Department information systems.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. I, title XCV, § 9509</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3907</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10307.</num>
<heading> Digital Connectivity and Cybersecurity Partnership</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Digital Connectivity and Cybersecurity Partnership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to establish a program, which may be known as the “Digital Connectivity and Cybersecurity Partnership”, to help foreign countries—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> expand and increase secure internet access and digital infrastructure in emerging markets, including demand for and availability of high-quality information and communications technology (ICT) equipment, software, and services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> protect technological assets, including data;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> adopt policies and regulatory positions that foster and encourage open, interoperable, reliable, and secure internet, the free flow of data, multi-stakeholder models of internet governance, and pro-competitive and secure ICT policies and regulations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> access United States exports of ICT goods and services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> expand interoperability and promote the diversification of ICT goods and supply chain services to be less reliant on imports from the People’s Republic of China;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> promote best practices and common standards for a national approach to cybersecurity; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> advance other priorities consistent with paragraphs (1) through (6), as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Funds made available to carry out this section may be used to strengthen civilian cybersecurity and information and communications technology capacity, including participation of foreign law enforcement and military personnel in non-military activities, notwithstanding any other provision of law, provided that such support is essential to enabling civilian and law enforcement of cybersecurity and information and communication technology related activities in their respective countries.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2023-12-22">December 22, 2023</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and the Committee on Oversight and Accountability of the House of Representatives an implementation plan for the coming year to advance the goals identified in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In developing and operationalizing the implementation plan required under subsection (c), the Secretary shall consult with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the appropriate congressional committees, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> United States industry leaders;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> other relevant technology experts, including the Open Technology Fund;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> representatives from relevant United States Government agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> representatives from like-minded allies and partners.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the purposes of carrying out this section, funds authorized to be appropriated to carry out chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 2346</ref> et seq.) may be made available, notwithstanding any other provision of law to strengthen civilian cybersecurity and information and communications technology capacity, including for participation of foreign law enforcement and military personnel in non-military activities, and for contributions to international organizations and international financial institutions of which the United States is a member. Such funds shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. F, title LXIII, § 6306</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 989</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10308.</num>
<heading> Cyber protection support for personnel of the Department of State in positions highly vulnerable to cyber attack</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> At-risk personnel</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “at-risk personnel” means personnel of the Department—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> whom the Secretary determines to be highly vulnerable to cyber attacks and hostile information collection activities because of their positions in the Department; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> whose personal technology devices or personal accounts are highly vulnerable to cyber attacks and hostile information collection activities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personal accounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “personal accounts” means accounts for online and telecommunications services, including telephone, residential internet access, email, text and multimedia messaging, cloud computing, social media, health care, and financial services, used by Department personnel outside of the scope of their employment with the Department.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personal technology devices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “personal technology devices” means technology devices used by personnel of the Department outside of the scope of their employment with the Department, including networks to which such devices connect.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement to provide cyber protection support</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Director of National Intelligence, as appropriate—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall offer cyber protection support for the personal technology devices and personal accounts of at-risk personnel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> may provide the support described in paragraph (1) to any Department personnel who request such support.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nature of cyber protection support</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the availability of resources, the cyber protection support provided to personnel pursuant to subsection (b) may include training, advice, assistance, and other services relating to protection against cyber attacks and hostile information collection activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Privacy protections for personal devices</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Department is prohibited pursuant to this section from accessing or retrieving any information from any personal technology device or personal account of Department employees unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> access or information retrieval is necessary for carrying out the cyber protection support specified in this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Department has received explicit consent from the employee to access a personal technology device or personal account prior to each time such device or account is accessed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this section may be construed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to encourage Department personnel to use personal technology devices for official business; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to authorize cyber protection support for senior Department personnel using personal devices, networks, and personal accounts in an official capacity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2023-12-22">December 22, 2023</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report regarding the provision of cyber protection support pursuant to subsection (b), which shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of the methodology used to make the determination under subsection (a)(1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> guidance for the use of cyber protection support and tracking of support requests for personnel receiving cyber protection support pursuant to subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate committees of Congress defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the appropriate congressional committees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Select Committee on Intelligence and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence and the Committee on Oversight and Accountability of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–31, div. F, title LXIII, § 6308</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 993</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>