<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 69A—</num>
<heading>CUBAN LIBERTY AND DEMOCRATIC SOLIDARITY (LIBERTAD)</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6021.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The economy of Cuba has experienced a decline of at least 60 percent in the last 5 years as a result of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the end of its subsidization by the former Soviet Union of between 5 billion and 6 billion dollars annually;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 36 years of communist tyranny and economic mismanagement by the Castro government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the extreme decline in trade between Cuba and the countries of the former Soviet bloc; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the stated policy of the Russian Government and the countries of the former Soviet bloc to conduct economic relations with Cuba on strictly commercial terms.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> At the same time, the welfare and health of the Cuban people have substantially deteriorated as a result of this economic decline and the refusal of the Castro regime to permit free and fair democratic elections in Cuba.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Castro regime has made it abundantly clear that it will not engage in any substantive political reforms that would lead to democracy, a market economy, or an economic recovery.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The repression of the Cuban people, including a ban on free and fair democratic elections, and continuing violations of fundamental human rights, have isolated the Cuban regime as the only completely nondemocratic government in the Western Hemisphere.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> As long as free elections are not held in Cuba, the economic condition of the country and the welfare of the Cuban people will not improve in any significant way.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The totalitarian nature of the Castro regime has deprived the Cuban people of any peaceful means to improve their condition and has led thousands of Cuban citizens to risk or lose their lives in dangerous attempts to escape from Cuba to freedom.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> Radio Marti and Television Marti have both been effective vehicles for providing the people of Cuba with news and information and have helped to bolster the morale of the people of Cuba living under tyranny.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The consistent policy of the United States towards Cuba since the beginning of the Castro regime, carried out by both Democratic and Republican administrations, has sought to keep faith with the people of Cuba, and has been effective in sanctioning the totalitarian Castro regime.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The United States has shown a deep commitment, and considers it a moral obligation, to promote and protect human rights and fundamental freedoms as expressed in the Charter of the United Nations and in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The Congress has historically and consistently manifested its solidarity and the solidarity of the American people with the democratic aspirations of the Cuban people.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> The Cuban Democracy Act of 1992 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 6001</ref> et seq.] calls upon the President to encourage the governments of countries that conduct trade with Cuba to restrict their trade and credit relations with Cuba in a manner consistent with the purposes of that Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> Amendments to the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.] made by the FREEDOM Support Act require that the President, in providing economic assistance to Russia and the emerging Eurasian democracies, take into account the extent to which they are acting to “terminate support for the communist regime in Cuba, including removal of troops, closing military facilities, and ceasing trade subsidies and economic, nuclear, and other assistance”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> The Cuban Government engages in the illegal international narcotics trade and harbors fugitives from justice in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> The Castro government threatens international peace and security by engaging in acts of armed subversion and terrorism such as the training and supplying of groups dedicated to international violence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> The Castro government has utilized from its inception and continues to utilize torture in various forms (including by psychiatry), as well as execution, exile, confiscation, political imprisonment, and other forms of terror and repression, as means of retaining power.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> Fidel Castro has defined democratic pluralism as “pluralistic garbage” and continues to make clear that he has no intention of tolerating the democratization of Cuban society.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(17)</num>
<content> The Castro government holds innocent Cubans hostage in Cuba by no fault of the hostages themselves solely because relatives have escaped the country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> Although a signatory state to the 1928 Inter-American Convention on Asylum and the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights (which protects the right to leave one’s own country), Cuba nevertheless surrounds embassies in its capital by armed forces to thwart the right of its citizens to seek asylum and systematically denies that right to the Cuban people, punishing them by imprisonment for seeking to leave the country and killing them for attempting to do so (as demonstrated in the case of the confirmed murder of over 40 men, women, and children who were seeking to leave Cuba on <date date="1994-07-13">July 13, 1994</date>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> The Castro government continues to utilize blackmail, such as the immigration crisis with which it threatened the United States in the summer of 1994, and other unacceptable and illegal forms of conduct to influence the actions of sovereign states in the Western Hemisphere in violation of the Charter of the Organization of American States and other international agreements and international law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<content> The United Nations Commission on Human Rights has repeatedly reported on the unacceptable human rights situation in Cuba and has taken the extraordinary step of appointing a Special Rapporteur.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<content> The Cuban Government has consistently refused access to the Special Rapporteur and formally expressed its decision not to “implement so much as one comma” of the United Nations Resolutions appointing the Rapporteur.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<content> The United Nations General Assembly passed Resolution 47–139 on <date date="1992-12-18">December 18, 1992</date>, Resolution 48–142 on <date date="1993-12-20">December 20, 1993</date>, and Resolution 49–200 on <date date="1994-12-23">December 23, 1994</date>, referencing the Special Rapporteur’s reports to the United Nations and condemning violations of human rights and fundamental freedoms in Cuba.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(23)</num>
<content> Article 39 of Chapter VII of the United Nations Charter provides that the United Nations Security Council “shall determine the existence of any threat to the peace, breach of the peace, or act of aggression and shall make recommendations, or decide what measures shall be taken . . ., to maintain or restore international peace and security.”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(24)</num>
<content> The United Nations has determined that massive and systematic violations of human rights may constitute a “threat to peace” under Article 39 and has imposed sanctions due to such violations of human rights in the cases of Rhodesia, South Africa, Iraq, and the former Yugoslavia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(25)</num>
<content> In the case of Haiti, a neighbor of Cuba not as close to the United States as Cuba, the United States led an effort to obtain and did obtain a United Nations Security Council embargo and blockade against that country due to the existence of a military dictatorship in power less than 3 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(26)</num>
<content> United Nations Security Council Resolution 940 of <date date="1994-07-31">July 31, 1994</date>, subsequently authorized the use of “all necessary means” to restore the “democratically elected government of Haiti”, and the democratically elected government of Haiti was restored to power on <date date="1994-10-15">October 15, 1994</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(27)</num>
<content> The Cuban people deserve to be assisted in a decisive manner to end the tyranny that has oppressed them for 36 years, and the continued failure to do so constitutes ethically improper conduct by the international community.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(28)</num>
<content> For the past 36 years, the Cuban Government has posed and continues to pose a national security threat to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, § 2</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 786</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6022.</num>
<heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to assist the Cuban people in regaining their freedom and prosperity, as well as in joining the community of democratic countries that are flourishing in the Western Hemisphere;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to strengthen international sanctions against the Castro government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to provide for the continued national security of the United States in the face of continuing threats from the Castro government of terrorism, theft of property from United States nationals by the Castro government, and the political manipulation by the Castro government of the desire of Cubans to escape that results in mass migration to the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to encourage the holding of free and fair democratic elections in Cuba, conducted under the supervision of internationally recognized observers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> to provide a policy framework for United States support to the Cuban people in response to the formation of a transition government or a democratically elected government in Cuba; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> to protect United States nationals against confiscatory takings and the wrongful trafficking in property confiscated by the Castro regime.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, § 3</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 788</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6023.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the following terms have the following meanings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agency or instrumentality of a foreign state</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “agency or instrumentality of a foreign state” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 1603(b) of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on International Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commercial activity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “commercial activity” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 1603(d) of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confiscated</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">As used in subchapters I and III, the term “confiscated” refers to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the nationalization, expropriation, or other seizure by the Cuban Government of ownership or control of property, on or after <date date="1959-01-01">January 1, 1959</date>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> without the property having been returned or adequate and effective compensation provided; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> without the claim to the property having been settled pursuant to an international claims settlement agreement or other mutually accepted settlement procedure; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the repudiation by the Cuban Government of, the default by the Cuban Government on, or the failure of the Cuban Government to pay, on or after <date date="1959-01-01">January 1, 1959</date>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a debt of any enterprise which has been nationalized, expropriated, or otherwise taken by the Cuban Government;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a debt which is a charge on property nationalized, expropriated, or otherwise taken by the Cuban Government; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a debt which was incurred by the Cuban Government in satisfaction or settlement of a confiscated property claim.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cuban Government</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “Cuban Government” includes the government of any political subdivision of Cuba, and any agency or instrumentality of the Government of Cuba.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “agency or instrumentality of the Government of Cuba” means an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state as defined in <ref>section 1603(b) of title 28</ref>, with each reference in such section to “a foreign state” deemed to be a reference to “Cuba”.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Democratically elected government in Cuba</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “democratically elected government in Cuba” means a government determined by the President to have met the requirements of <ref>section 6066 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Economic embargo of Cuba</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “economic embargo of Cuba” refers to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the economic embargo (including all restrictions on trade or transactions with, and travel to or from, Cuba, and all restrictions on transactions in property in which Cuba or nationals of Cuba have an interest) that was imposed against Cuba pursuant to <ref>section 2370(a) of this title</ref>, <ref>section 4305(b) of title 50</ref>, the Cuban Democracy Act of 1992 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 6001</ref> and following), or any other provision of law; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the restrictions imposed by section 902(c) of the Food Security Act of 1985.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign national</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “foreign national” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an alien; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any corporation, trust, partnership, or other juridical entity not organized under the laws of the United States, or of any State, the District of Columbia, or any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Knowingly</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “knowingly” means with knowledge or having reason to know.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Official of the Cuban Government or the ruling political party in Cuba</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “official of the Cuban Government or the ruling political party in Cuba” refers to any member of the Council of Ministers, Council of State, central committee of the Communist Party of Cuba, or the Politburo of Cuba, or their equivalents.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “person” means any person or entity, including any agency or instrumentality of a foreign state.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Property</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “property” means any property (including patents, copyrights, trademarks, and any other form of intellectual property), whether real, personal, or mixed, and any present, future, or contingent right, security, or other interest therein, including any leasehold interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of subchapter III of this chapter, the term “property” does not include real property used for residential purposes unless, as of <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the claim to the property is held by a United States national and the claim has been certified under title V of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1643</ref> et seq.]; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the property is occupied by an official of the Cuban Government or the ruling political party in Cuba.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Traffics</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> As used in subchapter III, and except as provided in subparagraph (B), a person “traffics” in confiscated property if that person knowingly and intentionally—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> sells, transfers, distributes, dispenses, brokers, manages, or otherwise disposes of confiscated property, or purchases, leases, receives, possesses, obtains control of, manages, uses, or otherwise acquires or holds an interest in confiscated property,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> engages in a commercial activity using or otherwise benefiting from confiscated property, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> causes, directs, participates in, or profits from, trafficking (as described in clause (i) or (ii)) by another person, or otherwise engages in trafficking (as described in clause (i) or (ii)) through another person,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">without the authorization of any United States national who holds a claim to the property.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The term “traffics” does not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the delivery of international telecommunication signals to Cuba;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the trading or holding of securities publicly traded or held, unless the trading is with or by a person determined by the Secretary of the Treasury to be a specially designated national;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> transactions and uses of property incident to lawful travel to Cuba, to the extent that such transactions and uses of property are necessary to the conduct of such travel; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> transactions and uses of property by a person who is both a citizen of Cuba and a resident of Cuba, and who is not an official of the Cuban Government or the ruling political party in Cuba.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(14)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transition government in Cuba</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “transition government in Cuba” means a government that the President determines is a transition government consistent with the requirements and factors set forth in <ref>section 6065 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(15)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States national</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “United States national” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any United States citizen; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other legal entity which is organized under the laws of the United States, or of any State, the District of Columbia, or any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, and which has its principal place of business in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, § 4</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 789</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6024.</num>
<heading> Severability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any provision of this chapter or the amendments made by this chapter or the application thereof to any person or circumstance is held invalid, the remainder of this chapter, the amendments made by this chapter, or the application thereof to other persons not similarly situated or to other circumstances shall not be affected by such invalidation.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, § 5</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 791</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>STRENGTHENING INTERNATIONAL SANCTIONS AGAINST THE CASTRO GOVERNMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6031.</num>
<heading> Statement of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the acts of the Castro government, including its massive, systematic, and extraordinary violations of human rights, are a threat to international peace;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the President should advocate, and should instruct the United States Permanent Representative to the United Nations to propose and seek within the Security Council, a mandatory international embargo against the totalitarian Cuban Government pursuant to chapter VII of the Charter of the United Nations, employing efforts similar to consultations conducted by United States representatives with respect to Haiti;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any resumption of efforts by any independent state of the former Soviet Union to make operational any nuclear facilities in Cuba, and any continuation of intelligence activities by such a state from Cuba that are targeted at the United States and its citizens will have a detrimental impact on United States assistance to such state; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> in view of the threat to the national security posed by the operation of any nuclear facility, and the Castro government’s continuing blackmail to unleash another wave of Cuban refugees fleeing from Castro’s oppression, most of whom find their way to United States shores, further depleting limited humanitarian and other resources of the United States, the President should do all in his power to make it clear to the Cuban Government that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the completion and operation of any nuclear power facility, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any further political manipulation of the desire of Cubans to escape that results in mass migration to the United States,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">will be considered an act of aggression which will be met with an appropriate response in order to maintain the security of the national borders of the United States and the health and safety of the American people.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 791</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6032.</num>
<heading> Enforcement of economic embargo of Cuba</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Policy</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions by other countries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Congress hereby reaffirms section 1704(a) of the Cuban Democracy Act of 1992 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 6003(a)</ref>], which states that the President should encourage foreign countries to restrict trade and credit relations with Cuba in a manner consistent with the purposes of that Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 6001</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanctions on other countries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Congress further urges the President to take immediate steps to apply the sanctions described in section 1704(b)(1) of that Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 6003(b)(1)</ref>] against countries assisting Cuba.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Diplomatic efforts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State should ensure that United States diplomatic personnel abroad understand and, in their contacts with foreign officials, are communicating the reasons for the United States economic embargo of Cuba, and are urging foreign governments to cooperate more effectively with the embargo.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall instruct the Secretary of the Treasury and the Attorney General to enforce fully the Cuban Assets Control Regulations set forth in part 515 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Denial of visas to certain Cuban nationals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that the President should instruct the Secretary of State and the Attorney General to enforce fully existing regulations to deny visas to Cuban nationals considered by the Secretary of State to be officers or employees of the Cuban Government or of the Communist Party of Cuba.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold">, (g) Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Codification of economic embargo</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The economic embargo of Cuba, as in effect on <date date="1996-03-01">March 1, 1996</date>, including all restrictions under part 515 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, shall be in effect on <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>, and shall remain in effect, subject to <ref>section 6064 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 792</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6033.</num>
<heading> Prohibition against indirect financing of Cuba</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no loan, credit, or other financing may be extended knowingly by a United States national, a permanent resident alien, or a United States agency to any person for the purpose of financing transactions involving any confiscated property the claim to which is owned by a United States national as of <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>, except for financing by the United States national owning such claim for a transaction permitted under United States law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension and termination of prohibition</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President is authorized to suspend the prohibition contained in subsection (a) upon a determination made under <ref>section 6063(c)(1) of this title</ref> that a transition government in Cuba is in power.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The prohibition contained in subsection (a) shall cease to apply on the date on which the economic embargo of Cuba terminates as provided in <ref>section 6064 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Violations of subsection (a) shall be punishable by such civil penalties as are applicable to violations of the Cuban Assets Control Regulations set forth in part 515 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “permanent resident alien” means an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence into the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “United States agency” has the meaning given the term “agency” in <ref>section 551(1) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 794</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6034.</num>
<heading> United States opposition to Cuban membership in international financial institutions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continued opposition to Cuban membership in international financial institutions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States executive director of each international financial institution to use the voice and vote of the United States to oppose the admission of Cuba as a member of such institution until the President submits a determination under <ref>section 6063(c)(3) of this title</ref> that a democratically elected government in Cuba is in power.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transition government</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Once the President submits a determination under <ref>section 6063(c)(1) of this title</ref> that a transition government in Cuba is in power—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the President is encouraged to take steps to support the processing of Cuba’s application for membership in any international financial institution, subject to the membership taking effect after a democratically elected government in Cuba is in power, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to instruct the United States executive director of each international financial institution to support loans or other assistance to Cuba only to the extent that such loans or assistance contribute to a stable foundation for a democratically elected government in Cuba.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction in United States payments to international financial institutions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If any international financial institution approves a loan or other assistance to the Cuban Government over the opposition of the United States, then the Secretary of the Treasury shall withhold from payment to such institution an amount equal to the amount of the loan or other assistance, with respect to either of the following types of payment:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The paid-in portion of the increase in capital stock of the institution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The callable portion of the increase in capital stock of the institution.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “International financial institution” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “international financial institution” means the International Monetary Fund, the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, the International Development Association, the International Finance Corporation, the Multilateral Investment Guaranty Agency, and the Inter-American Development Bank.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 794</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6035.</num>
<heading> United States opposition to termination of suspension of Cuban Government from participation in Organization of American States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President should instruct the United States Permanent Representative to the Organization of American States to oppose and vote against any termination of the suspension of the Cuban Government from participation in the Organization until the President determines under <ref>section 6063(c)(3) of this title</ref> that a democratically elected government in Cuba is in power.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 795</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6036.</num>
<heading> Assistance by independent states of former Soviet Union for Cuban Government</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report detailing progress toward the withdrawal of personnel of any independent state of the former Soviet Union (within the meaning of <ref>section 5801 of this title</ref>), including advisers, technicians, and military personnel, from the Cienfuegos nuclear facility in Cuba.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold">, (c) Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Facilities at Lourdes, Cuba</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disapproval of credits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Congress expresses its strong disapproval of the extension by Russia of credits equivalent to $200,000,000 in support of the intelligence facility at Lourdes, Cuba, in November 1994.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 795</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6037.</num>
<heading> Television broadcasting to Cuba</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conversion to UHF</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director of the International Broadcasting Bureau shall implement a conversion of television broadcasting to Cuba under the Television Marti Service to ultra high frequency (UHF) broadcasting.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Periodic reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 45 days after <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>, and every three months thereafter until the conversion described in subsection (a) is fully implemented, the Director of the International Broadcasting Bureau shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees on the progress made in carrying out subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of broadcasting authorities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon transmittal of a determination under <ref>section 6063(c)(3) of this title</ref>, the Television Broadcasting to Cuba Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 1465aa</ref> and following) and the Radio Broadcasting to Cuba Act (<ref>22 U.S.C. 1465</ref> and following) are repealed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 798</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1335(r), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–790</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6038.</num>
<heading> Reports on commerce with, and assistance to, Cuba from other foreign countries</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>, and by January 1 of each year thereafter until the President submits a determination under <ref>section 6063(c)(1) of this title</ref>, the President shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees on commerce with, and assistance to, Cuba from other foreign countries during the preceding 12-month period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each report required by subsection (a) shall, for the period covered by the report, contain the following, to the extent such information is available:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A description of all bilateral assistance provided to Cuba by other foreign countries, including humanitarian assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A description of Cuba’s commerce with foreign countries, including an identification of Cuba’s trading partners and the extent of such trade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A description of the joint ventures completed, or under consideration, by foreign nationals and business firms involving facilities in Cuba, including an identification of the location of the facilities involved and a description of the terms of agreement of the joint ventures and the names of the parties that are involved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A determination as to whether or not any of the facilities described in paragraph (3) is the subject of a claim against Cuba by a United States national.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> A determination of the amount of debt of the Cuban Government that is owed to each foreign country, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the amount of debt exchanged, forgiven, or reduced under the terms of each investment or operation in Cuba involving foreign nationals; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amount of debt owed the foreign country that has been exchanged, forgiven, or reduced in return for a grant by the Cuban Government of an equity interest in a property, investment, or operation of the Cuban Government or of a Cuban national.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> A description of the steps taken to assure that raw materials and semifinished or finished goods produced by facilities in Cuba involving foreign nationals do not enter the United States market, either directly or through third countries or parties.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> An identification of countries that purchase, or have purchased, arms or military supplies from Cuba or that otherwise have entered into agreements with Cuba that have a military application, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a description of the military supplies, equipment, or other material sold, bartered, or exchanged between Cuba and such countries,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a listing of the goods, services, credits, or other consideration received by Cuba in exchange for military supplies, equipment, or material, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the terms or conditions of any such agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 798</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6039.</num>
<heading> Authorization of support for democratic and human rights groups and international observers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including <ref>section 6032 of this title</ref>), except for <ref>section 2394–1 of this title</ref> and comparable notification requirements contained in any Act making appropriations for foreign operations, export financing, and related programs, the President is authorized to furnish assistance and provide other support for individuals and independent nongovernmental organizations to support democracy-building efforts for Cuba, including the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Published and informational matter, such as books, videos, and cassettes, on transitions to democracy, human rights, and market economies, to be made available to independent democratic groups in Cuba.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Humanitarian assistance to victims of political repression, and their families.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Support for democratic and human rights groups in Cuba.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Support for visits and permanent deployment of independent international human rights monitors in Cuba.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> OAS emergency fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> For support of human rights and elections</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President shall take the necessary steps to encourage the Organization of American States to create a special emergency fund for the explicit purpose of deploying human rights observers, election support, and election observation in Cuba.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action of other member states</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President should instruct the United States Permanent Representative to the Organization of American States to encourage other member states of the Organization to join in calling for the Cuban Government to allow the immediate deployment of independent human rights monitors of the Organization throughout Cuba and on-site visits to Cuba by the Inter-American Commission on Human Rights.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Voluntary contributions for fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding <ref>section 2227 of this title</ref> or any other provision of law limiting the United States proportionate share of assistance to Cuba by any international organization, the President should provide not less than $5,000,000 of the voluntary contributions of the United States to the Organization of American States solely for the purposes of the special fund referred to in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Denial of funds to Cuban Government</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In implementing this section, the President shall take all necessary steps to ensure that no funds or other assistance is provided to the Cuban Government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 799</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6040.</num>
<heading> Importation safeguard against certain Cuban products</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on import of and dealings in Cuban products</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress notes that section 515.204 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, prohibits the entry of, and dealings outside the United States in, merchandise that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is of Cuban origin;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is or has been located in or transported from or through Cuba; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is made or derived in whole or in part of any article which is the growth, produce, or manufacture of Cuba.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of NAFTA</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress notes that United States accession to the North American Free Trade Agreement does not modify or alter the United States sanctions against Cuba. The statement of administrative action accompanying that trade agreement specifically states the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> “The NAFTA rules of origin will not in any way diminish the Cuban sanctions program. … Nothing in the NAFTA would operate to override this prohibition.”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> “Article 309(3) [of the NAFTA] permits the United States to ensure that Cuban products or goods made from Cuban materials are not imported into the United States from Mexico or Canada and that United States products are not exported to Cuba through those countries.”.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restriction of sugar imports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Congress notes that section 902(c) of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<ref>Public Law 99–198</ref>) requires the President not to allocate any of the sugar import quota to a country that is a net importer of sugar unless appropriate officials of that country verify to the President that the country does not import for reexport to the United States any sugar produced in Cuba.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assurances regarding sugar products</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Protection of essential security interests of the United States requires assurances that sugar products that are entered, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, into the customs territory of the United States are not products of Cuba.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title I, § 110</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 800</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6041.</num>
<heading> Withholding of foreign assistance from countries supporting Juragua nuclear plant in Cuba</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> President Clinton stated in April 1993 that the United States opposed the construction of the Juragua nuclear power plant because of the concerns of the United States about Cuba’s ability to ensure the safe operation of the facility and because of Cuba’s refusal to sign the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty or ratify the Treaty of Tlatelolco.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Cuba has not signed the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons or ratified the Treaty of Tlatelolco, the latter of which establishes Latin America and the Caribbean as a nuclear weapons-free zone.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The State Department, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, and the Department of Energy have expressed concerns about the construction and operation of Cuba’s nuclear reactors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> In a September 1992 report to the Congress, the General Accounting Office outlined concerns among nuclear energy experts about deficiencies in the nuclear plant project in Juragua, near Cienfuegos, Cuba, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a lack in Cuba of a nuclear regulatory structure;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the absence in Cuba of an adequate infrastructure to ensure the plant’s safe operation and requisite maintenance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the inadequacy of training of plant operators;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> reports by a former technician from Cuba who, by examining with x-rays weld sites believed to be part of the auxiliary plumbing system for the plant, found that 10 to 15 percent of those sites were defective;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> since <date date="1992-09-05">September 5, 1992</date>, when construction on the plant was halted, the prolonged exposure to the elements, including corrosive salt water vapor, of the primary reactor components; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the possible inadequacy of the upper portion of the reactors’ dome retention capability to withstand only 7 pounds of pressure per square inch, given that normal atmospheric pressure is 32 pounds per square inch and United States reactors are designed to accommodate pressures of 50 pounds per square inch.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The United States Geological Survey claims that it had difficulty determining answers to specific questions regarding earthquake activity in the area near Cienfuegos because the Cuban Government was not forthcoming with information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The Geological Survey has indicated that the Caribbean plate, a geological formation near the south coast of Cuba, may pose seismic risks to Cuba and the site of the power plant, and may produce large to moderate earthquakes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> On <date date="1992-05-25">May 25, 1992</date>, the Caribbean plate produced an earthquake numbering 7.0 on the Richter scale.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> According to a study by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, summer winds could carry radioactive pollutants from a nuclear accident at the power plant throughout all of Florida and parts of the States on the coast of the Gulf of Mexico as far as Texas, and northern winds could carry the pollutants as far northeast as Virginia and Washington, D.C.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The Cuban Government, under dictator Fidel Castro, in 1962 advocated the Soviets’ launching of nuclear missiles to the United States, which represented a direct and dangerous provocation of the United States and brought the world to the brink of a nuclear conflict.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Fidel Castro over the years has consistently issued threats against the United States Government, most recently that he would unleash another perilous mass migration from Cuba upon the enactment of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> Despite the various concerns about the plant’s safety and operational problems, a feasibility study is being conducted that would establish a support group to include Russia, Cuba, and third countries with the objective of completing and operating the plant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withholding of foreign assistance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President shall withhold from assistance allocated, on or after <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>, for any country an amount equal to the sum of assistance and credits, if any, provided on or after <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>, by that country or any entity in that country in support of the completion of the Cuban nuclear facility at Juragua, near Cienfuegos, Cuba.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The requirement of paragraph (1) to withhold assistance shall not apply with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assistance to meet urgent humanitarian needs, including disaster and refugee relief;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> democratic political reform or rule of law activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the creation of private sector or nongovernmental organizations that are independent of government control;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the development of a free market economic system;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> assistance for the purposes described in the Cooperative Threat Reduction Act of 1993 (title XII of <ref>Public Law 103–160</ref>) [<ref>22 U.S.C. 5951</ref> et seq.]; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> assistance under the secondary school exchange program administered by the United States Information Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Assistance” defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">As used in paragraph (1), the term “assistance” means assistance under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.], credits, sales, guarantees of extensions of credit, and other assistance under the Arms Export Control Act [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.], assistance under titles I and III of the Food for Peace Act [<ref>7 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq., 1727 et seq.], assistance under the FREEDOM Support Act, and any other program of assistance or credits provided by the United States to other countries under other provisions of law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 800</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, title III, § 3001(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (2)(W), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1820</ref>, 1821.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6042.</num>
<heading> Reinstitution of family remittances and travel to Cuba</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that the President should—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> before considering the reinstitution of general licenses for family remittances to Cuba, insist that, prior to such reinstitution, the Cuban Government permit the unfettered operation of small businesses fully empowered with the right to hire others to whom they may pay wages and to buy materials necessary in the operation of the businesses, and with such other authority and freedom as are required to foster the operation of small businesses throughout Cuba; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if licenses described in subparagraph (A) are reinstituted, require a specific license for remittances described in subparagraph (A) in amounts of more than $500; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> before considering the reinstitution of general licenses for travel to Cuba by individuals resident in the United States who are family members of Cuban nationals who are resident in Cuba, insist on such actions by the Cuban Government as abrogation of the sanction for departure from Cuba by refugees, release of political prisoners, recognition of the right of association, and other fundamental freedoms.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title I, § 112</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 802</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6043.</num>
<heading> Expulsion of criminals from Cuba</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall instruct all United States Government officials who engage in official contacts with the Cuban Government to raise on a regular basis the extradition of or rendering to the United States all persons residing in Cuba who are sought by the United States Department of Justice for crimes committed in the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title I, § 113</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 803</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6044.</num>
<heading> News bureaus in Cuba</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of news bureaus</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President is authorized to establish and implement an exchange of news bureaus between the United States and Cuba, if the exchange meets the following conditions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The exchange is fully reciprocal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Cuban Government agrees not to interfere with the establishment of news bureaus or with the movement in Cuba of journalists of any United States-based news organizations, including Radio Marti and Television Marti.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Cuban Government agrees not to interfere with decisions of United States-based news organizations with respect to individuals assigned to work as journalists in their news bureaus in Cuba.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Department of the Treasury is able to ensure that only accredited journalists regularly employed with a news gathering organization travel to Cuba under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Cuban Government agrees not to interfere with the transmission of telecommunications signals of news bureaus or with the distribution within Cuba of publications of any United States-based news organization that has a news bureau in Cuba.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assurance against espionage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In implementing this section, the President shall take all necessary steps to ensure the safety and security of the United States against espionage by Cuban journalists it believes to be working for the intelligence agencies of the Cuban Government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fully reciprocal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As used in subsection (a)(1), the term “fully reciprocal” means that all news services, news organizations, and broadcasting services, including such services or organizations that receive financing, assistance, or other support from a governmental or official source, are permitted to establish and operate a news bureau in the United States and Cuba.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 803</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6045.</num>
<heading> Effect of chapter on lawful United States Government activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter prohibits any lawfully authorized investigative, protective, or intelligence activity of a law enforcement agency, or of an intelligence agency, of the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 803</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6046.</num>
<heading> Condemnation of Cuban attack on American aircraft</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Brothers to the Rescue is a Miami-based humanitarian organization engaged in searching for and aiding Cuban refugees in the Straits of Florida, and was engaged in such a mission on Saturday, <date date="1996-02-24">February 24, 1996</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The members of Brothers to the Rescue were flying unarmed and defenseless planes in a mission identical to hundreds they have flown since 1991 and posed no threat whatsoever to the Cuban Government, the Cuban military, or the Cuban people.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Statements by the Cuban Government that Brothers to the Rescue has engaged in covert operations, bombing campaigns, and commando operations against the Government of Cuba have no basis in fact.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The Brothers to the Rescue aircraft notified air traffic controllers as to their flight plans, which would take them south of the 24th parallel and close to Cuban airspace.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> International law provides a nation with airspace over the 12-mile territorial sea.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The response of Fidel Castro’s dictatorship to Saturday’s afternoon flight was to scramble 2 fighter jets from a Havana airfield.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> At approximately 3:24 p.m., the pilot of one of the Cuban MiGs received permission and proceeded to shoot down one Brothers to the Rescue airplane more than 6 miles north of the Cuban exclusion zone, or 18 miles from the Cuban coast.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Approximately 7 minutes later, the pilot of the Cuban fighter jet received permission and proceeded to shoot down the second Brothers to the Rescue airplane almost 18.5 miles north of the Cuban exclusion zone, or 30.5 miles from the Cuban coast.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The Cuban dictatorship, if it truly felt threatened by the flight of these unarmed aircraft, could have and should have pursued other peaceful options as required by international law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The response chosen by Fidel Castro, the use of lethal force, was completely inappropriate to the situation presented to the Cuban Government, making such actions a blatant and barbaric violation of international law and tantamount to cold-blooded murder.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> There were no survivors of the attack on these aircraft, and the crew of a third aircraft managed to escape this criminal attack by Castro’s Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> The crew members of the destroyed planes, Pablo Morales, Carlos Costa, Mario de la Pena, and Armando Alejandre, were United States citizens from Miami flying with Brothers to the Rescue on a voluntary basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> It is incumbent upon the United States Government to protect the lives and livelihoods of United States citizens as well as the rights of free passage and humanitarian missions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> This premeditated act took place after a week-long wave of repression by the Cuban Government against Concilio Cubano, an umbrella organization of human rights activists, dissidents, independent economists, and independent journalists, among others.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> The wave of repression against Concilio Cubano, whose membership is committed to peaceful democratic change in Cuba, included arrests, strip searches, house arrests, and in some cases sentences to more than 1 year in jail.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statements by Congress</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Congress strongly condemns the act of terrorism by the Castro regime in shooting down the Brothers to the Rescue aircraft on <date date="1996-02-24">February 24, 1996</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Congress extends its condolences to the families of Pablo Morales, Carlos Costa, Mario de la Pena, and Armando Alejandre, the victims of the attack.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The Congress urges the President to seek, in the International Court of Justice, indictment for this act of terrorism by Fidel Castro.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title I, § 116</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 803</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>ASSISTANCE TO FREE AND INDEPENDENT CUBA</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6061.</num>
<heading> Policy toward transition government and democratically elected government in Cuba</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The policy of the United States is as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To support the self-determination of the Cuban people.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To recognize that the self-determination of the Cuban people is a sovereign and national right of the citizens of Cuba which must be exercised free of interference by the government of any other country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To encourage the Cuban people to empower themselves with a government which reflects the self-determination of the Cuban people.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To recognize the potential for a difficult transition from the current regime in Cuba that may result from the initiatives taken by the Cuban people for self-determination in response to the intransigence of the Castro regime in not allowing any substantive political or economic reforms, and to be prepared to provide the Cuban people with humanitarian, developmental, and other economic assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> In solidarity with the Cuban people, to provide appropriate forms of assistance—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to a transition government in Cuba;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to facilitate the rapid movement from such a transition government to a democratically elected government in Cuba that results from an expression of the self-determination of the Cuban people; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to support such a democratically elected government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Through such assistance, to facilitate a peaceful transition to representative democracy and a market economy in Cuba and to consolidate democracy in Cuba.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> To deliver such assistance to the Cuban people only through a transition government in Cuba, through a democratically elected government in Cuba, through United States Government organizations, or through United States, international, or indigenous nongovernmental organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> To encourage other countries and multilateral organizations to provide similar assistance, and to work cooperatively with such countries and organizations to coordinate such assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> To ensure that appropriate assistance is rapidly provided and distributed to the people of Cuba upon the institution of a transition government in Cuba.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Not to provide favorable treatment or influence on behalf of any individual or entity in the selection by the Cuban people of their future government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> To assist a transition government in Cuba and a democratically elected government in Cuba to prepare the Cuban military forces for an appropriate role in a democracy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> To be prepared to enter into negotiations with a democratically elected government in Cuba either to return the United States Naval Base at Guantanamo to Cuba or to renegotiate the present agreement under mutually agreeable terms.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> To consider the restoration of diplomatic recognition and support the reintegration of the Cuban Government into Inter-American organizations when the President determines that there exists a democratically elected government in Cuba.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> To take steps to remove the economic embargo of Cuba when the President determines that a transition to a democratically elected government in Cuba has begun.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> To assist a democratically elected government in Cuba to strengthen and stabilize its national currency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> To pursue trade relations with a free, democratic, and independent Cuba.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 805</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6062.</num>
<heading> Assistance for Cuban people</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President shall develop a plan for providing economic assistance to Cuba at such time as the President determines that a transition government or a democratically elected government in Cuba (as determined under <ref>section 6063(c) of this title</ref>) is in power.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect on other laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Assistance may be provided under this section subject to an authorization of appropriations and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Plan for assistance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The President shall develop a plan for providing assistance under this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to Cuba when a transition government in Cuba is in power; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to Cuba when a democratically elected government in Cuba is in power.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Types of assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Assistance under the plan developed under paragraph (1) may, subject to an authorization of appropriations and subject to the availability of appropriations, include the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transition government</heading>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in clause (ii), assistance to Cuba under a transition government shall, subject to an authorization of appropriations and subject to the availability of appropriations, be limited to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> such food, medicine, medical supplies and equipment, and assistance to meet emergency energy needs, as is necessary to meet the basic human needs of the Cuban people; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> assistance described in subparagraph (C).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> Assistance in addition to assistance under clause (i) may be provided, but only after the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees, in accordance with procedures applicable to reprogramming notifications under section 634A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2394–1</ref>], that such assistance is essential to the successful completion of the transition to democracy.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> Only after a transition government in Cuba is in power, freedom of individuals to travel to visit their relatives without any restrictions shall be permitted.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Democratically elected government</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Assistance to a democratically elected government in Cuba may, subject to an authorization of appropriations and subject to the availability of appropriations, consist of economic assistance in addition to assistance available under subparagraph (A), together with assistance described in subparagraph (C). Such economic assistance may include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> assistance under chapter 1 of part I [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.] (relating to development assistance), and chapter 4 of part II [<ref>22 U.S.C. 2346</ref> et seq.] (relating to the economic support fund), of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> assistance under the Food for Peace Act [<ref>7 U.S.C. 1691</ref> et seq.];</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> financing, guarantees, and other forms of assistance provided by the Export-Import Bank of the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> financial support provided by the United States International Development Finance Corporation for investment projects in Cuba;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> assistance provided by the Trade and Development Agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> Peace Corps programs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> other appropriate assistance to carry out the policy of <ref>section 6061 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Military adjustment assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Assistance to a transition government in Cuba and to a democratically elected government in Cuba shall also include assistance in preparing the Cuban military forces to adjust to an appropriate role in a democracy.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Strategy for distribution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The plan developed under subsection (b) shall include a strategy for distributing assistance under the plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distribution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Assistance under the plan developed under subsection (b) shall be provided through United States Government organizations and nongovernmental organizations and private and voluntary organizations, whether within or outside the United States, including humanitarian, educational, labor, and private sector organizations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International efforts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall take the necessary steps—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to seek to obtain the agreement of other countries and of international financial institutions and multilateral organizations to provide to a transition government in Cuba, and to a democratically elected government in Cuba, assistance comparable to that provided by the United States under this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to work with such countries, institutions, and organizations to coordinate all such assistance programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Communication with Cuban people</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall take the necessary steps to communicate to the Cuban people the plan for assistance developed under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>, the President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing in detail the plan developed under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report on trade and investment relations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The President, following the transmittal to the Congress of a determination under <ref>section 6063(c)(3) of this title</ref> that a democratically elected government in Cuba is in power, shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the appropriate congressional committees a report that describes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> acts, policies, and practices which constitute significant barriers to, or distortions of, United States trade in goods or services or foreign direct investment with respect to Cuba;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> policy objectives of the United States regarding trade relations with a democratically elected government in Cuba, and the reasons therefor, including possible—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> reciprocal extension of nondiscriminatory trade treatment (most-favored-nation treatment);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> designation of Cuba as a beneficiary developing country under title V of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2461</ref> et seq.] (relating to the Generalized System of Preferences) or as a beneficiary country under the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2701</ref> et seq.], and the implications of such designation with respect to trade with any other country that is such a beneficiary developing country or beneficiary country or is a party to the North American Free Trade Agreement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> negotiations regarding free trade, including the accession of Cuba to the North American Free Trade Agreement;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> specific trade negotiating objectives of the United States with respect to Cuba, including the objectives described in section 108(b)(5) of the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act (<ref>19 U.S.C. 3317(b)(5)</ref>); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002329">1</ref> and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> actions proposed or anticipated to be undertaken, and any proposed legislation necessary or appropriate, to achieve any of such policy and negotiating objectives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President shall consult with the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the appropriate congressional committees and shall seek advice from the appropriate advisory committees established under section 135 of the Trade Act of 1974 [<ref>19 U.S.C. 2155</ref>] regarding the policy and negotiating objectives and the legislative proposals described in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 806</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, title III, § 3001(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (2)(W), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1820</ref>, 1821; <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. F, title VI, § 1470(n)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3518</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6063.</num>
<heading> Coordination of assistance program; implementation and reports to Congress; reprogramming</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordinating official</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall designate a coordinating official who shall be responsible for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> implementing the strategy for distributing assistance described in <ref>section 6062(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ensuring the speedy and efficient distribution of such assistance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ensuring coordination among, and appropriate oversight by, the agencies of the United States that provide assistance described in <ref>section 6062(b) of this title</ref>, including resolving any disputes among such agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States-Cuba council</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Upon making a determination under subsection (c)(3) that a democratically elected government in Cuba is in power, the President, after consultation with the coordinating official, is authorized to designate a United States-Cuba council—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to ensure coordination between the United States Government and the private sector in responding to change in Cuba, and in promoting market-based development in Cuba; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to establish periodic meetings between representatives of the United States and Cuban private sectors for the purpose of facilitating bilateral trade.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation of plan; reports to Congress</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation with respect to transition government</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon making a determination that a transition government in Cuba is in power, the President shall transmit that determination to the appropriate congressional committees and shall, subject to an authorization of appropriations and subject to the availability of appropriations, commence the delivery and distribution of assistance to such transition government under the plan developed under <ref>section 6062(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports to Congress</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report setting forth the strategy for providing assistance described in section 6062(b)(2)(A) and (C) of this title to the transition government in Cuba under the plan of assistance developed under <ref>section 6062(b) of this title</ref>, the types of such assistance, and the extent to which such assistance has been distributed in accordance with the plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The President shall transmit the report not later than 90 days after making the determination referred to in paragraph (1), except that the President shall transmit the report in preliminary form not later than 15 days after making that determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation with respect to democratically elected government</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President shall, upon determining that a democratically elected government in Cuba is in power, submit that determination to the appropriate congressional committees and shall, subject to an authorization of appropriations and subject to the availability of appropriations, commence the delivery and distribution of assistance to such democratically elected government under the plan developed under <ref>section 6062(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual reports to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 60 days after the end of each fiscal year, the President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the assistance provided under the plan developed under <ref>section 6062(b) of this title</ref>, including a description of each type of assistance, the amounts expended for such assistance, and a description of the assistance to be provided under the plan in the current fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reprogramming</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any changes in the assistance to be provided under the plan developed under <ref>section 6062(b) of this title</ref> may not be made unless the President notifies the appropriate congressional committees at least 15 days in advance in accordance with the procedures applicable to reprogramming notifications under <ref>section 2394–1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 809</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6064.</num>
<heading> Termination of economic embargo of Cuba</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon submitting a determination to the appropriate congressional committees under <ref>section 6063(c)(1) of this title</ref> that a transition government in Cuba is in power, the President, after consultation with the Congress, is authorized to take steps to suspend the economic embargo of Cuba and to suspend the right of action created in <ref>section 6082 of this title</ref> with respect to actions thereafter filed against the Cuban Government, to the extent that such steps contribute to a stable foundation for a democratically elected government in Cuba.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of certain provisions of law</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In carrying out subsection (a), the President may suspend the enforcement of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content><ref>section 2370(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content><ref>section 2370(f) of this title</ref> with respect to the “Republic of Cuba”;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> sections 6003, 6004(d), and 6005 of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> section 902(c) of the Food Security Act of 1985; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the prohibitions on transactions described in part 515 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional Presidential actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon submitting a determination to the appropriate congressional committees under <ref>section 6063(c)(3) of this title</ref> that a democratically elected government in Cuba is in power, the President shall take steps to terminate the economic embargo of Cuba, including the restrictions under part 515 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conforming amendments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">On the date on which the President submits a determination under <ref>section 6063(c)(3) of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content><ref>section 2370(a) of this title</ref> is repealed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content><ref>section 2370(f) of this title</ref> is amended by striking “Republic of Cuba”;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> sections 6003, 6004(d), and 6005 of this title are repealed; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> section 902(c) of the Food Security Act of 1985 is repealed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of suspension of economic embargo</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the President takes action under subsection (a) to suspend the economic embargo of Cuba, the President shall immediately so notify the Congress. The President shall report to the Congress no less frequently than every 6 months thereafter, until he submits a determination under <ref>section 6063(c)(3) of this title</ref> that a democratically elected government in Cuba is in power, on the progress being made by Cuba toward the establishment of such a democratically elected government. The action of the President under subsection (a) shall cease to be effective upon the enactment of a joint resolution described in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint resolutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “joint resolution” means only a joint resolution of the 2 Houses of Congress, the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: “That the Congress disapproves the action of the President under section 204(a) of the Cuban Liberty and Democratic Solidarity (LIBERTAD) Act of 1996 to suspend the economic embargo of Cuba, notice of which was submitted to the Congress on __.”, with the blank space being filled with the appropriate date.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Referral to committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Joint resolutions introduced in the House of Representatives shall be referred to the Committee on International Relations and joint resolutions introduced in the Senate shall be referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any joint resolution shall be considered in the Senate in accordance with the provisions of section 601(b) of the International Security Assistance and Arms Export Control Act of 1976.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For the purpose of expediting the consideration and enactment of joint resolutions, a motion to proceed to the consideration of any joint resolution after it has been reported by the appropriate committee shall be treated as highly privileged in the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Not more than 1 joint resolution may be considered in the House of Representatives and the Senate in the 6-month period beginning on the date on which the President notifies the Congress under paragraph (1) of the action taken under subsection (a), and in each 6-month period thereafter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 810</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6065.</num>
<heading> Requirements and factors for determining transition government</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter, a transition government in Cuba is a government that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has legalized all political activity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> has released all political prisoners and allowed for investigations of Cuban prisons by appropriate international human rights organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> has dissolved the present Department of State Security in the Cuban Ministry of the Interior, including the Committees for the Defense of the Revolution and the Rapid Response Brigades; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> has made public commitments to organizing free and fair elections for a new government—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to be held in a timely manner within a period not to exceed 18 months after the transition government assumes power;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with the participation of multiple independent political parties that have full access to the media on an equal basis, including (in the case of radio, television, or other telecommunications media) in terms of allotments of time for such access and the times of day such allotments are given; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to be conducted under the supervision of internationally recognized observers, such as the Organization of American States, the United Nations, and other election monitors;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> has ceased any interference with Radio Marti or Television Marti broadcasts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> makes public commitments to and is making demonstrable progress in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> establishing an independent judiciary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> respecting internationally recognized human rights and basic freedoms as set forth in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, to which Cuba is a signatory nation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> allowing the establishment of independent trade unions as set forth in conventions 87 and 98 of the International Labor Organization, and allowing the establishment of independent social, economic, and political associations;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> does not include Fidel Castro or Raul Castro; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> has given adequate assurances that it will allow the speedy and efficient distribution of assistance to the Cuban people.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional factors</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In addition to the requirements in subsection (a), in determining whether a transition government in Cuba is in power, the President shall take into account the extent to which that government—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is demonstrably in transition from a communist totalitarian dictatorship to representative democracy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> has made public commitments to, and is making demonstrable progress in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> effectively guaranteeing the rights of free speech and freedom of the press, including granting permits to privately owned media and telecommunications companies to operate in Cuba;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> permitting the reinstatement of citizenship to Cuban-born persons returning to Cuba;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> assuring the right to private property; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> taking appropriate steps to return to United States citizens (and entities which are 50 percent or more beneficially owned by United States citizens) property taken by the Cuban Government from such citizens and entities on or after <date date="1959-01-01">January 1, 1959</date>, or to provide equitable compensation to such citizens and entities for such property;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> has extradited or otherwise rendered to the United States all persons sought by the United States Department of Justice for crimes committed in the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> has permitted the deployment throughout Cuba of independent and unfettered international human rights monitors.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 811</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6066.</num>
<heading> Requirements for determining democratically elected government</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, a democratically elected government in Cuba, in addition to meeting the requirements of <ref>section 6065(a) of this title</ref>, is a government which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> results from free and fair elections—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> conducted under the supervision of internationally recognized observers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> in which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> opposition parties were permitted ample time to organize and campaign for such elections; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> all candidates were permitted full access to the media;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is showing respect for the basic civil liberties and human rights of the citizens of Cuba;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is substantially moving toward a market-oriented economic system based on the right to own and enjoy property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> is committed to making constitutional changes that would ensure regular free and fair elections and the full enjoyment of basic civil liberties and human rights by the citizens of Cuba;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> has made demonstrable progress in establishing an independent judiciary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> has made demonstrable progress in returning to United States citizens (and entities which are 50 percent or more beneficially owned by United States citizens) property taken by the Cuban Government from such citizens and entities on or after <date date="1959-01-01">January 1, 1959</date>, or providing full compensation for such property in accordance with international law standards and practice.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 812</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6067.</num>
<heading> Settlement of outstanding United States claims to confiscated property in Cuba</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>, the Secretary of State shall provide a report to the appropriate congressional committees containing an assessment of the property dispute question in Cuba, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an estimate of the number and amount of claims to property confiscated by the Cuban Government that are held by United States nationals in addition to those claims certified under <ref>section 1643f of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an assessment of the significance of promptly resolving confiscated property claims to the revitalization of the Cuban economy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a review and evaluation of technical and other assistance that the United States could provide to help either a transition government in Cuba or a democratically elected government in Cuba establish mechanisms to resolve property questions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> an assessment of the role and types of support the United States could provide to help resolve claims to property confiscated by the Cuban Government that are held by United States nationals who did not receive or qualify for certification under <ref>section 1643f of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> an assessment of any areas requiring legislative review or action regarding the resolution of property claims in Cuba prior to a change of government in Cuba.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002330">1</ref> Sense of Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that the satisfactory resolution of property claims by a Cuban Government recognized by the United States remains an essential condition for the full resumption of economic and diplomatic relations between the United States and Cuba.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 813</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>PROTECTION OF PROPERTY RIGHTS OF UNITED STATES NATIONALS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6081.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Individuals enjoy a fundamental right to own and enjoy property which is enshrined in the United States Constitution.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The wrongful confiscation or taking of property belonging to United States nationals by the Cuban Government, and the subsequent exploitation of this property at the expense of the rightful owner, undermines the comity of nations, the free flow of commerce, and economic development.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> Since Fidel Castro seized power in Cuba in 1959—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> he has trampled on the fundamental rights of the Cuban people; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> through his personal despotism, he has confiscated the property of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> millions of his own citizens;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> thousands of United States nationals; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> thousands more Cubans who claimed asylum in the United States as refugees because of persecution and later became naturalized citizens of the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> It is in the interest of the Cuban people that the Cuban Government respect equally the property rights of Cuban nationals and nationals of other countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The Cuban Government is offering foreign investors the opportunity to purchase an equity interest in, manage, or enter into joint ventures using property and assets some of which were confiscated from United States nationals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> This “trafficking” in confiscated property provides badly needed financial benefit, including hard currency, oil, and productive investment and expertise, to the current Cuban Government and thus undermines the foreign policy of the United States—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to bring democratic institutions to Cuba through the pressure of a general economic embargo at a time when the Castro regime has proven to be vulnerable to international economic pressure; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to protect the claims of United States nationals who had property wrongfully confiscated by the Cuban Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The United States Department of State has notified other governments that the transfer to third parties of properties confiscated by the Cuban Government “would complicate any attempt to return them to their original owners”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The international judicial system, as currently structured, lacks fully effective remedies for the wrongful confiscation of property and for unjust enrichment from the use of wrongfully confiscated property by governments and private entities at the expense of the rightful owners of the property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> International law recognizes that a nation has the ability to provide for rules of law with respect to conduct outside its territory that has or is intended to have substantial effect within its territory.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The United States Government has an obligation to its citizens to provide protection against wrongful confiscations by foreign nations and their citizens, including the provision of private remedies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> To deter trafficking in wrongfully confiscated property, United States nationals who were the victims of these confiscations should be endowed with a judicial remedy in the courts of the United States that would deny traffickers any profits from economically exploiting Castro’s wrongful seizures.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6082.</num>
<heading> Liability for trafficking in confiscated property claimed by United States nationals</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil remedy</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability for trafficking</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Except as otherwise provided in this section, any person that, after the end of the 3-month period beginning on the effective date of this subchapter, traffics in property which was confiscated by the Cuban Government on or after <date date="1959-01-01">January 1, 1959</date>, shall be liable to any United States national who owns the claim to such property for money damages in an amount equal to the sum of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the amount which is the greater of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the amount, if any, certified to the claimant by the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission under the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1621</ref> et seq.], plus interest;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the amount determined under <ref>section 6083(a)(2) of this title</ref>, plus interest; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the fair market value of that property, calculated as being either the current value of the property, or the value of the property when confiscated plus interest, whichever is greater; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> court costs and reasonable attorneys’ fees.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Interest under subparagraph (A)(i) shall be at the rate set forth in <ref>section 1961 of title 28</ref>, computed by the court from the date of confiscation of the property involved to the date on which the action is brought under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presumption in favor of the certified claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There shall be a presumption that the amount for which a person is liable under clause (i) of paragraph (1)(A) is the amount that is certified as described in subclause (I) of that clause. The presumption shall be rebuttable by clear and convincing evidence that the amount described in subclause (II) or (III) of that clause is the appropriate amount of liability under that clause.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Increased liability</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any person that traffics in confiscated property for which liability is incurred under paragraph (1) shall, if a United States national owns a claim with respect to that property which was certified by the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission under title V of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1643</ref> et seq.], be liable for damages computed in accordance with subparagraph (C).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> If the claimant in an action under this subsection (other than a United States national to whom subparagraph (A) applies) provides, after the end of the 3-month period described in paragraph (1) notice to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a person against whom the action is to be initiated, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a person who is to be joined as a defendant in the action,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">at least 30 days before initiating the action or joining such person as a defendant, as the case may be, and that person, after the end of the 30-day period beginning on the date the notice is provided, traffics in the confiscated property that is the subject of the action, then that person shall be liable to that claimant for damages computed in accordance with subparagraph (C).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> Damages for which a person is liable under subparagraph (A) or subparagraph (B) are money damages in an amount equal to the sum of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the amount determined under paragraph (1)(A)(ii), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 3 times the amount determined applicable under paragraph (1)(A)(i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> Notice to a person under subparagraph (B)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall be in writing;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall be posted by certified mail or personally delivered to the person; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> shall contain—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a statement of intention to commence the action under this section or to join the person as a defendant (as the case may be), together with the reasons therefor;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> a demand that the unlawful trafficking in the claimant’s property cease immediately; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> a copy of the summary statement published under paragraph (8).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, actions may be brought under paragraph (1) with respect to property confiscated before, on, or after <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the case of property confiscated before <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>, a United States national may not bring an action under this section on a claim to the confiscated property unless such national acquires ownership of the claim before <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> In the case of property confiscated on or after <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>, a United States national who, after the property is confiscated, acquires ownership of a claim to the property by assignment for value, may not bring an action on the claim under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of certain actions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of a United States national who was eligible to file a claim with the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission under title V of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1643</ref> et seq.] but did not so file the claim, that United States national may not bring an action on that claim under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the case of any action brought under this section by a United States national whose underlying claim in the action was timely filed with the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission under title V of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949 but was denied by the Commission, the court shall accept the findings of the Commission on the claim as conclusive in the action under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A United States national, other than a United States national bringing an action under this section on a claim certified under title V of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949, may not bring an action on a claim under this section before the end of the 2-year period beginning on <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> An interest in property for which a United States national has a claim certified under title V of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949 may not be the subject of a claim in an action under this section by any other person. Any person bringing an action under this section whose claim has not been so certified shall have the burden of establishing for the court that the interest in property that is the subject of the claim is not the subject of a claim so certified.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inapplicability of act of state doctrine</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No court of the United States shall decline, based upon the act of state doctrine, to make a determination on the merits in an action brought under paragraph (1) .</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Licenses not required</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an action under this section may be brought and may be settled, and a judgment rendered in such action may be enforced, without obtaining any license or other permission from any agency of the United States, except that this paragraph shall not apply to the execution of a judgment against, or the settlement of actions involving, property blocked under the authorities of <ref>section 4305(b) of title 50</ref>, that were being exercised on <date date="1977-07-01">July 1, 1977</date>, as a result of a national emergency declared by the President before such date, and are being exercised on <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, and for purposes of this subchapter only, any claim against the Cuban Government shall not be deemed to be an interest in property the transfer of which to a United States national required before <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>, or requires after <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>, a license issued by, or the permission of, any agency of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication by Attorney General</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 60 days after <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>, the Attorney General shall prepare and publish in the Federal Register a concise summary of the provisions of this subchapter, including a statement of the liability under this subchapter of a person trafficking in confiscated property, and the remedies available to United States nationals under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount in controversy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An action may be brought under this section by a United States national only where the amount in controversy exceeds the sum or value of $50,000, exclusive of interest, costs, and attorneys’ fees. In calculating $50,000 for purposes of the preceding sentence, the applicable amount under subclause (I), (II), or (III) of subsection (a)(1)(A)(i) may not be tripled as provided in subsection (a)(3).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedural requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in this subchapter, the provisions of title 28 and the rules of the courts of the United States apply to actions under this section to the same extent as such provisions and rules apply to any other action brought under <ref>section 1331 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service of process</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In an action under this section, service of process on an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state in the conduct of a commercial activity, or against individuals acting under color of law, shall be made in accordance with <ref>section 1608 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforceability of judgments against Cuban Government</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In an action brought under this section, any judgment against an agency or instrumentality of the Cuban Government shall not be enforceable against an agency or instrumentality of either a transition government in Cuba or a democratically elected government in Cuba.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election of remedies</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any United States national that brings an action under this section may not bring any other civil action or proceeding under the common law, Federal law, or the law of any of the several States, the District of Columbia, or any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, that seeks monetary or nonmonetary compensation by reason of the same subject matter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any person who brings, under the common law or any provision of law other than this section, a civil action or proceeding for monetary or nonmonetary compensation arising out of a claim for which an action would otherwise be cognizable under this section may not bring an action under this section on that claim.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of certified claimants</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> In the case of any United States national that brings an action under this section based on a claim certified under title V of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1643</ref> et seq.]—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> if the recovery in the action is equal to or greater than the amount of the certified claim, the United States national may not receive payment on the claim under any agreement entered into between the United States and Cuba settling claims covered by such title, and such national shall be deemed to have discharged the United States from any further responsibility to represent the United States national with respect to that claim;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if the recovery in the action is less than the amount of the certified claim, the United States national may receive payment under a claims agreement described in clause (i) but only to the extent of the difference between the amount of the recovery and the amount of the certified claim; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> if there is no recovery in the action, the United States national may receive payment on the certified claim under a claims agreement described in clause (i) to the same extent as any certified claimant who does not bring an action under this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the event some or all actions brought under this section are consolidated by judicial or other action in such manner as to create a pool of assets available to satisfy the claims in such actions, including a pool of assets in a proceeding in bankruptcy, every claimant whose claim in an action so consolidated was certified by the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission under title V of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1643</ref> et seq.] shall be entitled to payment in full of its claim from the assets in such pool before any payment is made from the assets in such pool with respect to any claim not so certified.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit of excess payments by Cuba under claims agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any amounts paid by Cuba under any agreement entered into between the United States and Cuba settling certified claims under title V of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1643</ref> et seq.] that are in excess of the payments made on such certified claims after the application of subsection (f) shall be deposited into the United States Treasury.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of rights</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">All rights created under this section to bring an action for money damages with respect to property confiscated by the Cuban Government—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may be suspended under <ref>section 6064(a) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall cease upon transmittal to the Congress of a determination of the President under <ref>section 6063(c)(3) of this title</ref> that a democratically elected government in Cuba is in power.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pending suits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The suspension or termination of rights under paragraph (1) shall not affect suits commenced before the date of such suspension or termination (as the case may be), and in all such suits, proceedings shall be had, appeals taken, and judgments rendered in the same manner and with the same effect as if the suspension or termination had not occurred.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Imposition of filing fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Judicial Conference of the United States shall establish a uniform fee that shall be imposed upon the plaintiff or plaintiffs in each action brought under this section. The fee should be established at a level sufficient to recover the costs to the courts of actions brought under this section. The fee under this subsection is in addition to any other fees imposed under title 28.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 815</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6083.</num>
<heading> Proof of ownership of claims to confiscated property</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Evidence of ownership</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conclusiveness of certified claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any action brought under this subchapter, the court shall accept as conclusive proof of ownership of an interest in property a certification of a claim to ownership of that interest that has been made by the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission under title V of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949 (<ref>22 U.S.C. 1643</ref> and following).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Claims not certified</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If in an action under this subchapter a claim has not been so certified by the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission, the court may appoint a special master, including the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission, to make determinations regarding the amount and ownership of the claim. Such determinations are only for evidentiary purposes in civil actions brought under this subchapter and do not constitute certifications under title V of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of determinations of foreign or international entities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In determining the amount or ownership of a claim in an action under this subchapter, the court shall not accept as conclusive evidence any findings, orders, judgments, or decrees from administrative agencies or courts of foreign countries or international organizations that declare the value of or invalidate the claim, unless the declaration of value or invalidation was found pursuant to binding international arbitration to which the United States or the claimant submitted the claim.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter or in section 514 of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1643</ref><i>l</i>], as added by subsection (b), shall be construed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to require or otherwise authorize the claims of Cuban nationals who became United States citizens after their property was confiscated to be included in the claims certified to the Secretary of State by the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission for purposes of future negotiation and espousal of claims with a friendly government in Cuba when diplomatic relations are restored; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> as superseding, amending, or otherwise altering certifications that have been made under title V of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 1643</ref> et seq.] before <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 819</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6084.</num>
<heading> Limitation of actions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An action under <ref>section 6082 of this title</ref> may not be brought more than 2 years after the trafficking giving rise to the action has ceased to occur.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 821</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6085.</num>
<heading> Effective date</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to subsections (b) and (c), this subchapter and the amendments made by this subchapter shall take effect on <date date="1996-08-01">August 1, 1996</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension authority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President may suspend the effective date under subsection (a) for a period of not more than 6 months if the President determines and reports in writing to the appropriate congressional committees at least 15 days before such effective date that the suspension is necessary to the national interests of the United States and will expedite a transition to democracy in Cuba.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional suspensions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President may suspend the effective date under subsection (a) for additional periods of not more than 6 months each, each of which shall begin on the day after the last day of the period during which a suspension is in effect under this subsection, if the President determines and reports in writing to the appropriate congressional committees at least 15 days before the date on which the additional suspension is to begin that the suspension is necessary to the national interests of the United States and will expedite a transition to democracy in Cuba.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other authorities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">After this subchapter and the amendments of this subchapter have taken effect—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> no person shall acquire a property interest in any potential or pending action under this subchapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the President may suspend the right to bring an action under this subchapter with respect to confiscated property for a period of not more than 6 months if the President determines and reports in writing to the appropriate congressional committees at least 15 days before the suspension takes effect that such suspension is necessary to the national interests of the United States and will expedite a transition to democracy in Cuba.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional suspensions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President may suspend the right to bring an action under this subchapter for additional periods of not more than 6 months each, each of which shall begin on the day after the last day of the period during which a suspension is in effect under this subsection, if the President determines and reports in writing to the appropriate congressional committees at least 15 days before the date on which the additional suspension is to begin that the suspension is necessary to the national interests of the United States and will expedite a transition to democracy in Cuba.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pending suits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The suspensions of actions under paragraph (1) shall not affect suits commenced before the date of such suspension, and in all such suits, proceedings shall be had, appeals taken, and judgments rendered in the same manner and with the same effect as if the suspension had not occurred.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rescission of suspension</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may rescind any suspension made under subsection (b) or (c) upon reporting to the appropriate congressional committees that doing so will expedite a transition to democracy in Cuba.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 821</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>EXCLUSION OF CERTAIN ALIENS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6091.</num>
<heading> Exclusion from United States of aliens who have confiscated property of United States nationals or who traffic in such property</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Grounds for exclusion</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall deny a visa to, and the Attorney General shall exclude from the United States, any alien who the Secretary of State determines is a person who, after <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> has confiscated, or has directed or overseen the confiscation of, property a claim to which is owned by a United States national, or converts or has converted for personal gain confiscated property, a claim to which is owned by a United States national;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> traffics in confiscated property, a claim to which is owned by a United States national;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> is a corporate officer, principal, or shareholder with a controlling interest of an entity which has been involved in the confiscation of property or trafficking in confiscated property, a claim to which is owned by a United States national; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> is a spouse, minor child, or agent of a person excludable under paragraph (1), (2), or (3).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this section, the following terms have the following meanings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confiscated; confiscation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The terms “confiscated” and “confiscation” refer to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the nationalization, expropriation, or other seizure by the Cuban Government of ownership or control of property—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> without the property having been returned or adequate and effective compensation provided; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> without the claim to the property having been settled pursuant to an international claims settlement agreement or other mutually accepted settlement procedure; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the repudiation by the Cuban Government of, the default by the Cuban Government on, or the failure of the Cuban Government to pay—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a debt of any enterprise which has been nationalized, expropriated, or otherwise taken by the Cuban Government;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a debt which is a charge on property nationalized, expropriated, or otherwise taken by the Cuban Government; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a debt which was incurred by the Cuban Government in satisfaction or settlement of a confiscated property claim.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Traffics</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a person “traffics” in confiscated property if that person knowingly and intentionally—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> transfers, distributes, dispenses, brokers, or otherwise disposes of confiscated property,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> purchases, receives, obtains control of, or otherwise acquires confiscated property, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> improves (other than for routine maintenance), invests in (by contribution of funds or anything of value, other than for routine maintenance), or begins after <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>, to manage, lease, possess, use, or hold an interest in confiscated property,</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> enters into a commercial arrangement using or otherwise benefiting from confiscated property, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> causes, directs, participates in, or profits from, trafficking (as described in clause (i) or (ii)) by another person, or otherwise engages in trafficking (as described in clause (i) or (ii)) through another person,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">without the authorization of any United States national who holds a claim to the property.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The term “traffics” does not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the delivery of international telecommunication signals to Cuba;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the trading or holding of securities publicly traded or held, unless the trading is with or by a person determined by the Secretary of the Treasury to be a specially designated national;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> transactions and uses of property incident to lawful travel to Cuba, to the extent that such transactions and uses of property are necessary to the conduct of such travel; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> transactions and uses of property by a person who is both a citizen of Cuba and a resident of Cuba, and who is not an official of the Cuban Government or the ruling political party in Cuba.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply where the Secretary of State finds, on a case by case basis, that the entry into the United States of the person who would otherwise be excluded under this section is necessary for medical reasons or for purposes of litigation of an action under subchapter III.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This section applies to aliens seeking to enter the United States on or after <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Trafficking</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This section applies only with respect to acts within the meaning of “traffics” that occur on or after <date date="1996-03-12">March 12, 1996</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 104–114, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 822</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>