<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 68—</num>
<heading>DEMILITARIZATION OF FORMER SOVIET UNION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>FINDINGS AND PROGRAM AUTHORITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5901.</num>
<heading> Demilitarization of independent states of former Soviet Union</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds that it is in the national security interest of the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to facilitate, on a priority basis—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the transportation, storage, safeguarding, and destruction of nuclear and other weapons of the independent states of the former Soviet Union, including the safe and secure storage of fissile materials, dismantlement of missiles and launchers, and the elimination of chemical and biological weapons capabilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the prevention of proliferation of weapons of mass destruction and their components and destabilizing conventional weapons of the independent states of the former Soviet Union, and the establishment of verifiable safeguards against the proliferation of such weapons;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the prevention of diversion of weapons-related scientific expertise of the former Soviet Union to terrorist groups or third countries; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> other efforts designed to reduce the military threat from the former Soviet Union;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to support the demilitarization of the massive defense-related industry and equipment of the independent states of the former Soviet Union and conversion of such industry and equipment to civilian purposes and uses; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to expand military-to-military contacts between the United States and the independent states of the former Soviet Union.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title XIV, § 1411</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2563</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5902.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XIII, § 1351(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3606</ref></heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>ADMINISTRATIVE AND FUNDING AUTHORITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5911.</num>
<heading> Administration of demilitarization programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> In recognition of the direct contributions to the national security interests of the United States of the activities specified in <ref>section 5902 of this title</ref>, funds transferred under sections 108 and 109 of <ref>Public Law 102–229</ref> (<ref>105 Stat. 1708</ref>) are authorized to be made available to carry out this chapter. Of the amount available to carry out this chapter—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not more than $40,000,000 may be made available for programs referred to in <ref>section 5902(b)(4) of this title</ref> relating to demilitarization of defense industries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> not more than $15,000,000 may be made available for programs referred to in <ref>section 5902(b)(6) of this title</ref> relating to military-to-military contacts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> not more than $25,000,000 may be made available for joint research development programs pursuant to <ref>section 5931 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> not more than $10,000,000 may be made available for the study, assessment, and identification of nuclear waste disposal activities by the former Soviet Union in the Arctic region;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> not more than $25,000,000 may be made available for Project PEACE; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> not more than $10,000,000 may be made available for the Volunteers Investing in Peace and Security (VIPS) program under chapter 89 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002326">1</ref> of title 10.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content>, (3) Omitted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title XIV, § 1421</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2564</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>REPORTING REQUIREMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5921.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XIII, § 1351(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 3606</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5922.</num>
<heading> Quarterly reports on programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 30 days after the end of the last fiscal year quarter of fiscal year 1992 and not later than 30 days after the end of each fiscal year quarter of fiscal year 1993, the President shall transmit to the Congress a report on the activities carried out under this chapter. Each such report shall set forth, for the preceding fiscal year quarter and cumulatively, the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The amounts expended for such activities and the purposes for which they were expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The source of the funds obligated for such activities, specified by program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A description of the participation of all United States Government departments and agencies and the United States private sector in such activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A description of the activities carried out under this chapter and the forms of assistance provided under this chapter, including, with respect to proposed industrial demilitarization projects, additional information on the progress toward demilitarization of facilities and the conversion of the demilitarized facilities to civilian activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Such other information as the President considers appropriate to fully inform the Congress concerning the operation of the programs authorized under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title XIV, § 1432</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2566</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>JOINT RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT PROGRAMS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5931.</num>
<heading> Programs with states of former Soviet Union</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress encourages the Secretary of Defense to participate actively in joint research and development programs with the independent states of the former Soviet Union through the nongovernmental foundation established for this purpose by <ref>section 5861 of this title</ref>. To that end, the Secretary of Defense may spend those funds authorized in <ref>section 5911(a)(1)(C) of this title</ref> for support, technical cooperation, in-kind assistance, and other activities with the following purposes:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> To advance defense conversion by funding civilian collaborative research and development projects between scientists and engineers in the United States and in the independent states of the former Soviet Union.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> To assist the establishment of a market economy in the independent states of the former Soviet Union by promoting, identifying, and partially funding joint research, development, and demonstration ventures between United States businesses and scientists, engineers, and entrepreneurs in those independent states.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> To provide a mechanism for scientists, engineers, and entrepreneurs in the independent states of the former Soviet Union to develop an understanding of commercial business practices by establishing linkages to United States scientists, engineers, and businesses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> To provide access for United States businesses to sophisticated new technologies, talented researchers, and potential new markets within the independent states of the former Soviet Union.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> To provide productive research and development opportunities within the independent states of the former Soviet Union that offer scientists and engineers alternatives to emigration and help prevent proliferation of weapons technologies and the dissolution of the technological infrastructure of those states.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title XIV, § 1441</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 2566</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XI, § 1182(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 1772</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>