<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 72—</num>
<heading>NUCLEAR PROLIFERATION PREVENTION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>SANCTIONS FOR NUCLEAR PROLIFERATION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6301.</num>
<heading> Imposition of procurement sanction on persons engaging in export activities that contribute to proliferation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination by President</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in subsection (b)(2), the President shall impose the sanction described in subsection (c) if the President determines in writing that, on or after the effective date of this subchapter, a foreign person or a United States person has materially and with requisite knowledge contributed, through the export from the United States or any other country of any goods or technology (as defined in <ref>section 6305(2) of this title</ref>), to the efforts by any individual, group, or non-nuclear-weapon state to acquire unsafeguarded special nuclear material or to use, develop, produce, stockpile, or otherwise acquire any nuclear explosive device.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Persons against which the sanction is to be imposed</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The sanction shall be imposed pursuant to paragraph (1) on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the foreign person or United States person with respect to which the President makes the determination described in that paragraph;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any successor entity to that foreign person or United States person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any foreign person or United States person that is a parent or subsidiary of that person if that parent or subsidiary materially and with requisite knowledge assisted in the activities which were the basis of that determination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any foreign person or United States person that is an affiliate of that person if that affiliate materially and with requisite knowledge assisted in the activities which were the basis of that determination and if that affiliate is controlled in fact by that person.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other sanctions available</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The sanction which is required to be imposed for activities described in this subsection is in addition to any other sanction which may be imposed for the same activities under any other provision of law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “requisite knowledge” means situations in which a person “knows”, as “knowing” is defined in <ref>section 78dd–2 of title 15</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with and actions by foreign government of jurisdiction</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the President makes a determination described in subsection (a)(1) with respect to a foreign person, the Congress urges the President to initiate consultations immediately with the government with primary jurisdiction over that foreign person with respect to the imposition of the sanction pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actions by government of jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In order to pursue such consultations with that government, the President may delay imposition of the sanction pursuant to this section for up to 90 days. Following these consultations, the President shall impose the sanction unless the President determines and certifies in writing to the Congress that that government has taken specific and effective actions, including appropriate penalties, to terminate the involvement of the foreign person in the activities described in subsection (a)(1). The President may delay the imposition of the sanction for up to an additional 90 days if the President determines and certifies in writing to the Congress that that government is in the process of taking the actions described in the preceding sentence.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after making a determination under subsection (a)(1), the President shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the status of consultations with the appropriate government under this subsection, and the basis for any determination under paragraph (2) of this subsection that such government has taken specific corrective actions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanction</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Description of sanction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The sanction to be imposed pursuant to subsection (a)(1) is, except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, that the United States Government shall not procure, or enter into any contract for the procurement of, any goods or services from any person described in subsection (a)(2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The President shall not be required to apply or maintain the sanction under this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of procurement of defense articles or defense services—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> under existing contracts or subcontracts, including the exercise of options for production quantities to satisfy requirements essential to the national security of the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if the President determines in writing that the person or other entity to which the sanction would otherwise be applied is a sole source supplier of the defense articles or services, that the defense articles or services are essential, and that alternative sources are not readily or reasonably available; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> if the President determines in writing that such articles or services are essential to the national security under defense coproduction agreements;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to products or services provided under contracts entered into before the date on which the President publishes his intention to impose the sanction;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> spare parts which are essential to United States products or production;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> component parts, but not finished products, essential to United States products or production; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> routine servicing and maintenance of products, to the extent that alternative sources are not readily or reasonably available;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to information and technology essential to United States products or production; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to medical or other humanitarian items.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advisory opinions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon the request of any person, the Secretary of State may, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, issue in writing an advisory opinion to that person as to whether a proposed activity by that person would subject that person to the sanction under this section. Any person who relies in good faith on such an advisory opinion which states that the proposed activity would not subject a person to such sanction, and any person who thereafter engages in such activity, may not be made subject to such sanction on account of such activity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of sanction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The sanction imposed pursuant to this section shall apply for a period of at least 12 months following the imposition of the sanction and shall cease to apply thereafter only if the President determines and certifies in writing to the Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> reliable information indicates that the foreign person or United States person with respect to which the determination was made under subsection (a)(1) has ceased to aid or abet any individual, group, or non-nuclear-weapon state in its efforts to acquire unsafeguarded special nuclear material or any nuclear explosive device, as described in that subsection; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the President has received reliable assurances from the foreign person or United States person, as the case may be, that such person will not, in the future, aid or abet any individual, group, or non-nuclear-weapon state in its efforts to acquire unsafeguarded special nuclear material or any nuclear explosive device, as described in subsection (a)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criterion for waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President may waive the application of the sanction imposed on any person pursuant to this section, after the end of the 12-month period beginning on the date on which that sanction was imposed on that person, if the President determines and certifies in writing to the Congress that the continued imposition of the sanction would have a serious adverse effect on vital United States interests.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of and report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the President decides to exercise the waiver authority provided in paragraph (1), the President shall so notify the Congress not less than 20 days before the waiver takes effect. Such notification shall include a report fully articulating the rationale and circumstances which led the President to exercise the waiver authority.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VIII, § 821</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 508</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6302.</num>
<heading> Role of international financial institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States executive director to each of the international financial institutions described in <ref>section 262d(a) of this title</ref> to use the voice and vote of the United States to oppose any use of the institution’s funds to promote the acquisition of unsafeguarded special nuclear material or the development, stockpiling, or use of any nuclear explosive device by any non-nuclear-weapon state.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VIII, § 823(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 512</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6303.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on assisting nuclear proliferation through provision of financing</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Prohibited activity” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “prohibited activity” means the act of knowingly, materially, and directly contributing or attempting to contribute, through the provision of financing, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the acquisition of unsafeguarded special nuclear material; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the use, development, production, stockpiling, or other acquisition of any nuclear explosive device,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">by any individual, group, or non-nuclear-weapon state.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the extent that the United States has jurisdiction to prohibit such activity by such person, no United States person and no foreign person may engage in any prohibited activity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential determination and order with respect to United States and foreign persons</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the President determines,,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002338">1</ref> that a United States person or a foreign person has engaged in a prohibited activity (without regard to whether subsection (b) applies), the President shall, by order, impose the sanctions described in subsection (d) on such person.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanctions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The following sanctions shall be imposed pursuant to any order issued under subsection (c) with respect to any United States person or any foreign person:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ban on dealings in Government finance</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation as primary dealer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Neither the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System nor the Federal Reserve Bank of New York may designate, or permit the continuation of any prior designation of, the person as a primary dealer in United States Government debt instruments.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service as depositary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The person may not serve as a depositary for United States Government funds.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions on operations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The person may not, directly or indirectly—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> commence any line of business in the United States in which the person was not engaged as of the date of the order; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> conduct business from any location in the United States at which the person did not conduct business as of the date of the order.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with and actions by foreign government of jurisdiction</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the President makes a determination under subsection (c) with respect to a foreign person, the Congress urges the President to initiate consultations immediately with any appropriate foreign government with respect to the imposition of any sanction pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actions by government of jurisdiction</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of period for imposing sanctions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In order to pursue consultations described in paragraph (1) with any government referred to in such paragraph, the President may delay, for up to 90 days, the effective date of an order under subsection (c) imposing any sanction.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with activities of foreign government</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Following consultations described in paragraph (1), the order issued by the President under subsection (c) imposing any sanction on a foreign person shall take effect unless the President determines, and certifies in writing to the Congress, that the government referred to in paragraph (1) has taken specific and effective actions, including the imposition of appropriate penalties, to terminate the involvement of the foreign person in any prohibited activity.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension of period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">After the end of the period described in subparagraph (A), the President may delay, for up to an additional 90 days, the effective date of an order issued under subsection (b) imposing any sanction on a foreign person if the President determines, and certifies in writing to the Congress, that the appropriate foreign government is in the process of taking actions described in subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Before the end of the 90-day period beginning on the date on which an order is issued under subsection (c), the President shall submit to the Congress a report on—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the status of consultations under this subsection with the government referred to in paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the basis for any determination under paragraph (2) that such government has taken specific corrective actions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of sanctions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any sanction imposed on any person pursuant to an order issued under subsection (c) shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> remain in effect for a period of not less than 12 months; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> cease to apply after the end of such 12-month period only if the President determines, and certifies in writing to the Congress, that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the person has ceased to engage in any prohibited activity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the President has received reliable assurances from such person that the person will not, in the future, engage in any prohibited activity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may waive the continued application of any sanction imposed on any person pursuant to an order issued under subsection (c) if the President determines, and certifies in writing to the Congress, that the continued imposition of the sanction would have a serious adverse effect on the safety and soundness of the domestic or international financial system or on domestic or international payments systems.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement action</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Attorney General may bring an action in an appropriate district court of the United States for injunctive and other appropriate relief with respect to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any violation of subsection (b); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any order issued pursuant to subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> “Knowingly” defined</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “knowingly” means the state of mind of a person with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result in which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such person is aware that such person is engaging in such conduct, that such circumstance exists, or that such result is substantially certain to occur; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such person has a firm belief that such circumstance exists or that such result is substantially certain to occur.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Knowledge of the existence of a particular circumstance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If knowledge of the existence of a particular circumstance is required for an offense, such knowledge is established if a person is aware of a high probability of the existence of such circumstance, unless the person actually believes that such circumstance does not exist.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scope of application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply with respect to prohibited activities which occur on or after the date this subchapter takes effect.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VIII, § 824</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 512</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–164, title I, § 157(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-07-21">July 21, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1440</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6304.</num>
<heading> Reporting on demarches</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> It is the sense of the Congress that the Department of State should, in the course of implementing its reporting responsibilities under <ref>section 3282(c) of this title</ref>, include a summary of demarches that the United States has issued or received from foreign governments with respect to activities which are of significance from the proliferation standpoint.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this section, the term “demarche” means any official communication by one government to another, by written or oral means, intended by the originating government to express—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a concern over a past, present, or possible future action or activity of the recipient government, or of a person within the jurisdiction of that government, contributing to the global spread of unsafeguarded special nuclear material or of nuclear explosive devices;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a request for the recipient government to counter such action or activity; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> both the concern and request described in subparagraphs (A) and (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VIII, § 828(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 520</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6305.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the term “foreign person” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an individual who is not a citizen of the United States or an alien admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a corporation, partnership, or other nongovernment entity which is created or organized under the laws of a foreign country or which has its principal place of business outside the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the term “goods or technology” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> nuclear materials and equipment and sensitive nuclear technology (as such terms are defined in <ref>section 3203 of this title</ref>), all export items designated by the President pursuant to <ref>section 2139a(c) of title 42</ref>, and all technical assistance requiring authorization under <ref>section 2077(b) of title 42</ref>, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of exports from a country other than the United States, any goods or technology that, if exported from the United States, would be goods or technology described in subparagraph (A);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “IAEA safeguards” means the safeguards set forth in an agreement between a country and the International Atomic Energy Agency, as authorized by Article III(A)(5) of the Statute of the International Atomic Energy Agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “nuclear explosive device” means any device, whether assembled or disassembled, that is designed to produce an instantaneous release of an amount of nuclear energy from special nuclear material that is greater than the amount of energy that would be released from the detonation of one pound of trinitrotoluene (TNT);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “non-nuclear-weapon state” means any country which is not a nuclear-weapon state, as defined by Article IX (3) of the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons, signed at Washington, London, and Moscow on <date date="1968-07-01">July 1, 1968</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the term “special nuclear material” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 2014(aa) of title 42</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> the term “United States person” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an individual who is a citizen of the United States or an alien admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a corporation, partnership, or other nongovernment entity which is not a foreign person; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the term “unsafeguarded special nuclear material” means special nuclear material which is held in violation of IAEA safeguards or not subject to IAEA safeguards (excluding any quantity of material that could, if it were exported from the United States, be exported under a general license issued by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VIII, § 830</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 521</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>INTERNATIONAL ATOMIC ENERGY AGENCY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6321.</num>
<heading> Bilateral and multilateral initiatives</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that in order to maintain and enhance international confidence in the effectiveness of IAEA safeguards and in other multilateral undertakings to halt the global proliferation of nuclear weapons, the United States should seek to negotiate with other nations and groups of nations, including the IAEA Board of Governors and the Nuclear Suppliers Group, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> build international support for the principle that nuclear supply relationships must require purchasing nations to agree to full-scope international safeguards;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> encourage each nuclear-weapon state within the meaning of the Treaty to undertake a comprehensive review of its own procedures for declassifying information relating to the design or production of nuclear explosive devices and to investigate any measures that would reduce the risk of such information contributing to nuclear weapons proliferation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> encourage the deferral of efforts to produce weapons-grade nuclear material for large-scale commercial uses until such time as safeguards are developed that can detect, on a timely and reliable basis, the diversion of significant quantities of such material for nuclear explosive purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> pursue greater financial support for the implementation and improvement of safeguards from all IAEA member nations with significant nuclear programs, particularly from those nations that are currently using or planning to use weapons-grade nuclear material for commercial purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> arrange for the timely payment of annual financial contributions by all members of the IAEA, including the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> pursue the elimination of international commerce in highly enriched uranium for use in research reactors while encouraging multilateral cooperation to develop and to use low-enriched alternative nuclear fuels;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> oppose efforts by non-nuclear-weapon states to develop or use unsafeguarded nuclear fuels for purposes of naval propulsion;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> pursue an international open skies arrangement that would authorize the IAEA to operate surveillance aircraft and would facilitate IAEA access to satellite information for safeguards verification purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> develop an institutional means for IAEA member nations to share intelligence material with the IAEA on possible safeguards violations without compromising national security or intelligence sources or methods;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> require any exporter of a sensitive nuclear facility or sensitive nuclear technology to a non-nuclear-weapon state to notify the IAEA prior to export and to require safeguards over that facility or technology, regardless of its destination; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> seek agreement among the parties to the Treaty to apply IAEA safeguards in perpetuity and to establish new limits on the right to withdraw from the Treaty.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VIII, § 841</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 522</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6322.</num>
<heading> IAEA internal reforms</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to promote the early adoption of reforms in the implementation of the safeguards responsibilities of the IAEA, the Congress urges the President to negotiate with other nations and groups of nations, including the IAEA Board of Governors and the Nuclear Suppliers Group, to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> improve the access of the IAEA within nuclear facilities that are capable of producing, processing, or fabricating special nuclear material suitable for use in a nuclear explosive device;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> facilitate the IAEA’s efforts to meet and to maintain its own goals for detecting the diversion of nuclear materials and equipment, giving particular attention to facilities in which there are bulk quantities of plutonium; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if it is not technically feasible for the IAEA to meet those detection goals in a particular facility, require the IAEA to declare publicly that it is unable to do so;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> enable the IAEA to issue fines for violations of safeguards procedures, to pay rewards for information on possible safeguards violations, and to establish a “hot line” for the reporting of such violations and other illicit uses of weapons-grade nuclear material;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> establish safeguards at facilities engaged in the manufacture of equipment or material that is especially designated or prepared for the processing, use, or production of special fissionable material or, in the case of non-nuclear-weapon states, of any nuclear explosive device;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> establish safeguards over nuclear research and development activities and facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> implement special inspections of undeclared nuclear facilities, as provided for under existing safeguards procedures, and seek authority for the IAEA to conduct challenge inspections on demand at suspected nuclear sites;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> expand the scope of safeguards to include tritium, uranium concentrates, and nuclear waste containing special fissionable material, and increase the scope of such safeguards on heavy water;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> revise downward the IAEA’s official minimum amounts of nuclear material (“significant quantity”) needed to make a nuclear explosive device and establish these amounts as national rather than facility standards;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> expand the use of full-time resident IAEA inspectors at sensitive fuel cycle facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> promote the use of near real time material accountancy in the conduct of safeguards at facilities that use, produce, or store significant quantities of special fissionable material;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> develop with other IAEA member nations an agreement on procedures to expedite approvals of visa applications by IAEA inspectors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> provide the IAEA the additional funds, technical assistance, and political support necessary to carry out the goals set forth in this subsection; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002339">1</ref> and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> make public the annual safeguards implementation report of the IAEA, establishing a public registry of commodities in international nuclear commerce, including dual-use goods, and creating a public repository of current nuclear trade control laws, agreements, regulations, and enforcement and judicial actions by IAEA member nations.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VIII, § 842</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 523</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6323.</num>
<heading> Reporting requirement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report required</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall, in the report required by <ref>section 3281(a) of this title</ref>, describe—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the steps he has taken to implement sections 6321 and 6322 of this title, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the progress that has been made and the obstacles that have been encountered in seeking to meet the objectives set forth in sections 6321 and 6322 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each report under paragraph (1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002340">1</ref> shall describe—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the bilateral and multilateral initiatives that the President has taken during the period since <date date="1994-04-30">April 30, 1994</date>, in pursuit of each of the objectives set forth in sections 6321 and 6322 of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any obstacles that have been encountered in the pursuit of those initiatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any additional initiatives that have been proposed by other countries or international organizations to strengthen the implementation of IAEA safeguards;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> all activities of the Federal Government in support of the objectives set forth in sections 6321 and 6322 of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> any recommendations of the President on additional measures to enhance the effectiveness of IAEA safeguards; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> any initiatives that the President plans to take in support of each of the objectives set forth in sections 6321 and 6322 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VIII, § 843</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 524</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6324.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “highly enriched uranium” means uranium enriched to 20 percent or more in the isotope U–235;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “IAEA” means the International Atomic Energy Agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “near real time material accountancy” means a method of accounting for the location, quantity, and disposition of special fissionable material at facilities that store or process such material, in which verification of peaceful use is continuously achieved by means of frequent physical inventories and the use of in-process instrumentation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the term “special fissionable material” has the meaning given that term by Article XX(1) of the Statute of the International Atomic Energy Agency, done at the Headquarters of the United Nations on <date date="1956-10-26">October 26, 1956</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the term “the Treaty” means the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons, signed at Washington, London, and Moscow on <date date="1968-07-01">July 1, 1968</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> the terms “IAEA safeguards”, “non-nuclear-weapon state”, “nuclear explosive device”, and “special nuclear material” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 6305 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 103–236, title VIII, § 844</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 524</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>