<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 53A—</num>
<heading>DISPOSITION OF PERSONAL PROPERTY ABROAD</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4341.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, the following terms have the following meanings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “employee” means an individual who is under the jurisdiction of a chief of mission to a foreign country (as provided under <ref>section 3927 of this title</ref>) and who is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an employee as defined by <ref>section 2105 of title 5</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an officer or employee of the United States Postal Service or of the Postal Regulatory Commission;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a member of a uniformed service who is not under the command of an area military commander; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an expert or consultant as authorized pursuant to <ref>section 3109 of title 5</ref> with the United States or any agency, department, or establishment thereof; but is not a national or permanent resident of the foreign country in which employed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “contractor” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an individual employed by personal services contract pursuant to <ref>section 2669(c) of this title</ref>, <ref>section 2396(a)(3) of this title</ref>, or pursuant to other similar authority, including, in the case of an organization performing services under such authority, an individual involved in the performance of such services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such other individuals or firms providing goods or services by contract as are designated by regulations issued pursuant to <ref>section 4343 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">but does not include a contractor with or under the supervision of an area military commander.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “charitable contribution” means a contribution or gift as defined in <ref>section 170(c) of title 26</ref>, or other similar contribution or gift to a bona fide charitable foreign entity as determined pursuant to regulations or policies issued pursuant to <ref>section 4343 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “chief of mission” has the meaning given such term by <ref>section 3902(3) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “foreign country” means any country or territory, excluding the United States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, American Samoa, Guam, the Virgin Islands, and other territories or possessions of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “personal property” means any item of personal property, including automobiles, computers, boats, audio and video equipment, and any other items acquired for personal use, but excluding items of minimal value as determined by regulation or policy issued pursuant to <ref>section 4343 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “profit” means any proceeds (including cash and other valuable consideration but not including amounts of such proceeds given as charitable contributions) for the sale, disposition, or assignment of personal property in excess of the basis for such property. For purposes of this chapter, basis shall include initial price, inland and overseas transportation costs (if not reimbursed by the United States Government), shipping insurance, taxes, customs fees, duties or other charges, and capital improvements, but shall not include insurance on an item while in use, or maintenance and related costs. For purposes of computing profit, proceeds and costs shall be valued in United States dollars at the time of receipt or payment, at a rate of exchange as determined by regulation or policy issued pursuant to <ref>section 4343 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title III, § 301, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–204, title I, § 186(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1366</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–435, title VI, § 604(f)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 3242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4342.</num>
<heading> Limitations on disposition of personal prop­erty</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as authorized under subsection (b), employees or members of their family shall not sell, assign, or otherwise dispose of personal property within a foreign country which was imported into or purchased within that foreign country and which, by virtue of the official status of the employee, was exempt from import limitation, customs duties, or taxes which would otherwise apply.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval by chief of mission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The chief of mission to a foreign country, or a designee of such chief of mission, is authorized to approve within that foreign country sales, assignment, or other dispositions of property by employees under the chief of mission’s jurisdiction (as described in <ref>section 3927 of this title</ref>) to the extent that such sale, assignment, or other disposition is in accordance with regulations and policies, rules, and procedures issued pursuant to <ref>section 4343 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Violation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Violation of this section, or other importation, sale, or other disposition of personal property within a foreign country which violates its laws or regulations or governing international law and is prohibited by regulations and policies, rules, and procedures issued pursuant to <ref>section 4343 of this title</ref>, shall be grounds for disciplinary action against an employee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title III, § 302, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–204, title I, § 186(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1368</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4343.</num>
<heading> Regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issuance; purpose</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State may issue regulations to carry out the purposes of this chapter. The primary purpose of such regulations and related policies, rules, and procedures shall be to assure that employees and members of their families do not profit personally from sales or other transactions with persons who are not themselves entitled to exemption from import restrictions, duties, or taxes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contractors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Such regulations shall require that, to the extent contractors enjoy importation or tax privileges in a foreign country because of their contractual relationship to the United States Government, after the effective date of this chapter contracting agencies shall include provisions in their contracts to carry out the purpose of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chief of mission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to ensure that due account is taken of local conditions, including applicable laws, markets, exchange rate factors, and accommodation exchange facilities, such regulations may authorize the chief of mission to each foreign country to establish more detailed policies, rules, or procedures for the application of this chapter within that country to employees under the chief of mission’s jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title III, § 303, as added <ref>Pub. L. 100–204, title I, § 186(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1368</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>