<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 10—</num>
<heading>HEMISPHERAL RELATIONS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>GENERALLY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 501.</num>
<heading> Utilization of services of Government agencies to promote inter-American relations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to render closer and more effective the relationship between the American republics the President of the United States is authorized, subject to such appropriations as are made available for the purpose, to utilize the services of the departments, agencies, and independent establishments of the Government in carrying out the reciprocal undertakings and cooperative purposes enunciated in the treaties, resolutions, declarations, and recommendations signed by all of the twenty-one American republics at the Inter-American Conference for the Maintenance of Peace held at Buenos Aires, Argentina, in 1936, and at the Eighth International Conference of American States held at Lima, Peru, in 1938.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 9, 1939, ch. 616, § 1</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 1290</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 502.</num>
<heading> Creation of advisory committees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is authorized to create such advisory committees as in his judgment may be of assistance in carrying out the undertakings of this Government under the treaties, resolutions, declarations, and recommendations referred to, but no committee or member thereof shall be allowed any salary or other compensation for services: <i>Provided, however</i>, That they may, within the limits of appropriations made available therefor by the Congress, which appropriations are authorized, be paid their actual transportation expenses and not to exceed $10 per diem in lieu of subsistence and other expenses while away from their homes in attendance upon meetings within the United States under instructions from the Secretary of State.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 9, 1939, ch. 616, § 2</ref>, <ref>53 Stat. 1290</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 503.</num>
<heading> Facilitating work of foreign traveling salesmen; licenses and certificates of identification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whereas the United States has entered into conventions with the Governments of Uruguay, Guatemala, Salvador, Panama, and Venezuela which were signed on <date date="1918-08-27">August 27, 1918</date>, <date date="1918-12-03">December 3, 1918</date>, <date date="1919-01-28">January 28, 1919</date>, <date date="1919-02-08">February 8, 1919</date>, and <date date="1919-07-03">July 3, 1919</date>, respectively, for facilitating the work of traveling salesmen; and</p>
<p class="indent0">Whereas Articles I and II of each of said conventions read as follows:</p>
<p class="indent0">“<inline class="small-caps">Article</inline> I. Manufacturers, merchants, and traders domiciled within the jurisdiction of one of the high contracting parties may operate as commercial travelers either personally or by means of agents or employees within the jurisdiction of the other high contracting party on obtaining from the latter, upon payment of a single fee, a license which shall be valid throughout its entire territorial jurisdiction.</p>
<p class="indent0">“In case either of the high contracting parties shall be engaged in war, it reserves to itself the right to prevent from operating within its jurisdiction under the provisions of this treaty, or otherwise, enemy nationals or other aliens whose presence it may consider prejudicial to public order and national safety.</p>
<p class="indent0">“<inline class="small-caps">Art</inline>. II. In order to secure the license above mentioned the applicant must obtain from the country of domicile of the manufacturers, merchants, and traders represented a certificate attesting his character as commercial traveler. This certificate, which shall be issued by the authority to be designated in each country for the purpose, shall be visaed by the consul of the country in which the applicant proposes to operate, and the authorities of the latter shall, upon the presentation of such certificate, issue to the applicant the national license as provided in Article I.”</p>
<p class="indent0">Now, therefore, the Secretary of Commerce, or any person in the Department of Commerce designated by him, is authorized to issue the licenses and certificates of identification which are provided for by the said Articles I and II, respectively, of the said conventions, or which may be provided for by similar articles in any convention or treaty that may, on and after <date date="1922-09-22">September 22, 1922</date>, be concluded by the United States with a foreign government, and is further authorized to collect a reasonable fee for each license and certificate of identification issued. The amount of such fee shall be fixed by regulations made by the Secretary of Commerce and shall be paid into the Treasury of the United States quarterly.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Sept. 22, 1922, ch. 414</ref>, <ref>42 Stat. 1028</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 504.</num>
<heading> Transfer of hemisphere territory from one non-American power to another; recognition; consultation with American Republics</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The United States would not recognize any transfer, and would not acquiesce in any attempt to transfer, any geographic region of this hemisphere from one non-American power to another non-American power; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If such transfer or attempt to transfer should appear likely, the United States shall, in addition to other measures, immediately consult with the other American republics to determine upon the steps which should be taken to safeguard their common interests.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Apr. 10, 1941, ch. 49</ref>, <ref>55 Stat. 133</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>WAR MATERIALS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 521.</num>
<heading> Military and naval assistance to governments of American Republics</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coast-defense and antiaircraft matériel; ammunition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may, in his discretion, authorize the Secretary of the Army to manufacture in factories and arsenals under his jurisdiction, or otherwise procure, coast-defense and antiaircraft matériel, including ammunition therefor, on behalf of the government of any American republic; to sell such matériel and ammunition to any such government; to test or prove such matériel and ammunition prior to sale or delivery to any such government; to repair such matériel on behalf of any such government; and to communicate to any such government plans, specifications, or other information relating to such matériel and ammunition as may be sold to any such government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Vessels of war; armament, artillery, equipment, and ammunition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may, in his discretion, authorize the Secretary of the Navy to construct vessels of war on behalf of the government of any American republic in shipyards under his jurisdiction; to manufacture armament and equipment for such vessels on behalf of any such government in arsenals under his jurisdiction; to sell armament and equipment for such vessels to any such government; to manufacture antiaircraft artillery and ammunition therefor, on behalf of any such government in factories and arsenals under his jurisdiction; to sell antiaircraft artillery and ammunition therefor to any such government; to test or prove such vessels, armament, artillery, ammunition, or equipment prior to sale or delivery to any such government; to repair such vessels, armament, artillery, or equipment on behalf of any such government; and to communicate to any such government plans, specifications, and other information relating to such vessels of war and their armament and equipment or antiaircraft artillery and ammunition therefor, as may be sold to any such government or relating to any vessels of war which any such government may propose to construct or manufacture within its own jurisdiction: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing contained herein shall be construed as authorizing the violation of any of the provisions of any treaty to which the United States is or may become a party or of any established principles or precedents of international law: <i>And provided further</i>, That no transaction authorized herein shall result in expense to the United States, nor involve the extension of credits by the United States: <i>And provided further</i>, That no contract shall be entered into under the terms of this subchapter which shall interfere with or delay the United States in the full use of its shipyards, arsenals, munition plants, and other equipment for its own purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 15, 1940, ch. 365, § 1</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 396</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 522.</num>
<heading> Transmission of information pertaining to implements of war, vessels, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out transactions authorized by <ref>section 521 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of the Army and the Secretary of the Navy are authorized, in their discretion and provided that it be not inconsistent with any defense requirements of the United States or of its possessions, to communicate or transmit to the government of any American republic or to any duly authorized person for the use of such government information pertaining to the arms, ammunition, or implements of war sold under the terms of that section or to any vessels of war constructed within the jurisdiction of any such government, and to export for the use of any such government coast defense and antiaircraft matériel and ammunition therefor, and vessels of war and their armament and equipment involving such information: <i>Provided</i>, That any information thus communicated or transmitted or involved in any such arms, ammunition, implements of war, or equipment when exported shall cease to be considered restricted after one year from the date that such communication or transmission has been authorized or such exportation made.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 15, 1940, ch. 365, § 2</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 396</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 523.</num>
<heading> Restriction in contracts against disposal of implements of war, vessels, etc., or information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All contracts or agreements made by the Secretary of the Army or the Secretary of the Navy for the sale to the government of any American republic of any of the arms, ammunition, or implements of war, the sale of which is authorized by this subchapter, shall contain a clause by which the purchaser undertakes not to dispose of such arms, ammunition, or implements of war, or any plans, specifications, or information pertaining thereto, by gift, sale, or any mode of transfer in such manner that such arms, ammunition, implements of war, or plans, specifications, or information pertaining thereto, may become a part of the armament of any state other than an American republic.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 15, 1940, ch. 365, § 3</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 397</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 524.</num>
<heading> Information on shipments to be given Chairman of National Munitions Control Board</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army or the Secretary of the Navy, as the case may be, shall, when any arms, ammunition, implements of war, or equipment are exported pursuant to the provisions of this subchapter, immediately inform the Secretary of State, Chairman of the National Munitions Control Board, of the quantities, character, value, terms of sale, and destination of the arms, ammunition, implements of war, or equipment so exported. Such information shall be included in the annual report of the Board.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 15, 1940, ch. 365, § 4</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 397</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 525.</num>
<heading> Appropriations and disposition of receipts</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> There is hereby authorized to be appropriated from time to time, out of any moneys in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, such amounts as may be necessary to carry out the provisions and accomplish the purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> All moneys which may be received from the government of any American republic, in payment for any article delivered or service rendered in compliance with the provisions of this subchapter, shall revert to the respective appropriation or appropriations out of which funds were expended in carrying out the transaction for which money is received, and such moneys shall be available for expenditure for the purpose for which such expended funds were appropriated by law, during the fiscal year in which such funds are received and the ensuing fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 15, 1940, ch. 365, § 5</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 397</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 526.</num>
<heading> Protection of patent rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Army and the Secretary of the Navy shall in all contracts or agreements for the sale of such matériel fully protect the rights of all citizens of the United States who have patent rights in and to any such matériel which is authorized to be sold and the funds collected for royalties on such patents shall be paid to the owners and holders of such patents.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 15, 1940, ch. 365, § 6</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 397</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 527.</num>
<heading> Purchases of implements of war, etc., from American Republics</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretaries of the Army and of the Navy are authorized to purchase arms, ammunition, and implements of war produced within the jurisdiction of any American republic if such arms, ammunition, or implements of war cannot be produced in the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>June 15, 1940, ch. 365, § 7</ref>, <ref>54 Stat. 397</ref>; <ref>July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref>61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>