<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 106—</num>
<heading>CHAMPIONING AMERICAN BUSINESS THROUGH DIPLOMACY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9901.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> According to the 2017 National Security Strategy of the United States of America, “Retaining our position as the world’s preeminent economic actor strengthens our ability to use the tools of economic diplomacy for the good of Americans and others.”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A <date date="2018-11-07">November 7, 2018</date>, cable from Secretary of State Michael R. Pompeo to all diplomatic and consular posts—“Boosting Commercial Diplomacy Around the World”—stated that “helping American companies is a foreign policy priority. . .Promoting broad-based, responsible, and sustainable economic growth helps to stabilize regions and creates new and growing markets for U.S. companies. A transparent and level playing field for U.S. investment in these countries counters real and growing challenges such as China’s Belt and Road initiative.”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In the January–February 2019 issue of The Foreign Service Journal, Ambassador Barbara Stephenson, the President of the American Foreign Service Association, wrote, “Foreign Service support for American business. . .is a major reason why the U.S. Foreign Service was created.”.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3069</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9902.</num>
<heading> Report from each mission on matters of commercial relations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2019-12-20">December 20, 2019</date>, and annually thereafter, the chief of mission at each bilateral diplomatic mission of the United States and the Director of the American Institute in Taiwan shall submit to the Secretary of State mission plans that include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Data and other information regarding actions taken by each such mission or Institute during the previous year to foster commercial relations and safeguard United States economic and business interests in the country or region in which each such chief of mission and the Director serves.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Each such mission’s and Institute’s anticipated economic and commercial priorities for the coming year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State, after receiving the information required under subsection (a), shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report, disaggregated by country or region, on activities and initiatives, including with appropriate examples, to create an enabling environment and otherwise promote United States economic and business interests in each such country or region, as well as information about significant foreign competition to United States businesses in the relevant country or region, including state-directed investments by foreign governments and United States strategic competitors in such country or region.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title VII, § 706</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3071</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9903.</num>
<heading> Consolidated report on unified investment climate statement and country commercial guide</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Commerce shall jointly produce and make publicly available on a United States Government internet website an annual country- and region-specific report regarding commercial relations with foreign countries and regions and safeguarding United States economic and business interests abroad, including with regard to United States exports and investments, including by small- and medium-size enterprises.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matters to be included</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Each report required under subsection (a) shall include the following with respect to each country or region covered by each such report:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Information about doing business in each country or region.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Background information about each country’s or region’s political environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Information about selling United States products and services in each country or region.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Leading sectors for United States exports and investment in each country or region.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> Information about trade regulations, customs, and standards in each country or region, such as—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> information on import tariffs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> documentation about which United States businesses should be aware when exporting, including any prohibited items or temporary entry procedures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> Investment climate statements describing each country’s or region’s openness to foreign investments, such as information relating to each country’s or region’s—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> investment policies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> market barriers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> business risks;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> legal and regulatory system, including dispute resolution;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> level of public and private sector corruption;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> level of political violence and instability;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> adherence to internationally recognized core labor standards; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> protection of property rights.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> Information about trade and project financing in each country or region, such as each country’s or region’s—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> banking and financial system, and how United States businesses typically get paid;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> foreign exchange controls; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> important sources of funding for project financing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> Relevant business travel information and business customs in each country or region.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> Information about services and personnel of the diplomatic mission of the United States available to United States businesses to support their activities in each country or region.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> Any significant trade or commercial agreement that exists between the United States and each country or region.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> A point of contact at the diplomatic or consular mission of the United States in each country or region for United States businesses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this section may be construed to require the duplication of existing reports.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title VII, § 707</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3071</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9904.</num>
<heading> Whole-of-government coordination and consultation to support United States economic and business interests</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the United States Trade Representative, shall have primary responsibility for coordinating a whole-of-government effort to expand United States efforts in supporting United States economic and business interests abroad. The Secretary may delegate responsibilities under this chapter to a senior, Senate-confirmed Department of State official.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> chair the interagency coordinating committee established under subsection (c);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> develop and implement the joint strategic plan required under subsection (c)(4) for all United States trade-related and trade capacity building and related technical assistance programs, in consultation with the coordinating committee established under subsection (c);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> advise the Federal departments and agencies designated by the President to participate in the interagency coordinating committee under this section in identifying the most needed and effective ways for United States diplomatic and consular posts and the departments and agencies that staff such posts to support the expansion of United States trade relations with host governments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> consult with the private sector in the development of government-wide trade expansion efforts, including establishing a point of contact and lead office within the Department of State to receive private-sector recommendations and comments concerning trade capacity assistance, coordination, consultations, and country-specific issues;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> consult with the Office of Management and Budget regarding the administrative and human resources needs that may be required to implement the provisions of this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> brief Congress on trade capacity building programs and make recommendations, as appropriate, to Congress for improvements in trade capacity building efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Economic Diplomacy Action Group</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President shall establish an interagency coordinating committee, to be known as the “Economic Diplomacy Action Group”, to coordinate and carry out the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Leadership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Group shall be chaired by the Secretary of State and the vice-chairs shall be the United States Trade Representative and the Secretary of Commerce. The Secretaries and the United States Trade Representative may delegate responsibilities under this chapter to appropriate, senior, Senate-confirmed officials.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Membership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President may appoint to the Group senior officials from the United States Agency for International Development, the Department of Agriculture, the Department of the Treasury, the Export-Import Bank, the United States Development Finance Corporation, and any such other relevant executive branch department or agency as the President determines to be substantially involved in trade capacity building and related assistance efforts in developing countries.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of joint strategic plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Group shall develop a joint strategic plan for all United States capacity building and technical assistance programs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Diplomacy trade expansion advisory committee</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of TEAC</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Chair and Vice-Chairs of the Economic Diplomacy Action Group shall establish a trade expansion advisory committee with selected representatives of the United States private sector and other organizations, including labor organizations, with direct and relevant operational experience in importing from and exporting into developing countries, as appropriate, to provide comment and advice on priorities for trade expansion initiatives. The Chair and Vice-Chairs of the Group may also appoint representatives from select non-profit organizations to the advisory committee if such representatives can demonstrate both a presence in and relevant operational or programmatic experience with trade capacity building efforts in developing countries.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The trade expansion advisory committee shall convene at least twice annually or more often as necessary at the call of the Chair and Vice-Chairs of the Group.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Strategic planning advice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The trade expansion advisory committee shall advise the Chair and Vice-Chairs of the Group on ways that embassies can better support the United States private sector abroad, including assisting the Chair and Vice-Chairs—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in soliciting private-sector advice;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with respect to implementation of strategic planning; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in advancing the overall mission and goals of United States national security.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title VII, § 708</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3072</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9905.</num>
<heading> Private sector consultation and coordination</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation with private sector by embassy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In developing the priorities for trade expansion initiatives described in <ref>section 9904(d) of this title</ref>, embassy mission teams shall convene local representatives of the United States private sector and the private sector of host countries to consult on issues affecting trade at the borders of such countries and take into account the private sector’s operational expertise and experience confronting the trade barriers in such countries as well as its recommendations for reform and best practices.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion of private-sector comments in mission plans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Written comments from local United States private sector representatives shall be included in the trade expansion component of mission plans submitted by the chief of mission to the Secretary of State, with recommendations and comments from the mission team, for the purpose of informing the development of the joint strategic plan on trade expansion priorities required pursuant to <ref>section 9904(c)(4) of this title</ref> and recommended funding for the implementation of such plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designated embassy point of contact for private sector consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each chief of mission shall designate an appropriate point of contact within the embassy who shall receive recommendations from appropriate private sector representatives regarding the implementation of the strategic plan required under <ref>section 9904(c)(4) of this title</ref> and ongoing trade barriers negatively impacting priority trade expansion. The chief of mission shall ensure that the designated point of contact shall be reasonably available for consultations with appropriate private sector representatives and to receive recommendations with respect to country-specific issues that may arise that will foreseeably disrupt trade.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement to protect business confidential information</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of State, Secretary of Commerce, and United States Trade Representative as well as the heads of all other agencies involved in the Economic Diplomacy Action Group established under <ref>section 9904(c) of this title</ref> shall protect from disclosure any proprietary information submitted by any private sector representative and marked as “business confidential information”, unless the party submitting the confidential business information had notice, at the time of submission, that such information would be released by the head of any such department or agency, or such party subsequently consents to the release of the information. To the extent business confidential information is provided, a non-confidential version of the information shall also be provided, in which the business confidential information is summarized or, if necessary, deleted.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment as trade secrets</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Proprietary information submitted by a private party in accordance with this chapter shall be considered to be a matter falling within the meaning of trade secrets and commercial or financial information exemption under <ref>section 552(b)(4) of title 5</ref> and shall be exempt from disclosure without the express approval of the private party.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title VII, § 709</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3074</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9906.</num>
<heading> Improving awareness of United States Government tools and services to support United States businesses overseas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Commerce shall take actions to improve the awareness of United States businesses with respect to United States Government tools and services to assist such businesses overseas, especially small and medium-sized enterprises, including by coordinating with State trade agencies, Export Assistance Centers, and Small Businesses Development Centers.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title VII, § 710</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3075</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>