<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 109—</num>
<heading>BURMA UNIFIED THROUGH RIGOROUS MILITARY ACCOUNTABILITY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10201.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Burmese military</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Burmese military”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means the Armed Forces of Burma, including the army, navy, and air force; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes security services under the control of the Armed Forces of Burma, such as the police and border guards.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Executive Order 14014</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Executive Order 14014” means Executive Order 14014 (86 Fed. Reg. 9429; relating to blocking property with respect to the situation in Burma).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Genocide</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “genocide” means any offense described in <ref>section 1091(a) of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> War crime</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “war crime” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 2441(c) of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LV, § 5568</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3361</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>MATTERS RELATING TO THE CONFLICT IN BURMA</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10211.</num>
<heading> Statement of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> continue to support the people of Burma in their struggle for democracy, human rights, and justice;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> support the efforts of the National Unity Government (NUG), the National Unity Consultative Council (NUCC), the Committee Representing Pyidaungsu Hluttaw (CRPH), the Burmese Civil Disobedience Movement, and other entities in Burma and in other countries to oppose the Burmese military and bring about an end to the military junta’s rule;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> support a credible process for the restoration of civilian government in Burma, with a reformed Burmese military under civilian control and the enactment of constitutional, political, and economic reform that protects the rights of minority groups and furthers a federalist form of government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> hold accountable perpetrators of human rights violations committed against ethnic groups in Burma and the people of Burma, including through the February 2022 coup d’etat;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> hold accountable the Russian Federation and the People’s Republic of China for their support of the Burmese military;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> continue to provide humanitarian assistance to populations impacted by violence perpetrated by the Burmese military wherever they may reside, and coordinate efforts among like-minded governments and other international donors to maximize the effectiveness of assistance and support for the people of Burma;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> secure the unconditional release of all unlawfully detained individuals in Burma, including those detained for the exercise of their fundamental freedoms; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> provide humanitarian assistance to the people of Burma in Burma, Bangladesh, Thailand, and the surrounding region without going through the Burmese military.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LV, § 5569</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3362</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>SANCTIONS AND POLICY COORDINATION WITH RESPECT TO BURMA</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10221.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Admitted; alien</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “admitted” and “alien” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 1101 of title 8</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Correspondent account; payable-through account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “correspondent account” and “payable-through account” have the meanings given those terms in <ref>section 5318A of title 31</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign financial institution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “foreign financial institution” has the meaning of that term as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury by regulation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “foreign person” means a person that is not a United States person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Knowingly</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “knowingly”, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person has actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “person” means an individual or entity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Support</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “support”, with respect to the Burmese military, means to knowingly have materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of the Burmese military.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States person</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “United States person” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any person in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LV, § 5570</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3362</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10222.</num>
<heading> Imposition of sanctions with respect to human rights abuses and perpetration of a coup in Burma</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mandatory sanctions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, the President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (d) with respect to any foreign person that the President determines—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> is a senior official of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Burmese military or security forces of Burma;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the State Administration Council, the military-appointed cabinet at the level of Deputy Minister or higher, or a military-appointed minister of a Burmese state or region; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an entity that primarily operates in the defense sector of the Burmese economy; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> is a Burmese state-owned commercial enterprise (other than an entity described in subsections (c)(1) and (c)(2)) that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is operating in the industrial or extractive sectors; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> significantly financially benefits the Burmese military.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional measure relating to facilitation of transactions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury may, in consultation with the Secretary of State, prohibit or impose strict conditions on the opening or maintaining in the United States of a correspondent account or payable-through account by a foreign financial institution that the President determines has, on or after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, knowingly conducted or facilitated a significant transaction or transactions on behalf of a foreign person subject to sanctions under this section imposed pursuant to subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional sanctions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President may impose the sanctions described in subsection (d) with respect to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Myanma Oil and Gas Enterprise;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> any Burmese state-owned enterprise that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is not operating in the industrial or extractive sectors; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> significantly financially benefits the Burmese military;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a spouse or adult child of any person described in subsection (a)(1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> any foreign person that, leading up to, during, and since the <date date="2021-02-01">February 1, 2021</date>, coup d’etat in Burma, is responsible for or has directly and knowingly engaged in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> actions or policies that significantly undermine democratic processes or institutions in Burma;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> actions or policies that significantly threaten the peace, security, or stability of Burma;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> actions or policies by a Burmese person that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> significantly prohibit, limit, or penalize the exercise of freedom of expression or assembly by people in Burma; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> limit access to print, online, or broadcast media in Burma; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the orchestration of arbitrary detention or torture in Burma or other serious human rights abuses in Burma; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> any Burmese entity that provides materiel to the Burmese military.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanctions described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Property blocking</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President may exercise all powers granted to the President by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of the foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign exchange</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President may, pursuant to such regulations as the President may prescribe, prohibit any transactions in foreign exchange that are subject to the jurisdiction of the United States and in which the foreign person has any interest.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Visas, admission, or parole</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">An alien who is described in subsection (a) or (c) is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> inadmissible to the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> ineligible for a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101</ref> et seq.).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Current visas revoked</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The issuing consular officer, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) shall, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</ref>), revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to an alien described in subparagraph (A) regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is issued.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of revocation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">A revocation under clause (i)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> shall take effect immediately; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> shall automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessment and report on sanctions with respect to Burmese State-owned enterprise operating in the energy sector</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, the President shall conduct an assessment with respect to the Burmese state-owned enterprise described in subsection (c)(1), including relevant factors pertaining to the possible application of sanctions on such enterprise.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon making the determination required by paragraph (1), the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the assessment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form of report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The report required by paragraph (2) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for intelligence, law enforcement, and national security activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Sanctions under this section shall not apply to any authorized intelligence, law enforcement, or national security activities of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception to comply with international obligations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Sanctions under subsection (d)(3) shall not apply with respect to the admission of an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success <date date="1947-06-26">June 26, 1947</date>, and entered into force <date date="1947-11-21">November 21, 1947</date>, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception relating to the provision of humanitarian assistance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Sanctions under this section may not be imposed with respect to transactions or the facilitation of transactions for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the sale of agricultural commodities, food, medicine, or medical devices to Burma;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the provision of humanitarian assistance to the people of Burma;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> financial transactions relating to humanitarian assistance or for humanitarian purposes in Burma; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> transporting goods or services that are necessary to carry out operations relating to humanitarian assistance or humanitarian purposes in Burma.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception relating to wind-down of projects</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Sanctions under this section shall not be imposed with respect to transactions or the facilitation of transactions related to the disposition of investments pursuant to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> agreements entered into between United States persons and the Government of Burma prior to <date date="1997-05-21">May 21, 1997</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the exercise of rights pursuant to such agreements; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> transactions related to the subsequent operation of the assets encompassed by such disposed investments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may, on a case-by-case basis waive the application of sanctions or restrictions imposed with respect to a foreign person under this section if the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees at the time such waiver is to take effect that the waiver is in the national interest of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation; penalties</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President may exercise all authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1702</ref> and 1704) to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1705</ref>) shall apply to a person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this section or any regulations promulgated under this section to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in section 206(a) of that Act [<ref>50 U.S.C. 1705(a)</ref>].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>, and annually thereafter for 8 years, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a classified report that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> describes the primary sources of income to which the Burmese military has access and that the United States has been unable to reach using sanctions authorities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assesses the impact of the sanctions imposed pursuant to the authorities under this section on the Burmese people and the Burmese military.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LV, § 5571</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3363</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10223.</num>
<heading> Sanctions and policy coordination for Burma</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The head of the Office of Sanctions Coordination in the Department of State should develop a comprehensive strategy for the implementation of the full range of United States diplomatic capabilities to implement Burma-related sanctions in order to promote human rights and the restoration of civilian government in Burma.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matters to be included</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The strategy described in subsection (a) should include plans and steps to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> coordinate the sanctions policies of the United States with relevant bureaus and offices in the Department of State and other relevant United States Government agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> conduct relevant research and vetting of entities and individuals that may be subject to sanctions and coordinate with other United States Government agencies and international financial intelligence units to assist in efforts to enforce anti-money laundering and anti-corruption laws and regulations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> promote a comprehensive international effort to impose and enforce multilateral sanctions with respect to Burma;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> support interagency United States Government efforts, including efforts of the United States Chief of Mission to Burma, the United States Ambassador to ASEAN, and the United States Permanent Representative to the United Nations, relating to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> identifying opportunities to exert pressure on the governments of the People’s Republic of China and the Russian Federation to support multilateral action against the Burmese military; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> working with like-minded partners to impose a coordinated arms embargo on the Burmese military and targeted sanctions on the economic interests of the Burmese military, including through the introduction and adoption of a United Nations Security Council resolution; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> provide timely input for reporting on the impacts of the implementation of sanctions on the Burmese military and the people of Burma.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LV, § 5572</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3366</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10224.</num>
<heading> Support for greater United Nations action with respect to Burma</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the United Nations Security Council has not taken adequate steps to condemn the <date date="2021-02-01">February 1, 2021</date>, coup in Burma, pressure the Burmese military to cease its violence against civilians, or secure the release of those unjustly detained;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> countries, such as the People’s Republic of China and the Russian Federation, that are directly or indirectly shielding the Burmese military from international scrutiny and action, should be obliged to endure the reputational damage of doing so by taking public votes on resolutions related to Burma that apply greater pressure on the Burmese military to restore Burma to its democratic path; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the United Nations Secretariat and the United Nations Security Council should take concrete steps to address the coup and ongoing crisis in Burma consistent with United Nations General Assembly resolution 75/287, “The situation in Myanmar,” which was adopted on <date date="2021-06-18">June 18, 2021</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Support for greater action</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The President shall direct the United States Permanent Representative to the United Nations to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States to spur greater action by the United Nations and the United Nations Security Council with respect to Burma by—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> pushing the United Nations Security Council to consider a resolution condemning the <date date="2021-02-01">February 1, 2021</date>, coup and calling on the Burmese military to cease its violence against the people of Burma and release without preconditions the journalists, pro-democracy activists, and political officials that it has unjustly detained;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> pushing the United Nations Security Council to consider a resolution that immediately imposes a global arms embargo against Burma to ensure that the Burmese military is not able to obtain weapons and munitions from other nations to further harm, murder, and oppress the people of Burma;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> pushing the United Nations and other United Nations authorities to cut off assistance to the Government of Burma while providing humanitarian assistance directly to the people of Burma through United Nations bodies and civil society organizations, particularly such organizations working with ethnic minorities that have been adversely affected by the coup and the Burmese military’s violent crackdown; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> spurring the United Nations Security Council to consider multilateral sanctions against the Burmese military for its atrocities against Rohingya and individuals of other ethnic and religious minorities, its coup, and the atrocities it has and continues to commit in the coup’s aftermath.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that the United States Permanent Representative to the United Nations should use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> object to the appointment of representatives to the United Nations and United Nations bodies such as the Human Rights Council that are sanctioned by the Burmese military; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> work to ensure the Burmese military is not recognized as the legitimate government of Burma in any United Nations body.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LV, § 5573</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3367</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10225.</num>
<heading> Sunset</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority to impose sanctions and the sanctions imposed under this subchapter shall terminate on the date that is 8 years after <date date="2022-12-23">December 23, 2022</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification for early sunset of sanctions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Sanctions imposed under this subchapter may be removed before the date specified in subsection (a), if the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees a certification that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Burmese military has released all political prisoners taken into custody on or after <date date="2021-02-01">February 1, 2021</date>, or is providing legal recourse to those that remain in custody;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the elected government of Burma has been reinstated or new free and fair elections have been held;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> all legal charges against those winning election in November 2020 are dropped; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the 2008 constitution of Burma has been amended or replaced to place the Burmese military under civilian oversight and ensure that the Burmese military no longer automatically receives 25 percent of seats in Burma’s state, regional, and national Hluttaws.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification for early sunset of sanctions on individuals</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The President may terminate the application of sanctions under this subchapter with respect to specific individuals if the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a notice of and justification for the termination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a notice that the individual is not engaging in the activity or is no longer occupying the position that was the basis for the sanctions or has taken significant verifiable steps toward stopping the activity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The notice required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LV, § 5574</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3368</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>AUTHORIZATIONS OF APPROPRIATIONS FOR ASSISTANCE FOR BURMA</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10241.</num>
<heading> General authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">During each of the fiscal years 2023 through 2027, following consultation with the appropriate congressional committees and subject to the limitations described in <ref>section 10242 of this title</ref>, funds authorized to be made available to carry out chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 may be made available, notwithstanding any other provision of law, for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> programs to strengthen federalism in and among ethnic states in Burma, including for non-lethal assistance for Ethnic Armed Organizations in Burma;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the administrative operations and programs of entities in Burma, including the political entities and affiliates of Ethnic Armed Organizations and pro-democracy movement organizations, that support efforts to establish an inclusive and representative democracy in Burma;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> technical support and non-lethal assistance for Burma’s Ethnic Armed Organizations, People’s Defense Forces, and pro-democracy movement organizations to strengthen communications and command and control, and coordination of international relief and other operations between and among such entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> programs and activities relating to former members of the Burmese military that have condemned the <date date="2022-02-01">February 1, 2022</date>, coup d’etat and voiced support for the restoration of civilian rule;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> programs to assist civil society organizations to investigate and document atrocities in Burma for the purposes of truth, justice, and accountability;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> programs to assist civil society organizations in Burma that support individuals that who are unlawfully detained in Burma for exercising their fundamental freedoms; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> programs to assist civil society organizations and ethnic groups with reconciliation activities related to Burma.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LV, § 5575</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3369</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10242.</num>
<heading> Limitations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided for by this subchapter, none of the funds authorized to be appropriated for assistance for Burma by this subchapter may be made available to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the State Administrative Council or any organization or entity controlled by, or an affiliate of, the Burmese military, or to any individual or organization that has committed a gross violation of human rights or advocates violence against ethnic or religious groups or individuals in Burma, as determined by the Secretary of State for programs administered by the Department of State and the United States Agency for International Development, or President of the National Endowment for Democracy (NED) for programs administered by NED; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Burmese military.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LV, § 5576</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3369</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10243.</num>
<heading> Appropriate congressional committees defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this subchapter, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LV, § 5577</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3370</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>EFFORTS AGAINST HUMAN RIGHTS ABUSES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10251.</num>
<heading> Authorization to provide technical assistance for efforts against human rights abuses</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State is authorized to provide assistance to support appropriate civilian or international entities that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> identify suspected perpetrators of war crimes, crimes against humanity, and genocide in Burma;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> collect, document, and protect evidence of crimes in Burma and preserving the chain of custody for such evidence;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> conduct criminal investigations of such crimes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> support investigations related to Burma conducted by other countries, and by entities mandated by the United Nations, such as the Independent Investigative Mechanism for Myanmar.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization for transitional justice mechanisms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State, taking into account any relevant findings in the report submitted under section 5941,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002463">1</ref> is authorized to provide support for the establishment and operation of transitional justice mechanisms, including a hybrid tribunal, to prosecute individuals suspected of committing war crimes, crimes against humanity, or genocide in Burma.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LV, § 5578</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3370</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>SANCTIONS EXCEPTION RELATING TO IMPORTATION OF GOODS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 10261.</num>
<heading> Sanctions exception relating to importation of goods</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authorities and requirements to impose sanctions under this chapter shall not include the authority or requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Good defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In this section, the term “good” means any article, natural or man-made substance, material, supply, or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LV, § 5579</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 3370</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>