<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 79—</num>
<heading>TRADE SANCTIONS REFORM AND EXPORT ENHANCEMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7201.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agricultural commodity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “agricultural commodity” has the meaning given the term in section 102 of the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 5602</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agricultural program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “agricultural program” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any program administered under the Food for Peace Act (<ref>7 U.S.C. 1691</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any program administered under <ref>section 1431 of title 7</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any program administered under the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 (<ref>7 U.S.C. 5601</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any commercial export sale of agricultural commodities; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any export financing (including credits or credit guarantees) provided by the United States Government for agricultural commodities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint resolution</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “joint resolution” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of <ref>section 7202(a)(1) of this title</ref>, only a joint resolution introduced within 10 session days of Congress after the date on which the report of the President under <ref>section 7202(a)(1) of this title</ref> is received by Congress, the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: “That Congress approves the report of the President pursuant to section 903(a)(1) of the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000, transmitted on _______.”, with the blank completed with the appropriate date; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of section 7205(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002378">1</ref> of this title, only a joint resolution introduced within 10 session days of Congress after the date on which the report of the President under section 7205(2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002378">1</ref> of this title is received by Congress, the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: “That Congress approves the report of the President pursuant to section 906(1) of the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000, transmitted on _______.”, with the blank completed with the appropriate date.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Medical device</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “medical device” has the meaning given the term “device” in <ref>section 321 of title 21</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Medicine</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “medicine” has the meaning given the term “drug” in <ref>section 321 of title 21</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unilateral agricultural sanction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “unilateral agricultural sanction” means any prohibition, restriction, or condition on carrying out an agricultural program with respect to a foreign country or foreign entity that is imposed by the United States for reasons of foreign policy or national security, except in a case in which the United States imposes the measure pursuant to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a multilateral regime and the other member countries of that regime have agreed to impose substantially equivalent measures; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a mandatory decision of the United Nations Security Council.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unilateral medical sanction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “unilateral medical sanction” means any prohibition, restriction, or condition on exports of, or the provision of assistance consisting of, medicine or a medical device with respect to a foreign country or foreign entity that is imposed by the United States for reasons of foreign policy or national security, except in a case in which the United States imposes the measure pursuant to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a multilateral regime and the other member countries of that regime have agreed to impose substantially equivalent measures; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a mandatory decision of the United Nations Security Council.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–387, § 1(a) [title IX, § 902]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1549</ref>, 1549A–67; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, title III, § 3001(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (2)(X), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1820</ref>, 1821; <ref>Pub. L. 113–79, title I, § 1423(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7202.</num>
<heading> Restriction</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> New sanctions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as provided in sections 7203 and 7204 of this title and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President may not impose a unilateral agricultural sanction or unilateral medical sanction against a foreign country or foreign entity, unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> not later than 60 days before the sanction is proposed to be imposed, the President submits a report to Congress that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> describes the activity proposed to be prohibited, restricted, or conditioned; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> describes the actions by the foreign country or foreign entity that justify the sanction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> there is enacted into law a joint resolution stating the approval of Congress for the report submitted under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing sanctions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall terminate any unilateral agricultural sanction or unilateral medical sanction that is in effect as of <date date="2000-10-28">October 28, 2000</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–387, § 1(a) [title IX, § 903]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1549</ref>, 1549A–68.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7203.</num>
<heading> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0"><ref>Section 7202 of this title</ref> shall not affect any authority or requirement to impose (or continue to impose) a sanction referred to in <ref>section 7202 of this title</ref>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> against a foreign country or foreign entity—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> pursuant to a declaration of war against the country or entity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> pursuant to specific statutory authorization for the use of the Armed Forces of the United States against the country or entity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> against which the Armed Forces of the United States are involved in hostilities; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> where imminent involvement by the Armed Forces of the United States in hostilities against the country or entity is clearly indicated by the circumstances; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to the extent that the sanction would prohibit, restrict, or condition the provision or use of any agricultural commodity, medicine, or medical device that is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> controlled on the United States Munitions List established under <ref>section 2778 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> controlled on any control list established under the Export Administration Act of 1979 or any successor statute (50 U.S.C. App. 2401 et seq.); <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002379">1</ref> or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> used to facilitate the design, development, or production of chemical or biological weapons, missiles, or weapons of mass destruction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–387, § 1(a) [title IX, § 904]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1549</ref>, 1549A–68; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title II, § 221(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 292</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7204.</num>
<heading> Termination of sanctions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any unilateral agricultural sanction or unilateral medical sanction that is imposed pursuant to the procedures described in <ref>section 7202(a) of this title</ref> shall terminate not later than 2 years after the date on which the sanction became effective unless—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> not later than 60 days before the date of termination of the sanction, the President submits to Congress a report containing—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the recommendation of the President for the continuation of the sanction for an additional period of not to exceed 2 years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the request of the President for approval by Congress of the recommendation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> there is enacted into law a joint resolution stating the approval of Congress for the report submitted under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–387, § 1(a) [title IX, § 905]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1549</ref>, 1549A–69.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7205.</num>
<heading> State sponsors of international terrorism</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter (other than <ref>section 7203 of this title</ref>), the export of agricultural commodities, medicine, or medical devices to Cuba, the Taliban or the territory of Afghanistan controlled by the Taliban, or to the government of a country that has been determined by the Secretary of State to have repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism under <ref>section 2371 of this title</ref>, section 4605(j)(1) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002380">1</ref> of title 50, or <ref>section 2780(d) of this title</ref>, or to any other entity in such a country, shall only be made pursuant to 1-year licenses issued by the United States Government for contracts entered into during the 1-year period of the license and shipped within the 12-month period beginning on the date of the signing of the contract, except that the requirements of such 1-year licenses shall be no more restrictive than license exceptions administered by the Department of Commerce or general licenses administered by the Department of the Treasury, except that procedures shall be in place to deny licenses for exports to any entity within such country, or in the territory of Afghanistan controlled by the Taliban, promoting international terrorism.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to the export of agricultural commodities, medicine, or medical devices to the Government of Syria or to the Government of North Korea, or to any other entity in Syria or North Korea.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Quarterly reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The applicable department or agency of the Federal Government shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees on a quarterly basis a report on any activities undertaken under subsection (a)(1) during the preceding calendar quarter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Biennial reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2000-10-28">October 28, 2000</date>, and every 2 years thereafter, the applicable department or agency of the Federal Government shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees on the operation of the licensing system under this section for the preceding 2-year period, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the number and types of licenses applied for;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the number and types of licenses approved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the average amount of time elapsed from the date of filing of a license application until the date of its approval;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the extent to which the licensing procedures were effectively implemented; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a description of comments received from interested parties about the extent to which the licensing procedures were effective, after the applicable department or agency holds a public 30-day comment period.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–387, § 1(a) [title IX, § 906]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1549</ref>, 1549A–69; <ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title II, § 221(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 292</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7206.</num>
<heading> Congressional procedures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Referral of report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A report described in section 7202(a)(1) or 7204(1) of this title shall be referred to the appropriate committee or committees of the House of Representatives and to the appropriate committee or committees of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Referral of joint resolution</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A joint resolution introduced in the Senate shall be referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations, and a joint resolution introduced in the House of Representatives shall be referred to the Committee on International Relations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A joint resolution referred to in paragraph (1) may not be reported before the eighth session day of Congress after the introduction of the joint resolution.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–387, § 1(a) [title IX, § 907]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1549</ref>, 1549A–70.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7207.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on United States assistance and financing</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on United States assistance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no United States Government assistance, including United States foreign assistance, United States export assistance, and any United States credit or guarantees shall be available for exports to Cuba or for commercial exports to Iran, Libya, North Korea, or Sudan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Nothing in paragraph (1) shall be construed to alter, modify, or otherwise affect the provisions of <ref>section 6039 of this title</ref> or any other provision of law relating to Cuba in effect on the day before <date date="2000-10-28">October 28, 2000</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President may waive the application of paragraph (1) with respect to Iran, Libya, North Korea, and Sudan to the degree the President determines that it is in the national security interest of the United States to do so, or for humanitarian reasons.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on financing of agricultural sales to Cuba</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">No United States person may provide payment or financing terms for sales of agricultural commodities or products to Cuba or any person in Cuba, except in accordance with the following terms (notwithstanding part 515 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, or any other provision of law):</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Payment of cash in advance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Financing by third country financial institutions (excluding United States persons or Government of Cuba entities), except that such financing may be confirmed or advised by a United States financial institution.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">Nothing in this paragraph authorizes payment terms or trade financing involving a debit or credit to an account of a person located in Cuba or of the Government of Cuba maintained on the books of a United States depository institution.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any private person or entity that violates paragraph (1) shall be subject to the penalties provided in the Trading With the Enemy Act [<ref>50 U.S.C. 4301</ref> et seq.] for violations under that Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration and enforcement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President shall issue such regulations as are necessary to carry out this section, except that the President, in lieu of issuing new regulations, may apply any regulations in effect on <date date="2000-10-28">October 28, 2000</date>, pursuant to the Trading With the Enemy Act [<ref>50 U.S.C. 4301</ref> et seq.], with respect to the conduct prohibited in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “financing” includes any loan or extension of credit;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “United States depository institution” means any entity (including its foreign branches or subsidiaries) organized under the laws of any jurisdiction within the United States, or any agency, office or branch located in the United States of a foreign entity, that is engaged primarily in the business of banking (including a bank, savings bank, savings association, credit union, trust company, or United States bank holding company); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the term “United States person” means the Federal Government, any State or local government, or any private person or entity of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–387, § 1(a) [title IX, § 908]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1549</ref>, 1549A–70.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7208.</num>
<heading> Prohibition on additional imports from Cuba</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to alter, modify, or otherwise affect the provisions of section 515.204 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, relating to the prohibition on the entry into the United States of merchandise that: (1) is of Cuban origin; (2) is or has been located in or transported from or through Cuba; or (3) is made or derived in whole or in part of any article which is the growth, produce, or manufacture of Cuba.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–387, § 1(a) [title IX, § 909]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1549</ref>, 1549A–71.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7209.</num>
<heading> Requirements relating to certain travel-related transactions with Cuba</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of travel relating to commercial sales of agricultural and medical goods</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall promulgate regulations under which the travel-related transactions listed in paragraph (c) of section 515.560 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, are authorized by general license for travel to, from, or within Cuba for the marketing and sale of agricultural and medical goods pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition on travel relating to tourist activities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law or regulation, the Secretary of the Treasury, or any other Federal official, may not authorize the travel-related transactions listed in subsection (c) of section 515.560 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, either by a general license or on a case-by-case basis by a specific license for travel to, from, or within Cuba for tourist activities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “tourist activities” means any activity with respect to travel to, from, or within Cuba that is not expressly authorized in subsection (a) of this section, in any of paragraphs (1) through (12) of section 515.560 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, or in any section referred to in any of such paragraphs (1) through (12) (as such sections were in effect on <date date="2000-06-01">June 1, 2000</date>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 106–387, § 1(a) [title IX, § 910]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1549</ref>, 1549A–71; <ref>Pub. L. 111–8, div. D, title VI, § 620</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 677</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7210.</num>
<heading> Application of the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Nothing in the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000 [22 U.S.C. § 7201 et seq.] shall limit the application or scope of any law establishing criminal or civil penalties, including any Executive order or regulation promulgated pursuant to such laws (or similar or successor laws), for the unlawful export of any agricultural commodity, medicine, or medical device to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a foreign organization, group, or person designated pursuant to Executive Order No. 12947 of <date date="1995-01-23">January 23, 1995</date>, as amended;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a Foreign Terrorist Organization pursuant to the Antiterrorism and Effective Death Penalty Act of 1996 (<ref>Public Law 104–132</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a foreign organization, group, or person designated pursuant to Executive Order No. 13224 (<date date="2001-09-23">September 23, 2001</date>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any narcotics trafficking entity designated pursuant to Executive Order No. 12978 (<date date="1995-10-21">October 21, 1995</date>) or the Foreign Narcotics Kingpin Designation Act (<ref>Public Law 106–120</ref>) [21 U.S.C. § 1901 et seq.]; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> any foreign organization, group, or persons subject to any restriction for its involvement in weapons of mass destruction or missile proliferation.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title II, § 221(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 292</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7211.</num>
<heading> Technical clarification relating to provision of material support to terrorism</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No provision of the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000 (title IX of <ref>Public Law 106–387</ref>) [22 U.S.C. § 7201 et seq.] shall be construed to limit or otherwise affect section 2339A or 2339B of title 18.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–56, title VIII, § 807</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 378</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>