<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 66—</num>
<heading>UNITED STATES-HONG KONG POLICY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5701.</num>
<heading> Findings and declarations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress makes the following findings and declarations:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The Congress recognizes that under the 1984 Sino-British Joint Declaration:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The People’s Republic of China and the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland have agreed that the People’s Republic of China will resume the exercise of sovereignty over Hong Kong on <date date="1997-07-01">July 1, 1997</date>. Until that time, the United Kingdom will be responsible for the administration of Hong Kong.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China, beginning on <date date="1997-07-01">July 1, 1997</date>, will continue to enjoy a high degree of autonomy on all matters other than defense and foreign affairs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> There is provision for implementation of a “one country, two systems” policy, under which Hong Kong will retain its current lifestyle and legal, social, and economic systems until at least the year 2047.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The legislature of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region will be constituted by elections, and the provisions of the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights and the International Covenant on Economic, Social and Cultural Rights, as applied to Hong Kong, shall remain in force.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Provision is made for the continuation in force of agreements implemented as of <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>, and for the ability of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region to conclude new agreements either on its own or with the assistance of the Government of the People’s Republic of China.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The Congress declares its wish to see full implementation of the provisions of the Joint Declaration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The President has announced his support for the policies and decisions reflected in the Joint Declaration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Hong Kong plays an important role in today’s regional and world economy. This role is reflected in strong economic, cultural, and other ties with the United States that give the United States a strong interest in the continued vitality, prosperity, and stability of Hong Kong.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Support for democratization is a fundamental principle of United States foreign policy. As such, it naturally applies to United States policy toward Hong Kong. This will remain equally true after <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The human rights of the people of Hong Kong are of great importance to the United States and are directly relevant to United States interests in Hong Kong. A fully successful transition in the exercise of sovereignty over Hong Kong must safeguard human rights in and of themselves. Human rights also serve as a basis for Hong Kong’s continued economic prosperity.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–383, § 2</ref>, <date date="1992-10-05">Oct. 5, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1448</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5702.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “Hong Kong” means, prior to <date date="1997-07-01">July 1, 1997</date>, the British Dependent Territory of Hong Kong, and on and after <date date="1997-07-01">July 1, 1997</date>, the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “Joint Declaration” means the Joint Declaration of the Government of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland and the Government of the People’s Republic of China on the Question of Hong Kong, done at Beijing on <date date="1984-12-19">December 19, 1984</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the term “laws of the United States” means provisions of law enacted by the Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–383, § 3</ref>, <date date="1992-10-05">Oct. 5, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1449</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>POLICY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5711.</num>
<heading> Bilateral ties between United States and Hong Kong</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that the following, which are based in part on the relevant provisions of the Joint Declaration, should be the policy of the United States with respect to its bilateral relationship with Hong Kong:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The United States should play an active role, before, on, and after <date date="1997-07-01">July 1, 1997</date>, in maintaining Hong Kong’s confidence and prosperity, Hong Kong’s role as an international financial center, and the mutually beneficial ties between the people of the United States and the people of Hong Kong.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The United States should actively seek to establish and expand direct bilateral ties and agreements with Hong Kong in economic, trade, financial, monetary, aviation, shipping, communications, tourism, cultural, sport, and other appropriate areas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The United States should seek to maintain, after <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>, the United States consulate-general in Hong Kong, together with other official and semi-official organizations, such as the United States Information Agency American Library.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The United States should invite Hong Kong to maintain, after <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>, its official and semi-official missions in the United States, such as the Hong Kong Economic &amp; Trade Office, the Office of the Hong Kong Trade Development Council, and the Hong Kong Tourist Association. The United States should invite Hong Kong to open and maintain other official or semi-official missions to represent Hong Kong in those areas in which Hong Kong is entitled to maintain relations on its own, including economic, trade, financial, monetary, aviation, shipping, communications, tourism, cultural, and sport areas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The United States should recognize passports and travel documents issued after <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>, by the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The resumption by the People’s Republic of China of the exercise of sovereignty over Hong Kong after <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>, should not affect treatment of Hong Kong residents who apply for visas to visit or reside permanently in the United States, so long as such treatment is consistent with the Immigration and Nationality Act [<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–383, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1992-10-05">Oct. 5, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1449</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5712.</num>
<heading> Participation in multilateral organizations, rights under international agreements, and trade status</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that the following, which are based in part on the relevant provisions of the Joint Declaration, should be the policy of the United States with respect to Hong Kong after <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The United States should support Hong Kong’s participation in all appropriate multilateral conferences, agreements, and organizations in which Hong Kong is eligible to participate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The United States should continue to fulfill its obligations to Hong Kong under international agreements, so long as Hong Kong reciprocates, regardless of whether the People’s Republic of China is a party to the particular international agreement, unless and until such obligations are modified or terminated in accordance with law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The United States should respect Hong Kong’s status as a separate customs territory, and as a WTO member country (as defined in <ref>section 3501(10) of title 19</ref>), whether or not the People’s Republic of China participates in the World Trade Organization (as defined in <ref>section 3501(8) of title 19</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–383, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1992-10-05">Oct. 5, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1450</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–36, title I, § 1002(e)</ref>, <date date="1999-06-25">June 25, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 133</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5713.</num>
<heading> Commerce between United States and Hong Kong</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that the following, which are based in part on the relevant provisions of the Joint Declaration, are and should continue after <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>, to be the policy of the United States with respect to commerce between the United States and Hong Kong:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The United States should seek to maintain and expand economic and trade relations with Hong Kong and should continue to treat Hong Kong as a separate territory in economic and trade matters, such as import quotas and certificates of origin.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The United States should continue to negotiate directly with Hong Kong to conclude bilateral economic agreements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The United States should continue to treat Hong Kong as a territory which is fully autonomous from the United Kingdom and, after <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>, should treat Hong Kong as a territory which is fully autonomous from the People’s Republic of China with respect to economic and trade matters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The United States should continue to grant the products of Hong Kong nondiscriminatory trade treatment by virtue of Hong Kong’s membership in the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The United States should recognize certificates of origin for manufactured goods issued by the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The United States should continue to allow the United States dollar to be freely exchanged with the Hong Kong dollar.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> United States businesses should be encouraged to continue to operate in Hong Kong, in accordance with applicable United States and Hong Kong law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The United States should continue to support access by Hong Kong to sensitive technologies controlled under the agreement of the Coordinating Committee for Multilateral Export Controls (commonly referred to as “COCOM”) for so long as the United States is satisfied that such technologies are protected from improper use or export.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The United States should encourage Hong Kong to continue its efforts to develop a framework which provides adequate protection for intellectual property rights.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The United States should negotiate a bilateral investment treaty directly with Hong Kong, in consultation with the Government of the People’s Republic of China.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> The change in the exercise of sovereignty over Hong Kong should not affect ownership in any property, tangible or intangible, held in the United States by any Hong Kong person.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–383, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1992-10-05">Oct. 5, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1450</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title V, § 5003(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 790</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5714.</num>
<heading> Transportation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that the following, which are based in part on the relevant provisions of the Joint Declaration, should be the policy of the United States after <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>, with respect to transportation from Hong Kong:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Recognizing Hong Kong’s position as an international transport center, the United States should continue to recognize ships and airplanes registered in Hong Kong and should negotiate air service agreements directly with Hong Kong.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The United States should continue to recognize ships registered by Hong Kong.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> United States commercial ships, in accordance with applicable United States and Hong Kong law, should remain free to port in Hong Kong.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The United States should continue to recognize airplanes registered by Hong Kong in accordance with applicable laws of the People’s Republic of China.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The United States should recognize licenses issued by the Hong Kong to Hong Kong airlines.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The United States should recognize certificates issued by the Hong Kong to United States air carriers for air service involving travel to, from, or through Hong Kong which does not involve travel to, from, or through other parts of the People’s Republic of China.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The United States should negotiate at the appropriate time directly with the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, acting under authorization from the Government of the People’s Republic of China, to renew or amend all air service agreements existing on <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>, and to conclude new air service agreements affecting all flights to, from, or through the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region which do not involve travel to, from, or through other parts of the People’s Republic of China.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The United States should make every effort to ensure that the negotiations described in paragraph (7) lead to procompetitive air service agreements.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–383, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1992-10-05">Oct. 5, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1451</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5715.</num>
<heading> Cultural and educational exchanges</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that the following, which are based in part on the relevant provisions of the Joint Declaration, are and should continue after <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>, to be the policy of the United States with respect to cultural and educational exchanges with Hong Kong:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The United States should seek to maintain and expand United States-Hong Kong relations and exchanges in culture, education, science, and academic research. The United States should encourage American participation in bilateral exchanges with Hong Kong, both official and unofficial.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The United States should actively seek to further United States-Hong Kong cultural relations and promote bilateral exchanges, including the negotiating and concluding of appropriate agreements in these matters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Hong Kong should be accorded separate status as a full partner under the Fulbright Academic Exchange Program (apart from the United Kingdom before <date date="1997-07-01">July 1, 1997</date>, and apart from the People’s Republic of China thereafter), with the continuation or establishment of a Fulbright Commission or functionally equivalent mechanism.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The United States should actively encourage Hong Kong residents to visit the United States on nonimmigrant visas for such purposes as business, tourism, education, and scientific and academic research, in accordance with applicable United States and Hong Kong laws.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Upon the request of the Legislative Council of Hong Kong, the Librarian of Congress, acting through the Congressional Research Service, should seek to expand educational and informational ties with the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–383, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1992-10-05">Oct. 5, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1452</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>STATUS OF HONG KONG IN UNITED STATES LAW</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5721.</num>
<heading> Continued application of United States law</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any change in the exercise of sovereignty over Hong Kong, the laws of the United States shall continue to apply with respect to Hong Kong, on and after <date date="1997-07-01">July 1, 1997</date>, in the same manner as the laws of the United States were applied with respect to Hong Kong before such date unless otherwise expressly provided by law or by Executive order under <ref>section 5722 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For all purposes, including actions in any court in the United States, the Congress approves the continuation in force on and after <date date="1997-07-01">July 1, 1997</date>, of all treaties and other international agreements, including multilateral conventions, entered into before <date date="2019-11-27">November 27, 2019</date>, between the United States and Hong Kong, or entered into before <date date="2019-11-27">November 27, 2019</date>, between the United States and the United Kingdom and applied to Hong Kong, unless or until terminated in accordance with law. If in carrying out this subchapter, the President determines that Hong Kong is not legally competent to carry out its obligations under any such treaty or other international agreement, or that the continuation of Hong Kong’s obligations or rights under any such treaty or other international agreement is not appropriate under the circumstances, such determination shall be reported to the Congress in accordance with <ref>section 5731 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–383, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1992-10-05">Oct. 5, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1452</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–76, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-11-27">Nov. 27, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1163</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5722.</num>
<heading> Presidential order</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presidential determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On or after <date date="1997-07-01">July 1, 1997</date>, whenever the President determines that Hong Kong is not sufficiently autonomous to justify treatment under a particular law of the United States, or any provision thereof, different from that accorded the People’s Republic of China, the President may issue an Executive order suspending the application of <ref>section 5721(a) of this title</ref> to such law or provision of law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Factor for consideration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In making a determination under subsection (a) with respect to the application of a law of the United States, or any provision thereof, to Hong Kong, the President should consider the terms, obligations, and expectations expressed in the Joint Declaration with respect to Hong Kong.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication in Federal Register</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any Executive order issued under subsection (a) shall be published in the Federal Register and shall specify the law or provision of law affected by the order.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of suspension</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An Executive order issued under subsection (a) may be terminated by the President with respect to a particular law or provision of law whenever the President determines that Hong Kong has regained sufficient autonomy to justify different treatment under the law or provision of law in question. Notice of any such termination shall be published in the Federal Register.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–383, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1992-10-05">Oct. 5, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1453</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5723.</num>
<heading> Rules and regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President is authorized to prescribe such rules and regulations as the President may deem appropriate to carry out this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–383, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1992-10-05">Oct. 5, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1453</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5724.</num>
<heading> Consultation with Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In carrying out this subchapter, the President shall consult appropriately with the Congress.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–383, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1992-10-05">Oct. 5, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1453</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5725.</num>
<heading> Secretary of State report regarding the autonomy of Hong Kong</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as provided in subsection (b), the Secretary of State, on at least an annual basis, and in conjunction with the report required under <ref>section 5731 of this title</ref>, shall issue a certification to Congress that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> indicates whether Hong Kong continues to warrant treatment under United States law in the same manner as United States laws were applied to Hong Kong before <date date="1997-07-01">July 1, 1997</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> addresses—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> commercial agreements;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> law enforcement cooperation, including extradition requests;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> sanctions enforcement;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> export controls, and any other agreements and forms of exchange involving dual use, critical, or other sensitive technologies;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> any formal treaties or agreements between the United States and Hong Kong;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> other areas of bilateral cooperation that the Secretary determines to be relevant; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<chapeau> decision-making within the Government of Hong Kong, including executive, legislative, and judicial structures, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> freedom of assembly;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> freedom of speech;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> freedom of expression; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> freedom of the press, including the Internet and social media;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> universal suffrage, including the ultimate aim of the selection of the Chief Executive and all members of the Legislative Council by universal suffrage;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ix)</num>
<content> judicial independence;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(x)</num>
<content> police and security functions;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xi)</num>
<content> education;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xii)</num>
<content> laws or regulations regarding treason, secession, sedition, subversion against the Central People’s Government of the People’s Republic of China, or theft of state secrets;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xiii)</num>
<content> laws or regulations regarding foreign political organizations or bodies;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xiv)</num>
<content> laws or regulations regarding political organizations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(xv)</num>
<content> other rights enumerated in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, done at Paris <date date="1948-12-10">December 10, 1948</date>, and the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights, done at New York <date date="1966-12-19">December 19, 1966</date>; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an assessment of the degree of any erosions to Hong Kong’s autonomy in each category listed in subparagraph (B) resulting from actions by the Government of the People’s Republic of China that are inconsistent with its commitments under the Basic Law or the Joint Declaration;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an evaluation of the specific impacts to any areas of cooperation between the United States and Hong Kong resulting from erosions of autonomy in Hong Kong or failures of the Government of Hong Kong to fulfill obligations to the United States under international agreements within the categories listed in subparagraph (B); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a list of any specific actions taken by the United States Government in response to any erosion of autonomy or failures to fulfill obligations to the United States under international agreements identified in this certification and the report required under <ref>section 5731 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Factor for consideration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In making each certification under paragraph (1), the Secretary of State should consider the terms, obligations, and expectations expressed in the Joint Declaration with respect to Hong Kong.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional certifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The certification under section (1) shall be issued annually, but the Secretary may issue additional certifications at any time if the Secretary determines it is warranted by circumstances in Hong Kong.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver authority</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of State may waive the application of subsection (a) if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines that such a waiver is in the national security interests of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on or before the date on which the waiver takes effect, the Secretary notifies the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives of the intent to waive such subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partial waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except for the list of actions described in subsection (a)(1)(C)(iii), the Secretary of State may waive relevant parts of the application of subsection (a) if the President issues an Executive order under <ref>section 5722 of this title</ref> that suspends the application of any particular United States law to Hong Kong.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–383, title II, § 205</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 116–76, § 4(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2019-11-27">Nov. 27, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1163</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5726.</num>
<heading> Treatment of Hong Kong applicants for visas to study or work in the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Visa eligibility for certain Hong Kong students</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, applications for visas to enter, study, or work in the United States, which are submitted by otherwise qualified applicants who resided in Hong Kong in 2014 and later, may not be denied primarily on the basis of the applicant’s subjection to politically-motivated arrest, detention, or other adverse government action.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall take such steps as may be necessary to ensure that consular officers are aware of the policy described in subsection (a) and receive appropriate training and support to ensure that the policy is carried out so that affected individuals do not face discrimination or unnecessary delay in the processing of their visa applications, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> providing specialized training for all consular officers posted to the United States Embassy in Beijing or to any United States consulate in the People’s Republic of China, the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, or the Macau Special Administrative Region;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> instructing the United States Consulate in Hong Kong to maintain an active list of individuals who are known to have been formally charged, detained, or convicted by the Government of Hong Kong Special Administrative Region or by the Government of the People’s Republic of China, or intermediaries of such governments, based on politically-motivated considerations related to their exercise of rights enumerated in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, done at Paris <date date="1948-12-10">December 10, 1948</date>, or the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights, done at New York <date date="1966-12-19">December 19, 1966</date>, to facilitate the cross-checking of visa applications for Hong Kong residents; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> updating any relevant United States Government websites with information on the policy described in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cooperation with like-minded countries</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall contact appropriate representatives of other democratic countries, particularly those who receive a large number of applicants for student and employment visas from Hong Kong—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to inform them of the United States policy regarding arrests for participation in nonviolent protests in Hong Kong; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to encourage them to take similar steps to ensure the rights of nonviolent protesters are protected from discrimination due to the actions of the Government of Hong Kong and of the Government of the People’s Republic of China.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–383, title II, § 206</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 116–76, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-11-27">Nov. 27, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1165</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>REPORTING PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5731.</num>
<heading> Reporting requirement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2019-03-31">March 31, 2019</date>, and annually thereafter through 2024, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on conditions in Hong Kong of interest to the United States. This report shall cover (in the case of the initial report) the period since <date date="1992-10-05">October 5, 1992</date>, or (in the case of subsequent reports) the period since the most recent report pursuant to this section and shall describe—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> significant developments in United States relations with Hong Kong, including a description of agreements that have entered into force between the United States and Hong Kong;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> other matters, including developments related to the change in the exercise of sovereignty over Hong Kong, affecting United States interests in Hong Kong or United States relations with Hong Kong;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the nature and extent of United States-Hong Kong cultural, education, scientific, and academic exchanges, both official and unofficial;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the laws of the United States with respect to which the application of <ref>section 5721(a) of this title</ref> has been suspended pursuant to <ref>section 5722(a) of this title</ref> or with respect to which such a suspension has been terminated pursuant to <ref>section 5722(d) of this title</ref>, and the reasons for the suspension or termination, as the case may be;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> treaties and other international agreements with respect to which the President has made a determination described in the last sentence of <ref>section 5721(b) of this title</ref>, and the reasons for each such determination;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> significant problems in cooperation between Hong Kong and the United States in the area of export controls;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> the development of democratic institutions in Hong Kong; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> the nature and extent of Hong Kong’s participation in multilateral forums.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form and shall be published on a publicly available website of the Department of State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–383, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1992-10-05">Oct. 5, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1453</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–107, title V, § 576(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-12">Feb. 12, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 750</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–115, title V, § 586(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-10">Jan. 10, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2173</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1256</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2056</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5732.</num>
<heading> Separate part of country reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whenever a report is transmitted to the Congress on a country-by-country basis there shall be included in such report, where applicable, a separate subreport on Hong Kong under the heading of the state that exercises sovereignty over Hong Kong. The reports to which this section applies include the reports transmitted under—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> sections 2151n(d) and 2304(b) of this title (relating to human rights);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content><ref>section 2241 of title 19</ref> (relating to trade barriers); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> section 4711 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002322">1</ref> of title 15 (relating to economic policy and trade practices).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 102–383, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1992-10-05">Oct. 5, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1454</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>