<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 101A—</num>
<heading>FIGHT AND COMBAT RAMPANT IRANIAN MISSILE EXPORTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9421.</num>
<heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Annex B to United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015) restricts certain missile-related activities and transfers to and from Iran, including all items, materials, equipment, goods, and technology set out in the Missile Technology Control Regime Annex, absent advance, case-by-case approval from the United Nations Security Council.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Iran has transferred Shahed and Mohajer drones, covered under the Missile Technology Control Regime Annex, to the Russian Federation, the Government of Ethiopia, and other Iran-aligned entities, including the Houthis in Yemen and militia units in Iraq, without prior authorization from the United Nations Security Council, in violation of the restrictions set forth in Annex B to United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Certain missile-related restrictions in Annex B to United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 expired in October 2023, removing international legal restrictions on missile-related activities and transfers to and from Iran.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–50, div. K, § 2</ref>, <date date="2024-04-24">Apr. 24, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9422.</num>
<heading> Statement of policy</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to urgently seek the extension of missile-related restrictions set forth in Annex B to United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to use all available authorities to constrain Iran’s domestic ballistic missile production capabilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to combat and deter the transfer of conventional and non-conventional arms, equipment, material, and technology to, or from Iran, or involving the Government of Iran; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to ensure countries, individuals, and entities engaged in, or attempting to engage in, the acquisition, facilitation, or development of arms and related components and technology subject to restrictions under Annex B to United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 are held to account under United States and international law, including through the application and enforcement of sanctions and use of export controls, regardless of whether the restrictions under Annex B to United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 remain in effect following their anticipated expiration in October 2023.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–50, div. K, § 3</ref>, <date date="2024-04-24">Apr. 24, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9423.</num>
<heading> Sanctions to combat the proliferation of Iranian missiles</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The sanctions described in subsection (b) shall apply to any foreign person the President determines, on or after <date date="2024-04-24">April 24, 2024</date>—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> knowingly engages in any effort to acquire, possess, develop, transport, transfer, or deploy covered technology to, from, or involving the Government of Iran or Iran-aligned entities, regardless of whether the restrictions set forth in Annex B to United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015) remain in effect after October 2023;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> knowingly provides entities owned or controlled by the Government of Iran or Iran-aligned entities with goods, technology, parts, or components, that may contribute to the development of covered technology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> knowingly participates in joint missile or drone development, including development of covered technology, with the Government of Iran or Iran-aligned entities, including technical training, storage, and transport;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> knowingly imports, exports, or re-exports to, into, or from Iran, whether directly or indirectly, any significant arms or related materiel prohibited under paragraph (5) or (6) to Annex B of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015) as of <date date="2023-04-01">April 1, 2023</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> knowingly provides significant financial, material, or technological support to, or knowingly engages in a significant transaction with, a foreign person subject to sanctions for conduct described in paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (4); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> is an adult family member of a person subject to sanctions for conduct described in paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (4).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sanctions described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Blocking of property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President shall exercise all authorities granted under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of the foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ineligibility for visas, admission, or parole</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Visas, admission, or parole</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">An alien described in subsection (a) shall be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> inadmissible to the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101</ref> et 16 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002443">1</ref> seq.).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Current visas revoked</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The visa or other entry documentation of any alien described in subsection (a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002444">2</ref> is subject to revocation regardless of the issue date of the visa or other entry documentation.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Immediate effect</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">A revocation under clause (i) shall, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</ref>)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> take effect immediately; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the possession of the alien.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person that violates, or attempts to violate, subsection (b) or any regulation, license, or order issued pursuant to that subsection, shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Economic <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002445">3</ref> Powers Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1705</ref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may waive the application of sanctions under this section with respect to a foreign person for renewable periods not to exceed 180 days only if, not later than 15 days after the date on which the waiver is to take effect, the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees a written determination and justification that the waiver is in the vital national security interests of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1702</ref> and 1704) to carry out any amendments made by this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President shall, not later than 120 days after <date date="2024-04-24">April 24, 2024</date>, promulgate regulations as necessary for the implementation of this division and the amendments made by this division.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not less than 10 days before the promulgation of regulations under subsection (a), the President shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of the proposed regulations and the provisions of this division and the amendments made by this division that the regulations are implementing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for intelligence activities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Sanctions under this section shall not apply to any activity subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 3091</ref> et seq.) or any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception to comply with international obligations and for law enforcement activities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Sanctions under this section shall not apply with respect to an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success <date date="1947-06-26">June 26, 1947</date>, and entered into force <date date="1947-11-21">November 21, 1947</date>, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to carry out or assist authorized law enforcement activity in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of sanctions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This section shall cease to be effective beginning on the date that is 30 days after the date on which the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the Government of Iran no longer repeatedly provides support for international terrorism as determined by the Secretary of State pursuant to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><ref>section 4813(c)(1)(A) of title 50</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>section 2371 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content><ref>section 2780 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any other provision of law; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Iran has ceased the pursuit, acquisition, and development of, and verifiably dismantled its, nuclear, biological, and chemical weapons and ballistic missiles and ballistic missile launch technology.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–50, div. K, § 5</ref>, <date date="2024-04-24">Apr. 24, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 972</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9424.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign person</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “foreign person”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> means an individual or entity that is not a United States person; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> includes a foreign state (as such term is defined in <ref>section 1603 of title 28</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Government of Iran</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Government of Iran” has the meaning given such term in section 560.304 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as such section was in effect on <date date="2021-01-01">January 1, 2021</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States person</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The terms “United States person” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a United States citizen;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a permanent resident alien of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a person in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Iran-aligned entity</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Iran-aligned entity” means a foreign person that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is controlled or significantly influenced by the Government of Iran; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> knowingly receives material or financial support from the Government of Iran, including Hezbollah, the Houthis, or any other proxy group that furthers Iran’s national security objectives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered technology</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “covered technology” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any goods, technology, software, or related material specified in the Missile Technology Control Regime Annex, as in effect on the day before <date date="2024-04-24">April 24, 2024</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any additional goods, technology, software, or related material added to the Missile Technology Control Regime Annex after the day before <date date="2024-04-24">April 24, 2024</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Family member</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “family member” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a child, grandchild, parent, grandparent, sibling, or spouse; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any spouse, widow, or widower of an individual described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Knowingly</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “knowingly” has the meaning given that term in section 14 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Missile Technology Control Regime</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Missile Technology Control Regime” means the policy statement, between the United States, the United Kingdom, the Federal Republic of Germany, France, Italy, Canada, and Japan, announced on <date date="1987-04-16">April 16, 1987</date>, to restrict sensitive missile-relevant transfers based on the Missile Technology Control Regime Annex, and any amendments thereto or expansions thereof, as in effect on the day before <date date="2024-04-24">April 24, 2024</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Missile Technology Control Regime Annex</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Missile Technology Control Regime Annex” means the Guidelines and Equipment and Technology Annex of the Missile Technology Control Regime, and any amendments thereto or updates thereof, as in effect on the day before <date date="2024-04-24">April 24, 2024</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 118–50, div. K, § 7</ref>, <date date="2024-04-24">Apr. 24, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 975</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>