<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 55—</num>
<heading>RESEARCH AND TRAINING FOR EASTERN EUROPE AND INDEPENDENT STATES OF FORMER SOVIET UNION</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4501.</num>
<heading> Findings and declarations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Congress finds and declares that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> factual knowledge, independently verified, about the countries of Eastern Europe and the independent states of the former Soviet Union is of the utmost importance for the national security of the United States, for the furtherance of our national interests in the conduct of foreign relations, and for the prudent management of our domestic affairs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the development and maintenance of knowledge about the countries of Eastern Europe and the independent states of the former Soviet Union depends upon the national capability for advanced research by highly trained and experienced specialists, available for service in and out of Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> certain essential functions are necessary to ensure the existence of that knowledge and the capability to sustain it, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> graduate training;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> advanced research;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> public dissemination of research data, methods, and findings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> contact and collaboration among Government and private specialists; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> firsthand experience of the countries of Eastern Europe and the independent states of the former Soviet Union by American specialists, including on site conduct of advanced training and research to the extent practicable; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> it is in the national interest for the United States Government to provide a stable source of financial support for the functions described in this section and to supplement the financial support for those functions which is currently being furnished by Federal, State, local, regional, and private agencies, organizations, and individuals, and thereby to stabilize the conduct of these functions on a national scale, consistently, and on a long range unclassified basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–164, title VIII, § 802</ref>, <date date="1983-11-22">Nov. 22, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1047</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–199, title III, § 302(3)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-17">Dec. 17, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2322</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4502.</num>
<heading> “Institution of higher education” and “Advisory Committee” defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">As used in this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “institution of higher education” has the same meaning given such term in <ref>section 1001 of title 20</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “Advisory Committee” means the Advisory Committee for Studies of Eastern Europe and the Independent States of the Former Soviet Union established by <ref>section 4503(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–164, title VIII, § 803</ref>, <date date="1983-11-22">Nov. 22, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1048</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–199, title III, § 302(4)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-17">Dec. 17, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2322</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–244, title I, § 102(a)(7)(C)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 1619</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4503.</num>
<heading> Establishment of Advisory Committee</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment; composition; Chairman</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established within the Department of State the Advisory Committee for Studies of Eastern Europe and the Independent States of the Former Soviet Union which shall be composed of the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Education, the Librarian of Congress, the President of the American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies, and the President of the Association of American Universities. The Secretary of State shall be the Chairman.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings; quorum</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Advisory Committee shall meet at the call of the Chairman and shall hold at least one meeting each year. Three members of the Advisory Committee shall constitute a quorum.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technical and clerical assistance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State may detail personnel of the Department of State to provide technical and clerical assistance to the Advisory Committee in carrying out its functions under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Advisory Committee shall recommend grant policies for the advancement of the objectives of this chapter. In proposing recipients for grants under this chapter, the Advisory Committee shall give the highest priority to national organizations with an interest and expertise in conducting research and training concerning the countries of Eastern Europe and the independent states of the former Soviet Union and in disseminating the results of such research. In making its recommendations, the Advisory Committee shall emphasize the development of a stable, long-term research program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–164, title VIII, § 804</ref>, <date date="1983-11-22">Nov. 22, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1048</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–199, title III, § 302(5)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-17">Dec. 17, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2322</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4504.</num>
<heading> Authority to make payments; purposes</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Secretary of State, after consultation with the Advisory Committee, shall make payments, in accordance with the provisions of this section, out of funds made available to carry out this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> One part of the payments made in each fiscal year shall be used to conduct a national research program at the postdoctoral or equivalent level, such program to include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the dissemination of information about the research program and the solicitation of proposals for research contracts from American institutions of higher education and not-for-profit corporations, such contracts to contain shared-cost provisions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the awarding of contracts for such research projects as the respective institution determines will best serve to carry out the purposes of this chapter after reviewing proposals submitted under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> One part of the payments made in each fiscal year shall be used—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> to establish and carry out a program of graduate, postdoctoral, and teaching fellowships for advanced training in studies on the countries of Eastern Europe and the independent states of the former Soviet Union and related studies, such program—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to be coordinated with the research program described in paragraph (1);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to be conducted, on a shared-cost basis, at American institutions of higher education; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> to include—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the dissemination of information on the fellowship program and the solicitation of applications for fellowships from qualified institutions of higher education and qualified individuals; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the awarding of such fellowships as the respective institution determines will best serve to carry out the purposes of this chapter after reviewing applications submitted under subclause (I); and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to disseminate research, data, and findings on studies on the countries of Eastern Europe and the independent states of the former Soviet Union and related fields in such a manner and to such extent as the respective institution determines will best serve to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> One part of the payments made in each fiscal year shall be used—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to provide fellowship and research support for American specialists in the independent states of the former Soviet Union and the countries of Eastern Europe and related fields to conduct advanced research with particular emphasis upon the use of data on those states and countries; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to conduct seminars, conferences, and other similar workshops designed to facilitate research collaboration between Government and private specialists in the independent states of the former Soviet Union and the countries of Eastern Europe and related fields.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> One part of the payments made in each fiscal year shall be used to conduct specialized programs in advanced training and research on a reciprocal basis in the independent states of the former Soviet Union and the countries of Eastern Europe designed to facilitate access for American specialists to research institutes, personnel, archives, documentation, and other research and training resources located in those states and countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> One part of the payments made in each fiscal year shall be used to support training in the languages of the independent states of the former Soviet Union and the countries of Eastern Europe. Such payments shall include grants to individuals to pursue such training and to summer language institutes operated by institutions of higher education. Preference shall be given for Russian language studies and, as appropriate, studies of other languages of the independent states of the former Soviet Union.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> Payments may be made to carry out other research and training in studies on the countries of Eastern Europe and the independent states of the former Soviet Union not otherwise described in this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–164, title VIII, § 805</ref>, <date date="1983-11-22">Nov. 22, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1048</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–199, title III, § 302(6)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-17">Dec. 17, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2323</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4505.</num>
<heading> Applications; payments to eligible institutions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> Any institution seeking funding under this chapter shall prepare and submit an application to the Secretary of State once each fiscal year. Each such application shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> provide a description of the purposes for which the payments will be used in accordance with <ref>section 4504 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide such fiscal control and such accounting procedures as may be necessary (A) to ensure a proper accounting of Federal funds paid under this chapter, and (B) to ensure the verification of the costs of the continuing education and research programs conducted under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Payments under this chapter may be made in installments, in advance, or by way of reimbursement, with necessary adjustments on account of overpayments and underpayments.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–164, title VIII, § 806</ref>, <date date="1983-11-22">Nov. 22, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1050</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4506.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 112–74, div. I, title VII, § 7034(n)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 1217</ref></heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4507.</num>
<heading> Federal control of education prohibited</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing contained in this chapter may be construed to authorize any department, agency, officer, or employee of the United States to exercise any direction, supervision, or control over the curriculum, program of instruction or research, administration, or personnel of any educational institution.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–164, title VIII, § 808</ref>, <date date="1983-11-22">Nov. 22, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1050</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4508.</num>
<heading> Allocation of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Of the funds authorized to be appropriated by section 102(1) of this Act—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> up to $5,000,000 for the fiscal year 1984 shall be available to carry out this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> $5,000,000 for the fiscal year 1985 shall be available only to carry out this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 98–164, title VIII, § 809</ref>, <date date="1983-11-22">Nov. 22, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 1050</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4509.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 102–138, title II, § 209</ref>, <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 694</ref></heading>
</section>
</chapter>