<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 1—</num>
<heading>ESTABLISHMENT, OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES, FUNCTIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1.</num>
<heading> Establishment</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The United States Patent and Trademark Office is established as an agency of the United States, within the Department of Commerce. In carrying out its functions, the United States Patent and Trademark Office shall be subject to the policy direction of the Secretary of Commerce, but otherwise shall retain responsibility for decisions regarding the management and administration of its operations and shall exercise independent control of its budget allocations and expenditures, personnel decisions and processes, procurements, and other administrative and management functions in accordance with this title and applicable provisions of law. Those operations designed to grant and issue patents and those operations which are designed to facilitate the registration of trademarks shall be treated as separate operating units within the Office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Offices</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The United States Patent and Trademark Office shall maintain its principal office in the metropolitan Washington, D.C., area, for the service of process and papers and for the purpose of carrying out its functions. The United States Patent and Trademark Office shall be deemed, for purposes of venue in civil actions, to be a resident of the district in which its principal office is located, except where jurisdiction is otherwise provided by law. The United States Patent and Trademark Office may establish satellite offices in such other places in the United States as it considers necessary and appropriate in the conduct of its business.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reference</inline>.—</heading>
<content>For purposes of this title, the United States Patent and Trademark Office shall also be referred to as the “Office” and the “Patent and Trademark Office”.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 792</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–596, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1949</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4711]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–572.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 2.</num>
<heading> Powers and duties</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The United States Patent and Trademark Office, subject to the policy direction of the Secretary of Commerce—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be responsible for the granting and issuing of patents and the registration of trademarks; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall be responsible for disseminating to the public information with respect to patents and trademarks.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Specific Powers</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Office—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall adopt and use a seal of the Office, which shall be judicially noticed and with which letters patent, certificates of trademark registrations, and papers issued by the Office shall be authenticated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> may establish regulations, not inconsistent with law, which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall govern the conduct of proceedings in the Office;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall be made in accordance with <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> shall facilitate and expedite the processing of patent applications, particularly those which can be filed, stored, processed, searched, and retrieved electronically, subject to the provisions of section 122 relating to the confidential status of applications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> may govern the recognition and conduct of agents, attorneys, or other persons representing applicants or other parties before the Office, and may require them, before being recognized as representatives of applicants or other persons, to show that they are of good moral character and reputation and are possessed of the necessary qualifications to render to applicants or other persons valuable service, advice, and assistance in the presentation or prosecution of their applications or other business before the Office;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> shall recognize the public interest in continuing to safeguard broad access to the United States patent system through the reduced fee structure for small entities under section 41(h)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> provide for the development of a performance-based process that includes quantitative and qualitative measures and standards for evaluating cost-effectiveness and is consistent with the principles of impartiality and competitiveness; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> may, subject to any conditions prescribed by the Director and at the request of the patent applicant, provide for prioritization of examination of applications for products, processes, or technologies that are important to the national economy or national competitiveness without recovering the aggregate extra cost of providing such prioritization, notwithstanding section 41 or any other provision of law;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> may acquire, construct, purchase, lease, hold, manage, operate, improve, alter, and renovate any real, personal, or mixed property, or any interest therein, as it considers necessary to carry out its functions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> may make such purchases, contracts for the construction, maintenance, or management and operation of facilities, and contracts for supplies or services, without regard to the provisions of subtitle I and chapter 33 of title 40, division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41, and the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 11301</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may enter into and perform such purchases and contracts for printing services, including the process of composition, platemaking, presswork, silk screen processes, binding, microform, and the products of such processes, as it considers necessary to carry out the functions of the Office, without regard to sections 501 through 517 and 1101 through 1123 of title 44;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> may use, with their consent, services, equipment, personnel, and facilities of other departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the Federal Government, on a reimbursable basis, and cooperate with such other departments, agencies, and instrumentalities in the establishment and use of services, equipment, and facilities of the Office;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> may, when the Director determines that it is practicable, efficient, and cost-effective to do so, use, with the consent of the United States and the agency, instrumentality, Patent and Trademark Office, or international organization concerned, the services, records, facilities, or personnel of any State or local government agency or instrumentality or foreign patent and trademark office or international organization to perform functions on its behalf;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> may retain and use all of its revenues and receipts, including revenues from the sale, lease, or disposal of any real, personal, or mixed property, or any interest therein, of the Office;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> shall advise the President, through the Secretary of Commerce, on national and certain international intellectual property policy issues;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> shall advise Federal departments and agencies on matters of intellectual property policy in the United States and intellectual property protection in other countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> shall provide guidance, as appropriate, with respect to proposals by agencies to assist foreign governments and international intergovernmental organizations on matters of intellectual property protection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> may conduct programs, studies, or exchanges of items or services regarding domestic and international intellectual property law and the effectiveness of intellectual property protection domestically and throughout the world, and the Office is authorized to expend funds to cover the subsistence expenses and travel-related expenses, including per diem, lodging costs, and transportation costs, of persons attending such programs who are not Federal employees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall advise the Secretary of Commerce on programs and studies relating to intellectual property policy that are conducted, or authorized to be conducted, cooperatively with foreign intellectual property offices and international intergovernmental organizations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> may conduct programs and studies described in subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in coordination with the Department of State, may conduct programs and studies cooperatively with foreign intellectual property offices and international intergovernmental organizations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, may authorize the transfer of not to exceed $100,000 in any year to the Department of State for the purpose of making special payments to international intergovernmental organizations for studies and programs for advancing international cooperation concerning patents, trademarks, and other matters.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Clarification of Specific Powers</inline>.—</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The special payments under subsection (b)(13)(B) shall be in addition to any other payments or contributions to international organizations described in subsection (b)(13)(B) and shall not be subject to any limitations imposed by law on the amounts of such other payments or contributions by the United States Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Nothing in subsection (b) shall derogate from the duties of the Secretary of State or from the duties of the United States Trade Representative as set forth in section 141 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<ref>19 U.S.C. 2171</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Nothing in subsection (b) shall derogate from the duties and functions of the Register of Copyrights or otherwise alter current authorities relating to copyright matters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> In exercising the Director’s powers under paragraphs (3) and (4)(A) of subsection (b), the Director shall consult with the Administrator of General Services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> In exercising the Director’s powers and duties under this section, the Director shall consult with the Register of Copyrights on all copyright and related matters.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Construction</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to nullify, void, cancel, or interrupt any pending request-for-proposal let or contract issued by the General Services Administration for the specific purpose of relocating or leasing space to the United States Patent and Trademark Office.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 792</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–596, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1949</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4712]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–572; <ref>Pub. L. 106–400, § 2</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 1675</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III, § 13206(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1904</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–178, § 4(g)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-15">Dec. 15, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2641</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3849</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–29</ref>, §§ 20(j), 21(a), 25, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 335</ref>, 337.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3.</num>
<heading> Officers and employees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Under Secretary and Director.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The powers and duties of the United States Patent and Trademark Office shall be vested in an Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office (in this title referred to as the “Director”), who shall be a citizen of the United States and who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Director shall be a person who has a professional background and experience in patent or trademark law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Duties.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director shall be responsible for providing policy direction and management supervision for the Office and for the issuance of patents and the registration of trademarks. The Director shall perform these duties in a fair, impartial, and equitable manner.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Consulting with the public advisory committees</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director shall consult with the Patent Public Advisory Committee established in section 5 on a regular basis on matters relating to the patent operations of the Office, shall consult with the Trademark Public Advisory Committee established in section 5 on a regular basis on matters relating to the trademark operations of the Office, and shall consult with the respective Public Advisory Committee before submitting budgetary proposals to the Office of Management and Budget or changing or proposing to change patent or trademark user fees or patent or trademark regulations which are subject to the requirement to provide notice and opportunity for public comment under <ref>section 553 of title 5</ref>, as the case may be.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Oath</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director shall, before taking office, take an oath to discharge faithfully the duties of the Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Removal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director may be removed from office by the President. The President shall provide notification of any such removal to both Houses of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Officers and Employees of the Office.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Deputy under secretary and deputy director</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Commerce, upon nomination by the Director, shall appoint a Deputy Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Deputy Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office who shall be vested with the authority to act in the capacity of the Director in the event of the absence or incapacity of the Director. The Deputy Director shall be a citizen of the United States who has a professional background and experience in patent or trademark law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Commissioners.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment and duties</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Commerce shall appoint a Commissioner for Patents and a Commissioner for Trademarks, without regard to chapter 33, 51, or 53 of title 5. The Commissioner for Patents shall be a citizen of the United States with demonstrated management ability and professional background and experience in patent law and serve for a term of 5 years. The Commissioner for Trademarks shall be a citizen of the United States with demonstrated management ability and professional background and experience in trademark law and serve for a term of 5 years. The Commissioner for Patents and the Commissioner for Trademarks shall serve as the chief operating officers for the operations of the Office relating to patents and trademarks, respectively, and shall be responsible for the management and direction of all aspects of the activities of the Office that affect the administration of patent and trademark operations, respectively. The Secretary may reappoint a Commissioner to subsequent terms of 5 years as long as the performance of the Commissioner as set forth in the performance agreement in subparagraph (B) is satisfactory.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Salary and performance agreement</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commissioners shall be paid an annual rate of basic pay not to exceed the maximum rate of basic pay for the Senior Executive Service established under <ref>section 5382 of title 5</ref>, including any applicable locality-based comparability payment that may be authorized under <ref>section 5304(h)(2)(C) of title 5</ref>. The compensation of the Commissioners shall be considered, for purposes of <ref>section 207(c)(2)(A) of title 18</ref>, to be the equivalent of that described under clause (ii) of <ref>section 207(c)(2)(A) of title 18</ref>. In addition, the Commissioners may receive a bonus in an amount of up to, but not in excess of, 50 percent of the Commissioners’ annual rate of basic pay, based upon an evaluation by the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Director, of the Commissioners’ performance as defined in an annual performance agreement between the Commissioners and the Secretary. The annual performance agreements shall incorporate measurable organization and individual goals in key operational areas as delineated in an annual performance plan agreed to by the Commissioners and the Secretary. Payment of a bonus under this subparagraph may be made to the Commissioners only to the extent that such payment does not cause the Commissioners’ total aggregate compensation in a calendar year to equal or exceed the amount of the salary of the Vice President under <ref>section 104 of title 3</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Removal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Commissioners may be removed from office by the Secretary for misconduct or nonsatisfactory performance under the performance agreement described in subparagraph (B), without regard to the provisions of title 5. The Secretary shall provide notification of any such removal to both Houses of Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other officers and employees</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> appoint such officers, employees (including attorneys), and agents of the Office as the Director considers necessary to carry out the functions of the Office; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> define the title, authority, and duties of such officers and employees and delegate to them such of the powers vested in the Office as the Director may determine.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">The Office shall not be subject to any administratively or statutorily imposed limitation on positions or personnel, and no positions or personnel of the Office shall be taken into account for purposes of applying any such limitation.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Training of examiners</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Office shall submit to the Congress a proposal to provide an incentive program to retain as employees patent and trademark examiners of the primary examiner grade or higher who are eligible for retirement, for the sole purpose of training patent and trademark examiners.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">National security positions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, shall maintain a program for identifying national security positions and providing for appropriate security clearances, in order to maintain the secrecy of certain inventions, as described in section 181, and to prevent disclosure of sensitive and strategic information in the interest of national security.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Administrative patent judges and administrative trademark judges</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director may fix the rate of basic pay for the administrative patent judges appointed pursuant to section 6 and the administrative trademark judges appointed pursuant to section 17 of the Trademark Act of 1946 (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1067</ref>) at not greater than the rate of basic pay payable for level III of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5314 of title 5</ref>. The payment of a rate of basic pay under this paragraph shall not be subject to the pay limitation under section 5306(e) or 5373 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continued Applicability of Title</inline> 5.—</heading>
<content>Officers and employees of the Office shall be subject to the provisions of title 5, relating to Federal employees.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Adoption of Existing Labor Agreements</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Office shall adopt all labor agreements which are in effect, as of the day before the effective date of the Patent and Trademark Office Efficiency Act, with respect to such Office (as then in effect).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Carryover of Personnel.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">From pto</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Effective as of the effective date of the Patent and Trademark Office Efficiency Act, all officers and employees of the Patent and Trademark Office on the day before such effective date shall become officers and employees of the Office, without a break in service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Other personnel</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Any individual who, on the day before the effective date of the Patent and Trademark Office Efficiency Act, is an officer or employee of the Department of Commerce (other than an officer or employee under paragraph (1)) shall be transferred to the Office, as necessary to carry out the purposes of that Act, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such individual serves in a position for which a major function is the performance of work reimbursed by the Patent and Trademark Office, as determined by the Secretary of Commerce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such individual serves in a position that performed work in support of the Patent and Trademark Office during at least half of the incumbent’s work time, as determined by the Secretary of Commerce; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> such transfer would be in the interest of the Office, as determined by the Secretary of Commerce in consultation with the Director.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Any transfer under this paragraph shall be effective as of the same effective date as referred to in paragraph (1), and shall be made without a break in service.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Transition Provisions.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Interim appointment of director</inline>.—</heading>
<content>On or after the effective date of the Patent and Trademark Office Efficiency Act, the President shall appoint an individual to serve as the Director until the date on which a Director qualifies under subsection (a). The President shall not make more than one such appointment under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Continuation in office of certain officers</inline>.—</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The individual serving as the Assistant Commissioner for Patents on the day before the effective date of the Patent and Trademark Office Efficiency Act may serve as the Commissioner for Patents until the date on which a Commissioner for Patents is appointed under subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The individual serving as the Assistant Commissioner for Trademarks on the day before the effective date of the Patent and Trademark Office Efficiency Act may serve as the Commissioner for Trademarks until the date on which a Commissioner for Trademarks is appointed under subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 792</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–933, § 1</ref>, <date date="1958-09-06">Sept. 6, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1793</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–370, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1959-09-23">Sept. 23, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 650</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–426, title III, § 305(26)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-14">Aug. 14, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 425</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–596, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1949</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–601, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1956</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–247, § 4</ref>, <date date="1982-08-27">Aug. 27, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 319</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–366, § 4</ref>, <date date="1982-10-25">Oct. 25, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1760</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–622, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3392</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–304, title IV, § 401(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-28">Oct. 28, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2887</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–44, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1999-08-05">Aug. 5, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 223</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4713]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–575; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III, § 13206(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1904</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–29</ref>, §§ 20(i)(1), 21(b), <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 334</ref>, 336.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4.</num>
<heading> Restrictions on officers and employees as to interest in patents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Officers and employees of the Patent and Trademark Office shall be incapable, during the period of their appointments and for one year thereafter, of applying for a patent and of acquiring, directly or indirectly, except by inheritance or bequest, any patent or any right or interest in any patent, issued or to be issued by the Office. In patents applied for thereafter they shall not be entitled to any priority date earlier than one year after the termination of their appointment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 793</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–596, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1949</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 5.</num>
<heading> Patent and Trademark Office Public Advisory Committees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Public Advisory Committees.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Appointment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The United States Patent and Trademark Office shall have a Patent Public Advisory Committee and a Trademark Public Advisory Committee, each of which shall have nine voting members who shall be appointed by the Secretary of Commerce and serve at the pleasure of the Secretary of Commerce. In each year, 3 members shall be appointed to each Advisory Committee for 3-year terms that shall begin on December 1 of that year. Any vacancy on an Advisory Committee shall be filled within 90 days after it occurs. A new member who is appointed to fill a vacancy shall be appointed to serve for the remainder of the predecessor’s term.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Chair</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Director, shall designate a Chair and Vice Chair of each Advisory Committee from among the members appointed under paragraph (1). If the Chair resigns before the completion of his or her term, or is otherwise unable to exercise the functions of the Chair, the Vice Chair shall exercise the functions of the Chair.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Basis for Appointments</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Members of each Advisory Committee—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall be citizens of the United States who shall be chosen so as to represent the interests of diverse users of the United States Patent and Trademark Office with respect to patents, in the case of the Patent Public Advisory Committee, and with respect to trademarks, in the case of the Trademark Public Advisory Committee;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall include members who represent small and large entity applicants located in the United States in proportion to the number of applications filed by such applicants, but in no case shall members who represent small entity patent applicants, including small business concerns, independent inventors, and nonprofit organizations, constitute less than 25 percent of the members of the Patent Public Advisory Committee, and such members shall include at least one independent inventor; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> shall include individuals with substantial background and achievement in finance, management, labor relations, science, technology, and office automation.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">In addition to the voting members, each Advisory Committee shall include a representative of each labor organization recognized by the United States Patent and Trademark Office. Such representatives shall be nonvoting members of the Advisory Committee to which they are appointed.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Meetings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each Advisory Committee shall meet at the call of the chair to consider an agenda set by the chair.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Each Advisory Committee shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> review the policies, goals, performance, budget, and user fees of the United States Patent and Trademark Office with respect to patents, in the case of the Patent Public Advisory Committee, and with respect to Trademarks, in the case of the Trademark Public Advisory Committee, and advise the Director on these matters;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> within 60 days after the end of each fiscal year—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> prepare an annual report on the matters referred to in paragraph (1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> transmit the report to the Secretary of Commerce, the President, and the Committees on the Judiciary of the Senate and the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> publish the report in the Official Gazette of the United States Patent and Trademark Office.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Compensation</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each member of each Advisory Committee shall be compensated for each day (including travel time) during which such member is attending meetings or conferences of that Advisory Committee or otherwise engaged in the business of that Advisory Committee, at the rate which is the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay in effect for level III of the Executive Schedule under <ref>section 5314 of title 5</ref>. While away from such member’s home or regular place of business such member shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by <ref>section 5703 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Access to Information</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Members of each Advisory Committee shall be provided access to records and information in the United States Patent and Trademark Office, except for personnel or other privileged information and information concerning patent applications required to be kept in confidence by section 122.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Certain Ethics Laws</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Members of each Advisory Committee shall be special Government employees within the meaning of <ref>section 202 of title 18</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability of Chapter </inline>10<inline class="small-caps"> of Title </inline>5.—</heading>
<content>Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to each Advisory Committee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Open Meetings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The meetings of each Advisory Committee shall be open to the public, except that each Advisory Committee may by majority vote meet in executive session when considering personnel, privileged, or other confidential information.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(j)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability of Patent Prohibition</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Section 4 shall not apply to voting members of the Advisory Committees.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4714]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–578; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III</ref>, §§ 13203(b), 13206(a)(3), <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1902</ref>, 1904; <ref>Pub. L. 112–274, § 1</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1), <date date="2013-01-14">Jan. 14, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2458</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(215)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 4329</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6.</num>
<heading> Patent Trial and Appeal Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>There shall be in the Office a Patent Trial and Appeal Board. The Director, the Deputy Director, the Commissioner for Patents, the Commissioner for Trademarks, and the administrative patent judges shall constitute the Patent Trial and Appeal Board. The administrative patent judges shall be persons of competent legal knowledge and scientific ability who are appointed by the Secretary, in consultation with the Director. Any reference in any Federal law, Executive order, rule, regulation, or delegation of authority, or any document of or pertaining to the Board of Patent Appeals and Interferences is deemed to refer to the Patent Trial and Appeal Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Patent Trial and Appeal Board shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> on written appeal of an applicant, review adverse decisions of examiners upon applications for patents pursuant to section 134(a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> review appeals of reexaminations pursuant to section 134(b);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> conduct derivation proceedings pursuant to section 135; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> conduct inter partes reviews and post-grant reviews pursuant to chapters 31 and 32.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading> 3-<inline class="small-caps">Member Panels</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Each appeal, derivation proceeding, post-grant review, and inter partes review shall be heard by at least 3 members of the Patent Trial and Appeal Board, who shall be designated by the Director. Only the Patent Trial and Appeal Board may grant rehearings.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Prior Appointments</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Secretary of Commerce may, in the Secretary’s discretion, deem the appointment of an administrative patent judge who, before the date of the enactment of this subsection, held office pursuant to an appointment by the Director to take effect on the date on which the Director initially appointed the administrative patent judge. It shall be a defense to a challenge to the appointment of an administrative patent judge on the basis of the judge’s having been originally appointed by the Director that the administrative patent judge so appointed was acting as a de facto officer.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4717(2)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–580; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III, § 13203(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1902</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–313, § 1(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-08-12">Aug. 12, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3014</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–29, § 7(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 313</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7.</num>
<heading> Library</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall maintain a library of scientific and other works and periodicals, both foreign and domestic, in the Patent and Trademark Office to aid the officers in the discharge of their duties.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 793</ref>, § 8; <ref>Pub. L. 93–596, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1949</ref>; renumbered § 7 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, §§ 4717(1), 4732(a)(10)(A)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–580, 1501A–582; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III, § 13206(b)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1906</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8.</num>
<heading> Classification of patents</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director may revise and maintain the classification by subject matter of United States letters patent, and such other patents and printed publications as may be necessary or practicable, for the purpose of determining with readiness and accuracy the novelty of inventions for which applications for patent are filed.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 794</ref>, § 9; renumbered § 8 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, §§ 4717(1), 4732(a)(10)(A)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–580, 1501A–582; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III, § 13206(b)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1906</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9.</num>
<heading> Certified copies of records</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director may furnish certified copies of specifications and drawings of patents issued by the Patent and Trademark Office, and of other records available either to the public or to the person applying therefor.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 794</ref>, § 10; <ref>Pub. L. 93–596, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1949</ref>; renumbered § 9 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, §§ 4717(1), 4732(a)(10)(A)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–580, 1501A–582; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III, § 13206(b)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1906</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 10.</num>
<heading> Publications</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Director may publish in printed, typewritten, or electronic form, the following:<p class="indent0" role="listItem">1. Patents and published applications for patents, including specifications and drawings, together with copies of the same. The Patent and Trademark Office may print the headings of the drawings for patents for the purpose of photolithography.</p>
<p class="indent0" role="listItem">2. Certificates of trade-mark registrations, including statements and drawings, together with copies of the same.</p>
<p class="indent0">3. The Official Gazette of the United States Patent and Trademark Office.</p>
<p class="indent0">4. Annual indexes of patents and patentees, and of trade-marks and registrants.</p>
<p class="indent0">5. Annual volumes of decisions in patent and trade-mark cases.</p>
<p class="indent0">6. Pamphlet copies of the patent laws and rules of practice, laws and rules relating to trade-marks, and circulars or other publications relating to the business of the Office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Director may exchange any of the publications specified in items 3, 4, 5, and 6 of subsection (a) of this section for publications desirable for the use of the Patent and Trademark Office.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 794</ref>, § 11; <ref>Pub. L. 93–596, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1949</ref>; renumbered § 10 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, §§ 4507(1), 4717(1), 4732(a)(10)(A), 4804(b)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–565, 1501A–580, 1501A–582, 1501A–589; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III</ref>, §§ 13205(2)(A), 13206(b)(1)(B), (3)(A), <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1903</ref>, 1906.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 11.</num>
<heading> Exchange of copies of patents and applications with foreign countries</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director may exchange copies of specifications and drawings of United States patents and published applications for patents for those of foreign countries. The Director shall not enter into an agreement to provide such copies of specifications and drawings of United States patents and applications to a foreign country, other than a USMCA country or a WTO member country, without the express authorization of the Secretary of Commerce.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term “USMCA country” has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement Implementation Act (<ref>19 U.S.C. 4502</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term “WTO member country” has the meaning given that term in section 2(10) of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act (<ref>19 U.S.C. 3501(10)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 794</ref>, § 12; renumbered § 11 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, §§ 4507(2), 4717(1), 4732(a)(10)(A), 4808]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–565, 1501A–580, 1501A–582, 1501A–591; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III</ref>, §§ 13205(2)(B), 13206(b)(1)(B), <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1903</ref>, 1906; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. O, title VI, § 602(d)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 2153</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 12.</num>
<heading> Copies of patents and applications for public libraries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director may supply copies of specifications and drawings of patents and published applications for patents in printed or electronic form to public libraries in the United States which shall maintain such copies for the use of the public, at the rate for each year’s issue established for this purpose in section 41(d).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 794</ref>, § 13; <ref>Pub. L. 97–247, § 15</ref>, <date date="1982-08-27">Aug. 27, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 321</ref>; renumbered § 12 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, §§ 4507(3), 4717(1), 4732(a)(10)(A), 4804(c)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–565, 1501A–580, 1501A–582, 1501A–589; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III</ref>, §§ 13205(2)(C), 13206(b)(1)(B), (3)(B), <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1903</ref>, 1906; <ref>Pub. L. 112–29, § 20(j)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 335</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 13.</num>
<heading> Annual report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Director shall report to the Congress, not later than 180 days after the end of each fiscal year, the moneys received and expended by the Office, the purposes for which the moneys were spent, the quality and quantity of the work of the Office, the nature of training provided to examiners, the evaluation of the Commissioner of Patents and the Commissioner of Trademarks by the Secretary of Commerce, the compensation of the Commissioners, and other information relating to the Office.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 794</ref>, § 14; renumbered § 13 and amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, §§ 4717(1), 4718]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–580, 1501A–581.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 14.</num>
<heading> Renumbered § 13]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>