<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 36—</num>
<heading>INTERNATIONAL STAGE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 361.</num>
<heading> Receiving Office</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Patent and Trademark Office shall act as a Receiving Office for international applications filed by nationals or residents of the United States. In accordance with any agreement made between the United States and another country, the Patent and Trademark Office may also act as a Receiving Office for international applications filed by residents or nationals of such country who are entitled to file international applications.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The Patent and Trademark Office shall perform all acts connected with the discharge of duties required of a Receiving Office, including the collection of international fees and their transmittal to the International Bureau.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> International applications filed in the Patent and Trademark Office shall be filed in the English language, or an English translation shall be filed within such later time as may be fixed by the Director.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The international fee, and the transmittal and search fees prescribed under section 376(a) of this part, shall either be paid on filing of an international application or within such later time as may be fixed by the Director.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–131, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-11-14">Nov. 14, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 686</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–622, title IV</ref>, §§ 401(a), 403(a), <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3391</ref>, 3392; <ref>Pub. L. 99–616, § 2(d)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-06">Nov. 6, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3485</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4732(a)(10)(A)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–582; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III, § 13206(b)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1906</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–211, title II, § 202(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-18">Dec. 18, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1536</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 362.</num>
<heading> International Searching Authority and International Preliminary Examining Authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> The Patent and Trademark Office may act as an International Searching Authority and International Preliminary Examining Authority with respect to international applications in accordance with the terms and conditions of an agreement which may be concluded with the International Bureau, and may discharge all duties required of such Authorities, including the collection of handling fees and their transmittal to the International Bureau.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The handling fee, preliminary examination fee, and any additional fees due for international preliminary examination shall be paid within such time as may be fixed by the Director.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–131, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-11-14">Nov. 14, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 686</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–622, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3392</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–616, § 4</ref>, <date date="1986-11-06">Nov. 6, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3485</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4732(a)(10)(A)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–582; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III, § 13206(b)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1906</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 363.</num>
<heading> International application designating the United States: Effect</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">An international application designating the United States shall have the effect, from its international filing date under article 11 of the treaty, of a national application for patent regularly filed in the Patent and Trademark Office.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–131, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-11-14">Nov. 14, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 686</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–622, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3392</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–29</ref>, §§ 3(g)(3), 20(j), <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 288</ref>, 335.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 364.</num>
<heading> International stage: Procedure</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> International applications shall be processed by the Patent and Trademark Office when acting as a Receiving Office, International Searching Authority, or International Preliminary Examining Authority, in accordance with the applicable provisions of the treaty, the Regulations, and this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> An applicant’s failure to act within prescribed time limits in connection with requirements pertaining to an international application may be excused as provided in the treaty and the Regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–131, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-11-14">Nov. 14, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 686</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–622, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3392</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–616, § 5</ref>, <date date="1986-11-06">Nov. 6, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3485</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4732(a)(10)(A)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–582; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III, § 13206(b)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1906</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–211, title II, § 202(b)(8)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-18">Dec. 18, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1536</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 365.</num>
<heading> Right of priority; benefit of the filing date of a prior application</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> In accordance with the conditions and requirements of subsections (a) through (d) of section 119, a national application shall be entitled to the right of priority based on a prior filed international application which designated at least one country other than the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In accordance with the conditions and requirement of section 119(a) and the treaty and the Regulations, an international application designating the United States shall be entitled to the right of priority based on a prior foreign application, or a prior international application designating at least one country other than the United States. The Director may establish procedures, including the requirement for payment of the fee specified in section 41(a)(7), to accept an unintentionally delayed claim for priority under the treaty and the Regulations, and to accept a priority claim that pertains to an application that was not filed within the priority period specified in the treaty and Regulations, but was filed within the additional 2-month period specified under section 119(a) or the treaty and Regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> In accordance with the conditions and requirements of section 120, an international application designating the United States shall be entitled to the benefit of the filing date of a prior national application, a prior international application designating the United States, or a prior international design application as defined in section 381(a)(6) designating the United States, and a national application shall be entitled to the benefit of the filing date of a prior international application designating the United States. If any claim for the benefit of an earlier filing date is based on a prior international application which designated but did not originate in the United States or a prior international design application as defined in section 381(a)(6) which designated but did not originate in the United States, the Director may require the filing in the Patent and Trademark Office of a certified copy of such application together with a translation thereof into the English language, if it was filed in another language.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–131, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-11-14">Nov. 14, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 686</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–622, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3392</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title V, § 532(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4987</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4732(a)(10)(A)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–582; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III, § 13206(b)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1906</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–29, § 20(j)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 335</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–211, title I, § 102(8)</ref>, title II, § 201(c)(2), <date date="2012-12-18">Dec. 18, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1532</ref>, 1535.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 366.</num>
<heading> Withdrawn international application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to section 367 of this part, if an international application designating the United States is withdrawn or considered withdrawn, either generally or as to the United States, under the conditions of the treaty and the Regulations, before the applicant has complied with the applicable requirements prescribed by section 371(c) of this part, the designation of the United States shall have no effect after the date of withdrawal, and shall be considered as not having been made, unless a claim for benefit of a prior filing date under section 365(c) of this section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002013">1</ref> was made in a national application, or an international application designating the United States, or a claim for benefit under section 386(c) was made in an international design application designating the United States, filed before the date of such withdrawal. However, such withdrawn international application may serve as the basis for a claim of priority under section 365(a) and (b), or under section 386(a) or (b), if it designated a country other than the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–131, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-11-14">Nov. 14, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 687</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–622, title IV, § 401(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3391</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–211, title I, § 102(9)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-18">Dec. 18, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1532</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 367.</num>
<heading> Actions of other authorities: Review</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Where a Receiving Office other than the Patent and Trademark Office has refused to accord an international filing date to an international application designating the United States or where it has held such application to be withdrawn either generally or as to the United States, the applicant may request review of the matter by the Director, on compliance with the requirements of and within the time limits specified by the treaty and the Regulations. Such review may result in a determination that such application be considered as pending in the national stage.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The review under subsection (a) of this section, subject to the same requirements and conditions, may also be requested in those instances where an international application designating the United States is considered withdrawn due to a finding by the International Bureau under article 12(3) of the treaty.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–131, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-11-14">Nov. 14, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 687</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–622, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3392</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4732(a)(10)(A)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–582; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III, § 13206(b)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1906</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 368.</num>
<heading> Secrecy of certain inventions; filing international applications in foreign countries</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> International applications filed in the Patent and Trademark Office shall be subject to the provisions of chapter 17.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> In accordance with article 27(8) of the treaty, the filing of an international application in a country other than the United States on the invention made in this country shall be considered to constitute the filing of an application in a foreign country within the meaning of chapter 17, whether or not the United States is designated in that international application.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<content> If a license to file in a foreign country is refused or if an international application is ordered to be kept secret and a permit refused, the Patent and Trademark Office when acting as a Receiving Office, International Searching Authority, or International Preliminary Examining Authority, may not disclose the contents of such application to anyone not authorized to receive such disclosure.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–131, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-11-14">Nov. 14, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 687</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–622, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3392</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–616, § 6</ref>, <date date="1986-11-06">Nov. 6, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3486</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–29, § 20(j)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 335</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>