<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 32—</num>
<heading>POST-GRANT REVIEW</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 321.</num>
<heading> Post-grant review</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the provisions of this chapter, a person who is not the owner of a patent may file with the Office a petition to institute a post-grant review of the patent. The Director shall establish, by regulation, fees to be paid by the person requesting the review, in such amounts as the Director determines to be reasonable, considering the aggregate costs of the post-grant review.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scope</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A petitioner in a post-grant review may request to cancel as unpatentable 1 or more claims of a patent on any ground that could be raised under paragraph (2) or (3) of section 282(b) (relating to invalidity of the patent or any claim).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Filing Deadline</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A petition for a post-grant review may only be filed not later than the date that is 9 months after the date of the grant of the patent or of the issuance of a reissue patent (as the case may be).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–29, § 6(d)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 306</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 322.</num>
<heading> Petitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Requirements of Petition</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>A petition filed under section 321 may be considered only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the petition is accompanied by payment of the fee established by the Director under section 321;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the petition identifies all real parties in interest;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> the petition identifies, in writing and with particularity, each claim challenged, the grounds on which the challenge to each claim is based, and the evidence that supports the grounds for the challenge to each claim, including—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> copies of patents and printed publications that the petitioner relies upon in support of the petition; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> affidavits or declarations of supporting evidence and opinions, if the petitioner relies on other factual evidence or on expert opinions;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the petition provides such other information as the Director may require by regulation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the petitioner provides copies of any of the documents required under paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) to the patent owner or, if applicable, the designated representative of the patent owner.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Public Availability</inline>.—</heading>
<content>As soon as practicable after the receipt of a petition under section 321, the Director shall make the petition available to the public.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–29, § 6(d)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 306</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 323.</num>
<heading> Preliminary response to petition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a post-grant review petition is filed under section 321, the patent owner shall have the right to file a preliminary response to the petition, within a time period set by the Director, that sets forth reasons why no post-grant review should be instituted based upon the failure of the petition to meet any requirement of this chapter.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–29, § 6(d)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 306</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 324.</num>
<heading> Institution of post-grant review</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Threshold</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director may not authorize a post-grant review to be instituted unless the Director determines that the information presented in the petition filed under section 321, if such information is not rebutted, would demonstrate that it is more likely than not that at least 1 of the claims challenged in the petition is unpatentable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional Grounds</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The determination required under subsection (a) may also be satisfied by a showing that the petition raises a novel or unsettled legal question that is important to other patents or patent applications.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Timing</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director shall determine whether to institute a post-grant review under this chapter pursuant to a petition filed under section 321 within 3 months after—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> receiving a preliminary response to the petition under section 323; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if no such preliminary response is filed, the last date on which such response may be filed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Notice</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director shall notify the petitioner and patent owner, in writing, of the Director’s determination under subsection (a) or (b), and shall make such notice available to the public as soon as is practicable. Such notice shall include the date on which the review shall commence.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">No Appeal</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The determination by the Director whether to institute a post-grant review under this section shall be final and nonappealable.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–29, § 6(d)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 306</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 325.</num>
<heading> Relation to other proceedings or actions</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Infringer’s Civil Action.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Post-grant review barred by civil action</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A post-grant review may not be instituted under this chapter if, before the date on which the petition for such a review is filed, the petitioner or real party in interest filed a civil action challenging the validity of a claim of the patent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Stay of civil action</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>If the petitioner or real party in interest files a civil action challenging the validity of a claim of the patent on or after the date on which the petitioner files a petition for post-grant review of the patent, that civil action shall be automatically stayed until either—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the patent owner moves the court to lift the stay;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the patent owner files a civil action or counterclaim alleging that the petitioner or real party in interest has infringed the patent; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the petitioner or real party in interest moves the court to dismiss the civil action.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Treatment of counterclaim</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A counterclaim challenging the validity of a claim of a patent does not constitute a civil action challenging the validity of a claim of a patent for purposes of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Preliminary Injunctions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a civil action alleging infringement of a patent is filed within 3 months after the date on which the patent is granted, the court may not stay its consideration of the patent owner’s motion for a preliminary injunction against infringement of the patent on the basis that a petition for post-grant review has been filed under this chapter or that such a post-grant review has been instituted under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Joinder</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If more than 1 petition for a post-grant review under this chapter is properly filed against the same patent and the Director determines that more than 1 of these petitions warrants the institution of a post-grant review under section 324, the Director may consolidate such reviews into a single post-grant review.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Multiple Proceedings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Notwithstanding sections 135(a), 251, and 252, and chapter 30, during the pendency of any post-grant review under this chapter, if another proceeding or matter involving the patent is before the Office, the Director may determine the manner in which the post-grant review or other proceeding or matter may proceed, including providing for the stay, transfer, consolidation, or termination of any such matter or proceeding. In determining whether to institute or order a proceeding under this chapter, chapter 30, or chapter 31, the Director may take into account whether, and reject the petition or request because, the same or substantially the same prior art or arguments previously were presented to the Office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Estoppel.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Proceedings before the office</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The petitioner in a post-grant review of a claim in a patent under this chapter that results in a final written decision under section 328(a), or the real party in interest or privy of the petitioner, may not request or maintain a proceeding before the Office with respect to that claim on any ground that the petitioner raised or reasonably could have raised during that post-grant review.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Civil actions and other proceedings</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The petitioner in a post-grant review of a claim in a patent under this chapter that results in a final written decision under section 328(a), or the real party in interest or privy of the petitioner, may not assert either in a civil action arising in whole or in part under <ref>section 1338 of title 28</ref> or in a proceeding before the International Trade Commission under section 337 of the Tariff Act of 1930 that the claim is invalid on any ground that the petitioner raised or reasonably could have raised during that post-grant review.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Reissue Patents</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A post-grant review may not be instituted under this chapter if the petition requests cancellation of a claim in a reissue patent that is identical to or narrower than a claim in the original patent from which the reissue patent was issued, and the time limitations in section 321(c) would bar filing a petition for a post-grant review for such original patent.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–29, § 6(d)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 307</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 326.</num>
<heading> Conduct of post-grant review</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The Director shall prescribe regulations—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> providing that the file of any proceeding under this chapter shall be made available to the public, except that any petition or document filed with the intent that it be sealed shall, if accompanied by a motion to seal, be treated as sealed pending the outcome of the ruling on the motion;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> setting forth the standards for the showing of sufficient grounds to institute a review under subsections (a) and (b) of section 324;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> establishing procedures for the submission of supplemental information after the petition is filed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> establishing and governing a post-grant review under this chapter and the relationship of such review to other proceedings under this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> setting forth standards and procedures for discovery of relevant evidence, including that such discovery shall be limited to evidence directly related to factual assertions advanced by either party in the proceeding;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> prescribing sanctions for abuse of discovery, abuse of process, or any other improper use of the proceeding, such as to harass or to cause unnecessary delay or an unnecessary increase in the cost of the proceeding;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> providing for protective orders governing the exchange and submission of confidential information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> providing for the filing by the patent owner of a response to the petition under section 323 after a post-grant review has been instituted, and requiring that the patent owner file with such response, through affidavits or declarations, any additional factual evidence and expert opinions on which the patent owner relies in support of the response;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> setting forth standards and procedures for allowing the patent owner to move to amend the patent under subsection (d) to cancel a challenged claim or propose a reasonable number of substitute claims, and ensuring that any information submitted by the patent owner in support of any amendment entered under subsection (d) is made available to the public as part of the prosecution history of the patent;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> providing either party with the right to an oral hearing as part of the proceeding;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> requiring that the final determination in any post-grant review be issued not later than 1 year after the date on which the Director notices the institution of a proceeding under this chapter, except that the Director may, for good cause shown, extend the 1-year period by not more than 6 months, and may adjust the time periods in this paragraph in the case of joinder under section 325(c); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<content> providing the petitioner with at least 1 opportunity to file written comments within a time period established by the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Considerations</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In prescribing regulations under this section, the Director shall consider the effect of any such regulation on the economy, the integrity of the patent system, the efficient administration of the Office, and the ability of the Office to timely complete proceedings instituted under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Patent Trial and Appeal Board</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Patent Trial and Appeal Board shall, in accordance with section 6, conduct each post-grant review instituted under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Amendment of the Patent.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>During a post-grant review instituted under this chapter, the patent owner may file 1 motion to amend the patent in 1 or more of the following ways:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Cancel any challenged patent claim.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> For each challenged claim, propose a reasonable number of substitute claims.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Additional motions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Additional motions to amend may be permitted upon the joint request of the petitioner and the patent owner to materially advance the settlement of a proceeding under section 327, or upon the request of the patent owner for good cause shown.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Scope of claims</inline>.—</heading>
<content>An amendment under this subsection may not enlarge the scope of the claims of the patent or introduce new matter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Evidentiary Standards</inline>.—</heading>
<content>In a post-grant review instituted under this chapter, the petitioner shall have the burden of proving a proposition of unpatentability by a preponderance of the evidence.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–29, § 6(d)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 308</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 327.</num>
<heading> Settlement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A post-grant review instituted under this chapter shall be terminated with respect to any petitioner upon the joint request of the petitioner and the patent owner, unless the Office has decided the merits of the proceeding before the request for termination is filed. If the post-grant review is terminated with respect to a petitioner under this section, no estoppel under section 325(e) shall attach to the petitioner, or to the real party in interest or privy of the petitioner, on the basis of that petitioner’s institution of that post-grant review. If no petitioner remains in the post-grant review, the Office may terminate the post-grant review or proceed to a final written decision under section 328(a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Agreements in Writing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any agreement or understanding between the patent owner and a petitioner, including any collateral agreements referred to in such agreement or understanding, made in connection with, or in contemplation of, the termination of a post-grant review under this section shall be in writing, and a true copy of such agreement or understanding shall be filed in the Office before the termination of the post-grant review as between the parties. At the request of a party to the proceeding, the agreement or understanding shall be treated as business confidential information, shall be kept separate from the file of the involved patents, and shall be made available only to Federal Government agencies on written request, or to any person on a showing of good cause.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–29, § 6(d)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 310</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 328.</num>
<heading> Decision of the Board</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Final Written Decision</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If a post-grant review is instituted and not dismissed under this chapter, the Patent Trial and Appeal Board shall issue a final written decision with respect to the patentability of any patent claim challenged by the petitioner and any new claim added under section 326(d).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Certificate</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If the Patent Trial and Appeal Board issues a final written decision under subsection (a) and the time for appeal has expired or any appeal has terminated, the Director shall issue and publish a certificate canceling any claim of the patent finally determined to be unpatentable, confirming any claim of the patent determined to be patentable, and incorporating in the patent by operation of the certificate any new or amended claim determined to be patentable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Intervening Rights</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Any proposed amended or new claim determined to be patentable and incorporated into a patent following a post-grant review under this chapter shall have the same effect as that specified in section 252 for reissued patents on the right of any person who made, purchased, or used within the United States, or imported into the United States, anything patented by such proposed amended or new claim, or who made substantial preparation therefor, before the issuance of a certificate under subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Data on Length of Review</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Office shall make available to the public data describing the length of time between the institution of, and the issuance of a final written decision under subsection (a) for, each post-grant review.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added and amended <ref>Pub. L. 112–29</ref>, §§ 6(d), 20(j), <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 310</ref>, 335.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 329.</num>
<heading> Appeal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A party dissatisfied with the final written decision of the Patent Trial and Appeal Board under section 328(a) may appeal the decision pursuant to sections 141 through 144. Any party to the post-grant review shall have the right to be a party to the appeal.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–29, § 6(d)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 311</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>