<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 14—</num>
<heading>ISSUE OF PATENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 151.</num>
<heading> Issue of patent</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading>
<content>If it appears that an applicant is entitled to a patent under the law, a written notice of allowance of the application shall be given or mailed to the applicant. The notice shall specify a sum, constituting the issue fee and any required publication fee, which shall be paid within 3 months thereafter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effect of Payment</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Upon payment of this sum the patent may issue, but if payment is not timely made, the application shall be regarded as abandoned.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–211, title II, § 202(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-18">Dec. 18, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1536</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 152.</num>
<heading> Issue of patent to assignee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Patents may be granted to the assignee of the inventor of record in the Patent and Trademark Office, upon the application made and the specification sworn to by the inventor, except as otherwise provided in this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 804</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–596, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1949</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 153.</num>
<heading> How issued</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Patents shall be issued in the name of the United States of America, under the seal of the Patent and Trademark Office, and shall be signed by the Director or have his signature placed thereon and shall be recorded in the Patent and Trademark Office.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 804</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–596, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1949</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4732(a)(10)(A)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–582; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III</ref>, §§ 13203(c), 13206(b)(1)(B), <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1902</ref>, 1906.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 154.</num>
<heading> Contents and term of patent; provisional rights</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">In General.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Every patent shall contain a short title of the invention and a grant to the patentee, his heirs or assigns, of the right to exclude others from making, using, offering for sale, or selling the invention throughout the United States or importing the invention into the United States, and, if the invention is a process, of the right to exclude others from using, offering for sale or selling throughout the United States, or importing into the United States, products made by that process, referring to the specification for the particulars thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Term</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Subject to the payment of fees under this title, such grant shall be for a term beginning on the date on which the patent issues and ending 20 years from the date on which the application for the patent was filed in the United States or, if the application contains a specific reference to an earlier filed application or applications under section 120, 121, 365(c), or 386(c), from the date on which the earliest such application was filed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Priority</inline>.—</heading>
<content>Priority under section 119, 365(a), 365(b), 386(a), or 386(b) shall not be taken into account in determining the term of a patent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Specification and drawing</inline>.—</heading>
<content>A copy of the specification and drawing shall be annexed to the patent and be a part of such patent.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Adjustment of Patent Term.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Patent term guarantees.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guarantee of prompt patent and trademark office responses</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to the limitations under paragraph (2), if the issue of an original patent is delayed due to the failure of the Patent and Trademark Office to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> provide at least one of the notifications under section 132 or a notice of allowance under section 151 not later than 14 months after—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the date on which an application was filed under section 111(a); or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the date of commencement of the national stage under section 371 in an international application;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> respond to a reply under section 132, or to an appeal taken under section 134, within 4 months after the date on which the reply was filed or the appeal was taken;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> act on an application within 4 months after the date of a decision by the Patent Trial and Appeal Board under section 134 or 135 or a decision by a Federal court under section 141, 145, or 146 in a case in which allowable claims remain in the application; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> issue a patent within 4 months after the date on which the issue fee was paid under section 151 and all outstanding requirements were satisfied,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">the term of the patent shall be extended 1 day for each day after the end of the period specified in clause (i), (ii), (iii), or (iv), as the case may be, until the action described in such clause is taken.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guarantee of no more than 3-year application pendency</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to the limitations under paragraph (2), if the issue of an original patent is delayed due to the failure of the United States Patent and Trademark Office to issue a patent within 3 years after the actual filing date of the application under section 111(a) in the United States or, in the case of an international application, the date of commencement of the national stage under section 371 in the international application, not including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any time consumed by continued examination of the application requested by the applicant under section 132(b);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any time consumed by a proceeding under section 135(a), any time consumed by the imposition of an order under section 181, or any time consumed by appellate review by the Patent Trial and Appeal Board or by a Federal court; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any delay in the processing of the application by the United States Patent and Trademark Office requested by the applicant except as permitted by paragraph (3)(C),</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">the term of the patent shall be extended 1 day for each day after the end of that 3-year period until the patent is issued.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Guarantee of adjustments for delays due to derivation proceedings, secrecy orders, and appeals</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>Subject to the limitations under paragraph (2), if the issue of an original patent is delayed due to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a proceeding under section 135(a);</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the imposition of an order under section 181; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> appellate review by the Patent Trial and Appeal Board or by a Federal court in a case in which the patent was issued under a decision in the review reversing an adverse determination of patentability,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">the term of the patent shall be extended 1 day for each day of the pendency of the proceeding, order, or review, as the case may be.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Limitations.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<content>To the extent that periods of delay attributable to grounds specified in paragraph (1) overlap, the period of any adjustment granted under this subsection shall not exceed the actual number of days the issuance of the patent was delayed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Disclaimed term</inline>.—</heading>
<content>No patent the term of which has been disclaimed beyond a specified date may be adjusted under this section beyond the expiration date specified in the disclaimer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Reduction of period of adjustment.—</inline>
</heading>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The period of adjustment of the term of a patent under paragraph (1) shall be reduced by a period equal to the period of time during which the applicant failed to engage in reasonable efforts to conclude prosecution of the application.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> With respect to adjustments to patent term made under the authority of paragraph (1)(B), an applicant shall be deemed to have failed to engage in reasonable efforts to conclude processing or examination of an application for the cumulative total of any periods of time in excess of 3 months that are taken to respond to a notice from the Office making any rejection, objection, argument, or other request, measuring such 3-month period from the date the notice was given or mailed to the applicant.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The Director shall prescribe regulations establishing the circumstances that constitute a failure of an applicant to engage in reasonable efforts to conclude processing or examination of an application.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Procedures for patent term adjustment determination.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Director shall prescribe regulations establishing procedures for the application for and determination of patent term adjustments under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Under the procedures established under subparagraph (A), the Director shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> make a determination of the period of any patent term adjustment under this subsection, and shall transmit a notice of that determination no later than the date of issuance of the patent; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> provide the applicant one opportunity to request reconsideration of any patent term adjustment determination made by the Director.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Director shall reinstate all or part of the cumulative period of time of an adjustment under paragraph (2)(C) if the applicant, prior to the issuance of the patent, makes a showing that, in spite of all due care, the applicant was unable to respond within the 3-month period, but in no case shall more than three additional months for each such response beyond the original 3-month period be reinstated.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Director shall proceed to grant the patent after completion of the Director’s determination of a patent term adjustment under the procedures established under this subsection, notwithstanding any appeal taken by the applicant of such determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Appeal of patent term adjustment determination.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> An applicant dissatisfied with the Director’s decision on the applicant’s request for reconsideration under paragraph (3)(B)(ii) shall have exclusive remedy by a civil action against the Director filed in the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia within 180 days after the date of the Director’s decision on the applicant’s request for reconsideration. Chapter 7 of title 5 shall apply to such action. Any final judgment resulting in a change to the period of adjustment of the patent term shall be served on the Director, and the Director shall thereafter alter the term of the patent to reflect such change.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The determination of a patent term adjustment under this subsection shall not be subject to appeal or challenge by a third party prior to the grant of the patent.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Continuation.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Determination</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The term of a patent that is in force on or that results from an application filed before the date that is 6 months after the date of the enactment of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act shall be the greater of the 20-year term as provided in subsection (a), or 17 years from grant, subject to any terminal disclaimers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Remedies</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>The remedies of sections 283, 284, and 285 shall not apply to acts which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> were commenced or for which substantial investment was made before the date that is 6 months after the date of the enactment of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> became infringing by reason of paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Remuneration</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The acts referred to in paragraph (2) may be continued only upon the payment of an equitable remuneration to the patentee that is determined in an action brought under chapter 28 and chapter 29 (other than those provisions excluded by paragraph (2)).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Provisional Rights.—</inline>
</heading>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading>
<chapeau>In addition to other rights provided by this section, a patent shall include the right to obtain a reasonable royalty from any person who, during the period beginning on the date of publication of the application for such patent under section 122(b), or in the case of an international application filed under the treaty defined in section 351(a) designating the United States under Article 21(2)(a) of such treaty or an international design application filed under the treaty defined in section 381(a)(1) designating the United States under Article 5 of such treaty, the date of publication of the application, and ending on the date the patent is issued—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> makes, uses, offers for sale, or sells in the United States the invention as claimed in the published patent application or imports such an invention into the United States; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if the invention as claimed in the published patent application is a process, uses, offers for sale, or sells in the United States or imports into the United States products made by that process as claimed in the published patent application; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> had actual notice of the published patent application and, in a case in which the right arising under this paragraph is based upon an international application designating the United States that is published in a language other than English, had a translation of the international application into the English language.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Right based on substantially identical inventions</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The right under paragraph (1) to obtain a reasonable royalty shall not be available under this subsection unless the invention as claimed in the patent is substantially identical to the invention as claimed in the published patent application.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Time limitation on obtaining a reasonable royalty</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The right under paragraph (1) to obtain a reasonable royalty shall be available only in an action brought not later than 6 years after the patent is issued. The right under paragraph (1) to obtain a reasonable royalty shall not be affected by the duration of the period described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<heading>
<inline class="small-caps">Requirements for international applications.—</inline>
</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Effective date</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The right under paragraph (1) to obtain a reasonable royalty based upon the publication under the treaty defined in section 351(a) of an international application designating the United States shall commence on the date of publication under the treaty of the international application, or, if the publication under the treaty of the international application is in a language other than English, on the date on which the Patent and Trademark Office receives a translation of the publication in the English language.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<heading><inline class="small-caps">Copies</inline>.—</heading>
<content>The Director may require the applicant to provide a copy of the international application and a translation thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 804</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–83, § 5</ref>, <date date="1965-07-24">July 24, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 261</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–517, § 4</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3018</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title IX, § 9002</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1563</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title V, § 532(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4983</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–295, § 20(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 3529</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, §§ 4402(a), 4504]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–557, 1501A–564; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III</ref>, §§ 13204, 13206(a)(8), <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1902</ref>, 1904; <ref>Pub. L. 112–29</ref>, §§ 3(j)(1), (2)(B), 9(a), 20(j), <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 290</ref>, 316, 335; <ref>Pub. L. 112–211, title I, § 102(6)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-18">Dec. 18, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1531</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–274, § 1(h)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-14">Jan. 14, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2457</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 155, 155A.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 112–29, § 20(k)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 335</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 156.</num>
<heading> Extension of patent term</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The term of a patent which claims a product, a method of using a product, or a method of manufacturing a product shall be extended in accordance with this section from the original expiration date of the patent, which shall include any patent term adjustment granted under section 154(b), if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the term of the patent has not expired before an application is submitted under subsection (d)(1) for its extension;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the term of the patent has never been extended under subsection (e)(1) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an application for extension is submitted by the owner of record of the patent or its agent and in accordance with the requirements of paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (d);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the product has been subject to a regulatory review period before its commercial marketing or use;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> except as provided in subparagraph (B) or (C), the permission for the commercial marketing or use of the product after such regulatory review period is the first permitted commercial marketing or use of the product under the provision of law under which such regulatory review period occurred;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a patent which claims a method of manufacturing the product which primarily uses recombinant DNA technology in the manufacture of the product, the permission for the commercial marketing or use of the product after such regulatory review period is the first permitted commercial marketing or use of a product manufactured under the process claimed in the patent; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> for purposes of subparagraph (A), in the case of a patent which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> claims a new animal drug or a veterinary biological product which (I) is not covered by the claims in any other patent which has been extended, and (II) has received permission for the commercial marketing or use in non-food-producing animals and in food-producing animals, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> was not extended on the basis of the regulatory review period for use in non-food-producing animals,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">the permission for the commercial marketing or use of the drug or product after the regulatory review period for use in food-producing animals is the first permitted commercial marketing or use of the drug or product for administration to a food-producing animal.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The product referred to in paragraphs (4) and (5) is hereinafter in this section referred to as the “approved product”.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (d)(5)(F), the rights derived from any patent the term of which is extended under this section shall during the period during which the term of the patent is extended—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a patent which claims a product, be limited to any use approved for the product—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> before the expiration of the term of the patent—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> under the provision of law under which the applicable regulatory review occurred, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> under the provision of law under which any regulatory review described in paragraph (1), (4), or (5) of subsection (g) occurred, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on or after the expiration of the regulatory review period upon which the extension of the patent was based;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a patent which claims a method of using a product, be limited to any use claimed by the patent and approved for the product—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> before the expiration of the term of the patent—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> under any provision of law under which an applicable regulatory review occurred, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> under the provision of law under which any regulatory review described in paragraph (1), (4), or (5) of subsection (g) occurred, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> on or after the expiration of the regulatory review period upon which the extension of the patent was based; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a patent which claims a method of manufacturing a product, be limited to the method of manufacturing as used to make—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the approved product, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the product if it has been subject to a regulatory review period described in paragraph (1), (4), or (5) of subsection (g).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">As used in this subsection, the term “product” includes an approved product.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The term of a patent eligible for extension under subsection (a) shall be extended by the time equal to the regulatory review period for the approved product which period occurs after the date the patent is issued, except that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> each period of the regulatory review period shall be reduced by any period determined under subsection (d)(2)(B) during which the applicant for the patent extension did not act with due diligence during such period of the regulatory review period;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> after any reduction required by paragraph (1), the period of extension shall include only one-half of the time remaining in the periods described in paragraphs (1)(B)(i), (2)(B)(i), (3)(B)(i), (4)(B)(i), and (5)(B)(i) of subsection (g);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> if the period remaining in the term of a patent after the date of the approval of the approved product under the provision of law under which such regulatory review occurred when added to the regulatory review period as revised under paragraphs (1) and (2) exceeds fourteen years, the period of extension shall be reduced so that the total of both such periods does not exceed fourteen years; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in no event shall more than one patent be extended under subsection (e)(1) for the same regulatory review period for any product.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> To obtain an extension of the term of a patent under this section, the owner of record of the patent or its agent shall submit an application to the Director. Except as provided in paragraph (5), such an application may only be submitted within the sixty-day period beginning on the date the product received permission under the provision of law under which the applicable regulatory review period occurred for commercial marketing or use, or in the case of a drug product described in subsection (i), within the sixty-day period beginning on the covered date (as defined in subsection (i)). The application shall contain—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the identity of the approved product and the Federal statute under which regulatory review occurred;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the identity of the patent for which an extension is being sought and the identity of each claim of such patent which claims the approved product or a method of using or manufacturing the approved product;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> information to enable the Director to determine under subsections (a) and (b) the eligibility of a patent for extension and the rights that will be derived from the extension and information to enable the Director and the Secretary of Health and Human Services or the Secretary of Agriculture to determine the period of the extension under subsection (g);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a brief description of the activities undertaken by the applicant during the applicable regulatory review period with respect to the approved product and the significant dates applicable to such activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> such patent or other information as the Director may require.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of determining the date on which a product receives permission under the second sentence of this paragraph, if such permission is transmitted after 4:30 P.M., Eastern Time, on a business day, or is transmitted on a day that is not a business day, the product shall be deemed to receive such permission on the next business day. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term “business day” means any Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday, or Friday, excluding any legal holiday under <ref>section 6103 of title 5</ref>.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Within 60 days of the submittal of an application for extension of the term of a patent under paragraph (1), the Director shall notify—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Agriculture if the patent claims a drug product or a method of using or manufacturing a drug product and the drug product is subject to the Virus-Serum-Toxin Act, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Secretary of Health and Human Services if the patent claims any other drug product, a medical device, or a food additive or color additive or a method of using or manufacturing such a product, device, or additive and if the product, device, and additive are subject to the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">of the extension application and shall submit to the Secretary who is so notified a copy of the application. Not later than 30 days after the receipt of an application from the Director, the Secretary receiving the application shall review the dates contained in the application pursuant to paragraph (1)(C) and determine the applicable regulatory review period, shall notify the Director of the determination, and shall publish in the Federal Register a notice of such determination.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> If a petition is submitted to the Secretary making the determination under subparagraph (A), not later than 180 days after the publication of the determination under subparagraph (A), upon which it may reasonably be determined that the applicant did not act with due diligence during the applicable regulatory review period, the Secretary making the determination shall, in accordance with regulations promulgated by such Secretary, determine if the applicant acted with due diligence during the applicable regulatory review period. The Secretary making the determination shall make such determination not later than 90 days after the receipt of such a petition. For a drug product, device, or additive subject to the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act or the Public Health Service Act, the Secretary may not delegate the authority to make the determination prescribed by this clause to an office below the Office of the Director <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002005">1</ref> of Food and Drugs. For a product subject to the Virus-Serum-Toxin Act, the Secretary of Agriculture may not delegate the authority to make the determination prescribed by this clause to an office below the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Marketing and Inspection Services.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent0">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The Secretary making a determination under clause (i) shall notify the Director of the determination and shall publish in the Federal Register a notice of such determination together with the factual and legal basis for such determination. Any interested person may request, within the 60-day period beginning on the publication of a determination, the Secretary making the determination to hold an informal hearing on the determination. If such a request is made within such period, such Secretary shall hold such hearing not later than 30 days after the date of the request, or at the request of the person making the request, not later than 60 days after such date. The Secretary who is holding the hearing shall provide notice of the hearing to the owner of the patent involved and to any interested person and provide the owner and any interested person an opportunity to participate in the hearing. Within 30 days after the completion of the hearing, such Secretary shall affirm or revise the determination which was the subject of the hearing and shall notify the Director of any revision of the determination and shall publish any such revision in the Federal Register.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For the purposes of paragraph (2)(B), the term “due diligence” means that degree of attention, continuous directed effort, and timeliness as may reasonably be expected from, and are ordinarily exercised by, a person during a regulatory review period.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> An application for the extension of the term of a patent is subject to the disclosure requirements prescribed by the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> If the owner of record of the patent or its agent reasonably expects that the applicable regulatory review period described in paragraph (1)(B)(ii), (2)(B)(ii), (3)(B)(ii), (4)(B)(ii), or (5)(B)(ii) of subsection (g) that began for a product that is the subject of such patent may extend beyond the expiration of the patent term in effect, the owner or its agent may submit an application to the Director for an interim extension during the period beginning 6 months, and ending 15 days, before such term is due to expire. The application shall contain—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the identity of the product subject to regulatory review and the Federal statute under which such review is occurring;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the identity of the patent for which interim extension is being sought and the identity of each claim of such patent which claims the product under regulatory review or a method of using or manufacturing the product;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> information to enable the Director to determine under subsection (a)(1), (2), and (3) the eligibility of a patent for extension;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a brief description of the activities undertaken by the applicant during the applicable regulatory review period to date with respect to the product under review and the significant dates applicable to such activities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> such patent or other information as the Director may require.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If the Director determines that, except for permission to market or use the product commercially, the patent would be eligible for an extension of the patent term under this section, the Director shall publish in the Federal Register a notice of such determination, including the identity of the product under regulatory review, and shall issue to the applicant a certificate of interim extension for a period of not more than 1 year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The owner of record of a patent, or its agent, for which an interim extension has been granted under subparagraph (B), may apply for not more than 4 subsequent interim extensions under this paragraph, except that, in the case of a patent subject to subsection (g)(6)(C), the owner of record of the patent, or its agent, may apply for only 1 subsequent interim extension under this paragraph. Each such subsequent application shall be made during the period beginning 60 days before, and ending 30 days before, the expiration of the preceding interim extension.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Each certificate of interim extension under this paragraph shall be recorded in the official file of the patent and shall be considered part of the original patent.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> Any interim extension granted under this paragraph shall terminate at the end of the 60-day period beginning on the date on which the product involved receives permission for commercial marketing or use, except that, if within that 60-day period the applicant notifies the Director of such permission and submits any additional information under paragraph (1) of this subsection not previously contained in the application for interim extension, the patent shall be further extended, in accordance with the provisions of this section—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for not to exceed 5 years from the date of expiration of the original patent term; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if the patent is subject to subsection (g)(6)(C), from the date on which the product involved receives approval for commercial marketing or use.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent0">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> The rights derived from any patent the term of which is extended under this paragraph shall, during the period of interim extension—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of a patent which claims a product, be limited to any use then under regulatory review;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of a patent which claims a method of using a product, be limited to any use claimed by the patent then under regulatory review; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in the case of a patent which claims a method of manufacturing a product, be limited to the method of manufacturing as used to make the product then under regulatory review.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A determination that a patent is eligible for extension may be made by the Director solely on the basis of the representations contained in the application for the extension. If the Director determines that a patent is eligible for extension under subsection (a) and that the requirements of paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (d) have been complied with, the Director shall issue to the applicant for the extension of the term of the patent a certificate of extension, under seal, for the period prescribed by subsection (c). Such certificate shall be recorded in the official file of the patent and shall be considered as part of the original patent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the term of a patent for which an application has been submitted under subsection (d)(1) would expire before a certificate of extension is issued or denied under paragraph (1) respecting the application, the Director shall extend, until such determination is made, the term of the patent for periods of up to one year if he determines that the patent is eligible for extension.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this section:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> The term “product” means:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A drug product.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any medical device, food additive, or color additive subject to regulation under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> The term “drug product” means the active ingredient of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a new drug, antibiotic drug, or human biological product (as those terms are used in the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and the Public Health Service Act), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a new animal drug or veterinary biological product (as those terms are used in the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and the Virus-Serum-Toxin Act) which is not primarily manufactured using recombinant DNA, recombinant RNA, hybridoma technology, or other processes involving site specific genetic manipulation techniques,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">including any salt or ester of the active ingredient, as a single entity or in combination with another active ingredient.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “major health or environmental effects test” means a test which is reasonably related to the evaluation of the health or environmental effects of a product, which requires at least six months to conduct, and the data from which is submitted to receive permission for commercial marketing or use. Periods of analysis or evaluation of test results are not to be included in determining if the conduct of a test required at least six months.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Any reference to section 351 is a reference to section 351 of the Public Health Service Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Any reference to section 503, 505, 512, or 515 is a reference to section 503, 505, 512, or 515 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Any reference to the Virus-Serum-Toxin Act is a reference to the Act of <date date="1913-03-04">March 4, 1913</date> (<ref>21 U.S.C. 151–158</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “informal hearing” has the meaning prescribed for such term by section 201(y) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002006">2</ref> of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “patent” means a patent issued by the United States Patent and Trademark Office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “date of enactment” as used in this section means <date date="1984-09-24">September 24, 1984</date>, for a human drug product, a medical device, food additive, or color additive.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “date of enactment” as used in this section means the date of enactment of the Generic Animal Drug and Patent Term Restoration Act for an animal drug or a veterinary biological product.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(g)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this section, the term “regulatory review period” has the following meanings:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of a product which is a new drug, antibiotic drug, or human biological product, the term means the period described in subparagraph (B) to which the limitation described in paragraph (6) applies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The regulatory review period for a new drug, antibiotic drug, or human biological product is the sum of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the period beginning on the date an exemption under subsection (i) of section 505 or subsection (d) of section 507 <sup>2</sup> became effective for the approved product and ending on the date an application was initially submitted for such drug product under section 351, 505, or 507,<sup>2</sup> and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the period beginning on the date the application was initially submitted for the approved product under section 351, subsection (b) of section 505, or section 507 <sup>2</sup> and ending on the date such application was approved under such section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of a product which is a food additive or color additive, the term means the period described in subparagraph (B) to which the limitation described in paragraph (6) applies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The regulatory review period for a food or color additive is the sum of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the period beginning on the date a major health or environmental effects test on the additive was initiated and ending on the date a petition was initially submitted with respect to the product under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act requesting the issuance of a regulation for use of the product, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the period beginning on the date a petition was initially submitted with respect to the product under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act requesting the issuance of a regulation for use of the product, and ending on the date such regulation became effective or, if objections were filed to such regulation, ending on the date such objections were resolved and commercial marketing was permitted or, if commercial marketing was permitted and later revoked pending further proceedings as a result of such objections, ending on the date such proceedings were finally resolved and commercial marketing was permitted.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of a product which is a medical device, the term means the period described in subparagraph (B) to which the limitation described in paragraph (6) applies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The regulatory review period for a medical device is the sum of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the period beginning on the date a clinical investigation on humans involving the device was begun and ending on the date an application was initially submitted with respect to the device under section 515, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the period beginning on the date an application was initially submitted with respect to the device under section 515 and ending on the date such application was approved under such Act or the period beginning on the date a notice of completion of a product development protocol was initially submitted under section 515(f)(5) and ending on the date the protocol was declared completed under section 515(f)(6).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of a product which is a new animal drug, the term means the period described in subparagraph (B) to which the limitation described in paragraph (6) applies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The regulatory review period for a new animal drug product is the sum of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the period beginning on the earlier of the date a major health or environmental effects test on the drug was initiated or the date an exemption under subsection (j) of section 512 became effective for the approved new animal drug product and ending on the date an application was initially submitted for such animal drug product under section 512, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the period beginning on the date the application was initially submitted for the approved animal drug product under subsection (b) of section 512 and ending on the date such application was approved under such section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> In the case of a product which is a veterinary biological product, the term means the period described in subparagraph (B) to which the limitation described in paragraph (6) applies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> The regulatory period for a veterinary biological product is the sum of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the period beginning on the date the authority to prepare an experimental biological product under the Virus-Serum-Toxin Act became effective and ending on the date an application for a license was submitted under the Virus-Serum-Toxin Act, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the period beginning on the date an application for a license was initially submitted for approval under the Virus-Serum-Toxin Act and ending on the date such license was issued.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> A period determined under any of the preceding paragraphs is subject to the following limitations:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> If the patent involved was issued after the date of the enactment of this section, the period of extension determined on the basis of the regulatory review period determined under any such paragraph may not exceed five years.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> If the patent involved was issued before the date of the enactment of this section and—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> no request for an exemption described in paragraph (1)(B) or (4)(B) was submitted and no request for the authority described in paragraph (5)(B) was submitted,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> no major health or environmental effects test described in paragraph (2)(B) or (4)(B) was initiated and no petition for a regulation or application for registration described in such paragraph was submitted, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> no clinical investigation described in paragraph (3) was begun or product development protocol described in such paragraph was submitted,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">before such date for the approved product the period of extension determined on the basis of the regulatory review period determined under any such paragraph may not exceed five years.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> If the patent involved was issued before the date of the enactment of this section and if an action described in subparagraph (B) was taken before the date of the enactment of this section with respect to the approved product and the commercial marketing or use of the product has not been approved before such date, the period of extension determined on the basis of the regulatory review period determined under such paragraph may not exceed two years or in the case of an approved product which is a new animal drug or veterinary biological product (as those terms are used in the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act or the Virus-Serum-Toxin Act), three years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(h)</num>
<content> The Director may establish such fees as the Director determines appropriate to cover the costs to the Office of receiving and acting upon applications under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(i)</num>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this section, if the Secretary of Health and Human Services provides notice to the sponsor of an application or request for approval, conditional approval, or indexing of a drug product for which the Secretary intends to recommend controls under the Controlled Substances Act, beginning on the covered date, the drug product shall be considered to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have been approved or indexed under the relevant provision of the Public Health Service Act or Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> have permission for commercial marketing or use.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> In this subsection, the term “covered date” means the later of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the date an application is approved—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> under section 351(a)(2)(C) of the Public Health Service Act; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> under section 505(b) or 512(c) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date an application is conditionally approved under section 571(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the date a request for indexing is granted under section 572(d) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the date of issuance of the interim final rule controlling the drug under section 201(j) of the Controlled Substances Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–417, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-09-24">Sept. 24, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1598</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–670, title II, § 201(a)</ref>–(h), <date date="1988-11-16">Nov. 16, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3984–3987</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–179</ref>, §§ 5, 6, <date date="1993-12-03">Dec. 3, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2040</ref>, 2042; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title V, § 532(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4987</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–115, title I, § 125(b)(2)(P)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-21">Nov. 21, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 2326</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, §§ 4404, 4732(a)(10)(A)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–560, 1501A–582; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III, § 13206(a)(9)</ref>, (b)(1)(B), <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1904</ref>, 1906; <ref>Pub. L. 112–29, § 37(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 341</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–89, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 700</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 157.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 112–29, § 3(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 287</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>