<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 37—</num>
<heading>NATIONAL STAGE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 371.</num>
<heading> National stage: Commencement</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> Receipt from the International Bureau of copies of international applications with any amendments to the claims, international search reports, and international preliminary examination reports including any annexes thereto may be required in the case of international applications designating or electing the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Subject to subsection (f) of this section, the national stage shall commence with the expiration of the applicable time limit under article 22(1) or (2), or under article 39(1)(a) of the treaty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(c)</num>
<chapeau> The applicant shall file in the Patent and Trademark Office—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the national fee provided in section 41(a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a copy of the international application, unless not required under subsection (a) of this section or already communicated by the International Bureau, and a translation into the English language of the international application, if it was filed in another language;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> amendments, if any, to the claims in the international application, made under article 19 of the treaty, unless such amendments have been communicated to the Patent and Trademark Office by the International Bureau, and a translation into the English language if such amendments were made in another language;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> an oath or declaration of the inventor (or other person authorized under chapter 11) complying with the requirements of section 115 and with regulations prescribed for oaths or declarations of applicants;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a translation into the English language of any annexes to the international preliminary examination report, if such annexes were made in another language.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(d)</num>
<content> The requirements with respect to the national fee referred to in subsection (c)(1), the translation referred to in subsection (c)(2), and the oath or declaration referred to in subsection (c)(4) of this section shall be complied with by the date of the commencement of the national stage or by such later time as may be fixed by the Director. The copy of the international application referred to in subsection (c)(2) shall be submitted by the date of the commencement of the national stage. Failure to comply with these requirements shall be regarded as abandonment of the application by the parties thereof. The payment of a surcharge may be required as a condition of accepting the national fee referred to in subsection (c)(1) or the oath or declaration referred to in subsection (c)(4) of this section if these requirements are not met by the date of the commencement of the national stage. The requirements of subsection (c)(3) of this section shall be complied with by the date of the commencement of the national stage, and failure to do so shall be regarded as a cancellation of the amendments to the claims in the international application made under article 19 of the treaty. The requirement of subsection (c)(5) shall be complied with at such time as may be fixed by the Director and failure to do so shall be regarded as cancellation of the amendments made under article 34(2)(b) of the treaty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(e)</num>
<content> After an international application has entered the national stage, no patent may be granted or refused thereon before the expiration of the applicable time limit under article 28 or article 41 of the treaty, except with the express consent of the applicant. The applicant may pre­sent amendments to the specification, claims and drawings of the application after the national stage has commenced.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(f)</num>
<content> At the express request of the applicant, the national stage of processing may be commenced at any time at which the application is in order for such purpose and the applicable requirements of subsection (c) of this section have been complied with.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–131, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-11-14">Nov. 14, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 688</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–622, title IV</ref>, §§ 402(a)–(d), 403(a), <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3391</ref>, 3392; <ref>Pub. L. 99–616, § 7</ref>, <date date="1986-11-06">Nov. 6, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3486</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–204, § 5(g)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-10">Dec. 10, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1641</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4732(a)(10)(A)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–582; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III, § 13206(a)(20)</ref>, (b)(1)(B), <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1905</ref>, 1906; <ref>Pub. L. 112–29, § 20(i)(5)</ref>, (j), <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 335</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–211, title II, § 202(b)(9)</ref>, <date date="2012-12-18">Dec. 18, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 1536</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 372.</num>
<heading> National stage: Requirements and procedure</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> All questions of substance and, within the scope of the requirements of the treaty and Regulations, procedure in an international application designating the United States shall be determined as in the case of national applications regularly filed in the Patent and Trademark Office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<chapeau> In case of international applications designating but not originating in, the United States—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Director may cause to be reexamined questions relating to form and contents of the application in accordance with the requirements of the treaty and the Regulations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Director may cause the question of unity of invention to be reexamined under section 121, within the scope of the requirements of the treaty and the Regulations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Director may require a verification of the translation of the international application or any other document pertaining to the application if the application or other document was filed in a language other than English.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–131, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-11-14">Nov. 14, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 689</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–622, title IV</ref>, §§ 402(e), (f), 403(a), <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3392</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4732(a)(10)(A)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–582; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III, § 13206(b)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1906</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–29, § 20(j)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 335</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 373.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 112–274, § 1(i)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-14">Jan. 14, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2457</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 374.</num>
<heading> Publication of international application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The publication under the treaty defined in section 351(a), of an international application designating the United States shall be deemed a publication under section 122(b), except as provided in section 154(d).</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–131, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-11-14">Nov. 14, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 689</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4507(10)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–566; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III, § 13205(2)(E)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1903</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–29</ref>, §§ 3(g)(4), 20(j), <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 288</ref>, 335.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 375.</num>
<heading> Patent issued on international application: Effect</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<content> A patent may be issued by the Director based on an international application designating the United States, in accordance with the provisions of this title. Such patent shall have the force and effect of a patent issued on a national application filed under the provisions of chapter 11.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> Where due to an incorrect translation the scope of a patent granted on an international application designating the United States, which was not originally filed in the English language, exceeds the scope of the international application in its original language, a court of competent jurisdiction may retroactively limit the scope of the patent, by declaring it unenforceable to the extent that it exceeds the scope of the international application in its original language.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–131, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-11-14">Nov. 14, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 689</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4732(a)(10)(A)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–582; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III, § 13206(b)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1906</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–29</ref>, §§ 3(g)(5), 20(j), <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 288</ref>, 335.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 376.</num>
<heading> Fees</heading>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(a)</num>
<chapeau> The required payment of the international fee and the handling fee, which amounts are specified in the Regulations, shall be paid in United States currency. The Patent and Trademark Office shall charge a national fee as provided in section 41(a), and may also charge the following fees:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> A transmittal fee (see section 361(d)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> A search fee (see section 361(d)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> A supplemental search fee (to be paid when required).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> A preliminary examination fee and any additional fees (see section 362(b)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> Such other fees as established by the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent0">
<num>(b)</num>
<content> The amounts of fees specified in subsection (a) of this section, except the international fee and the handling fee, shall be prescribed by the Director. He may refund any sum paid by mistake or in excess of the fees so specified, or if required under the treaty and the Regulations. The Director may also refund any part of the search fee, the national fee, the preliminary examination fee, and any additional fees, where he determines such refund to be warranted.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–131, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-11-14">Nov. 14, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 690</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–622, title IV</ref>, §§ 402(g), 403(a), <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3392</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–616, § 8</ref>, <date date="1986-11-06">Nov. 6, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 3486</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–204, § 5(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-10">Dec. 10, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 1640</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4732(a)(10)(A)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–582; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III, § 13206(a)(21)</ref>, (b)(1)(B), <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1905</ref>, 1906.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>