<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 15—</num>
<heading>PLANT PATENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 161.</num>
<heading> Patents for plants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whoever invents or discovers and asexually reproduces any distinct and new variety of plant, including cultivated sports, mutants, hybrids, and newly found seedlings, other than a tuber propagated plant or a plant found in an uncultivated state, may obtain a patent therefor, subject to the conditions and requirements of this title.</p>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of this title relating to patents for inventions shall apply to patents for plants, except as otherwise provided.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 804</ref>; <ref>Sept. 3, 1954, ch. 1259</ref>, <ref>68 Stat. 1190</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 162.</num>
<heading> Description, claim</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No plant patent shall be declared invalid for noncompliance with section 112 if the description is as complete as is reasonably possible.</p>
<p class="indent0">The claim in the specification shall be in formal terms to the plant shown and described.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 804</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–29, § 20(j)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 335</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 163.</num>
<heading> Grant</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of a plant patent, the grant shall include the right to exclude others from asexually reproducing the plant, and from using, offering for sale, or selling the plant so reproduced, or any of its parts, throughout the United States, or from importing the plant so reproduced, or any parts thereof, into the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 804</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–289, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2781</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 164.</num>
<heading> Assistance of Department of Agriculture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President may by Executive order direct the Secretary of Agriculture, in accordance with the requests of the Director, for the purpose of carrying into effect the provisions of this title with respect to plants (1) to furnish available information of the Department of Agriculture, (2) to conduct through the appropriate bureau or division of the Department research upon special problems, or (3) to detail to the Director officers and employees of the Department.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>July 19, 1952, ch. 950</ref>, <ref>66 Stat. 804</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4732(a)(10)(A)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref>113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–582; <ref>Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title III, § 13206(b)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 1906</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>