<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 55—</num>
<heading>STRUCTURED SETTLEMENT FACTORING TRANSACTIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5891.</num>
<heading> Structured settlement factoring transactions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Imposition of tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby imposed on any person who acquires directly or indirectly structured settlement payment rights in a structured settlement factoring transaction a tax equal to 40 percent of the factoring discount as determined under subsection (c)(4) with respect to such factoring transaction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for certain approved transactions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The tax under subsection (a) shall not apply in the case of a structured settlement factoring transaction in which the transfer of structured settlement payment rights is approved in advance in a qualified order.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified order</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “qualified order” means a final order, judgment, or decree which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> finds that the transfer described in paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> does not contravene any Federal or State statute or the order of any court or responsible administrative authority, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is in the best interest of the payee, taking into account the welfare and support of the payee’s dependents, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> is issued—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> under the authority of an applicable State statute by an applicable State court, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> by the responsible administrative authority (if any) which has exclusive jurisdiction over the underlying action or proceeding which was resolved by means of the structured settlement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable State statute</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “applicable State statute” means a statute providing for the entry of an order, judgment, or decree described in paragraph (2)(A) which is enacted by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the State in which the payee of the structured settlement is domiciled, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if there is no statute described in subparagraph (A), the State in which either the party to the structured settlement (including an assignee under a qualified assignment under section 130) or the person issuing the funding asset for the structured settlement is domiciled or has its principal place of business.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable State court</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “applicable State court” means, with respect to any applicable State statute, a court of the State which enacted such statute.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of an applicable State statute described in paragraph (3)(B), such term also includes a court of the State in which the payee of the structured settlement is domiciled.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified order dispositive</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A qualified order shall be treated as dispositive for purposes of the exception under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Structured settlement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “structured settlement” means an arrangement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> which is established by—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> suit or agreement for the periodic payment of damages excludable from the gross income of the recipient under section 104(a)(2), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> agreement for the periodic payment of compensation under any workers’ compensation law excludable from the gross income of the recipient under section 104(a)(1), and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> under which the periodic payments are—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> of the character described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 130(c)(2), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> payable by a person who is a party to the suit or agreement or to the workers’ compensation claim or by a person who has assumed the liability for such periodic payments under a qualified assignment in accordance with section 130.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Structured settlement payment rights</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “structured settlement payment rights” means rights to receive payments under a structured settlement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Structured settlement factoring transaction</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “structured settlement factoring transaction” means a transfer of structured settlement payment rights (including portions of structured settlement payments) made for consideration by means of sale, assignment, pledge, or other form of encumbrance or alienation for consideration.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Such term shall not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the creation or perfection of a security interest in structured settlement payment rights under a blanket security agreement entered into with an insured depository institution in the absence of any action to redirect the structured settlement payments to such institution (or agent or successor thereof) or otherwise to enforce such blanket security interest as against the structured settlement payment rights, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a subsequent transfer of structured settlement payment rights acquired in a structured settlement factoring transaction.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Factoring discount</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “factoring discount” means an amount equal to the excess of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the aggregate undiscounted amount of structured settlement payments being acquired in the structured settlement factoring transaction, over</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the total amount actually paid by the acquirer to the person from whom such structured settlement payments are acquired.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsible administrative authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “responsible administrative authority” means the administrative authority which had jurisdiction over the underlying action or proceeding which was resolved by means of the structured settlement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” includes the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and any possession of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with other provisions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the applicable requirements of sections 72, 104(a)(1), 104(a)(2), 130, and 461(h) were satisfied at the time the structured settlement involving structured settlement payment rights was entered into, the subsequent occurrence of a structured settlement factoring transaction shall not affect the application of the provisions of such sections to the parties to the structured settlement (including an assignee under a qualified assignment under section 130) in any taxable year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No withholding of tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The provisions of section 3405 regarding withholding of tax shall not apply to the person making the payments in the event of a structured settlement factoring transaction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–134, title I, § 115(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-23">Jan. 23, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2436</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>