<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 40—</num>
<heading>GENERAL PROVISIONS RELATING TO OCCUPATIONAL TAXES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4901.</num>
<heading> Payment of tax</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Condition precedent to carrying on certain business</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No person shall be engaged in or carry on any trade or business subject to the tax imposed by section 4411 (wagering) until he has paid the special tax therefor.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Computation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All special taxes shall be imposed as of on the first day of July in each year, or on commencing any trade or business on which such tax is imposed. In the former case the tax shall be reckoned for 1 year, and in the latter case it shall be reckoned proportionately, from the first day of the month in which the liability to a special tax commenced, to and including the 30th day of June following.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 593</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–44, title IV, § 405(b)</ref>, <date date="1965-06-21">June 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 149</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–513, title III, § 1102(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1292</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1904(a)(19)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–600, title V, § 521(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2884</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4902.</num>
<heading> Liability of partners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any number of persons doing business in copartnership at any one place shall be required to pay but one special tax.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 593</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4903.</num>
<heading> Liability in case of business in more than one location</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The payment of the special tax imposed, other than the tax imposed by section 4411, shall not exempt from an additional special tax the person carrying on a trade or business in any other place than that stated in the register kept in the office of the official in charge of the internal revenue district; but nothing herein contained shall require a special tax for the storage of goods, wares, or merchandise in other places than the place of business, nor, except as provided in this subtitle, for the sale by manufacturers or producers of their own goods, wares, and merchandise, at the place of production or manufacture, and at their principal office or place of business, provided no goods, wares, or merchandise shall be kept except as samples at said office or place of business.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 593</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4904.</num>
<heading> Liability in case of different businesses of same ownership and location</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever more than one of the pursuits or occupations described in this subtitle are carried on in the same place by the same person at the same time, except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, the tax shall be paid for each according to the rates severally prescribed.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 594</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4905.</num>
<heading> Liability in case of death or change of location</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When any person who has paid the special tax for any trade or business dies, his spouse or child, or executors or administrators or other legal representatives, may occupy the house or premises, and in like manner carry on, for the residue of the term for which the tax is paid, the same trade or business as the deceased before carried on, in the same house and upon the same premises, without the payment of any additional tax. When any person removes from the house or premises for which any trade or business was taxed to any other place, he may carry on the trade or business specified in the register kept in the office of the official in charge of the internal revenue district at the place to which he removes, without the payment of any additional tax: <i>Provided</i>, That all cases of death, change, or removal, as aforesaid, with the name of the successor to any person deceased, or of the person making such change or removal, shall be registered with the Secretary, under regulations to be prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Registration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2 fontsize7">For registration in case of wagering, see section 4412.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 594</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–44, title IV, § 405(c)</ref>, <date date="1965-06-21">June 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 149</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–513, title III, § 1102(b)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1292</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX</ref>, §§ 1904(a)(20), (b)(8)(A), 1906(b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1814</ref>, 1816, 1834.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4906.</num>
<heading> Application of State laws</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The payment of any special tax imposed by this subtitle for carrying on any trade or business shall not be held to exempt any person from any penalty or punishment provided by the laws of any State for carrying on the same within such State, or in any manner to authorize the commencement or continuance of such trade or business contrary to the laws of such State or in places prohibited by municipal law; nor shall the payment of any such tax be held to prohibit any State from placing a duty or tax on the same trade or business, for State or other purposes.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 594</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4907.</num>
<heading> Federal agencies or instrumentalities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any special tax imposed by this subtitle, except the tax imposed by section 4411, shall apply to any agency or instrumentality of the United States unless such agency or instrumentality is granted by statute a specific exemption from such tax.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 594</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>