<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 64—</num>
<heading>COLLECTION</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter A—</num>
<heading>General Provisions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6301.</num>
<heading> Collection authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall collect the taxes imposed by the internal revenue laws.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 775</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6302.</num>
<heading> Mode or time of collection</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment by regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the mode or time for collecting any tax is not provided for by this title, the Secretary may establish the same by regulations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discretionary method</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whether or not the method of collecting any tax imposed by chapter 21, 31, 32, or 33, or by section 4481 is specifically provided for by this title, any such tax may, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, be collected by means of returns, stamps, coupons, tickets, books, or such other reasonable devices or methods as may be necessary or helpful in securing a complete and proper collection of the tax.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of Government depositaries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may authorize Federal Reserve banks, and incorporated banks, trust companies, domestic building and loan associations, or credit unions which are depositaries or financial agents of the United States, to receive any tax imposed under the internal revenue laws, in such manner, at such times, and under such conditions as he may prescribe; and he shall prescribe the manner, times, and conditions under which the receipt of such tax by such banks, trust companies, domestic building and loan associations, and credit unions is to be treated as payment of such tax to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time for payment of manufacturers’ excise tax on recreational equipment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The taxes imposed by subchapter D of chapter 32 of this title (relating to taxes on recreational equipment) shall be due and payable on the date for filing the return for such taxes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time for deposit of taxes on communications services and airline tickets</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), if, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, a person is required to make deposits of any tax imposed by section 4251 or subsection (a) or (b) of section 4261 with respect to amounts considered collected by such person during any semimonthly period, such deposit shall be made not later than the 3rd day (not including Saturdays, Sundays, or legal holidays) after the close of the 1st week of the 2nd semimonthly period following the period to which such amounts relate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for tax due in September</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amounts considered collected</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of a person required to make deposits of the tax imposed by section 4251, 4261, or 4271 with respect to amounts considered collected by such person during any semimonthly period, the amount of such tax included in bills rendered or tickets sold during the period beginning on September 1 and ending on September 11 shall be deposited not later than September 29.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule where September 29 is on Saturday or Sunday</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If September 29 falls on a Saturday or Sunday, the due date under subparagraph (A) shall be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of Saturday, the preceding day, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of Sunday, the following day.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxpayers not required to use electronic funds transfer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of deposits not required to be made by electronic funds transfer, subparagraphs (A) and (B) shall be applied by substituting “September 10” for “September 11” and “September 28” for “September 29”.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time for deposit of certain excise taxes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection and subsection (e), if any person is required under regulations to make deposits of taxes under subtitle D with respect to semimonthly periods, such person shall make deposits of such taxes for the period beginning on September 16 and ending on September 26 not later than September 29.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxes on ozone depleting chemicals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If any person is required under regulations to make deposits of taxes under subchapter D of chapter 38 with respect to semimonthly periods, in lieu of paragraph (1), such person shall make deposits of such taxes for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the second semimonthly period in August, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the period beginning on September 1 and ending on September 11,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">not later than September 29.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxpayers not required to use electronic funds transfer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of deposits not required to be made by electronic funds transfer, paragraphs (1) and (2) shall be applied by substituting “September 25” for “September 26”, “September 10” for “September 11”, and “September 28” for “September 29”.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule where due date on Saturday or Sunday</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If, but for this paragraph, the due date under paragraph (1), (2), or (3) would fall on a Saturday or Sunday, such due date shall be deemed to be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of Saturday, the preceding day, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of Sunday, the following day.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposits of social security taxes and withheld income taxes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, a person is required to make deposits of taxes imposed by chapters 21, 22, and 24 on the basis of eighth-month periods, such person shall make deposits of such taxes on the 1st banking day after any day on which such person has $100,000 or more of such taxes for deposit.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of electronic fund transfer system for collection of certain taxes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of system</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary for the development and implementation of an electronic fund transfer system which is required to be used for the collection of depository taxes. Such system shall be designed in such manner as may be necessary to ensure that such taxes are credited to the general account of the Treasury on the date on which such taxes would otherwise have been required to be deposited under the Federal tax deposit system.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemptions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The regulations prescribed under subparagraph (A) may contain such exemptions as the Secretary may deem appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Depository tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “depository tax” means any tax if the Secretary is authorized to require deposits of such tax.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Electronic fund transfer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “electronic fund transfer” means any transfer of funds, other than a transaction originated by check, draft, or similar paper instrument, which is initiated through an electronic terminal, telephonic instrument, or computer or magnetic tape so as to order, instruct, or authorize a financial institution or other financial intermediary to debit or credit an account.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with other electronic fund transfer requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Under regulations, any tax required to be paid by electronic fund transfer under section 5061(e) or 5703(b) shall be paid in such a manner as to ensure that the requirements of the second sentence of paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection are satisfied.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 775</ref>; <ref>June 29, 1956, ch. 462</ref>, title II, § 206(b), <ref>70 Stat. 391</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(a)(17)</ref>, (b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1825</ref>, 1834; <ref>Pub. L. 95–147, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-10-28">Oct. 28, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1228</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–600, title I, § 105(e)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2776</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–223, title I, § 101(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1980-04-02">Apr. 2, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 250</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title X, § 1015(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1018</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1941(b)(2)(G)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1323</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VI, § 6107(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3712</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–239, title VII</ref>, §§ 7502(a), 7507(a), 7632(a), <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2362</ref>, 2369, 2379; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XI</ref>, §§ 11217(b)(1), 11334(a), 11801(c)(22)(A), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–437</ref>, 1388–470, 1388–528; <ref>Pub. L. 103–66, title XIII, § 13242(d)(15)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 524</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–182, title V, § 523(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-08">Dec. 8, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2161</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–465, title VII, § 712(a)</ref>, (d), <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4999</ref>, 5001; <ref>Pub. L. 104–188, title I</ref>, §§ 1702(c)(3), 1704(t)(52), <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1869</ref>, 1890; <ref>Pub. L. 111–226, title II, § 219(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-08-10">Aug. 10, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2403</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–237, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-08-16">Aug. 16, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2497</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(110)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4053</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(279)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1197</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6303.</num>
<heading> Notice and demand for tax</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Where it is not otherwise provided by this title, the Secretary shall, as soon as practicable, and within 60 days, after the making of an assessment of a tax pursuant to section 6203, give notice to each person liable for the unpaid tax, stating the amount and demanding payment thereof. Such notice shall be left at the dwelling or usual place of business of such person, or shall be sent by mail to such person’s last known address.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessment prior to last date for payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except where the Secretary believes collection would be jeopardized by delay, if any tax is assessed prior to the last date prescribed for payment of such tax, payment of such tax shall not be demanded under subsection (a) until after such date.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 775</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6304.</num>
<heading> Fair tax collection practices</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Communication with the taxpayer</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Without the prior consent of the taxpayer given directly to the Secretary or the express permission of a court of competent jurisdiction, the Secretary may not communicate with a taxpayer in connection with the collection of any unpaid tax—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> at any unusual time or place or a time or place known or which should be known to be inconvenient to the taxpayer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the Secretary knows the taxpayer is represented by any person authorized to practice before the Internal Revenue Service with respect to such unpaid tax and has knowledge of, or can readily ascertain, such person’s name and address, unless such person fails to respond within a reasonable period of time to a communication from the Secretary or unless such person consents to direct communication with the taxpayer; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> at the taxpayer’s place of employment if the Secretary knows or has reason to know that the taxpayer’s employer prohibits the taxpayer from receiving such communication.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">In the absence of knowledge of circumstances to the contrary, the Secretary shall assume that the convenient time for communicating with a taxpayer is after 8 a.m. and before 9 p.m., local time at the taxpayer’s location.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibition of harassment and abuse</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may not engage in any conduct the natural consequence of which is to harass, oppress, or abuse any person in connection with the collection of any unpaid tax. Without limiting the general application of the foregoing, the following conduct is a violation of this subsection:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The use or threat of use of violence or other criminal means to harm the physical person, reputation, or property of any person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The use of obscene or profane language or language the natural consequence of which is to abuse the hearer or reader.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Causing a telephone to ring or engaging any person in telephone conversation repeatedly or continuously with intent to annoy, abuse, or harass any person at the called number.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Except as provided under rules similar to the rules in section 804 of the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1692b</ref>), the placement of telephone calls without meaningful disclosure of the caller’s identity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Civil action for violations of section</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2 fontsize7">For civil action for violations of this section, see section 7433.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title III, § 3466(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 768</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6305.</num>
<heading> Collection of certain liability</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Upon receiving a certification from the Secretary of Health and Human Services, under section 452(b) of the Social Security Act with respect to any individual, the Secretary shall assess and collect the amount certified by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in the same manner, with the same powers, and (except as provided in this section) subject to the same limitations as if such amount were a tax imposed by subtitle C the collection of which would be jeopardized by delay, except that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> no interest or penalties shall be assessed or collected,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> for such purposes, paragraphs (4), (6), and (8) of section 6334(a) (relating to property exempt from levy) shall not apply,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> there shall be exempt from levy so much of the salary, wages, or other income of an individual as is being withheld therefrom in garnishment pursuant to a judgment entered by a court of competent jurisdiction for the support of his minor children,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> in the case of the first assessment against an individual for delinquency under a court or administrative order against such individual for a particular person or persons, the collection shall be stayed for a period of 60 days immediately following notice and demand as described in section 6303, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> no additional fee may be assessed for adjustments to an amount previously certified pursuant to such section 452(b) with respect to the same obligor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of assessments and collections</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No court of the United States, whether established under article I or article III of the Constitution, shall have jurisdiction of any action, whether legal or equitable, brought to restrain or review the assessment and collection of amounts by the Secretary under subsection (a), nor shall any such assessment and collection be subject to review by the Secretary in any proceeding. This subsection does not preclude any legal, equitable, or administrative action against the State by an individual in any State court or before any State agency to determine his liability for any amount assessed against him and collected, or to recover any such amount collected from him, under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 93–647, § 101(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2358</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–35, title XXIII, § 2332(g)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 862</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–193, title III, § 361(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6306.</num>
<heading> Qualified tax collection contracts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in any provision of law shall be construed to prevent the Secretary from entering into a qualified tax collection contract.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified tax collection contract</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “qualified tax collection contract” means any contract which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> is for the services of any person (other than an officer or employee of the Treasury Department)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to locate and contact any taxpayer specified by the Secretary,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to request full payment from such taxpayer of an amount of Federal tax specified by the Secretary and, if such request cannot be met by the taxpayer, to offer the taxpayer an installment agreement providing for full payment of such amount during a period not to exceed 7 years, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to obtain financial information specified by the Secretary with respect to such taxpayer,</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> prohibits each person providing such services under such contract from committing any act or omission which employees of the Internal Revenue Service are prohibited from committing in the performance of similar services,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> prohibits subcontractors from—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> having contacts with taxpayers,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> providing quality assurance services, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> composing debt collection notices, and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> permits subcontractors to perform other services only with the approval of the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collection of inactive tax receivables</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall enter into one or more qualified tax collection contracts for the collection of all outstanding inactive tax receivables.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inactive tax receivables</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “inactive tax receivable” means any tax receivable if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> at any time after assessment, the Internal Revenue Service removes such receivable from the active inventory for lack of resources or inability to locate the taxpayer,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> more than 2 years has passed since assessment and such receivable has not been assigned for collection to any employee of the Internal Revenue Service, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in the case of a receivable which has been assigned for collection, more than 365 days have passed without interaction with the taxpayer or a third party for purposes of furthering the collection of such receivable.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax receivable</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “tax receivable” means any outstanding assessment which the Internal Revenue Service includes in potentially collectible inventory.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain tax receivables not eligible for collection under qualified tax collections contracts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A tax receivable shall not be eligible for collection pursuant to a qualified tax collection contract if such receivable—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is subject to a pending or active offer-in-compromise or installment agreement,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is classified as an innocent spouse case,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> involves a taxpayer identified by the Secretary as being—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> deceased,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> under the age of 18,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in a designated combat zone,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a victim of tax-related identity theft,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a taxpayer substantially all of whose income consists of disability insurance benefits under section 223 of the Social Security Act or supplemental security income benefits under title XVI of the Social Security Act (including supplemental security income benefits of the type described in section 1616 of such Act or <ref>section 212 of Public Law 93–66</ref>), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a taxpayer who is an individual with adjusted gross income, as determined for the most recent taxable year for which such information is available, which does not exceed 200 percent of the applicable poverty level (as determined by the Secretary),</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> is currently under examination, litigation, criminal investigation, or levy, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> is currently subject to a proper exercise of a right of appeal under this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may retain and use—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an amount not in excess of 25 percent of the amount collected under any qualified tax collection contract for the costs of services performed under such contract, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an amount not in excess of 25 percent of such amount collected to fund the special compliance personnel program account under section 6307.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary shall keep adequate records regarding amounts so retained and used. The amount credited as paid by any taxpayer shall be determined without regard to this subsection.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No Federal liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The United States shall not be liable for any act or omission of any person performing services under a qualified tax collection contract.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of Fair Debt Collection Practices Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1692</ref> et seq.) shall apply to any qualified tax collection contract, except to the extent superseded by section 6304, section 7602(c), or by any other provision of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contracting priority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In contracting for the services of any person under this section, the Secretary shall utilize private collection contractors and debt collection centers on the schedule required under <ref>section 3711(g) of title 31</ref>, United States Code, including the technology and communications infrastructure established therein, to the extent such private collection contractors and debt collection centers are appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxpayers in presidentially declared disaster areas</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary may prescribe procedures under which a taxpayer determined to be affected by a Federally declared disaster (as defined by section 165(i)(5)) may request—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> relief from immediate collection measures by contractors under this section, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a return of the inactive tax receivable to the inventory of the Internal Revenue Service to be collected by an employee thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after the last day of each fiscal year (beginning with the first such fiscal year ending after the date of the enactment of this subsection), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report with respect to qualified tax collection contracts under this section which shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> annually, with respect to such fiscal year—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the total number and amount of tax receivables provided to each contractor for collection under this section,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the total amounts collected (and amounts of installment agreements entered into under subsection (b)(1)(B)) with respect to each contractor and the collection costs incurred (directly and indirectly) by the Internal Revenue Service with respect to such amounts,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the impact of such contracts on the total number and amount of unpaid assessments, and on the number and amount of assessments collected by Internal Revenue Service personnel after initial contact by a contractor,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the amount of fees retained by the Secretary under subsection (e) and a description of the use of such funds, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a disclosure safeguard report in a form similar to that required under section 6103(p)(5), and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> biannually (beginning with the second report submitted under this subsection)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an independent evaluation of contractor performance, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a measurement plan that includes a comparison of the best practices used by the private collectors to the collection techniques used by the Internal Revenue Service and mechanisms to identify and capture information on successful collection techniques used by the contractors that could be adopted by the Internal Revenue Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cross references</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For damages for certain unauthorized collection actions by persons performing services under a qualified tax collection contract, see section 7433A.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For application of Taxpayer Assistance Orders to persons performing services under a qualified tax collection contract, see section 7811(g).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–357, title VIII, § 881(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1625</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. C, title XXXII</ref>, §§ 32102(a)–(c), (e), (f)(1), 32103(a), <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1733–1736</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(351)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1201</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–25, title I, § 1205(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2019-07-01">July 1, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 989</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6307.</num>
<heading> Special compliance personnel program account</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of a special compliance personnel program account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish an account within the Department for carrying out a program consisting of the hiring, training, and employment of special compliance personnel, and shall transfer to such account from time to time amounts retained by the Secretary under section 6306(e)(2).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The program described in subsection (a) shall be subject to the following restrictions:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> No funds shall be transferred to such account except as described in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> No other funds from any other source shall be expended for special compliance personnel employed under such program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Notwithstanding any other authority, the Secretary is prohibited from spending funds out of such account for other than program costs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than March of each year, the Commissioner of Internal Revenue shall submit a report to the Committees on Finance and Appropriations of the Senate and the Committees on Ways and Means and Appropriations of the House of Representatives consisting of the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For the preceding fiscal year, all funds received in the account established under subsection (a), administrative and program costs for the program described in such subsection, the number of special compliance personnel hired and employed under the program, and the amount of revenue actually collected by such personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For the current fiscal year, all actual and estimated funds received or to be received in the account, all actual and estimated administrative and program costs, the number of all actual and estimated special compliance personnel hired and employed under the program, and the actual and estimated revenue actually collected or to be collected by such personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For the following fiscal year, an estimate of all funds to be received in the account, all estimated administrative and program costs, the estimated number of special compliance personnel hired and employed under the program, and the estimated revenue to be collected by such personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special compliance personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “special compliance personnel” means individuals employed by the Internal Revenue Service as field function collection officers or in a similar position, or employed to collect taxes using the automated collection system or an equivalent replacement system.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program costs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “program costs” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> total salaries (including locality pay and bonuses), benefits, and employment taxes for special compliance personnel employed or trained under the program described in subsection (a),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> direct overhead costs, salaries, benefits, and employment taxes relating to support staff, rental payments, office equipment and furniture, travel, data processing services, vehicle costs, utilities, communications, software, technology, postage, printing and reproduction, supplies and materials, lands and structures, insurance claims, and indemnities for special compliance personnel hired and employed under this section, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> reimbursement of the Internal Revenue Service or other government agencies for the cost of administering the qualified tax collection program under section 6306.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of subparagraph (B), the cost of management and supervision of special compliance personnel shall be taken into account as direct overhead costs to the extent such costs, when included in total program costs under this paragraph, do not represent more than 10 percent of such total costs.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. C, title XXXII, § 32103(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1736</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–25, title I, § 1205(d)</ref>, <date date="2019-07-01">July 1, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 989</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter B—</num>
<heading>Receipt of Payment</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6311.</num>
<heading> Payment of tax by commercially acceptable means</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to receive</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">It shall be lawful for the Secretary to receive for internal revenue taxes (or in payment for internal revenue stamps) any commercially acceptable means that the Secretary deems appropriate to the extent and under the conditions provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ultimate liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a check, money order, or other method of payment, including payment by credit card, debit card, or charge card so received is not duly paid, or is paid and subsequently charged back to the Secretary, the person by whom such check, or money order, or other method of payment has been tendered shall remain liable for the payment of the tax or for the stamps, and for all legal penalties and additions, to the same extent as if such check, money order, or other method of payment had not been tendered.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability of banks and others</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If any certified, treasurer’s, or cashier’s check (or other guaranteed draft), or any money order, or any other means of payment that has been guaranteed by a financial institution (such as a credit card, debit card, or charge card transaction which has been guaranteed expressly by a financial institution) so received is not duly paid, the United States shall, in addition to its right to exact payment from the party originally indebted therefor, have a lien for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the amount of such check (or draft) upon all assets of the financial institution on which drawn,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the amount of such money order upon all the assets of the issuer thereof, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the guaranteed amount of any other transaction upon all the assets of the institution making such guarantee,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">and such amount shall be paid out of such assets in preference to any other claims whatsoever against such financial institution, issuer, or guaranteeing institution, except the necessary costs and expenses of administration and the reimbursement of the United States for the amount expended in the redemption of the circulating notes of such financial institution.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment by other means</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to prescribe regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as the Secretary deems necessary to receive payment by commercially acceptable means, including regulations that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> specify which methods of payment by commercially acceptable means will be acceptable,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> specify when payment by such means will be considered received,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> identify types of nontax matters related to payment by such means that are to be resolved by persons ultimately liable for payment and financial intermediaries, without the involvement of the Secretary, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> ensure that tax matters will be resolved by the Secretary, without the involvement of financial intermediaries.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to enter into contracts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding <ref>section 3718(f) of title 31</ref>, United States Code, the Secretary is authorized to enter into contracts to obtain services related to receiving payment by other means where cost beneficial to the Government. The Secretary may not pay any fee or provide any other consideration under any such contract for the use of credit, debit, or charge cards for the payment of taxes imposed by subtitle A. The preceding sentence shall not apply to the extent that the Secretary ensures that any such fee or other consideration is fully recouped by the Secretary in the form of fees paid to the Secretary by persons paying taxes imposed under subtitle A with credit, debit, or charge cards pursuant to such contract. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, the Secretary shall seek to minimize the amount of any fee or other consideration that the Secretary pays under any such contract.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special provisions for use of credit cards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If use of credit cards is accepted as a method of payment of taxes pursuant to subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a payment of internal revenue taxes (or a payment for internal revenue stamps) by a person by use of a credit card shall not be subject to section 161 of the Truth in Lending Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1666</ref>), or to any similar provisions of State law, if the error alleged by the person is an error relating to the underlying tax liability, rather than an error relating to the credit card account such as a computational error or numerical transposition in the credit card transaction or an issue as to whether the person authorized payment by use of the credit card,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a payment of internal revenue taxes (or a payment for internal revenue stamps) shall not be subject to section 170 of the Truth in Lending Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1666i</ref>), or to any similar provisions of State law,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a payment of internal revenue taxes (or a payment for internal revenue stamps) by a person by use of a debit card shall not be subject to section 908 of the Electronic Fund Transfer Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1693f</ref>), or to any similar provisions of State law, if the error alleged by the person is an error relating to the underlying tax liability, rather than an error relating to the debit card account such as a computational error or numerical transposition in the debit card transaction or an issue as to whether the person authorized payment by use of the debit card,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the term “creditor” under section 103(g) of the Truth in Lending Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1602(g)</ref>) shall not include the Secretary with respect to credit card transactions in payment of internal revenue taxes (or payment for internal revenue stamps), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, in the case of payment made by credit card or debit card transaction of an amount owed to a person as the result of the correction of an error under section 161 of the Truth in Lending Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1666</ref>) or section 908 of the Electronic Fund Transfer Act (<ref>15 U.S.C. 1693f</ref>), the Secretary is authorized to provide such amount to such person as a credit to that person’s credit card or debit card account through the applicable credit card or debit card system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confidentiality of information</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as otherwise authorized by this subsection, no person may use or disclose any information relating to credit or debit card transactions obtained pursuant to section 6103(k)(9) other than for purposes directly related to the processing of such transactions, or the billing or collection of amounts charged or debited pursuant thereto.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Debit or credit card issuers or others acting on behalf of such issuers may also use and disclose such information for purposes directly related to servicing an issuer’s accounts.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Debit or credit card issuers or others directly involved in the processing of credit or debit card transactions or the billing or collection of amounts charged or debited thereto may also use and disclose such information for purposes directly related to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> statistical risk and profitability assessment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> transferring receivables, accounts, or interest therein;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> auditing the account information;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> complying with Federal, State, or local law; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> properly authorized civil, criminal, or regulatory investigation by Federal, State, or local authorities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Use and disclosure of information under this paragraph shall be made only to the extent authorized by written procedures promulgated by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cross reference</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2 fontsize7">For provision providing for civil damages for violation of paragraph (1), see section 7431.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 777</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title IV, § 448(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 817</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–34, title XII, § 1205(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 995</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title VI, § 6012(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 819</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. J, title IV, § 4003(k)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–910</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(280)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1197</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–25, title II, § 2303</ref>, <date date="2019-07-01">July 1, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1013</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 6312.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 92–5, title I, § 4(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1971-03-17">Mar. 17, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 5</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6313.</num>
<heading> Fractional parts of a cent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the payment of any tax imposed by this title, a fractional part of a cent shall be disregarded unless it amounts to one-half cent or more, in which case it shall be increased to 1 cent.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 778</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(a)(19)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1825</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6314.</num>
<heading> Receipt for taxes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall, upon request, give receipts for all sums collected by him, excepting only when the same are in payment for stamps sold and delivered; but no receipt shall be issued in lieu of a stamp representing a tax.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duplicate receipts for payment of estate taxes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall, upon request, give to the person paying the tax under chapter 11 (relating to the estate tax) duplicate receipts, either of which shall be sufficient evidence of such payment, and shall entitle the executor to be credited and allowed the amount thereof by any court having jurisdiction to audit or settle his accounts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cross references</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For receipt required to be furnished by employer to employee with respect to employment taxes, see section 6051.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For receipt of discharge of fiduciary from personal liability, see section 2204.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 778</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–614, title I, § 101(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1837</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6315.</num>
<heading> Payments of estimated income tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Payment of the estimated income tax, or any installment thereof, shall be considered payment on account of the income taxes imposed by subtitle A for the taxable year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 778</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6316.</num>
<heading> Payment by foreign currency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized in his discretion to allow payment of taxes in the currency of a foreign country under such circumstances and subject to such conditions as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 778</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6317.</num>
<heading> Payments of Federal unemployment tax for calendar quarter</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Payment of Federal unemployment tax for a calendar quarter or other period within a calendar year pursuant to section 6157 shall be considered payment on account of the tax imposed by chapter 23 of such calendar year.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–53, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1969-08-07">Aug. 7, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 92</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–76, title II, § 231(b)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1983-08-12">Aug. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VII, § 7106(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3773</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter C—</num>
<heading>Lien for Taxes</heading>
<part>
<num>PART I—</num>
<heading>DUE PROCESS FOR LIENS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6320.</num>
<heading> Notice and opportunity for hearing upon filing of notice of lien</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement of notice</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall notify in writing the person described in section 6321 of the filing of a notice of lien under section 6323.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time and method for notice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The notice required under paragraph (1) shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> given in person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> left at the dwelling or usual place of business of such person; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> sent by certified or registered mail to such person’s last known address,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">not more than 5 business days after the day of the filing of the notice of lien.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information included with notice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The notice required under paragraph (1) shall include in simple and nontechnical terms—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the amount of unpaid tax;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the right of the person to request a hearing during the 30-day period beginning on the day after the 5-day period described in paragraph (2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the administrative appeals available to the taxpayer with respect to such lien and the procedures relating to such appeals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the provisions of this title and procedures relating to the release of liens on property; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the provisions of section 7345 relating to the certification of seriously delinquent tax debts and the denial, revocation, or limitation of passports of individuals with such debts pursuant to section 32101 of the FAST Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Right to fair hearing</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the person requests a hearing in writing under subsection (a)(3)(B) and states the grounds for the requested hearing, such hearing shall be held by the Internal Revenue Service Independent Office of Appeals.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> One hearing per period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A person shall be entitled to only one hearing under this section with respect to the taxable period to which the unpaid tax specified in subsection (a)(3)(A) relates.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Impartial officer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The hearing under this subsection shall be conducted by an officer or employee who has had no prior involvement with respect to the unpaid tax specified in subsection (a)(3)(A) before the first hearing under this section or section 6330. A taxpayer may waive the requirement of this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with section 6330</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To the extent practicable, a hearing under this section shall be held in conjunction with a hearing under section 6330.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conduct of hearing; review; suspensions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, subsections (c), (d) (other than paragraph (3)(B) thereof), (e), and (g) of section 6330 shall apply.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title III, § 3401(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 746</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–432, div. A, title IV, § 407(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2962</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. C, title XXXII, § 32101(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1731</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. Q, title IV, § 424(c)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 3125</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–25, title I, § 1001(b)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2019-07-01">July 1, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 985</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num>PART II—</num>
<heading>LIENS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6321.</num>
<heading> Lien for taxes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any person liable to pay any tax neglects or refuses to pay the same after demand, the amount (including any interest, additional amount, addition to tax, or assessable penalty, together with any costs that may accrue in addition thereto) shall be a lien in favor of the United States upon all property and rights to property, whether real or personal, belonging to such person.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 779</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6322.</num>
<heading> Period of lien</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Unless another date is specifically fixed by law, the lien imposed by section 6321 shall arise at the time the assessment is made and shall continue until the liability for the amount so assessed (or a judgment against the taxpayer arising out of such liability) is satisfied or becomes unenforceable by reason of lapse of time.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 779</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–719, title I, § 113(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1146</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6323.</num>
<heading> Validity and priority against certain persons</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purchasers, holders of security interests, mechanic’s lienors, and judgment lien creditors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The lien imposed by section 6321 shall not be valid as against any purchaser, holder of a security interest, mechanic’s lienor, or judgment lien creditor until notice thereof which meets the requirements of subsection (f) has been filed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protection for certain interests even though notice filed</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Even though notice of a lien imposed by section 6321 has been filed, such lien shall not be valid—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Securities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">With respect to a security (as defined in subsection (h)(4))—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> as against a purchaser of such security who at the time of purchase did not have actual notice or knowledge of the existence of such lien; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> as against a holder of a security interest in such security who, at the time such interest came into existence, did not have actual notice or knowledge of the existence of such lien.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Motor vehicles</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">With respect to a motor vehicle (as defined in subsection (h)(3)), as against a purchaser of such motor vehicle, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> at the time of the purchase such purchaser did not have actual notice or knowledge of the existence of such lien, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> before the purchaser obtains such notice or knowledge, he has acquired possession of such motor vehicle and has not thereafter relinquished possession of such motor vehicle to the seller or his agent.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personal property purchased at retail</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to tangible personal property purchased at retail, as against a purchaser in the ordinary course of the seller’s trade or business, unless at the time of such purchase such purchaser intends such purchase to (or knows such purchase will) hinder, evade, or defeat the collection of any tax under this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personal property purchased in casual sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to household goods, personal effects, or other tangible personal property described in section 6334(a) purchased (not for resale) in a casual sale for less than $1,000, as against the purchaser, but only if such purchaser does not have actual notice or knowledge (A) of the existence of such lien, or (B) that this sale is one of a series of sales.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personal property subject to possessory lien</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to tangible personal property subject to a lien under local law securing the reasonable price of the repair or improvement of such property, as against a holder of such a lien, if such holder is, and has been, continuously in possession of such property from the time such lien arose.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Real property tax and special assessment liens</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">With respect to real property, as against a holder of a lien upon such property, if such lien is entitled under local law to priority over security interests in such property which are prior in time, and such lien secures payment of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a tax of general application levied by any taxing authority based upon the value of such property;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a special assessment imposed directly upon such property by any taxing authority, if such assessment is imposed for the purpose of defraying the cost of any public improvement; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> charges for utilities or public services furnished to such property by the United States, a State or political subdivision thereof, or an instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Residential property subject to a mechanic’s lien for certain repairs and improvements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to real property subject to a lien for repair or improvement of a personal residence (containing not more than four dwelling units) occupied by the owner of such residence, as against a mechanic’s lienor, but only if the contract price on the contract with the owner is not more than $5,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Attorneys’ liens</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to a judgment or other amount in settlement of a claim or of a cause of action, as against an attorney who, under local law, holds a lien upon or a contract enforcible against such judgment or amount, to the extent of his reasonable compensation for obtaining such judgment or procuring such settlement, except that this paragraph shall not apply to any judgment or amount in settlement of a claim or of a cause of action against the United States to the extent that the United States offsets such judgment or amount against any liability of the taxpayer to the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain insurance contracts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">With respect to a life insurance, endowment, or annuity contract, as against the organization which is the insurer under such contract, at any time—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> before such organization had actual notice or knowledge of the existence of such lien;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> after such organization had such notice or knowledge, with respect to advances required to be made automatically to maintain such contract in force under an agreement entered into before such organization had such notice or knowledge; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> after satisfaction of a levy pursuant to section 6332(b), unless and until the Secretary delivers to such organization a notice, executed after the date of such satisfaction, of the existence of such lien.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit-secured loans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to a savings deposit, share, or other account with an institution described in section 581 or 591, to the extent of any loan made by such institution without actual notice or knowledge of the existence of such lien, as against such institution, if such loan is secured by such account.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protection for certain commercial transactions financing agreements, etc.</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">To the extent provided in this subsection, even though notice of a lien imposed by section 6321 has been filed, such lien shall not be valid with respect to a security interest which came into existence after tax lien filing but which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> is in qualified property covered by the terms of a written agreement entered into before tax lien filing and constituting—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a commercial transactions financing agreement,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a real property construction or improvement financing agreement, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an obligatory disbursement agreement, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is protected under local law against a judgment lien arising, as of the time of tax lien filing, out of an unsecured obligation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commercial transactions financing agreement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “commercial transactions financing agreement” means an agreement (entered into by a person in the course of his trade or business)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to make loans to the taxpayer to be secured by commercial financing security acquired by the taxpayer in the ordinary course of his trade or business, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to purchase commercial financing security (other than inventory) acquired by the taxpayer in the ordinary course of his trade or business;</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">but such an agreement shall be treated as coming within the term only to the extent that such loan or purchase is made before the 46th day after the date of tax lien filing or (if earlier) before the lender or purchaser had actual notice or knowledge of such tax lien filing.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on qualified property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “qualified property”, when used with respect to a commercial transactions financing agreement, includes only commercial financing security acquired by the taxpayer before the 46th day after the date of tax lien filing.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commercial financing security defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “commercial financing security” means (i) paper of a kind ordinarily arising in commercial transactions, (ii) accounts receivable, (iii) mortgages on real property, and (iv) inventory.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purchaser treated as acquiring security interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A person who satisfies subparagraph (A) by reason of clause (ii) thereof shall be treated as having acquired a security interest in commercial financing security</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Real property construction or improvement financing agreement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “real property construction or improvement financing agreement” means an agreement to make cash disbursements to finance—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the construction or improvement of real property,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a contract to construct or improve real property, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the raising or harvesting of a farm crop or the raising of livestock or other animals.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">For purposes of clause (iii), the furnishing of goods and services shall be treated as the disbursement of cash.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on qualified property</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “qualified property”, when used with respect to a real property construction or improvement financing agreement, includes only—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of subparagraph (A)(i), the real property with respect to which the construction or improvement has been or is to be made,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of subparagraph (A)(ii), the proceeds of the contract described therein, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in the case of subparagraph (A)(iii), property subject to the lien imposed by section 6321 at the time of tax lien filing and the crop or the livestock or other animals referred to in subparagraph (A)(iii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Obligatory disbursement agreement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “obligatory disbursement agreement” means an agreement (entered into by a person in the course of his trade or business) to make disbursements, but such an agreement shall be treated as coming within the term only to the extent of disbursements which are required to be made by reason of the intervention of the rights of a person other than the taxpayer.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on qualified property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “qualified property”, when used with respect to an obligatory disbursement agreement, means property subject to the lien imposed by section 6321 at the time of tax lien filing and (to the extent that the acquisition is directly traceable to the disbursements referred to in subparagraph (A)) property acquired by the taxpayer after tax lien filing.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules for surety agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Where the obligatory disbursement agreement is an agreement ensuring the performance of a contract between the taxpayer and another person—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the term “qualified property” shall be treated as also including the proceeds of the contract the performance of which was ensured, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if the contract the performance of which was ensured was a contract to construct or improve real property, to produce goods, or to furnish services, the term “qualified property” shall be treated as also including any tangible personal property used by the taxpayer in the performance of such ensured contract.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 45-day period for making disbursements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Even though notice of a lien imposed by section 6321 has been filed, such lien shall not be valid with respect to a security interest which came into existence after tax lien filing by reason of disbursements made before the 46th day after the date of tax lien filing, or (if earlier) before the person making such disbursements had actual notice or knowledge of tax lien filing, but only if such security interest—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> is in property (A) subject, at the time of tax lien filing, to the lien imposed by section 6321, and (B) covered by the terms of a written agreement entered into before tax lien filing, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is protected under local law against a judgment lien arising, as of the time of tax lien filing, out of an unsecured obligation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority of interest and expenses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the lien imposed by section 6321 is not valid as against a lien or security interest, the priority of such lien or security interest shall extend to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any interest or carrying charges upon the obligation secured,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the reasonable charges and expenses of an indenture trustee or agent holding the security interest for the benefit of the holder of the security interest,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the reasonable expenses, including reasonable compensation for attorneys, actually incurred in collecting or enforcing the obligation secured,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the reasonable costs of insuring, preserving, or repairing the property to which the lien or security interest relates,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> the reasonable costs of insuring payment of the obligation secured, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> amounts paid to satisfy any lien on the property to which the lien or security interest relates, but only if the lien so satisfied is entitled to priority over the lien imposed by section 6321,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">to the extent that, under local law, any such item has the same priority as the lien or security interest to which it relates.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Place for filing notice; form</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Place for filing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The notice referred to in subsection (a) shall be filed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Under State laws</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Real property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In the case of real property, in one office within the State (or the county, or other governmental subdivision), as designated by the laws of such State, in which the property subject to the lien is situated; and</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personal property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In the case of personal property, whether tangible or intangible, in one office within the State (or the county, or other governmental subdivision), as designated by the laws of such State, in which the property subject to the lien is situated, except that State law merely conforming to or reenacting Federal law establishing a national filing system does not constitute a second office for filing as designated by the laws of such State; or</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> With clerk of district court</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the office of the clerk of the United States district court for the judicial district in which the property subject to the lien is situated, whenever the State has not by law designated one office which meets the requirements of subparagraph (A); or</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> With Recorder of Deeds of the District of Columbia</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the office of the Recorder of Deeds of the District of Columbia, if the property subject to the lien is situated in the District of Columbia.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Situs of property subject to lien</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of paragraphs (1) and (4), property shall be deemed to be situated—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Real property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of real property, at its physical location; or</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Personal property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of personal property, whether tangible or intangible, at the residence of the taxpayer at the time the notice of lien is filed.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of paragraph (2)(B), the residence of a corporation or partnership shall be deemed to be the place at which the principal executive office of the business is located, and the residence of a taxpayer whose residence is without the United States shall be deemed to be in the District of Columbia.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Form</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The form and content of the notice referred to in subsection (a) shall be prescribed by the Secretary. Such notice shall be valid notwithstanding any other provision of law regarding the form or content of a notice of lien.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indexing required with respect to certain real property</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of real property, if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> under the laws of the State in which the real property is located, a deed is not valid as against a purchaser of the property who (at the time of purchase) does not have actual notice or knowledge of the existence of such deed unless the fact of filing of such deed has been entered and recorded in a public index at the place of filing in such a manner that a reasonable inspection of the index will reveal the existence of the deed, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> there is maintained (at the applicable office under paragraph (1)) an adequate system for the public indexing of Federal tax liens,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">then the notice of lien referred to in subsection (a) shall not be treated as meeting the filing requirements under paragraph (1) unless the fact of filing is entered and recorded in the index referred to in subparagraph (B) in such a manner that a reasonable inspection of the index will reveal the existence of the lien.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> National filing systems</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The filing of a notice of lien shall be governed solely by this title and shall not be subject to any other Federal law establishing a place or places for the filing of liens or encumbrances under a national filing system.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refiling of notice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Unless notice of lien is refiled in the manner prescribed in paragraph (2) during the required refiling period, such notice of lien shall be treated as filed on the date on which it is filed (in accordance with subsection (f)) after the expiration of such refiling period.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Place for filing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A notice of lien refiled during the required refiling period shall be effective only—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such notice of lien is refiled in the office in which the prior notice of lien was filed, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of real property, the fact of refiling is entered and recorded in an index to the extent required by subsection (f)(4); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in any case in which, 90 days or more prior to the date of a refiling of notice of lien under subparagraph (A), the Secretary received written information (in the manner prescribed in regulations issued by the Secretary) concerning a change in the taxpayer’s residence, if a notice of such lien is also filed in accordance with subsection (f) in the State in which such residence is located.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required refiling period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of any notice of lien, the term “required refiling period” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the one-year period ending 30 days after the expiration of 10 years after the date of the assessment of the tax, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the one-year period ending with the expiration of 10 years after the close of the preceding required refiling period for such notice of lien.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transitional rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraph (3), if the assessment of the tax was made before <date date="1962-01-01">January 1, 1962</date>, the first required refiling period shall be the calendar year 1967.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section and section 6324—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Security interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “security interest” means any interest in property acquired by contract for the purpose of securing payment or performance of an obligation or indemnifying against loss or liability. A security interest exists at any time (A) if, at such time, the property is in existence and the interest has become protected under local law against a subsequent judgment lien arising out of an unsecured obligation, and (B) to the extent that, at such time, the holder has parted with money or money’s worth.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mechanic’s lienor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “mechanic’s lienor” means any person who under local law has a lien on real property (or on the proceeds of a contract relating to real property) for services, labor, or materials furnished in connection with the construction or improvement of such property. For purposes of the preceding sentence, a person has a lien on the earliest date such lien becomes valid under local law against subsequent purchasers without actual notice, but not before he begins to furnish the services, labor, or materials.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Motor vehicle</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “motor vehicle” means a self-propelled vehicle which is registered for highway use under the laws of any State or foreign country.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Security</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “security” means any bond, debenture, note, or certificate or other evidence of indebtedness, issued by a corporation or a government or political subdivision thereof, with interest coupons or in registered form, share of stock, voting trust certificate, or any certificate of interest or participation in, certificate of deposit or receipt for, temporary or interim certificate for, or warrant or right to subscribe to or purchase, any of the foregoing; negotiable instrument; or money.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax lien filing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “tax lien filing” means the filing of notice (referred to in subsection (a)) of the lien imposed by section 6321.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purchaser</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “purchaser” means a person who, for adequate and full consideration in money or money’s worth, acquires an interest (other than a lien or security interest) in property which is valid under local law against subsequent purchasers without actual notice. In applying the preceding sentence for purposes of subsection (a) of this section, and for purposes of section 6324—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a lease of property,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a written executory contract to purchase or lease property,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an option to purchase or lease property or any interest therein, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an option to renew or extend a lease of property,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">which is not a lien or security interest shall be treated as an interest in property.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Actual notice or knowledge</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subchapter, an organization shall be deemed for purposes of a particular transaction to have actual notice or knowledge of any fact from the time such fact is brought to the attention of the individual conducting such transaction, and in any event from the time such fact would have been brought to such individual’s attention if the organization had exercised due diligence. An organization exercises due diligence if it maintains reasonable routines for communicating significant information to the person conducting the transaction and there is reasonable compliance with the routine. Due diligence does not require an individual acting for the organization to communicate information unless such communication is part of his regular duties or unless he has reason to know of the transaction and that the transaction would be materially affected by the information.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subrogation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Where, under local law, one person is subrogated to the rights of another with respect to a lien or interest, such person shall be subrogated to such rights for purposes of any lien imposed by section 6321 or 6324.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forfeitures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subchapter, a forfeiture under local law of property seized by a law enforcement agency of a State, county, or other local governmental subdivision shall relate back to the time of seizure, except that this paragraph shall not apply to the extent that under local law the holder of an intervening claim or interest would have priority over the interest of the State, county, or other local governmental subdivision in the property.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cost-of-living adjustment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of notices of liens imposed by section 6321 which are filed in any calendar year after 1998, each of the dollar amounts under paragraph (4) or (7) of subsection (b) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such dollar amount, multiplied by</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year, determined by substituting “calendar year 1996” for “calendar year 2016” in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">If any amount as adjusted under the preceding sentence is not a multiple of $10, such amount shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $10.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withdrawal of notice in certain circumstances</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may withdraw a notice of a lien filed under this section and this chapter shall be applied as if the withdrawn notice had not been filed, if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the filing of such notice was premature or otherwise not in accordance with administrative procedures of the Secretary,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the taxpayer has entered into an agreement under section 6159 to satisfy the tax liability for which the lien was imposed by means of installment payments, unless such agreement provides otherwise,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the withdrawal of such notice will facilitate the collection of the tax liability, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> with the consent of the taxpayer or the National Taxpayer Advocate, the withdrawal of such notice would be in the best interests of the taxpayer (as determined by the National Taxpayer Advocate) and the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">Any such withdrawal shall be made by filing notice at the same office as the withdrawn notice. A copy of such notice of withdrawal shall be provided to the taxpayer.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice to credit agencies, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon written request by the taxpayer with respect to whom a notice of a lien was withdrawn under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall promptly make reasonable efforts to notify credit reporting agencies, and any financial institution or creditor whose name and address is specified in such request, of the withdrawal of such notice. Any such request shall be in such form as the Secretary may prescribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 779</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–272, title II, § 236(a)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="1964-02-26">Feb. 26, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 127</ref>, 128; <ref>Pub. L. 89–493, § 17(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-07-05">July 5, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 266</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–719, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1125</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XII, § 1202(h)(2)</ref>, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), title XX, § 2008(c), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1688</ref>, 1834, 1892; <ref>Pub. L. 95–600, title VII, § 702(q)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2937</ref>, 2938; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title XV, § 1569(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2764</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1015(s)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3573</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XI</ref>, §§ 11317(b), 11704(a)(26), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–458</ref>, 1388–519; <ref>Pub. L. 104–168, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-07-30">July 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1460</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title I, § 1102(d)(1)(A)</ref>, title III, § 3435(a), (b), <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 704</ref>, 760, 761; <ref>Pub. L. 115–97, title I, § 11002(d)(1)(HH)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 2060</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6324.</num>
<heading> Special liens for estate and gift taxes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liens for estate tax</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Upon gross estate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Unless the estate tax imposed by chapter 11 is sooner paid in full, or becomes unenforceable by reason of lapse of time, it shall be a lien upon the gross estate of the decedent for 10 years from the date of death, except that such part of the gross estate as is used for the payment of charges against the estate and expenses of its administration, allowed by any court having jurisdiction thereof, shall be divested of such lien.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability of transferees and others</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the estate tax imposed by chapter 11 is not paid when due, then the spouse, transferee, trustee (except the trustee of an employees’ trust which meets the requirements of section 401(a)), surviving tenant, person in possession of the property by reason of the exercise, nonexercise, or release of a power of appointment, or beneficiary, who receives, or has on the date of the decedent’s death, property included in the gross estate under sections 2034 to 2042, inclusive, to the extent of the value, at the time of the decedent’s death, of such property, shall be personally liable for such tax. Any part of such property transferred by (or transferred by a transferee of) such spouse, transferee, trustee, surviving tenant, person in possession, or beneficiary, to a purchaser or holder of a security interest shall be divested of the lien provided in paragraph (1) and a like lien shall then attach to all the property of such spouse, transferee, trustee, surviving tenant, person in possession, or beneficiary, or transferee of any such person, except any part transferred to a purchaser or a holder of a security interest.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuance after discharge of fiduciary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The provisions of section 2204 (relating to discharge of fiduciary from personal liability) shall not operate as a release of any part of the gross estate from the lien for any deficiency that may thereafter be determined to be due, unless such part of the gross estate (or any interest therein) has been transferred to a purchaser or a holder of a security interest, in which case such part (or such interest) shall not be subject to a lien or to any claim or demand for any such deficiency, but the lien shall attach to the consideration received from such purchaser or holder of a security interest, by the heirs, legatees, devisees, or distributees.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lien for gift tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c), unless the gift tax imposed by chapter 12 is sooner paid in full or becomes unenforceable by reason of lapse of time, such tax shall be a lien upon all gifts made during the period for which the return was filed, for 10 years from the date the gifts are made. If the tax is not paid when due, the donee of any gift shall be personally liable for such tax to the extent of the value of such gift. Any part of the property comprised in the gift transferred by the donee (or by a transferee of the donee) to a purchaser or holder of a security interest shall be divested of the lien imposed by this subsection and such lien, to the extent of the value of such gift, shall attach to all the property (including after-acquired property) of the donee (or the transferee) except any part transferred to a purchaser or holder of a security interest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The lien imposed by subsection (a) or (b) shall not be valid as against a mechanic’s lienor and, subject to the conditions provided by section 6323(b) (relating to protection for certain interests even though notice filed), shall not be valid with respect to any lien or interest described in section 6323(b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If a lien imposed by subsection (a) or (b) is not valid as against a lien or security interest, the priority of such lien or security interest shall extend to any item described in section 6323(e) (relating to priority of interest and expenses) to the extent that, under local law, such item has the same priority as the lien or security interest to which it relates.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 780</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–272, title II, § 236(b)</ref>, (c)(2), <date date="1964-02-26">Feb. 26, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 127</ref>, 128; <ref>Pub. L. 89–719, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1132</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–614, title I</ref>, §§ 101(d)(2), 102(d)(7), <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1837</ref>, 1842.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6324A.</num>
<heading> Special lien for estate tax deferred under section 6166</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of any estate with respect to which an election has been made under section 6166, if the executor makes an election under this section (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary shall by regulations prescribe) and files the agreement referred to in subsection (c), the deferred amount (plus any interest, additional amount, addition to tax, assessable penalty, and costs attributable to the deferred amount) shall be a lien in favor of the United States on the section 6166 lien property.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Section 6166 lien property</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “section 6166 lien property” means interests in real and other property to the extent such interests—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> can be expected to survive the deferral period, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> are designated in the agreement referred to in subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum value of required property</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The maximum value of the property which the Secretary may require as section 6166 lien property with respect to any estate shall be a value which is not greater than the sum of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the deferred amount, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the required interest amount.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of the preceding sentence, the value of any property shall be determined as of the date prescribed by section 6151(a) for payment of the tax imposed by chapter 11 and shall be determined by taking into account any encumbrance such as a lien under section 6324B.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partial substitution of bond for lien</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the value required as section 6166 lien property pursuant to paragraph (2) exceeds the value of the interests in property covered by the agreement referred to in subsection (c), the Secretary may accept bond in an amount equal to such excess conditioned on the payment of the amount extended in accordance with the terms of such extension.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The agreement referred to in this subsection is a written agreement signed by each person in being who has an interest (whether or not in possession) in any property designated in such agreement—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> consenting to the creation of the lien under this section with respect to such property, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> designating a responsible person who shall be the agent for the beneficiaries of the estate and for the persons who have consented to the creation of the lien in dealings with the Secretary on matters arising under section 6166 or this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement that lien be filed</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The lien imposed by this section shall not be valid as against any purchaser, holder of a security interest, mechanic’s lien, or judgment lien creditor until notice thereof which meets the requirements of section 6323(f) has been filed by the Secretary. Such notice shall not be required to be refiled.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period of lien</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The lien imposed by this section shall arise at the time the executor is discharged from liability under section 2204 (or, if earlier, at the time notice is filed pursuant to paragraph (1)) and shall continue until the liability for the deferred amount is satisfied or becomes unenforceable by reason of lapse of time.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priorities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Even though notice of a lien imposed by this section has been filed as provided in paragraph (1), such lien shall not be valid—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Real property tax and special assessment liens</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To the extent provided in section 6323(b)(6).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Real property subject to a mechanic’s lien for repairs and improvement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of any real property subject to a lien for repair or improvement, as against a mechanic’s lienor.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Real property construction or improvement financing agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">As against any security interest set forth in paragraph (3) of section 6323(c) (whether such security interest came into existence before or after tax lien filing).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">Subparagraphs (B) and (C) shall not apply to any security interest which came into existence after the date on which the Secretary filed notice (in a manner similar to notice filed under section 6323(f)) that payment of the deferred amount has been accelerated under section 6166(g).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lien to be in lieu of section 6324 lien</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If there is a lien under this section on any property with respect to any estate, there shall not be any lien under section 6324 on such property with respect to the same estate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional lien property required in certain cases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If at any time the value of the property covered by the agreement is less than the unpaid portion of the deferred amount and the required interest amount, the Secretary may require the addition of property to the agreement (but he may not require under this paragraph that the value of the property covered by the agreement exceed such unpaid portion). If property having the required value is not added to the property covered by the agreement (or if other security equal to the required value is not furnished) within 90 days after notice and demand therefor by the Secretary, the failure to comply with the preceding sentence shall be treated as an act accelerating payment of the installments under section 6166(g).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lien to be in lieu of bond</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may not require under section 6165 the furnishing of any bond for the payment of any tax to which an agreement which meets the requirements of subsection (c) applies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deferred amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “deferred amount” means the aggregate amount deferred under section 6166 (determined as of the date prescribed by section 6151(a) for payment of the tax imposed by chapter 11).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required interest amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “required interest amount” means the aggregate amount of interest which will be payable over the first 4 years of the deferral period with respect to the deferred amount (determined as of the date prescribed by section 6151(a) for the payment of the tax imposed by chapter 11).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deferral period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “deferral period” means the period for which the payment of tax is deferred pursuant to the election under section 6166.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of definitions in case of deficiencies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a deficiency, a separate deferred amount, required interest amount, and deferral period shall be determined as of the due date of the first installment after the deficiency is prorated to installments under section 6166.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XX, § 2004(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1868</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–600, title VII, § 702(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2929</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–34, title IV, § 422(e)(6)(A)</ref>–(C), <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6324B.</num>
<heading> Special lien for additional estate tax attributable to farm, etc., valuation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of any interest in qualified real property (within the meaning of section 2032A(b)), an amount equal to the adjusted tax difference attributable to such interest (within the meaning of section 2032A(c)(2)(B)) shall be a lien in favor of the United States on the property in which such interest exists.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period of lien</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The lien imposed by this section shall arise at the time an election is filed under section 2032A and shall continue with respect to any interest in the qualified real property—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> until the liability for tax under subsection (c) of section 2032A with respect to such interest has been satisfied or has become unenforceable by reason of lapse of time, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> until it is established to the satisfaction of the Secretary that no further tax liability may arise under section 2032A(c) with respect to such interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain rules and definitions made applicable</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The rule set forth in paragraphs (1), (3), and (4) of section 6324A(d) shall apply with respect to the lien imposed by this section as if it were a lien imposed by section 6324A.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified real property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “qualified real property” includes qualified replacement property (within the meaning of section 2032A(h)(3)(B)) and qualified exchange property (within the meaning of section 2032A(i)(3)).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Substitution of security for lien</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">To the extent provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the furnishing of security may be substituted for the lien imposed by this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XX, § 2003(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1861</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–600, title VII, § 702(r)(4)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2939</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–222, title I, § 108(d)</ref>, <date date="1980-04-01">Apr. 1, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 228</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–34, title IV, § 421(d)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 309</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6325.</num>
<heading> Release of lien or discharge of property</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Release of lien</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary shall issue a certificate of release of any lien imposed with respect to any internal revenue tax not later than 30 days after the day on which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability satisfied or unenforceable</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary finds that the liability for the amount assessed, together with all interest in respect thereof, has been fully satisfied or has become legally unenforceable; or</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bond accepted</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is furnished to the Secretary and accepted by him a bond that is conditioned upon the payment of the amount assessed, together with all interest in respect thereof, within the time prescribed by law (including any extension of such time), and that is in accordance with such requirements relating to terms, conditions, and form of the bond and sureties thereon, as may be specified by such regulations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Discharge of property</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Property double the amount of the liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary may issue a certificate of discharge of any part of the property subject to any lien imposed under this chapter if the Secretary finds that the fair market value of that part of such property remaining subject to the lien is at least double the amount of the unsatisfied liability secured by such lien and the amount of all other liens upon such property which have priority over such lien.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Part payment; interest of United States valueless</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary may issue a certificate of discharge of any part of the property subject to the lien if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> there is paid over to the Secretary in partial satisfaction of the liability secured by the lien an amount determined by the Secretary, which shall not be less than the value, as determined by the Secretary, of the interest of the United States in the part to be so discharged, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines at any time that the interest of the United States in the part to be so discharged has no value.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">In determining the value of the interest of the United States in the part to be so discharged, the Secretary shall give consideration to the value of such part and to such liens thereon as have priority over the lien of the United States.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Substitution of proceeds of sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary may issue a certificate of discharge of any part of the property subject to the lien if such part of the property is sold and, pursuant to an agreement with the Secretary, the proceeds of such sale are to be held, as a fund subject to the liens and claims of the United States, in the same manner and with the same priority as such liens and claims had with respect to the discharged property.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Right of substitution of value</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">At the request of the owner of any property subject to any lien imposed by this chapter, the Secretary shall issue a certificate of discharge of such property if such owner—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> deposits with the Secretary an amount of money equal to the value of the interest of the United States (as determined by the Secretary) in the property; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> furnishes a bond acceptable to the Secretary in a like amount.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refund of deposit with interest and release of bond</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall refund the amount so deposited (and shall pay interest at the overpayment rate under section 6621), and shall release such bond, to the extent that the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the unsatisfied liability giving rise to the lien can be satisfied from a source other than such property; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the value of the interest of the United States in the property is less than the Secretary’s prior determination of such value.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of deposit, etc., if action to contest lien not filed</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If no action is filed under section 7426(a)(4) within the period prescribed therefor, the Secretary shall, within 60 days after the expiration of such period—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> apply the amount deposited, or collect on such bond, to the extent necessary to satisfy the unsatisfied liability secured by the lien; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> refund (with interest as described in subparagraph (B)) any portion of the amount deposited which is not used to satisfy such liability.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply if the owner of the property is the person whose unsatisfied liability gave rise to the lien.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Estate or gift tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary may issue a certificate of discharge of any or all of the property subject to any lien imposed by section 6324 if the Secretary finds that the liability secured by such lien has been fully satisfied or provided for.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subordination of lien</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary may issue a certificate of subordination of any lien imposed by this chapter upon any part of the property subject to such lien if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> there is paid over to the Secretary an amount equal to the amount of the lien or interest to which the certificate subordinates the lien of the United States,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary believes that the amount realizable by the United States from the property to which the certificate relates, or from any other property subject to the lien, will ultimately be increased by reason of the issuance of such certificate and that the ultimate collection of the tax liability will be facilitated by such subordination, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in the case of any lien imposed by section 6324B, if the Secretary determines that the United States will be adequately secured after such subordination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonattachment of lien</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary determines that, because of confusion of names or otherwise, any person (other than the person against whom the tax was assessed) is or may be injured by the appearance that a notice of lien filed under section 6323 refers to such person, the Secretary may issue a certificate that the lien does not attach to the property of such person.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of certificate</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conclusiveness</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), if a certificate is issued pursuant to this section by the Secretary and is filed in the same office as the notice of lien to which it relates (if such notice of lien has been filed) such certificate shall have the following effect:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a certificate of release, such certificate shall be conclusive that the lien referred to in such certificate is extinguished;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a certificate of discharge, such certificate shall be conclusive that the property covered by such certificate is discharged from the lien;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of a certificate of subordination, such certificate shall be conclusive that the lien or interest to which the lien of the United States is subordinated is superior to the lien of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> in the case of a certificate of nonattachment, such certificate shall be conclusive that the lien of the United States does not attach to the property of the person referred to in such certificate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Revocation of certificate of release or non­attachment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If the Secretary determines that a certificate of release or nonattachment of a lien imposed by section 6321 was issued erroneously or improvidently, or if a certificate of release of such lien was issued pursuant to a collateral agreement entered into in connection with a compromise under section 7122 which has been breached, and if the period of limitation on collection after assessment has not expired, the Secretary may revoke such certificate and reinstate the lien—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by mailing notice of such revocation to the person against whom the tax was assessed at his last known address, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by filing notice of such revocation in the same office in which the notice of lien to which it relates was filed (if such notice of lien had been filed).</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">Such reinstated lien (i) shall be effective on the date notice of revocation is mailed to the taxpayer in accordance with the provisions of subparagraph (A), but not earlier than the date on which any required filing of notice of revocation is filed in accordance with the provisions of subparagraph (B), and (ii) shall have the same force and effect (as of such date), until the expiration of the period of limitation on collection after assessment, as a lien imposed by section 6321 (relating to lien for taxes).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certificates void under certain conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, any lien imposed by this chapter shall attach to any property with respect to which a certificate of discharge has been issued if the person liable for the tax reacquires such property after such certificate has been issued.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Filing of certificates and notices</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a certificate or notice issued pursuant to this section may not be filed in the office designated by State law in which the notice of lien imposed by section 6321 is filed, such certificate or notice shall be effective if filed in the office of the clerk of the United States district court for the judicial district in which such office is situated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cross reference</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2 fontsize7">For provisions relating to bonds, see chapter 73 (sec. 7101 and following).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 783</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–866, title I, § 77</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1662</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–719, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1133</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–600, title V, § 513(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2883</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–248, title III, § 348(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 638</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title III, § 3106(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 732</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6326.</num>
<heading> Administrative appeal of liens</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In such form and at such time as the Secretary shall prescribe by regulations, any person shall be allowed to appeal to the Secretary after the filing of a notice of a lien under this subchapter on the property or the rights to property of such person for a release of such lien alleging an error in the filing of the notice of such lien.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certificate of release</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary determines that the filing of the notice of any lien was erroneous, the Secretary shall expeditiously (and, to the extent practicable, within 14 days after such determination) issue a certificate of release of such lien and shall include in such certificate a statement that such filing was erroneous.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VI, § 6238(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3743</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6327.</num>
<heading> Cross references</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For lien in case of tax on distilled spirits, see section 5004.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For exclusion of tax liability from discharge in cases under title 11 of the United States Code, see section 523 of such title 11.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For recognition of tax liens in cases under title 11 of the United States Code, see sections 545 and 724 of such title 11.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For collection of taxes in connection with plans for individuals with regular income in cases under title 11 of the United States Code, see section 1328 of such title 11.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> For provisions permitting the United States to be made party defendant in a proceeding in a State court for the foreclosure of a lien upon real estate where the United States may have a claim upon the premises involved, see <ref>section 2410 of Title 28</ref> of the United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> For priority of lien of the United States in case of insolvency, see <ref>section 3713(a) of title 31</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 782</ref>, § 6326; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(a)(20)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1825</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–589, § 6(i)(10)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3411</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–258, § 3(f)(7)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 1064</ref>; renumbered § 6327, <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VI, § 6238(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3743</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter D—</num>
<heading>Seizure of Property for Collection of Taxes</heading>
<part>
<num>PART I—</num>
<heading>DUE PROCESS FOR COLLECTIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6330.</num>
<heading> Notice and opportunity for hearing before levy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement of notice before levy</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No levy may be made on any property or right to property of any person unless the Secretary has notified such person in writing of their right to a hearing under this section before such levy is made. Such notice shall be required only once for the taxable period to which the unpaid tax specified in paragraph (3)(A) relates.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time and method for notice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The notice required under paragraph (1) shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> given in person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> left at the dwelling or usual place of business of such person; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> sent by certified or registered mail, return receipt requested, to such person’s last known address;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">not less than 30 days before the day of the first levy with respect to the amount of the unpaid tax for the taxable period.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information included with notice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The notice required under paragraph (1) shall include in simple and nontechnical terms—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the amount of unpaid tax;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the right of the person to request a hearing during the 30-day period under paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> the proposed action by the Secretary and the rights of the person with respect to such action, including a brief statement which sets forth—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the provisions of this title relating to levy and sale of property;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the procedures applicable to the levy and sale of property under this title;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the administrative appeals available to the taxpayer with respect to such levy and sale and the procedures relating to such appeals;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> the alternatives available to taxpayers which could prevent levy on property (including installment agreements under section 6159); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> the provisions of this title and procedures relating to redemption of property and release of liens on property.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Right to fair hearing</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the person requests a hearing in writing under subsection (a)(3)(B) and states the grounds for the requested hearing, such hearing shall be held by the Internal Revenue Service Independent Office of Appeals.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> One hearing per period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A person shall be entitled to only one hearing under this section with respect to the taxable period to which the unpaid tax specified in subsection (a)(3)(A) relates.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Impartial officer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The hearing under this subsection shall be conducted by an officer or employee who has had no prior involvement with respect to the unpaid tax specified in subsection (a)(3)(A) before the first hearing under this section or section 6320. A taxpayer may waive the requirement of this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Matters considered at hearing</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of any hearing conducted under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement of investigation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The appeals officer shall at the hearing obtain verification from the Secretary that the requirements of any applicable law or administrative procedure have been met.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Issues at hearing</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The person may raise at the hearing any relevant issue relating to the unpaid tax or the proposed levy, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> appropriate spousal defenses;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> challenges to the appropriateness of collection actions; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> offers of collection alternatives, which may include the posting of a bond, the substitution of other assets, an installment agreement, or an offer-in-compromise.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Underlying liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The person may also raise at the hearing challenges to the existence or amount of the underlying tax liability for any tax period if the person did not receive any statutory notice of deficiency for such tax liability or did not otherwise have an opportunity to dispute such tax liability.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Basis for the determination</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The determination by an appeals officer under this subsection shall take into consideration—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the verification presented under paragraph (1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the issues raised under paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> whether any proposed collection action balances the need for the efficient collection of taxes with the legitimate concern of the person that any collection action be no more intrusive than necessary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain issues precluded</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An issue may not be raised at the hearing if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the issue was raised and considered at a previous hearing under section 6320 or in any other previous administrative or judicial proceeding; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the person seeking to raise the issue participated meaningfully in such hearing or proceeding;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the issue meets the requirement of clause (i) or (ii) of section 6702(b)(2)(A); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a final determination has been made with respect to such issue in a proceeding brought under subchapter C of chapter 63.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">This paragraph shall not apply to any issue with respect to which subsection (d)(3)(B) applies.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proceeding after hearing</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Petition for review by Tax Court</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The person may, within 30 days of a determination under this section, petition the Tax Court for review of such determination (and the Tax Court shall have jurisdiction with respect to such matter).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of running of period for filing petition in title 11 cases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a person who is prohibited by reason of a case under title 11, United States Code, from filing a petition under paragraph (1) with respect to a determination under this section, the running of the period prescribed by such subsection for filing such a petition with respect to such determination shall be suspended for the period during which the person is so prohibited from filing such a petition, and for 30 days thereafter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction retained at IRS Independent Office of Appeals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Internal Revenue Service Independent Office of Appeals shall retain jurisdiction with respect to any determination made under this section, including subsequent hearings requested by the person who requested the original hearing on issues regarding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> collection actions taken or proposed with respect to such determination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> after the person has exhausted all administrative remedies, a change in circumstances with respect to such person which affects such determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of collections and statute of limitations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), if a hearing is requested under subsection (a)(3)(B), the levy actions which are the subject of the requested hearing and the running of any period of limitations under section 6502 (relating to collection after assessment), section 6531 (relating to criminal prosecutions), or section 6532 (relating to other suits) shall be suspended for the period during which such hearing, and appeals therein, are pending. In no event shall any such period expire before the 90th day after the day on which there is a final determination in such hearing. Notwithstanding the provisions of section 7421(a), the beginning of a levy or proceeding during the time the suspension under this paragraph is in force may be enjoined by a proceeding in the proper court, including the Tax Court. The Tax Court shall have no jurisdiction under this paragraph to enjoin any action or proceeding unless a timely appeal has been filed under subsection (d)(1) and then only in respect of the unpaid tax or proposed levy to which the determination being appealed relates.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Levy upon appeal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a levy action while an appeal is pending if the underlying tax liability is not at issue in the appeal and the court determines that the Secretary has shown good cause not to suspend the levy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Secretary has made a finding under the last sentence of section 6331(a) that the collection of tax is in jeopardy,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Secretary has served a levy on a State to collect a Federal tax liability from a State tax refund,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Secretary has served a disqualified employment tax levy, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> the Secretary has served a Federal contractor levy,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">this section shall not apply, except that the taxpayer shall be given the opportunity for the hearing described in this section within a reasonable period of time after the levy.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Frivolous requests for hearing, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, if the Secretary determines that any portion of a request for a hearing under this section or section 6320 meets the requirement of clause (i) or (ii) of section 6702(b)(2)(A), then the Secretary may treat such portion as if it were never submitted and such portion shall not be subject to any further administrative or judicial review.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions related to exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (f)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disqualified employment tax levy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A disqualified employment tax levy is any levy in connection with the collection of employment taxes for any taxable period if the person subject to the levy (or any predecessor thereof) requested a hearing under this section with respect to unpaid employment taxes arising in the most recent 2-year period before the beginning of the taxable period with respect to which the levy is served. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term “employment taxes” means any taxes under chapter 21, 22, 23, or 24.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal contractor levy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A Federal contractor levy is any levy if the person whose property is subject to the levy (or any predecessor thereof) is a Federal contractor.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title III, § 3401(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 747</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(7) [title III, § 313(b)(2)(A), (d)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–642, 2763A–643; <ref>Pub. L. 109–280, title VIII, § 855(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1019</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–432, div. A, title IV, § 407(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2961</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–28, title VIII, § 8243(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2007-05-25">May 25, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 200</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–240, title II, § 2104(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2010-09-27">Sept. 27, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2565</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–74, title XI, § 1101(d)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 637</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. Q, title IV, § 424(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 3124</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(281)</ref>, (282), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1197</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–25, title I, § 1001(b)(1)(C)</ref>, (3), <date date="2019-07-01">July 1, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 985</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num>PART II—</num>
<heading>LEVY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6331.</num>
<heading> Levy and distraint</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any person liable to pay any tax neglects or refuses to pay the same within 10 days after notice and demand, it shall be lawful for the Secretary to collect such tax (and such further sum as shall be sufficient to cover the expenses of the levy) by levy upon all property and rights to property (except such property as is exempt under section 6334) belonging to such person or on which there is a lien provided in this chapter for the payment of such tax. Levy may be made upon the accrued salary or wages of any officer, employee, or elected official, of the United States, the District of Columbia, or any agency or instrumentality of the United States or the District of Columbia, by serving a notice of levy on the employer (as defined in section 3401(d)) of such officer, employee, or elected official. If the Secretary makes a finding that the collection of such tax is in jeopardy, notice and demand for immediate payment of such tax may be made by the Secretary and, upon failure or refusal to pay such tax, collection thereof by levy shall be lawful without regard to the 10-day period provided in this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Seizure and sale of property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The term “levy” as used in this title includes the power of distraint and seizure by any means. Except as otherwise provided in subsection (e), a levy shall extend only to property possessed and obligations existing at the time thereof. In any case in which the Secretary may levy upon property or rights to property, he may seize and sell such property or rights to property (whether real or personal, tangible or intangible).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Successive seizures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever any property or right to property upon which levy has been made by virtue of subsection (a) is not sufficient to satisfy the claim of the United States for which levy is made, the Secretary may, thereafter, and as often as may be necessary, proceed to levy in like manner upon any other property liable to levy of the person against whom such claim exists, until the amount due from him, together with all expenses, is fully paid.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement of notice before levy</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Levy may be made under subsection (a) upon the salary or wages or other property of any person with respect to any unpaid tax only after the Secretary has notified such person in writing of his intention to make such levy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 30-day requirement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The notice required under paragraph (1) shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> given in person,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> left at the dwelling or usual place of business of such person, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> sent by certified or registered mail to such persons’s last known address,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">no less than 30 days before the day of the levy.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jeopardy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a levy if the Secretary has made a finding under the last sentence of subsection (a) that the collection of tax is in jeopardy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information included with notice</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The notice required under paragraph (1) shall include a brief statement which sets forth in simple and nontechnical terms—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the provisions of this title relating to levy and sale of property,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the procedures applicable to the levy and sale of property under this title,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the administrative appeals available to the taxpayer with respect to such levy and sale and the procedures relating to such appeals,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the alternatives available to taxpayers which could prevent levy on the property (including installment agreements under section 6159),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the provisions of this title relating to redemption of property and release of liens on property,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> the procedures applicable to the redemption of property and the release of a lien on property under this title, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> the provisions of section 7345 relating to the certification of seriously delinquent tax debts and the denial, revocation, or limitation of passports of individuals with such debts pursuant to section 32101 of the FAST Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuing levy on salary and wages</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The effect of a levy on salary or wages payable to or received by a taxpayer shall be continuous from the date such levy is first made until such levy is released under section 6343.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Uneconomical levy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No levy may be made on any property if the amount of the expenses which the Secretary estimates (at the time of levy) would be incurred by the Secretary with respect to the levy and sale of such property exceeds the fair market value of such property at the time of levy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Levy on appearance date of summons</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No levy may be made on the property of any person on any day on which such person (or officer or employee of such person) is required to appear in response to a summons issued by the Secretary for the purpose of collecting any underpayment of tax.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No application in case of jeopardy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This subsection shall not apply if the Secretary finds that the collection of tax is in jeopardy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continuing levy on certain payments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Secretary approves a levy under this subsection, the effect of such levy on specified payments to or received by a taxpayer shall be continuous from the date such levy is first made until such levy is released. Notwithstanding section 6334, such continuous levy shall attach to up to 15 percent of any specified payment due to the taxpayer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specified payment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For the purposes of paragraph (1), the term “specified payment” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any Federal payment other than a payment for which eligibility is based on the income or assets (or both) of a payee,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any payment described in paragraph (4), (7), (9), or (11) of section 6334(a), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any annuity or pension payment under the Railroad Retirement Act or benefit under the Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Increase in levy for certain payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall be applied by substituting “100 percent” for “15 percent” in the case of any specified payment due to a vendor of property, goods, or services sold or leased to the Federal Government and by substituting “100 percent” for “15 percent” in the case of any specified payment due to a Medicare provider or supplier under title XVIII of the Social Security Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No levy during pendency of proceedings for refund of divisible tax</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">No levy may be made under subsection (a) on the property or rights to property of any person with respect to any unpaid divisible tax during the pendency of any proceeding brought by such person in a proper Federal trial court for the recovery of any portion of such divisible tax which was paid by such person if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the decision in such proceeding would be res judicata with respect to such unpaid tax; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such person would be collaterally estopped from contesting such unpaid tax by reason of such proceeding.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Divisible tax</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), the term “divisible tax” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any tax imposed by subtitle C; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the penalty imposed by section 6672 with respect to any such tax.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain unpaid taxes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">This subsection shall not apply with respect to any unpaid tax if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the taxpayer files a written notice with the Secretary which waives the restriction imposed by this subsection on levy with respect to such tax; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the Secretary finds that the collection of such tax is in jeopardy.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain levies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">This subsection shall not apply to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any levy to carry out an offset under section 6402; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any levy which was first made before the date that the applicable proceeding under this subsection commenced.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on collection activity; authority to enjoin collection</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on collection</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">No proceeding in court for the collection of any unpaid tax to which paragraph (1) applies shall be begun by the Secretary during the pendency of a proceeding under such paragraph. This subparagraph shall not apply to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any counterclaim in a proceeding under such paragraph; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any proceeding relating to a proceeding under such paragraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to enjoin</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding section 7421(a), a levy or collection proceeding prohibited by this subsection may be enjoined (during the period such prohibition is in force) by the court in which the proceeding under paragraph (1) is brought.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of statute of limitations on collection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The period of limitations under section 6502 shall be suspended for the period during which the Secretary is prohibited under this subsection from making a levy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pendency of proceeding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, a proceeding is pending beginning on the date such proceeding commences and ending on the date that a final order or judgment from which an appeal may be taken is entered in such proceeding.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No levy before investigation of status of property</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of applying the provisions of this subchapter, no levy may be made on any property or right to property which is to be sold under section 6335 until a thorough investigation of the status of such property has been completed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elements in investigation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), an investigation of the status of any property shall include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a verification of the taxpayer’s liability;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the completion of an analysis under subsection (f);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the determination that the equity in such property is sufficient to yield net proceeds from the sale of such property to apply to such liability; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a thorough consideration of alternative collection methods.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No levy while certain offers pending or installment agreement pending or in effect</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Offer-in-compromise pending</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">No levy may be made under subsection (a) on the property or rights to property of any person with respect to any unpaid tax—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> during the period that an offer-in-compromise by such person under section 7122 of such unpaid tax is pending with the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if such offer is rejected by the Secretary, during the 30 days thereafter (and, if an appeal of such rejection is filed within such 30 days, during the period that such appeal is pending).</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of subparagraph (A), an offer is pending beginning on the date the Secretary accepts such offer for processing.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Installment agreements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">No levy may be made under subsection (a) on the property or rights to property of any person with respect to any unpaid tax—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> during the period that an offer by such person for an installment agreement under section 6159 for payment of such unpaid tax is pending with the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if such offer is rejected by the Secretary, during the 30 days thereafter (and, if an appeal of such rejection is filed within such 30 days, during the period that such appeal is pending);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> during the period that such an installment agreement for payment of such unpaid tax is in effect; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> if such agreement is terminated by the Secretary, during the 30 days thereafter (and, if an appeal of such termination is filed within such 30 days, during the period that such appeal is pending).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain rules to apply</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Rules similar to the rules of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> paragraphs (3) and (4) of subsection (i), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> except in the case of paragraph (2)(C), paragraph (5) of subsection (i),</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall apply for purposes of this subsection.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cross references</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For provisions relating to jeopardy, see subchapter A of chapter 70.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For proceedings applicable to sale of seized property see section 6335.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For release and notice of release of levy, see section 6343.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 783</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–719, title I, § 104(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1135</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–178, title II, § 211(a)</ref>, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 520</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XII, § 1209(d)(1)</ref>, (2), (4), title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1710</ref>, 1711, 1834; <ref>Pub. L. 97–248, title III, § 349(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 639</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title VII, § 714</ref>(<i>o</i>), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 964</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VI, § 6236(a)</ref>, (b), (d), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3737</ref>, 3739; <ref>Pub. L. 105–34, title X, § 1024(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 923</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title III</ref>, §§ 3433(a), 3444(a), 3462(b), title VI, § 6010(f), <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 759</ref>, 762, 765, 814; <ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(7) [title III, § 313(b)(3)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–642; <ref>Pub. L. 107–147, title IV, § 416(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-03-09">Mar. 9, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 55</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–357, title VIII, § 887(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1641</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–56, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-11-21">Nov. 21, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 733</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. B, title II, § 209(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4074</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–10, title IV, § 413(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-04-16">Apr. 16, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 162</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. C, title XXXII, § 32101(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1731</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6332.</num>
<heading> Surrender of property subject to levy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this section, any person in possession of (or obligated with respect to) property or rights to property subject to levy upon which a levy has been made shall, upon demand of the Secretary, surrender such property or rights (or discharge such obligation) to the Secretary, except such part of the property or rights as is, at the time of such demand, subject to an attachment or execution under any judicial process.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for life insurance and endowment contracts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A levy on an organization with respect to a life insurance or endowment contract issued by such organization shall, without necessity for the surrender of the contract document, constitute a demand by the Secretary for payment of the amount described in paragraph (2) and the exercise of the right of the person against whom the tax is assessed to the advance of such amount. Such organization shall pay over such amount 90 days after service of notice of levy. Such notice shall include a certification by the Secretary that a copy of such notice has been mailed to the person against whom the tax is assessed at his last known address.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Satisfaction of levy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Such levy shall be deemed to be satisfied if such organization pays over to the Secretary the amount which the person against whom the tax is assessed could have had advanced to him by such organization on the date prescribed in paragraph (1) for the satisfaction of such levy, increased by the amount of any advance (including contractual interest thereon) made to such person on or after the date such organization had actual notice or knowledge (within the meaning of section 6323(i)(1)) of the existence of the lien with respect to which such levy is made, other than an advance (including contractual interest thereon) made automatically to maintain such contract in force under an agreement entered into before such organization had such notice or knowledge.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement proceedings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The satisfaction of a levy under paragraph (2) shall be without prejudice to any civil action for the enforcement of any lien imposed by this title with respect to such contract.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for banks</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any bank (as defined in section 408(n)) shall surrender (subject to an attachment or execution under judicial process) any deposits (including interest thereon) in such bank only after 21 days after service of levy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enforcement of levy</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extent of personal liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any person who fails or refuses to surrender any property or rights to property, subject to levy, upon demand by the Secretary, shall be liable in his own person and estate to the United States in a sum equal to the value of the property or rights not so surrendered, but not exceeding the amount of taxes for the collection of which such levy has been made, together with costs and interest on such sum at the underpayment rate established under section 6621 from the date of such levy (or, in the case of a levy described in section 6331(d)(3), from the date such person would otherwise have been obligated to pay over such amounts to the taxpayer). Any amount (other than costs) recovered under this paragraph shall be credited against the tax liability for the collection of which such levy was made.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalty for violation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to the personal liability imposed by paragraph (1), if any person required to surrender property or rights to property fails or refuses to surrender such property or rights to property without reasonable cause, such person shall be liable for a penalty equal to 50 percent of the amount recoverable under paragraph (1). No part of such penalty shall be credited against the tax liability for the collection of which such levy was made.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of honoring levy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person in possession of (or obligated with respect to) property or rights to property subject to levy upon which a levy has been made who, upon demand by the Secretary, surrenders such property or rights to property (or discharges such obligation) to the Secretary (or who pays a liability under subsection (d)(1)) shall be discharged from any obligation or liability to the delinquent taxpayer and any other person with respect to such property or rights to property arising from such surrender or payment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Person defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The term “person,” as used in subsection (a), includes an officer or employee of a corporation or a member or employee of a partnership, who as such officer, employee, or member is under a duty to surrender the property or rights to property, or to discharge the obligation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 784</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–719, title I, § 104(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1135</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–625, § 7(a)(2)(D)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 2115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XII, § 1209(d)(3)</ref>, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1710</ref>, 1834; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title XV, § 1511(c)(9)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2745</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1015(t)(1)</ref>, title VI, § 6236(e), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3573</ref>, 3739; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11704(a)(27)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–519</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6333.</num>
<heading> Production of books</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a levy has been made or is about to be made on any property, or right to property, any person having custody or control of any books or records, containing evidence or statements relating to the property or right to property subject to levy, shall, upon demand of the Secretary, exhibit such books or records to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 784</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6334.</num>
<heading> Property exempt from levy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enumeration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There shall be exempt from levy—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wearing apparel and school books</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Such items of wearing apparel and such school books as are necessary for the taxpayer or for members of his family;</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fuel, provisions, furniture, and personal effects</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">So much of the fuel, provisions, furniture, and personal effects in the taxpayer’s household, and of the arms for personal use, livestock, and poultry of the taxpayer, as does not exceed $6,250 in value;</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Books and tools of a trade, business, or profession</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">So many of the books and tools necessary for the trade, business, or profession of the taxpayer as do not exceed in the aggregate $3,125 in value.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unemployment benefits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any amount payable to an individual with respect to his unemployment (including any portion thereof payable with respect to dependents) under an unemployment compensation law of the United States, of any State, or of the District of Columbia or of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Undelivered mail</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Mail, addressed to any person, which has not been delivered to the addressee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain annuity and pension payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Annuity or pension payments under the Railroad Retirement Act, benefits under the Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act, special pension payments received by a person whose name has been entered on the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard Medal of Honor roll (<ref>38 U.S.C. 1562</ref>), and annuities based on retired or retainer pay under chapter 73 of title 10 of the United States Code.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Workmen’s compensation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any amount payable to an individual as workmen’s compensation (including any portion thereof payable with respect to dependents) under a workmen’s compensation law of the United States, any State, the District of Columbia, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Judgments for support of minor children</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the taxpayer is required by judgment of a court of competent jurisdiction, entered prior to the date of levy, to contribute to the support of his minor children, so much of his salary, wages, or other income as is necessary to comply with such judgment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum exemption for wages, salary, and other income</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any amount payable to or received by an individual as wages or salary for personal services, or as income derived from other sources, during any period, to the extent that the total of such amounts payable to or received by him during such period does not exceed the applicable exempt amount determined under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain service-connected disability payments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any amount payable to an individual as a service-connected (within the meaning of <ref>section 101(16) of title 38</ref>, United States Code) disability benefit under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subchapter II, III, IV, V, or VI of chapter 11 of such title 38, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> chapter 13, 21, 23, 31, 32, 34, 35, 37, or 39 of such title 38.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain public assistance payments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any amount payable to an individual as a recipient of public assistance under—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> title IV or title XVI (relating to supplemental security income for the aged, blind, and disabled) of the Social Security Act, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> State or local government public assistance or public welfare programs for which eligibility is determined by a needs or income test.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance under Job Training Partnership Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any amount payable to a participant under the Job Training Partnership Act (<ref>29 U.S.C. 1501</ref> et seq.) from funds appropriated pursuant to such Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(13)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Residences exempt in small deficiency cases and principal residences and certain business assets exempt in absence of certain approval or jeopardy</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Residences in small deficiency cases</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If the amount of the levy does not exceed $5,000—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any real property used as a residence by the taxpayer; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any real property of the taxpayer (other than real property which is rented) used by any other individual as a residence.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Principal residences and certain business assets</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Except to the extent provided in subsection (e)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the principal residence of the taxpayer (within the meaning of section 121); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> tangible personal property or real property (other than real property which is rented) used in the trade or business of an individual taxpayer.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appraisal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The officer seizing property of the type described in subsection (a) shall appraise and set aside to the owner the amount of such property declared to be exempt. If the taxpayer objects at the time of the seizure to the valuation fixed by the officer making the seizure, the Secretary shall summon three disinterested individuals who shall make the valuation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No other property exempt</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other law of the United States (including section 207 of the Social Security Act), no property or rights to property shall be exempt from levy other than the property specifically made exempt by subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exempt amount of wages, salary, or other income</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Individuals on weekly basis</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of an individual who is paid or receives all of his wages, salary, and other income on a weekly basis, the amount of the wages, salary, and other income payable to or received by him during any week which is exempt from levy under subsection (a)(9) shall be the exempt amount.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exempt amount</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), the term “exempt amount” means an amount equal to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the sum of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the standard deduction, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the aggregate amount of the deductions for personal exemptions allowed the taxpayer under section 151 in the taxable year in which such levy occurs, divided by</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> 52.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">Unless the taxpayer submits to the Secretary a written and properly verified statement specifying the facts necessary to determine the proper amount under subparagraph (A), subparagraph (A) shall be applied as if the taxpayer were a married individual filing a separate return with only 1 personal exemption.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Individuals on basis other than weekly</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of any individual not described in paragraph (1), the amount of the wages, salary, and other income payable to or received by him during any applicable pay period or other fiscal period (as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary) which is exempt from levy under subsection (a)(9) shall be an amount (determined under such regulations) which as nearly as possible will result in the same total exemption from levy for such individual over a period of time as he would have under paragraph (1) if (during such period of time) he were paid or received such wages, salary, and other income on a regular weekly basis.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Years when personal exemption amount is zero</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In the case of any taxable year in which the exemption amount under section 151(d) is zero, paragraph (2) shall not apply and for purposes of paragraph (1) the term “exempt amount” means an amount equal to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the sum of the amount determined under subparagraph (B) and the standard deduction, divided by</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 52.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount determined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the amount determined under this subparagraph is $4,150 multiplied by the number of the taxpayer’s dependents for the taxable year in which the levy occurs.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inflation adjustment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In the case of any taxable year beginning in a calendar year after 2018, the $4,150 amount in subparagraph (B) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such dollar amount, multiplied by</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting “2017” for “2016” in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">If any increase determined under the preceding sentence is not a multiple of $100, such increase shall be rounded to the next lowest multiple of $100.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Verified statement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Unless the taxpayer submits to the Secretary a written and properly verified statement specifying the facts necessary to determine the proper amount under subparagraph (A), subparagraph (A) shall be applied as if the taxpayer were a married individual filing a separate return with no dependents.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Levy allowed on principal residences and certain business assets in certain circumstances</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Principal residences</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval required</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A principal residence shall not be exempt from levy if a judge or magistrate of a district court of the United States approves (in writing) the levy of such residence.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The district courts of the United States shall have exclusive jurisdiction to approve a levy under subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain business assets</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Property (other than a principal residence) described in subsection (a)(13)(B) shall not be exempt from levy if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a district director or assistant district director of the Internal Revenue Service personally approves (in writing) the levy of such property; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary finds that the collection of tax is in jeopardy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">An official may not approve a levy under subparagraph (A) unless the official determines that the taxpayer’s other assets subject to collection are insufficient to pay the amount due, together with expenses of the proceedings.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Levy allowed on certain specified payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any payment described in subparagraph (B) or (C) of section 6331(h)(2) shall not be exempt from levy if the Secretary approves the levy thereon under section 6331(h).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inflation adjustment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of any calendar year beginning after 1999, each dollar amount referred to in paragraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (a) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such dollar amount, multiplied by</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for such calendar year, by substituting “calendar year 1998” for “calendar year 2016” in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rounding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If any dollar amount after being increased under paragraph (1) is not a multiple of $10, such dollar amount shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $10.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 784</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–840, title IV, § 406</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1047</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–44, title VIII, § 812(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-06-21">June 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 170</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–719, title I, § 104(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1137</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–172, title IX, § 945(a)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 729</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XII, § 1209(a)</ref>–(c), title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1709</ref>, 1710, 1834; <ref>Pub. L. 97–248, title III, § 347(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 638</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title VI, § 2661</ref>(<i>o</i>)(5), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1159</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title XV, § 1565(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2763</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1015</ref>(<i>o</i>), title VI, § 6236(c), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3572</ref>, 3738; <ref>Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–168, title V, § 502(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1996-07-30">July 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1461</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–193, title I, § 110</ref>(<i>l</i>)(3), formerly § 110(<i>l</i>)(6), <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2173</ref>, renumbered and amended <ref>Pub. L. 105–33, title V, § 5514(a)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 620</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–34, title III, § 312(d)(1)</ref>, title X, § 1025(a), <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 839</ref>, 924; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title III</ref>, §§ 3431(a)–(c), 3445(a), (b), <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 758</ref>, 762, 763; <ref>Pub. L. 115–97, title I</ref>, §§ 11002(d)(1)(II), 11041(d), <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 2060</ref>, 2084; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(283)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1198</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6335.</num>
<heading> Sale of seized property</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice of seizure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As soon as practicable after seizure of property, notice in writing shall be given by the Secretary to the owner of the property (or, in the case of personal property, the possessor thereof), or shall be left at his usual place of abode or business if he has such within the internal revenue district where the seizure is made. If the owner cannot be readily located, or has no dwelling or place of business within such district, the notice may be mailed to his last known address. Such notice shall specify the sum demanded and shall contain, in the case of personal property, an account of the property seized and, in the case of real property, a description with reasonable certainty of the property seized.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice of sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall as soon as practicable after the seizure of the property give notice to the owner, in the manner prescribed in subsection (a), and shall cause a notification to be published in some newspaper published or generally circulated within the county wherein such seizure is made, or if there be no newspaper published or generally circulated in such county, shall post such notice at the post office nearest the place where the seizure is made, and in not less than two other public places. Such notice shall specify the property to be sold, and the time, place, manner, and conditions of the sale thereof. Whenever levy is made without regard to the 10-day period provided in section 6331(a), public notice of sale of the property seized shall not be made within such 10-day period unless section 6336 (relating to sale of perishable goods) is applicable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sale of indivisible property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any property liable to levy is not divisible, so as to enable the Secretary by sale of a part thereof to raise the whole amount of the tax and expenses, the whole of such property shall be sold.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time and place of sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The time of sale shall not be less than 10 days nor more than 40 days from the time of giving public notice under subsection (b). The place of sale shall be within the county in which the property is seized, except by special order of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Manner and conditions of sale</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determinations relating to minimum price</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Before the sale of property seized by levy, the Secretary shall determine—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a minimum price below which such property shall not be sold (taking into account the expense of making the levy and conducting the sale), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> whether, on the basis of criteria prescribed by the Secretary, the purchase of such property by the United States at such minimum price would be in the best interest of the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sale to highest bidder at or above minimum price</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If, at the sale, one or more persons offer to purchase such property for not less than the amount of the minimum price, the property shall be declared sold to the highest bidder.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Property deemed sold to United States at minimum price in certain cases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If no person offers the amount of the minimum price for such property at the sale and the Secretary has determined that the purchase of such property by the United States would be in the best interest of the United States, the property shall be declared to be sold to the United States at such minimum price.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Release to owner in other cases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If, at the sale, the property is not declared sold under subparagraph (B) or (C), the property shall be released to the owner thereof and the expense of the levy and sale shall be added to the amount of tax for the collection of which the levy was made. Any property released under this subparagraph shall remain subject to any lien imposed by subchapter C.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional rules applicable to sale</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall by regulations prescribe the manner and other conditions of the sale of property seized by levy. If one or more alternative methods or conditions are permitted by regulations, the Secretary shall select the alternatives applicable to the sale. Such regulations shall provide:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> That the sale shall not be conducted in any manner other than—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> by public auction, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> by public sale under sealed bids.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> In the case of the seizure of several items of property, whether such items shall be offered separately, in groups, or in the aggregate; and whether such property shall be offered both separately (or in groups) and in the aggregate, and sold under whichever method produces the highest aggregate amount.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Whether the announcement of the minimum price determined by the Secretary may be delayed until the receipt of the highest bid.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Whether payment in full shall be required at the time of acceptance of a bid, or whether a part of such payment may be deferred for such period (not to exceed 1 month) as may be determined by the Secretary to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The extent to which methods (including advertising) in addition to those prescribed in subsection (b) may be used in giving notice of the sale.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Under what circumstances the Secretary may adjourn the sale from time to time (but such adjournments shall not be for a period to exceed in all 1 month).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment of amount bid</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If payment in full is required at the time of acceptance of a bid and is not then and there paid, the Secretary shall forthwith proceed to again sell the property in the manner provided in this subsection. If the conditions of the sale permit part of the payment to be deferred, and if such part is not paid within the prescribed period, suit may be instituted against the purchaser for the purchase price or such part thereof as has not been paid, together with interest at the rate of 6 percent per annum from the date of the sale; or, in the discretion of the Secretary, the sale may be declared by the Secretary to be null and void for failure to make full payment of the purchase price and the property may again be advertised and sold as provided in subsections (b) and (c) and this subsection. In the event of such readvertisement and sale any new purchaser shall receive such property or rights to property, free and clear of any claim or right of the former defaulting purchaser, of any nature whatsoever, and the amount paid upon the bid price by such defaulting purchaser shall be forfeited.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cross reference</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2 fontsize7">For provision providing for civil damages for violation of paragraph (1)(A)(i), see section 7433.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Right to request sale of seized property within 60 days</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The owner of any property seized by levy may request that the Secretary sell such property within 60 days after such request (or within such longer period as may be specified by the owner). The Secretary shall comply with such request unless the Secretary determines (and notifies the owner within such period) that such compliance would not be in the best interests of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Stay of sale of seized property pending Tax Court decision</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2 fontsize7">For restrictions on sale of seized property pending Tax Court decision, see section 6863(b)(3).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 785</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–719, title I, § 104(d)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1137</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title XV, § 1570(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2764</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VI, § 6236(g)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3740</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title III, § 3441(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 761</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6336.</num>
<heading> Sale of perishable goods</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the Secretary determines that any property seized is liable to perish, he shall appraise the value of such property and—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Return to owner</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If the owner of the property can be readily found, the Secretary shall give him notice of such determination of the appraised value of the property. The property shall be returned to the owner if, within such time as may be specified in the notice, the owner—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Pays to the Secretary an amount equal to the appraised value, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Gives bond in such form, with such sureties, and in such amount as the Secretary shall prescribe, to pay the appraised amount at such time as the Secretary determines to be appropriate in the circumstances.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Immediate sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the owner does not pay such amount or furnish such bond in accordance with this section, the Secretary shall as soon as practicable make public sale of the property in accordance with such regulations as may be prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 786</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–25, title I, § 1404(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-07-01">July 1, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 997</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6337.</num>
<heading> Redemption of property</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Before sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person whose property has been levied upon shall have the right to pay the amount due, together with the expenses of the proceeding, if any, to the Secretary at any time prior to the sale thereof, and upon such payment the Secretary shall restore such property to him, and all further proceedings in connection with the levy on such property shall cease from the time of such payment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Redemption of real estate after sale</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The owners of any real property sold as provided in section 6335, their heirs, executors, or administrators, or any person having any interest therein, or a lien thereon, or any person in their behalf, shall be permitted to redeem the property sold, or any particular tract of such property, at any time within 180 days after the sale thereof.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Price</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Such property or tract of property shall be permitted to be redeemed upon payment to the purchaser, or in case he cannot be found in the county in which the property to be redeemed is situated, then to the Secretary, for the use of the purchaser, his heirs, or assigns, the amount paid by such purchaser and interest thereon at the rate of 20 percent per annum.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Record</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When any lands sold are redeemed as provided in this section, the Secretary shall cause entry of the fact to be made upon the record mentioned in section 6340, and such entry shall be evidence of such redemption.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 787</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–719, title I, § 104(e)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1137</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–248, title III, § 349A(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 639</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6338.</num>
<heading> Certificate of sale; deed of real property</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certificate of sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of property sold as provided in section 6335, the Secretary shall give to the purchaser a certificate of sale upon payment in full of the purchase price. In the case of real property, such certificate shall set forth the real property purchased, for whose taxes the same was sold, the name of the purchaser, and the price paid therefor.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deed to real property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of any real property sold as provided in section 6335 and not redeemed in the manner and within the time provided in section 6337, the Secretary shall execute (in accordance with the laws of the State in which such real property is situated pertaining to sales of real property under execution) to the purchaser of such real property at such sale, upon his surrender of the certificate of sale, a deed of the real property so purchased by him, reciting the facts set forth in the certificate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Real property purchased by United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If real property is declared purchased by the United States at a sale pursuant to section 6335, the Secretary shall at the proper time execute a deed therefor; and without delay cause such deed to be duly recorded in the proper registry of deeds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 787</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–866, title I, § 78</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1662</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–719, title I, § 104(f)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1137</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6339.</num>
<heading> Legal effect of certificate of sale of personal property and deed of real property</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certificate of sale of property other than real property</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In all cases of sale pursuant to section 6335 of property (other than real property), the certificate of such sale—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> As evidence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Shall be prima facie evidence of the right of the officer to make such sale, and conclusive evidence of the regularity of his proceedings in making the sale; and</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> As conveyances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Shall transfer to the purchaser all right, title, and interest of the party delinquent in and to the property sold; and</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> As authority for transfer of corporate stock</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If such property consists of stocks, shall be notice, when received, to any corporation, company, or association of such transfer, and shall be authority to such corporation, company, or association to record the transfer on its books and records in the same manner as if the stocks were transferred or assigned by the party holding the same, in lieu of any original or prior certificate, which shall be void, whether canceled or not; and</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> As receipts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the subject of sale is securities or other evidences of debt, shall be a good and valid receipt to the person holding the same, as against any person holding or claiming to hold possession of such securities or other evidences of debt; and</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> As authority for transfer of title to motor vehicle</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If such property consists of a motor vehicle, shall be notice, when received, to any public official charged with the registration of title to motor vehicles, of such transfer and shall be authority to such official to record the transfer on his books and records in the same manner as if the certificate of title to such motor vehicle were transferred or assigned by the party holding the same, in lieu of any original or prior certificate, which shall be void, whether canceled or not.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deed of real property</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of the sale of real property pursuant to section 6335—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deed as evidence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The deed of sale given pursuant to section 6338 shall be prima facie evidence of the facts therein stated; and</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deed as conveyance of title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the proceedings of the Secretary as set forth have been substantially in accordance with the provisions of law, such deed shall be considered and operate as a conveyance of all the right, title, and interest the party delinquent had in and to the real property thus sold at the time the lien of the United States attached thereto.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of junior encumbrances</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A certificate of sale of personal property given or a deed to real property executed pursuant to section 6338 shall discharge such property from all liens, encumbrances, and titles over which the lien of the United States with respect to which the levy was made had priority.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cross references</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For distribution of surplus proceeds, see section 6342(b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For judicial procedure with respect to surplus proceeds, see section 7426(a)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 788</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–866, title I, § 79</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1662</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–719, title I, § 104(g)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1137</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6340.</num>
<heading> Records of sale</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall, for each internal revenue district, keep a record of all sales of property under section 6335 and of redemptions of such property. The record shall set forth the tax for which any such sale was made, the dates of seizure and sale, the name of the party assessed and all proceedings in making such sale, the amount of expenses, the names of the purchasers, and the date of the deed or certificate of sale of personal property.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Copy as evidence</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A copy of such record, or any part thereof, certified by the Secretary shall be evidence in any court of the truth of the facts therein stated.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accounting to taxpayer</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The taxpayer with respect to whose liability the sale was conducted or who redeemed the property shall be furnished—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the record under subsection (a) (other than the names of the purchasers);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the amount from such sale applied to the taxpayer’s liability; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the remaining balance of such liability.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 789</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title III, § 3442(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 761</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6341.</num>
<heading> Expense of levy and sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall determine the expenses to be allowed in all cases of levy and sale.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 789</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6342.</num>
<heading> Application of proceeds of levy</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collection of liability</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any money realized by proceedings under this subchapter (whether by seizure, by surrender under section 6332 (except pursuant to subsection (d)(2) thereof), or by sale of seized property) or by sale of property redeemed by the United States (if the interest of the United States in such property was a lien arising under the provisions of this title) shall be applied as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expense of levy and sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">First, against the expenses of the proceedings;</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specific tax liability on seized property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the property seized and sold is subject to a tax imposed by any internal revenue law which has not been paid, the amount remaining after applying paragraph (1) shall then be applied against such tax liability (and, if such tax was not previously assessed, it shall then be assessed);</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability of delinquent taxpayer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amount, if any, remaining after applying paragraphs (1) and (2) shall then be applied against the liability in respect of which the levy was made or the sale was conducted.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Surplus proceeds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any surplus proceeds remaining after the application of subsection (a) shall, upon application and satisfactory proof in support thereof, be credited or refunded by the Secretary to the person or persons legally entitled thereto.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 789</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–719, title I, § 104(h)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1137</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(284)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1198</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6343.</num>
<heading> Authority to release levy and return property</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Release of levy and notice of release</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the Secretary shall release the levy upon all, or part of, the property or rights to property levied upon and shall promptly notify the person upon whom such levy was made (if any) that such levy has been released if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the liability for which such levy was made is satisfied or becomes unenforceable by reason of lapse of time,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> release of such levy will facilitate the collection of such liability,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the taxpayer has entered into an agreement under section 6159 to satisfy such liability by means of installment payments, unless such agreement provides otherwise,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the Secretary has determined that such levy is creating an economic hardship due to the financial condition of the taxpayer, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the fair market value of the property exceeds such liability and release of the levy on a part of such property could be made without hindering the collection of such liability.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of subparagraph (C), the Secretary is not required to release such levy if such release would jeopardize the secured creditor status of the Secretary.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expedited determination on certain business property</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of any tangible personal property essential in carrying on the trade or business of the taxpayer, the Secretary shall provide for an expedited determination under paragraph (1) if levy on such tangible personal property would prevent the taxpayer from carrying on such trade or business.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequent levy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The release of levy on any property under paragraph (1) shall not prevent any subsequent levy on such property.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Return of property</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the Secretary determines that property has been wrongfully levied upon, it shall be lawful for the Secretary to return—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the specific property levied upon,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an amount of money equal to the amount of money levied upon, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an amount of money equal to the amount of money received by the United States from a sale of such property.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Property may be returned at any time. An amount equal to the amount of money levied upon or received from such sale may be returned at any time before the expiration of 2 years from the date of such levy. For purposes of paragraph (3), if property is declared purchased by the United States at a sale pursuant to section 6335(e) (relating to manner and conditions of sale), the United States shall be treated as having received an amount of money equal to the minimum price determined pursuant to such section or (if larger) the amount received by the United States from the resale of such property.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Interest shall be allowed and paid at the overpayment rate established under section 6621—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in a case described in subsection (b)(2), from the date the Secretary receives the money to a date (to be determined by the Secretary) preceding the date of return by not more than 30 days, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in a case described in subsection (b)(3), from the date of the sale of the property to a date (to be determined by the Secretary) preceding the date of return by not more than 30 days.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Return of property in certain cases</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any property has been levied upon, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the Secretary determines that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the levy on such property was premature or otherwise not in accordance with administrative procedures of the Secretary,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the taxpayer has entered into an agreement under section 6159 to satisfy the tax liability for which the levy was imposed by means of installment payments, unless such agreement provides otherwise,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the return of such property will facilitate the collection of the tax liability, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> with the consent of the taxpayer or the National Taxpayer Advocate, the return of such property would be in the best interests of the taxpayer (as determined by the National Taxpayer Advocate) and the United States,</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">the provisions of subsection (b) shall apply in the same manner as if such property had been wrongly levied upon, except that no interest shall be allowed under subsection (c).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Release of levy upon agreement that amount is not collectible</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of a levy on the salary or wages payable to or received by the taxpayer, upon agreement with the taxpayer that the tax is not collectible, the Secretary shall release such levy as soon as practicable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Individuals held harmless on wrongful levy, etc.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002291">1</ref> on retirement plan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If the Secretary determines that an individual’s account or benefit under an eligible retirement plan (as defined in section 402(c)(8)(B)) has been levied upon in a case to which subsection (b) or (d)(2)(A) applies and property or an amount of money is returned to the individual—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the individual may contribute such property or an amount equal to the sum of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the amount of money so returned by the Secretary, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> interest paid under subsection (c) on such amount of money,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">into such eligible retirement plan if such contribution is permitted by the plan, or into an individual retirement plan (other than an endowment contract) to which a rollover contribution of a distribution from such eligible retirement plan is permitted, but only if such contribution is made not later than the due date (not including extensions) for filing the return of tax for the taxable year in which such property or amount of money is returned, and</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary shall, at the time such property or amount of money is returned, notify such individual that a contribution described in subparagraph (A) may be made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment as rollover</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The distribution on account of the levy and any contribution under paragraph (1) with respect to the return of such distribution shall be treated for purposes of this title as if such distribution and contribution were described in section 402(c), 402A(c)(3), 403(a)(4), 403(b)(8), 408(d)(3), 408A(d)(3), or 457(e)(16), whichever is applicable; except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the contribution shall be treated as having been made for the taxable year in which the distribution on account of the levy occurred, and the interest paid under subsection (c) shall be treated as earnings within the plan after the contribution and shall not be included in gross income, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such contribution shall not be taken into account under section 408(d)(3)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refund, etc., of income tax on levy</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If any amount is includible in gross income for a taxable year by reason of a distribution on account of a levy referred to in paragraph (1) and any portion of such amount is treated as a rollover contribution under paragraph (2), any tax imposed by chapter 1 on such portion shall not be assessed, and if assessed shall be abated, and if collected shall be credited or refunded as an overpayment made on the due date for filing the return of tax for such taxable year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to a rollover contribution under this subsection which is made from an eligible retirement plan which is not a Roth IRA or a designated Roth account (within the meaning of section 402A) to a Roth IRA or a designated Roth account under an eligible retirement plan.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding subsection (d), interest shall be allowed under subsection (c) in a case in which the Secretary makes a determination described in subsection (d)(2)(A) with respect to a levy upon an individual retirement plan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of inherited accounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1)(A), section 408(d)(3)(C) shall be disregarded in determining whether an individual retirement plan is a plan to which a rollover contribution of a distribution from the plan levied upon is permitted.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 789</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–719, title I, § 104(i)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1138</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–167, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-12-29">Dec. 29, 1979</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 1275</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title XV, § 1511(c)(10)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2745</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VI, § 6236(f)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3740</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–168, title V, § 501(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-07-30">July 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1460</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title I, § 1102(d)(1)(B)</ref>, title III, § 3432(a), <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 704</ref>, 759; <ref>Pub. L. 115–97, title I, § 11071(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 2091</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–123, div. D, title II, § 41104(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-02-09">Feb. 9, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 155</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6344.</num>
<heading> Cross references</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Length of period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2 fontsize7">For period within which levy may be begun in case of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 fontsize7">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Income, estate, and gift taxes, and taxes imposed by chapter 41, 42, 43, or 44, see sections 6502(a) and 6503(a)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 fontsize7">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Employment and miscellaneous excise taxes, see section 6502(a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Delinquent collection officers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2 fontsize7">For distraint proceedings against delinquent internal revenue officers, see section 7804(c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other references</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2 fontsize7">For provisions relating to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 fontsize7">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Stamps, marks and brands, see section 6807.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 fontsize7">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Administration of real estate acquired by the United States, see section 7506.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 789</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–172, title I, § 101(j)(45)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 531</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–406, title II, § 1016(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 930</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIII, § 1307(d)(2)(F)(v)</ref>, title XVI, § 1605(b)(8), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1728</ref>, 1755; <ref>Pub. L. 96–223, title I, § 101(f)(1)(I)</ref>, <date date="1980-04-02">Apr. 2, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 252</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1941(b)(2)(B)(ix)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1323</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title I, § 1104(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 710</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>[Subchapter E—</num>
<heading>Repealed]</heading>
<section>
<num>[§§ 6361 to 6365.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11801(a)(45)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–522</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>