<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 31—</num>
<heading>RETAIL EXCISE TAXES</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>[Subchapter A—</num>
<heading>Repealed]</heading>
<section>
<num>[§§ 4001 to 4003.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(103)(A)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4052</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter B—</num>
<heading>Special Fuels</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4041.</num>
<heading> Imposition of tax</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Diesel fuel and special motor fuels</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax on diesel fuel and kerosene in certain cases</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">There is hereby imposed a tax on any liquid other than gasoline (as defined in section 4083)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> sold by any person to an owner, lessee, or other operator of a diesel-powered highway vehicle or a diesel-powered train for use as a fuel in such vehicle or train, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> used by any person as a fuel in a diesel-powered highway vehicle or a diesel-powered train unless there was a taxable sale of such fuel under clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption for previously taxed fuel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No tax shall be imposed by this paragraph on the sale or use of any liquid if tax was imposed on such liquid under section 4081 (other than such tax at the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate) and the tax thereon was not credited or refunded.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rate of tax</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Except as otherwise provided in this subparagraph, the rate of the tax imposed by this paragraph shall be the rate of tax specified in section 4081(a)(2)(A) on diesel fuel which is in effect at the time of such sale or use.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rate of tax on trains</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">In the case of any sale for use, or use, of diesel fuel in a train, the rate of tax imposed by this paragraph shall be—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> 3.3 cents per gallon after <date date="2004-12-31">December 31, 2004</date>, and before <date date="2005-07-01">July 1, 2005</date>,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> 2.3 cents per gallon after <date date="2005-06-30">June 30, 2005</date>, and before <date date="2007-01-01">January 1, 2007</date>, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> 0 after <date date="2006-12-31">December 31, 2006</date>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rate of tax on certain buses</heading>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(I)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">Except as provided in subclause (II), in the case of fuel sold for use or used in a use described in section 6427(b)(1) (after the application of section 6427(b)(3)), the rate of tax imposed by this paragraph shall be 7.3 cents per gallon (4.3 cents per gallon after <date date="2028-09-30">September 30, 2028</date>).</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent6 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(II)</num>
<heading class="bold"> School bus and intracity transportation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent4">No tax shall be imposed by this paragraph on any sale for use, or use, described in subparagraph (B) or (C) of section 6427(b)(2).</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alternative fuels</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">There is hereby imposed a tax on any liquid (other than gas oil, fuel oil, or any product taxable under section 4081 (other than such tax at the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate))—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> sold by any person to an owner, lessee, or other operator of a motor vehicle or motorboat for use as a fuel in such motor vehicle or motorboat, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> used by any person as a fuel in a motor vehicle or motorboat unless there was a taxable sale of such liquid under clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rate of tax</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The rate of the tax imposed by this paragraph shall be—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> except as otherwise provided in this subparagraph, the rate of tax specified in section 4081(a)(2)(A)(i) which is in effect at the time of such sale or use,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of liquefied petroleum gas, 18.3 cents per energy equivalent of a gallon of gasoline,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in the case of any liquid fuel (other than ethanol and methanol) derived from coal (including peat) and liquid hydrocarbons derived from biomass (as defined in section 45K(c)(3)), 24.3 cents per gallon, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> in the case of liquefied natural gas, 24.3 cents per energy equivalent of a gallon of diesel.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Energy equivalent of a gallon of gasoline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “energy equivalent of a gallon of gasoline” means, with respect to a liquefied petroleum gas fuel, the amount of such fuel having a Btu content of 115,400 (lower heating value). For purposes of the preceding sentence, a Btu content of 115,400 (lower heating value) is equal to 5.75 pounds of liquefied petroleum gas.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Energy equivalent of a gallon of diesel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “energy equivalent of a gallon of diesel” means, with respect to a liquefied natural gas fuel, the amount of such fuel having a Btu content of 128,700 (lower heating value). For purposes of the preceding sentence, a Btu content of 128,700 (lower heating value) is equal to 6.06 pounds of liquefied natural gas.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compressed natural gas</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">There is hereby imposed a tax on compressed natural gas—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> sold by any person to an owner, lessee, or other operator of a motor vehicle or motorboat for use as a fuel in such motor vehicle or motorboat, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> used by any person as a fuel in a motor vehicle or motorboat unless there was a taxable sale of such gas under clause (i).</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">The rate of the tax imposed by this paragraph shall be 18.3 cents per energy equivalent of a gallon of gasoline.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Bus uses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No tax shall be imposed by this paragraph on any sale for use, or use, described in subparagraph (B) or (C) of section 6427(b)(2) (relating to school bus and intracity transportation).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of applying this title with respect to the taxes imposed by this subsection, references to any liquid subject to tax under this subsection shall be treated as including references to compressed natural gas subject to tax under this paragraph, and references to gallons shall be treated as including references to energy equivalent of a gallon of gasoline with respect to such gas.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Energy equivalent of a gallon of gasoline</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “energy equivalent of a gallon of gasoline” means 5.66 pounds of compressed natural gas.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption for off-highway business use; reduction in tax for qualified methanol and ethanol fuel</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption for off-highway business use</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">No tax shall be imposed by subsection (a) on liquids sold for use or used in an off-highway business use.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax where other use</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If a liquid on which no tax was imposed by reason of subparagraph (A) is used otherwise than in an off-highway business use, a tax shall be imposed by paragraph (1)(B), (2)(B), or (3)(A)(ii) of subsection (a) (whichever is appropriate) and by the corresponding provision of subsection (d)(1) (if any).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Off-highway business use defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of this subsection, the term “off-highway business use” has the meaning given to such term by section 6421(e)(2); except that such term shall not, for purposes of subsection (a)(1), include use in a diesel-powered train.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified methanol and ethanol fuel</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In the case of any qualified methanol or ethanol fuel—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the rate applicable under subsection (a)(2) shall be the applicable blender rate per gallon less than the otherwise applicable rate (6 cents per gallon in the case of a mixture none of the alcohol in which consists of ethanol), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> subsection (d)(1) shall be applied by substituting “0.05 cent” for “0.1 cent” with respect to the sales and uses to which clause (i) applies.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified methanol and ethanol fuel produced from coal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “qualified methanol or ethanol fuel” means any liquid at least 85 percent of which consists of methanol, ethanol, or other alcohol produced from coal (including peat).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable blender rate</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A)(i), the applicable blender rate is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> except as provided in clause (ii), 5.4 cents, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for sales or uses during calendar years 2001 through 2008, ⅒ of the blender amount applicable under section 40(h)(2) for the calendar year in which the sale or use occurs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">On and after <date date="2009-01-01">January 1, 2009</date>, subparagraph (A) shall not apply.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain liquids used as a fuel in aviation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">There is hereby imposed a tax upon any liquid for use as a fuel other than aviation gasoline—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sold by any person to an owner, lessee, or other operator of an aircraft for use in such aircraft, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> used by any person in an aircraft unless there was a taxable sale of such fuel under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption for previously taxed fuel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No tax shall be imposed by this subsection on the sale or use of any liquid for use as a fuel other than aviation gasoline if tax was imposed on such liquid under section 4081 (other than such tax at the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate) and the tax thereon was not credited or refunded.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rate of tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The rate of tax imposed by this subsection shall be 21.8 cents per gallon (4.3 cents per gallon with respect to any sale or use for commercial aviation).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional taxes to fund Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax on sales and uses subject to tax under subsection (a)</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to the taxes imposed by subsection (a), there is hereby imposed a tax of 0.1 cent a gallon on the sale or use of any liquid (other than liquefied petroleum gas and other than liquefied natural gas) if tax is imposed by subsection (a)(1) or (2) on such sale or use. No tax shall be imposed under the preceding sentence on the sale or use of any liquid if tax was imposed with respect to such liquid under section 4081 at the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liquids used in aviation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In addition to the taxes imposed by subsection (c), there is hereby imposed a tax of 0.1 cent a gallon on any liquid (other than gasoline (as defined in section 4083))—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sold by any person to an owner, lessee, or other operator of an aircraft for use as a fuel in such aircraft, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> used by any person as a fuel in an aircraft unless there was a taxable sale of such liquid under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">No tax shall be imposed by this paragraph on the sale or use of any liquid if there was a taxable sale of such liquid under section 4081.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Diesel fuel used in trains</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of any sale for use or use after <date date="2006-12-31">December 31, 2006</date>, there is hereby imposed a tax of 0.1 cent per gallon on any liquid other than gasoline (as defined in section 4083)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sold by any person to an owner, lessee, or other operator of a diesel-powered train for use as a fuel in such train, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> used by any person as a fuel in a diesel-powered train unless there was a taxable sale of such fuel under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">No tax shall be imposed by this paragraph on the sale or use of any liquid if tax was imposed on such liquid under section 4081.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The taxes imposed by this subsection shall not apply during any period during which the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate under section 4081 does not apply.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonapplication of exemptions other than for exports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the tax imposed under this subsection shall be determined without regard to subsections (b)(1)(A), (f), (g), (h), and (<i>l</i>). The preceding sentence shall not apply with respect to subsection (g)(3) and so much of subsection (g)(1) as relates to vessels (within the meaning of section 4221(d)(3)) employed in foreign trade or trade between the United States and any of its possessions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">[(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 108–357, title VIII, § 853(d)(2)(C)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1613</ref>]</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption for farm use</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, no tax shall be imposed under this section on any liquid sold for use or used on a farm for farming purposes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use on a farm for farming purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1) of this subsection, use on a farm for farming purposes shall be determined in accordance with paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 6420(c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other exemptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, no tax shall be imposed under this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> on any liquid sold for use or used as supplies for vessels or aircraft (within the meaning of section 4221(d)(3));</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with respect to the sale of any liquid for the exclusive use of any State, any political subdivision of a State, or the District of Columbia, or with respect to the use by any of the foregoing of any liquid as a fuel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> upon the sale of any liquid for export, or for shipment to a possession of the United States, and in due course so exported or shipped;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> with respect to the sale of any liquid to a nonprofit educational organization for its exclusive use, or with respect to the use by a nonprofit educational organization of any liquid as a fuel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> with respect to the sale of any liquid to a qualified blood collector organization (as defined in section 7701(a)(49)) for such organization’s exclusive use in the collection, storage, or transportation of blood.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of paragraph (4), the term “nonprofit educational organization” means an educational organization described in section 170(b)(1)(A)(ii) which is exempt from income tax under section 501(a). The term also includes a school operated as an activity of an organization described in section 501(c)(3) which is exempt from income tax under section 501(a), if such school normally maintains a regular faculty and curriculum and normally has a regularly enrolled body of pupils or students in attendance at the place where its educational activities are regularly carried on.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption for use by certain aircraft museums</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, no tax shall be imposed under this section on any liquid sold for use or used by an aircraft museum in an aircraft or vehicle owned by such museum and used exclusively for purposes set forth in paragraph (2)(C).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of aircraft museum</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “aircraft museum” means an organization—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> described in section 501(c)(3) which is exempt from income tax under section 501(a),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> operated as a museum under charter by a State or the District of Columbia, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> operated exclusively for the procurement, care, and exhibition of aircraft of the type used for combat or transport in World War II.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">[(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 108–357, title VIII, § 853(d)(2)(D)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1613</ref>]</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sales by United States, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The taxes imposed by this section shall apply with respect to liquids sold at retail by the United States, or by any agency or instrumentality of the United States, unless sales by such agency or instrumentality are by statute specifically exempted from such taxes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">[(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 108–357, title III, § 301(c)(6)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1461</ref>]</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption for certain uses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No tax shall be imposed under this section on any liquid sold for use in, or used in, a helicopter or a fixed-wing aircraft for purposes of providing transportation with respect to which the requirements of subsection (f) or (g) of section 4261 are met.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(m)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain alcohol fuels</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of the sale or use of any partially exempt methanol or ethanol fuel the rate of the tax imposed by subsection (a)(2) shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> after <date date="1997-09-30">September 30, 1997</date>, and before <date date="2028-10-01">October 1, 2028</date>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of fuel none of the alcohol in which consists of ethanol, 9.15 cents per gallon, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in any other case, 11.3 cents per gallon, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> after <date date="2028-09-30">September 30, 2028</date>—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of fuel none of the alcohol in which consists of ethanol, 2.15 cents per gallon, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in any other case, 4.3 cents per gallon.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partially exempt methanol or ethanol fuel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “partially exempt methanol or ethanol fuel” means any liquid at least 85 percent of which consists of methanol, ethanol, or other alcohol produced from natural gas.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 478</ref>; <ref>Mar. 30, 1955, ch. 18, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, <ref>69 Stat. 14</ref>; <ref>Mar. 29, 1956, ch. 115, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 66</ref>; <ref>Apr. 2, 1956, ch. 160, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 89</ref>; <ref>June 29, 1956, ch. 462</ref>, title II, § 202, <ref>70 Stat. 387</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–859, title I, § 119(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1286</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–342, title II, § 201(b)</ref>, <date date="1959-09-21">Sept. 21, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 613</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–61, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, (c), (d), <date date="1961-06-29">June 29, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 123</ref>, 124; <ref>Pub. L. 89–44, title VIII, § 802(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1965-06-21">June 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 159</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–258, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1970-05-21">May 21, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 237</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–605, title III, § 303(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1743</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–280, title III, § 303(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1976-05-05">May 5, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 456</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX</ref>, §§ 1904(a)(1)(B), (C), 1906(b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1810</ref>, 1811, 1834; <ref>Pub. L. 94–530, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-17">Oct. 17, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2487</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–599, title V, § 502(a)(1)</ref>, (b), <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2756</ref>, 2757; <ref>Pub. L. 95–600, title VII, § 703</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1), (2), <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2942</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–618, title II</ref>, §§ 221(b)(1), 222(a)(2), 233(a)(3)(B), <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3185</ref>, 3187, 3191; <ref>Pub. L. 96–223, title II, § 232(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1980-04-02">Apr. 2, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 273</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–298, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-07-01">July 1, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 829</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–248, title II, § 279(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 563</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–424, title V</ref>, §§ 511(a)(2), (b)(1), (c)(2), (d)(2), (g)(1), 516(a)(1), (b)(1), <date date="1983-01-06">Jan. 6, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2169–2171</ref>, 2173, 2182, 2183; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title IX</ref>, §§ 911(a), 912(a), 913(a), title X, § 1018(a), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1005</ref>, 1007, 1008, 1021; <ref>Pub. L. 99–499, title V, § 521(a)(2)</ref>, (d)(1)–(3), <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1776</ref>, 1779; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title IV, § 422(a)(1)</ref>, (2), title XVII, § 1702(a), title XVIII, § 1878(c)(1), <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2229</ref>, 2773, 2903; <ref>Pub. L. 100–17, title V, § 502(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(1)–(3), (c)(1), <date date="1987-04-02">Apr. 2, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 256</ref>, 257; <ref>Pub. L. 100–203, title X, § 10502(b)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1330–441</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–223, title IV</ref>, §§ 402(b), 404(b), 405(b)(3), <date date="1987-12-30">Dec. 30, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1532</ref>, 1533, 1535; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1017(c)(3)</ref>, (4), title II, § 2001(d)(2), (3)(A)–(D), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3576</ref>, 3595; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XI</ref>, §§ 11211(a)(4), (b)(3), (6)(C)–(E)(i), (F), (d)(1), (2), (e)(1), (2), 11213(b)(2)(A), (B), (d)(2)(B), (e)(3), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–423</ref>, 1388–425 to 1388–427, 1388–433, 1388–436; <ref>Pub. L. 102–240, title VIII, § 8002(b)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 2203</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–66, title XIII</ref>, §§ 13163(a)(2), 13241(b)(2)(A), (B)(iii), (c), (e), (f)(1), (2), 13242(d)(3)–(13), <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 453</ref>, 510, 511, 522–524; <ref>Pub. L. 104–188, title I</ref>, §§ 1208, 1609(a)(3), (g)(3), (4)(A), <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1776</ref>, 1841–1843; <ref>Pub. L. 105–2, § 2(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1997-02-28">Feb. 28, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 4</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–34, title IX</ref>, §§ 902(b)(1), (2), 907(a), (b), title X, §§ 1031(a)(3), 1032(e)(1), (2), title XIV, § 1435(b), title XVI, § 1601(f)(4)(A), (B), <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 873</ref>, 875, 929, 935, 1053, 1090; <ref>Pub. L. 105–178, title IX</ref>, §§ 9002(a)(1)(A)–(C), 9003(a)(1)(A), (B), (b)(2)(A), 9006(a), <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 499</ref>, 501, 502, 506; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title VI, § 6010(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–357, title II, § 241(a)(1)</ref>, (2)(A), title III, § 301(c)(5), (6), title VIII, § 853(a)(6), (d)(2)(A)–(E), <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1437</ref>, 1461, 1611–1613; <ref>Pub. L. 109–58, title XIII, § 1362(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1059</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–59, title XI</ref>, §§ 11101(a)(1)(A)–(C), 11113(a), 11151(e)(2), 11161(b)(1), (3)(A), <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1943</ref>, 1946, 1969–1971; <ref>Pub. L. 109–280, title XII, § 1207(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1070</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–432, div. A, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2946</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–172, § 6(d)(1)(A)</ref>, (2)(A), (3), <date date="2007-12-29">Dec. 29, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2480</ref>, 2481; <ref>Pub. L. 112–30, title I, § 142(a)(1)(A)</ref>, (B), (2)(A), <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 355</ref>, 356; <ref>Pub. L. 112–102, title IV, § 402(a)(1)(A)</ref>, (B), (2)(A), <date date="2012-03-30">Mar. 30, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 281</ref>, 282; <ref>Pub. L. 112–140, title IV, § 402(a)(1)(A)</ref>, (B), (2)(A), <date date="2012-06-29">June 29, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 402</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–141, div. D, title I, § 40102(a)(1)(A)</ref>, (B), (2)(A), <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 844</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–41, title II, § 2008(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2015-07-31">July 31, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 459</ref>, 460; <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. C, title XXXI, § 31102(a)(1)(A)</ref>, (B), (2)(A), <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1727</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. H, title I, § 80102(a)(1)(A)</ref>, (B), (2)(A), <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1327</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4042.</num>
<heading> Tax on fuel used in commercial transportation on inland waterways</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby imposed a tax on any liquid used during any calendar quarter by any person as a fuel in a vessel in commercial waterway transportation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of tax</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The rate of the tax imposed by subsection (a) is the sum of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Inland Waterways Trust Fund financing rate, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rates</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Inland Waterways Trust Fund financing rate is 29 cents per gallon.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate is 0.1 cent per gallon.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for fuel on which Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate separately imposed</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate under paragraph (2)(B) shall not apply to the use of any fuel if tax was imposed with respect to such fuel under section 4041(d) or 4081 at the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate under paragraph (2)(B) shall not apply during any period during which the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate under section 4081 does not apply.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemptions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deep-draft ocean-going vessels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The tax imposed by subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to any vessel designed primarily for use on the high seas which has a draft of more than 12 feet.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Passenger vessels</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The tax imposed by subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to any vessel used primarily for the transportation of persons.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use by State or local government in transporting property in a state or local business</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subparagraph (B) of subsection (d)(1) shall not apply with respect to use by a State or political subdivision thereof.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use in moving lash and seabee ocean-going barges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The tax imposed by subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to use for movement by tug of exclusively LASH (Lighter-aboard-ship) and SEABEE ocean-going barges released by their ocean-going carriers solely to pick up or deliver international cargoes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Commercial waterway transportation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “commercial waterway transportation” means any use of a vessel on any inland or intracoastal waterway of the United States—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the business of transporting property for compensation or hire, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in transporting property in the business of the owner, lessee, or operator of the vessel (other than fish or other aquatic animal life caught on the voyage).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inland or intracoastal waterway of the United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “inland or intracoastal waterway of the United States” means any inland or intracoastal waterway of the United States which is described in section 206 of the Inland Waterways Revenue Act of 1978.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “person” includes the United States, a State, a political subdivision of a State, or any agency or instrumentality of any of the foregoing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Date for filing return</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The date for filing the return of the tax imposed by this section for any calendar quarter shall be the last day of the first month following such quarter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–502, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1696</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–499, title V, § 521(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1777</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–662, title XIV, § 1404(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 4270</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title II, § 2002(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3597</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–66, title XIII, § 13241(d)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 510</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–357, title II, § 241(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1438</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–172, § 6(d)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-29">Dec. 29, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2480</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. B, title II, § 205(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4065</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(b)(40)</ref>, (41), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1204</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4043.</num>
<heading> Surtax on fuel used in aircraft part of a fractional ownership program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is hereby imposed a tax on any liquid used (during any calendar quarter by any person) in a fractional program aircraft as fuel—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for the transportation of a qualified fractional owner with respect to the fractional ownership aircraft program of which such aircraft is a part, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with respect to the use of such aircraft on account of such a qualified fractional owner, including use in deadhead service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The rate of tax imposed by subsection (a) is 14.1 cents per gallon.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions and special rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fractional program aircraft</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “fractional program aircraft” means, with respect to any fractional ownership aircraft program, any aircraft which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is listed as a fractional program aircraft in the management specifications issued to the manager of such program by the Federal Aviation Administration under subpart K of part 91 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is registered in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fractional ownership aircraft program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “fractional ownership aircraft program” means a program under which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a single fractional ownership program manager provides fractional ownership program management services on behalf of the fractional owners,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> there are 1 or more fractional owners per fractional program aircraft, with at least 1 fractional program aircraft having more than 1 owner,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to at least 2 fractional program aircraft, none of the ownership interests in such aircraft are—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> less than the minimum fractional ownership interest, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> held by the program manager referred to in subparagraph (A),</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> there exists a dry-lease aircraft exchange arrangement among all of the fractional owners, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> there are multi-year program agreements covering the fractional ownership, fractional ownership program management services, and dry-lease aircraft exchange aspects of the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions related to fractional ownership interests</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified fractional owner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “qualified fractional owner” means any fractional owner which has a minimum fractional ownership interest in at least one fractional program aircraft.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum fractional ownership interest</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “minimum fractional ownership interest” means, with respect to each type of aircraft—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a fractional ownership interest equal to or greater than 1/16 of at least 1 subsonic, fixed wing, or powered lift aircraft, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a fractional ownership interest equal to or greater than 1/32 of at least 1 rotorcraft aircraft.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fractional ownership interest</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “fractional ownership interest” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the ownership of an interest in a fractional program aircraft,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the holding of a multi-year leasehold interest in a fractional program aircraft, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the holding of a multi-year leasehold interest which is convertible into an ownership interest in a fractional program aircraft.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fractional owner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “fractional owner” means any person owning any interest (including the entire interest) in a fractional program aircraft.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Dry-lease aircraft exchange</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “dry-lease aircraft exchange” means an agreement, documented by the written program agreements, under which the fractional program aircraft are available, on an as needed basis without crew, to each fractional owner.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule relating to use of fractional program aircraft for flight demonstration, maintenance, or training</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of subsection (a), a fractional program aircraft shall not be considered to be used for the transportation of a qualified fractional owner, or on account of such qualified fractional owner, when it is used for flight demonstration, maintenance, or crew training.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule relating to deadhead service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A fractional program aircraft shall not be considered to be used on account of a qualified fractional owner when it is used in deadhead service and a person other than a qualified fractional owner is separately charged for such service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply to liquids used as a fuel in an aircraft after <date date="2028-09-30">September 30, 2028</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 112–95, title XI, § 1103(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 149</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title VIII, § 802(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–15, div. B, title II, § 2212(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2023-09-30">Sept. 30, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 85</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–34, title II, § 202(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-26">Dec. 26, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 1115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–41, title II, § 202(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-03-08">Mar. 8, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 24</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title XIII, § 1302(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter C—</num>
<heading>Heavy Trucks and Trailers</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4051.</num>
<heading> Imposition of tax on heavy trucks and trailers sold at retail</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Imposition of tax</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">There is hereby imposed on the first retail sale of the following articles (including in each case parts or accessories sold on or in connection therewith or with the sale thereof) a tax of 12 percent of the amount for which the article is so sold:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Automobile truck chassis.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Automobile truck bodies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Truck trailer and semitrailer chassis.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Truck trailer and semitrailer bodies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Tractors of the kind chiefly used for highway transportation in combination with a trailer or semitrailer.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion for trucks weighing 33,000 pounds or less</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The tax imposed by paragraph (1) shall not apply to automobile truck chassis and automobile truck bodies, suitable for use with a vehicle which has a gross vehicle weight of 33,000 pounds or less (as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion for trailers weighing 26,000 pounds or less</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The tax imposed by paragraph (1) shall not apply to truck trailer and semitrailer chassis and bodies, suitable for use with a trailer or semitrailer which has a gross vehicle weight of 26,000 pounds or less (as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion for tractors weighing 19,500 pounds or less</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The tax imposed by paragraph (1) shall not apply to tractors of the kind chiefly used for highway transportation in combination with a trailer or semitrailer if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such tractor has a gross vehicle weight of 19,500 pounds or less (as determined by the Secretary), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such tractor, in combination with a trailer or semitrailer, has a gross combined weight of 33,000 pounds or less (as determined by the Secretary).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sale of trucks, etc., treated as sale of chassis and body</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, a sale of an automobile truck or truck trailer or semitrailer shall be considered to be a sale of a chassis and of a body described in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Separate purchase of truck or trailer and parts and accessories therefor</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the owner, lessee, or operator of any vehicle which contains an article taxable under subsection (a) installs (or causes to be installed) any part or accessory on such vehicle, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such installation is not later than the date 6 months after the date such vehicle (as it contains such article) was first placed in service,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">then there is hereby imposed on such installation a tax equal to 12 percent of the price of such part or accessory and its installation.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the part or accessory installed is a replacement part or accessory, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the aggregate price of the parts and accessories (and their installation) described in paragraph (1) with respect to any vehicle does not exceed $1,000 (or such other amount or amounts as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Installers secondarily liable for tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The owners of the trade or business installing the parts or accessories shall be secondarily liable for the tax imposed by paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">On and after <date date="2028-10-01">October 1, 2028</date>, the taxes imposed by this section shall not apply.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Credit against tax for tire tax</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> tires are sold on or in connection with the sale of any article, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> tax is imposed by this subchapter on the sale of such tires,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this subchapter an amount equal to the tax (if any) imposed by section 4071 on such tires.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–424, title V, § 512(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-06">Jan. 6, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2174</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title VII, § 734(g)</ref>, title IX, § 921, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 980</ref>, 1009; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1877(c), 1899A(47), <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2902</ref>, 2961; <ref>Pub. L. 100–17, title V, § 502(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-02">Apr. 2, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 256</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11211(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–426</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–240, title VIII, § 8002(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 2203</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–34, title XIV</ref>, §§ 1401(a), 1402(a), 1432(a), <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1045</ref>, 1046, 1050; <ref>Pub. L. 105–178, title IX, § 9002(a)(1)(D)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 499</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–59, title XI</ref>, §§ 11101(a)(1)(D), 11112(a), <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1943</ref>, 1946; <ref>Pub. L. 112–30, title I, § 142(a)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 356</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–102, title IV, § 402(a)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2012-03-30">Mar. 30, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 282</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–140, title IV, § 402(a)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2012-06-29">June 29, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 402</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–141, div. D, title I, § 40102(a)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2012-07-06">July 6, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 844</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. C, title XXXI, § 31102(a)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1727</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(219)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1194</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. H, title I, § 80102(a)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1327</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4052.</num>
<heading> Definitions and special rules</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> First retail sale</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “first retail sale” means the first sale, for a purpose other than for resale or leasing in a long-term lease, after production, manufacture, or importation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Leases considered as sales</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Rules similar to the rules of section 4217 shall apply.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use treated as sale</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If any person uses an article taxable under section 4051 before the first retail sale of such article, then such person shall be liable for tax under section 4051 in the same manner as if such article were sold at retail by him.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption for use in further manufacture</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to use of an article as material in the manufacture or production of, or as a component part of, another article to be manufactured or produced by him.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Computation of tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of any person made liable for tax by subparagraph (A), the tax shall be computed on the price at which similar articles are sold at retail in the ordinary course of trade, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of price</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In determining price for purposes of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> there shall be included any charge incident to placing the article in condition ready for use,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> there shall be excluded—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the amount of the tax imposed by this subchapter,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if stated as a separate charge, the amount of any retail sales tax imposed by any State or political subdivision thereof or the District of Columbia, whether the liability for such tax is imposed on the vendor or vendee, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> the value of any component of such article if—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> such component is furnished by the first user of such article, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> such component has been used before such furnishing, and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the price shall be determined without regard to any trade-in.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sales not at arm’s length</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of any article sold (otherwise than through an arm’s-length transaction) at less than the fair market price, the tax under this subchapter shall be computed on the price for which similar articles are sold at retail in the ordinary course of trade, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Long-term lease</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In the case of any long-term lease of an article which is treated as the first retail sale of such article, the tax under this subchapter shall be computed on a price equal to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the sum of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the price (determined under this subchapter but without regard to paragraph (4)) at which such article was sold to the lessor, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the cost of any parts and accessories installed by the lessor on such article before the first use by the lessee or leased in connection with such long-term lease, plus</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an amount equal to the presumed markup percentage of the sum described in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Presumed markup percentage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “presumed markup percentage” means the average markup percentage of retailers of articles of the type involved, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions under regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To the extent provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary, subparagraph (A) shall not apply to specified types of leases where its application is not necessary to carry out the purposes of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule where tax paid by manufacturer, producer, or importer</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In any case where the manufacturer, producer, or importer of any article (or a related person) is liable for tax imposed by this subchapter with respect to such article, the tax under this subchapter shall be computed on a price equal to the sum of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the price which would (but for this paragraph) be determined under this subchapter, plus</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the product of the price referred to in clause (i) and the presumed markup percentage determined under paragraph (3)(B).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Related person</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Except as provided in clause (ii), the term “related person” means any person who is a member of the same controlled group (within the meaning of section 5061(e)(3)) as the manufacturer, producer, or importer.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for retail establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">To the extent provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary, a person shall not be treated as a related person with respect to the sale of any article if such article is sold through a permanent retail establishment in the normal course of the trade or business of being a retailer.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain combinations not treated as manufacture</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subchapter (other than subsection (a)(3)(B)), a person shall not be treated as engaged in the manufacture of any article by reason of merely combining such article with any item listed in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Items</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The items listed in this paragraph are any coupling device (including any fifth wheel), wrecker crane, loading and unloading equipment (including any crane, hoist, winch, or power liftgate), aerial ladder or tower, snow and ice control equipment, earthmoving, excavation and construction equipment, spreader, sleeper cab, cab shield, or wood or metal floor.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain other rules made applicable</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, rules similar to the rules of subsections (c) and (d) of section 4216 (relating to partial payments) shall apply for purposes of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Long-term lease</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “long-term lease” means any lease with a term of 1 year or more. In determining a lease term for purposes of the preceding sentence, the rules of section 168(i)(3)(A) shall apply.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain repairs and modifications not treated as manufacture</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An article described in section 4051(a)(1) shall not be treated as manufactured or produced solely by reason of repairs or modifications to the article (including any modification which changes the transportation function of the article or restores a wrecked article to a functional condition) if the cost of such repairs and modifications does not exceed 75 percent of the retail price of a comparable new article.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply if the article (as repaired or modified) would, if new, be taxable under section 4051 and the article when new was not taxable under such section or the corresponding provision of prior law.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall prescribe regulations which permit, in lieu of any other certification, persons who are purchasing articles taxable under this subchapter for resale or leasing in a long-term lease to execute a statement (made under penalties of perjury) on the sale invoice that such sale is for resale. The Secretary shall not impose any registration requirement as a condition of using such procedure.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–424, title V, § 512(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-06">Jan. 6, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2175</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title VII</ref>, §§ 731, 735(b)(2), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 976</ref>, 981; <ref>Pub. L. 100–17, title V</ref>, §§ 505(a)–(c), 506(a), <date date="1987-04-02">Apr. 2, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 258</ref>, 259; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VI, § 6111(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3713</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–34, title XIV</ref>, §§ 1402(b), 1434(a), (b), <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1046</ref>, 1052; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title VI, § 6014(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 820</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4053.</num>
<heading> Exemptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No tax shall be imposed by section 4051 on any of the following articles:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Camper coaches bodies for self-propelled mobile homes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any article designed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to be mounted or placed on automobile trucks, automobile truck chassis, or automobile chassis, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to be used primarily as living quarters or camping accommodations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Feed, seed, and fertilizer equipment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any body primarily designed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to process or prepare seed, feed, or fertilizer for use on farms,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to haul feed, seed, or fertilizer to and on farms,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to spread feed, seed, or fertilizer on farms,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to load or unload feed, seed, or fertilizer on farms, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> for any combination of the foregoing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> House trailers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any house trailer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ambulances, hearses, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any ambulance, hearse, or combination ambulance-hearse.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Concrete mixers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any article designed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to be placed or mounted on an automobile truck chassis or truck trailer or semitrailer chassis, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to be used to process or prepare concrete.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Trash containers, etc.</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any box, container, receptacle, bin or other similar article—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> which is designed to be used as a trash container and is not designed for the transportation of freight other than trash, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> which is not designed to be permanently mounted on or permanently affixed to an automobile truck chassis or body.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rail trailers and rail vans</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any chassis or body of a trailer or semitrailer which is designed for use both as a highway vehicle and a railroad car. For purposes of the preceding sentence, piggy-back trailer or semitrailer shall not be treated as designed for use as a railroad car.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mobile machinery</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any vehicle which consists of a chassis—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to which there has been permanently mounted (by welding, bolting, riveting, or other means) machinery or equipment to perform a construction, manufacturing, processing, farming, mining, drilling, timbering, or similar operation if the operation of the machinery or equipment is unrelated to transportation on or off the public highways,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> which has been specially designed to serve only as a mobile carriage and mount (and a power source, where applicable) for the particular machinery or equipment involved, whether or not such machinery or equipment is in operation, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> which, by reason of such special design, could not, without substantial structural modification, be used as a component of a vehicle designed to perform a function of transporting any load other than that particular machinery or equipment or similar machinery or equipment requiring such a specially designed chassis.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Idling reduction device</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any device or system of devices which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is designed to provide to a vehicle those services (such as heat, air conditioning, or electricity) that would otherwise require the operation of the main drive engine while the vehicle is temporarily parked or remains stationary using one or more devices affixed to a tractor, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is determined by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Transportation, to reduce idling of such vehicle at a motor vehicle rest stop or other location where such vehicles are temporarily parked or remain stationary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advanced insulation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any insulation that has an R value of not less than R35 per inch.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 97–424, title V, § 512(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-06">Jan. 6, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2176</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title VII, § 735(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 981</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–357, title VIII, § 851(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1607</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–343, div. B, title II, § 206(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-03">Oct. 3, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3839</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>