<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 4—</num>
<heading>TAXES TO ENFORCE REPORTING ON CERTAIN FOREIGN ACCOUNTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1471.</num>
<heading> Withholdable payments to foreign financial institutions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of any withholdable payment to a foreign financial institution which does not meet the requirements of subsection (b), the withholding agent with respect to such payment shall deduct and withhold from such payment a tax equal to 30 percent of the amount of such payment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reporting requirements, etc.</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The requirements of this subsection are met with respect to any foreign financial institution if an agreement is in effect between such institution and the Secretary under which such institution agrees—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to obtain such information regarding each holder of each account maintained by such institution as is necessary to determine which (if any) of such accounts are United States accounts,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to comply with such verification and due diligence procedures as the Secretary may require with respect to the identification of United States accounts,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of any United States account maintained by such institution, to report on an annual basis the information described in subsection (c) with respect to such account,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> to deduct and withhold a tax equal to 30 percent of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any passthru payment which is made by such institution to a recalcitrant account holder or another foreign financial institution which does not meet the requirements of this subsection, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of any passthru payment which is made by such institution to a foreign financial institution which has in effect an election under paragraph (3) with respect to such payment, so much of such payment as is allocable to accounts held by recalcitrant account holders or foreign financial institutions which do not meet the requirements of this subsection,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to comply with requests by the Secretary for additional information with respect to any United States account maintained by such institution, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> in any case in which any foreign law would (but for a waiver described in clause (i)) prevent the reporting of any information referred to in this subsection or subsection (c) with respect to any United States account maintained by such institution—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to attempt to obtain a valid and effective waiver of such law from each holder of such account, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if a waiver described in clause (i) is not obtained from each such holder within a reasonable period of time, to close such account.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">Any agreement entered into under this subsection may be terminated by the Secretary upon a determination by the Secretary that the foreign financial institution is out of compliance with such agreement.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial institutions deemed to meet requirements in certain cases</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A foreign financial institution may be treated by the Secretary as meeting the requirements of this subsection if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> such institution—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> complies with such procedures as the Secretary may prescribe to ensure that such institution does not maintain United States accounts, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> meets such other requirements as the Secretary may prescribe with respect to accounts of other foreign financial institutions maintained by such institution, or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such institution is a member of a class of institutions with respect to which the Secretary has determined that the application of this section is not necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election to be withheld upon rather than withhold on payments to recalcitrant account holders and nonparticipating foreign financial institutions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of a foreign financial institution which meets the requirements of this subsection and such other requirements as the Secretary may provide and which elects the application of this paragraph—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the requirements of paragraph (1)(D) shall not apply,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the withholding tax imposed under subsection (a) shall apply with respect to any withholdable payment to such institution to the extent such payment is allocable to accounts held by recalcitrant account holders or foreign financial institutions which do not meet the requirements of this subsection, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> the agreement described in paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> require such institution to notify the withholding agent with respect to each such payment of the institution’s election under this paragraph and such other information as may be necessary for the withholding agent to determine the appropriate amount to deduct and withhold from such payment, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> include a waiver of any right under any treaty of the United States with respect to any amount deducted and withheld pursuant to an election under this paragraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">To the extent provided by the Secretary, the election under this paragraph may be made with respect to certain classes or types of accounts of the foreign financial institution.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information required to be reported on United States accounts</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The agreement described in subsection (b) shall require the foreign financial institution to report the following with respect to each United States account maintained by such institution:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The name, address, and TIN of each account holder which is a specified United States person and, in the case of any account holder which is a United States owned foreign entity, the name, address, and TIN of each substantial United States owner of such entity.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The account number.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The account balance or value (determined at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may provide).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Except to the extent provided by the Secretary, the gross receipts and gross withdrawals or payments from the account (determined for such period and in such manner as the Secretary may provide).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election to be subject to same reporting as United States financial institutions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of a foreign financial institution which elects the application of this paragraph—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subparagraphs (C) and (D) of paragraph (1) shall not apply, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the agreement described in subsection (b) shall require such foreign financial institution to report such information with respect to each United States account maintained by such institution as such institution would be required to report under sections 6041, 6042, 6045, and 6049 if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such institution were a United States person, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> each holder of such account which is a specified United States person or United States owned foreign entity were a natural person and citizen of the United States.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">An election under this paragraph shall be made at such time, in such manner, and subject to such conditions as the Secretary may provide.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Separate requirements for qualified intermediaries</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a foreign financial institution which is treated as a qualified intermediary by the Secretary for purposes of section 1441 and the regulations issued thereunder, the requirements of this section shall be in addition to any reporting or other requirements imposed by the Secretary for purposes of such treatment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States account</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “United States account” means any financial account which is held by one or more specified United States persons or United States owned foreign entities.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for certain accounts held by individuals</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Unless the foreign financial institution elects to not have this subparagraph apply, such term shall not include any depository account maintained by such financial institution if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> each holder of such account is a natural person, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> with respect to each holder of such account, the aggregate value of all depository accounts held (in whole or in part) by such holder and maintained by the same financial institution which maintains such account does not exceed $50,000.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">To the extent provided by the Secretary, financial institutions which are members of the same expanded affiliated group shall be treated for purposes of clause (ii) as a single financial institution.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Elimination of duplicative reporting requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Such term shall not include any financial account in a foreign financial institution if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such account is held by another financial institution which meets the requirements of subsection (b), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the holder of such account is otherwise subject to information reporting requirements which the Secretary determines would make the reporting required by this section with respect to United States accounts duplicative.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial account</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, the term “financial account” means, with respect to any financial institution—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any depository account maintained by such financial institution,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any custodial account maintained by such financial institution, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any equity or debt interest in such financial institution (other than interests which are regularly traded on an established securities market).</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">Any equity or debt interest which constitutes a financial account under subparagraph (C) with respect to any financial institution shall be treated for purposes of this section as maintained by such financial institution.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States owned foreign entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “United States owned foreign entity” means any foreign entity which has one or more substantial United States owners.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign financial institution</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “foreign financial institution” means any financial institution which is a foreign entity. Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, such term shall not include a financial institution which is organized under the laws of any possession of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Financial institution</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, the term “financial institution” means any entity that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> accepts deposits in the ordinary course of a banking or similar business,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> as a substantial portion of its business, holds financial assets for the account of others, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is engaged (or holding itself out as being engaged) primarily in the business of investing, reinvesting, or trading in securities (as defined in section 475(c)(2) without regard to the last sentence thereof), partnership interests, commodities (as defined in section 475(e)(2)), or any interest (including a futures or forward contract or option) in such securities, partnership interests, or commodities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recalcitrant account holder</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “recalcitrant account holder” means any account holder which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> fails to comply with reasonable requests for the information referred to in subsection (b)(1)(A) or (c)(1)(A), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> fails to provide a waiver described in subsection (b)(1)(F) upon request.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Passthru payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “passthru payment” means any withholdable payment or other payment to the extent attributable to a withholdable payment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Affiliated groups</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The requirements of subsections (b) and (c)(1) shall apply—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> with respect to United States accounts maintained by the foreign financial institution, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, with respect to United States accounts maintained by each other foreign financial institution (other than any foreign financial institution which meets the requirements of subsection (b)) which is a member of the same expanded affiliated group as such foreign financial institution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expanded affiliated group</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “expanded affiliated group” means an affiliated group as defined in section 1504(a), determined—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by substituting “more than 50 percent” for “at least 80 percent” each place it appears, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> without regard to paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 1504(b).</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">A partnership or any other entity (other than a corporation) shall be treated as a member of an expanded affiliated group if such entity is controlled (within the meaning of section 954(d)(3)) by members of such group (including any entity treated as a member of such group by reason of this sentence).</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for certain payments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall not apply to any payment to the extent that the beneficial owner of such payment is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any foreign government, any political subdivision of a foreign government, or any wholly owned agency or instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any international organization or any wholly owned agency or instrumentality thereof,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> any foreign central bank of issue, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any other class of persons identified by the Secretary for purposes of this subsection as posing a low risk of tax evasion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–147, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-18">Mar. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 97</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1472.</num>
<heading> Withholdable payments to other foreign entities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of any withholdable payment to a non-financial foreign entity, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the beneficial owner of such payment is such entity or any other non-financial foreign entity, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the requirements of subsection (b) are not met with respect to such beneficial owner,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">then the withholding agent with respect to such payment shall deduct and withhold from such payment a tax equal to 30 percent of the amount of such payment.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements for waiver of withholding</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The requirements of this subsection are met with respect to the beneficial owner of a payment if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> such beneficial owner or the payee provides the withholding agent with either—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a certification that such beneficial owner does not have any substantial United States owners, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the name, address, and TIN of each substantial United States owner of such beneficial owner,</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the withholding agent does not know, or have reason to know, that any information provided under paragraph (1) is incorrect, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the withholding agent reports the information provided under paragraph (1)(B) to the Secretary in such manner as the Secretary may provide.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, any payment beneficially owned by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any corporation the stock of which is regularly traded on an established securities market,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any corporation which is a member of the same expanded affiliated group (as defined in section 1471(e)(2) without regard to the last sentence thereof) as a corporation described in subparagraph (A),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any entity which is organized under the laws of a possession of the United States and which is wholly owned by one or more bona fide residents (as defined in section 937(a)) of such possession,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any foreign government, any political subdivision of a foreign government, or any wholly owned agency or instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any international organization or any wholly owned agency or instrumentality thereof,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> any foreign central bank of issue, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> any other class of persons identified by the Secretary for purposes of this subsection, and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any class of payments identified by the Secretary for purposes of this subsection as posing a low risk of tax evasion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-financial foreign entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “non-financial foreign entity” means any foreign entity which is not a financial institution (as defined in section 1471(d)(5)).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–147, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-18">Mar. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 102</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1473.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withholdable payment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “withholdable payment” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any payment of interest (including any original issue discount), dividends, rents, salaries, wages, premiums, annuities, compensations, remunerations, emoluments, and other fixed or determinable annual or periodical gains, profits, and income, if such payment is from sources within the United States, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any gross proceeds from the sale or other disposition of any property of a type which can produce interest or dividends from sources within the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for income connected with United States business</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Such term shall not include any item of income which is taken into account under section 871(b)(1) or 882(a)(1) for the taxable year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for sourcing interest paid by foreign branches of domestic financial institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subparagraph (B) of section 861(a)(1) shall not apply.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Substantial United States owner</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “substantial United States owner” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> with respect to any corporation, any specified United States person which owns, directly or indirectly, more than 10 percent of the stock of such corporation (by vote or value),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> with respect to any partnership, any specified United States person which owns, directly or indirectly, more than 10 percent of the profits interests or capital interests in such partnership, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a trust—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> any specified United States person treated as an owner of any portion of such trust under subpart E of part I of subchapter J of chapter 1, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> to the extent provided by the Secretary in regulations or other guidance, any specified United States person which holds, directly or indirectly, more than 10 percent of the beneficial interests of such trust.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for investment vehicles</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of any financial institution described in section 1471(d)(5)(C), clauses (i), (ii), and (iii) of subparagraph (A) shall be applied by substituting “0 percent” for “10 percent”.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specified United States person</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, the term “specified United States person” means any United States person other than—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any corporation the stock of which is regularly traded on an established securities market,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any corporation which is a member of the same expanded affiliated group (as defined in section 1471(e)(2) without regard to the last sentence thereof) as a corporation the stock of which is regularly traded on an established securities market,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any organization exempt from taxation under section 501(a) or an individual retirement plan,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the United States or any wholly owned agency or instrumentality thereof,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any State, the District of Columbia, any possession of the United States, any political subdivision of any of the foregoing, or any wholly owned agency or instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> any bank (as defined in section 581),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> any real estate investment trust (as defined in section 856),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> any regulated investment company (as defined in section 851),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> any common trust fund (as defined in section 584(a)), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<chapeau> any trust which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is exempt from tax under section 664(c), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is described in section 4947(a)(1).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withholding agent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “withholding agent” means all persons, in whatever capacity acting, having the control, receipt, custody, disposal, or payment of any withholdable payment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “foreign entity” means any entity which is not a United States person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–147, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-18">Mar. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 103</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1474.</num>
<heading> Special rules</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability for withheld tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every person required to deduct and withhold any tax under this chapter is hereby made liable for such tax and is hereby indemnified against the claims and demands of any person for the amount of any payments made in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Credits and refunds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the determination of whether any tax deducted and withheld under this chapter results in an overpayment by the beneficial owner of the payment to which such tax is attributable shall be made as if such tax had been deducted and withheld under subchapter A of chapter 3.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule where foreign financial institution is beneficial owner of payment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In the case of any tax properly deducted and withheld under section 1471 from a specified financial institution payment—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> if the foreign financial institution referred to in subparagraph (B) with respect to such payment is entitled to a reduced rate of tax with respect to such payment by reason of any treaty obligation of the United States—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the amount of any credit or refund with respect to such tax shall not exceed the amount of credit or refund attributable to such reduction in rate, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> no interest shall be allowed or paid with respect to such credit or refund, and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if such foreign financial institution is not so entitled, no credit or refund shall be allowed or paid with respect to such tax.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specified financial institution payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “specified financial institution payment” means any payment if the beneficial owner of such payment is a foreign financial institution.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement to identify substantial United States owners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No credit or refund shall be allowed or paid with respect to any tax properly deducted and withheld under this chapter unless the beneficial owner of the payment provides the Secretary such information as the Secretary may require to determine whether such beneficial owner is a United States owned foreign entity (as defined in section 1471(d)(3)) and the identity of any substantial United States owners of such entity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Confidentiality of information</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this chapter, rules similar to the rules of section 3406(f) shall apply.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disclosure of list of participating foreign financial institutions permitted</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The identity of a foreign financial institution which meets the requirements of section 1471(b) shall not be treated as return information for purposes of section 6103.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with other withholding provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide for the coordination of this chapter with other withholding provisions under this title, including providing for the proper crediting of amounts deducted and withheld under this chapter against amounts required to be deducted and withheld under such other provisions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of withholding under agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any tax deducted and withheld pursuant to an agreement described in section 1471(b) shall be treated for purposes of this title as a tax deducted and withheld by a withholding agent under section 1471(a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of, and prevent the avoidance of, this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–147, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-18">Mar. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 104</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>