<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 95—</num>
<heading>PRESIDENTIAL ELECTION CAMPAIGN FUND</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 9001.</num>
<heading> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter may be cited as the “Presidential Election Campaign Fund Act”.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–178, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 563</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9002.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The term “authorized committee” means, with respect to the candidates of a political party for President and Vice President of the United States, any political committee which is authorized in writing by such candidates to incur expenses to further the election of such candidates. Such authorization shall be addressed to the chairman of such political committee, and a copy of such authorization shall be filed by such candidates with the Commission. Any withdrawal of any authorization shall also be in writing and shall be addressed and filed in the same manner as the authorization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “candidate” means, with respect to any presidential election, an individual who (A) has been nominated for election to the office of President of the United States or the office of Vice President of the United States by a major party, or (B) has qualified to have his name on the election ballot (or to have the names of electors pledged to him on the election ballot) as the candidate of a political party for election to either such office in 10 or more States. For purposes of paragraphs (6) and (7) of this section and purposes of section 9004(a)(2), the term “candidate” means, with respect to any preceding presidential election, an individual who received popular votes for the office of President in such election. The term “candidate” shall not include any individual who has ceased actively to seek election to the office of President of the United States or to the office of Vice President of the United States, in more than one State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The term “Commission” means the Federal Election Commission established by section 306(a)(1) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The term “eligible candidates” means the candidates of a political party for President and Vice President of the United States who have met all applicable conditions for eligibility to receive payments under this chapter set forth in section 9003.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> The term “fund” means the Presidential Election Campaign Fund established by section 9006(a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> The term “major party” means, with respect to any presidential election, a political party whose candidate for the office of President in the preceding presidential election received, as the candidate of such party, 25 percent or more of the total number of popular votes received by all candidates for such office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> The term “minor party” means, with respect to any presidential election, a political party whose candidate for the office of President in the preceding presidential election received, as the candidate of such party, 5 percent or more but less than 25 percent of the total number of popular votes received by all candidates for such office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> The term “new party” means, with respect to any presidential election, a political party which is neither a major party nor a minor party.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> The term “political committee” means any committee, association, or organization (whether or not incorporated) which accepts contributions or makes expenditures for the purpose of influencing, or attempting to influence, the nomination or election of one or more individuals to Federal, State, or local elective public office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> The term “presidential election” means the election of presidential and vice-presidential electors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<chapeau> The term “qualified campaign expense” means an expense—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> incurred (i) by the candidate of a political party for the office of President to further his election to such office or to further the election of the candidate of such political party for the office of Vice President, or both (ii) by the candidate of a political party for the office of Vice President to further his election to such office or to further the election of the candidate of such political party for the office of President, or both, or (iii) by an authorized committee of the candidates of a political party for the offices of President and Vice President to further the election of either or both of such candidates to such offices,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> incurred within the expenditure report period (as defined in paragraph (12)), or incurred before the beginning of such period to the extent such expense is for property, services, or facilities used during such period, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> neither the incurring nor payment of which constitutes a violation of any law of the United States or of the State in which such expense is incurred or paid.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">An expense shall be considered as incurred by a candidate or an authorized committee if it is incurred by a person authorized by such candidate or such committee, as the case may be, to incur such expense on behalf of such candidate or such committee. If an authorized committee of the candidates of a political party for President and Vice President of the United States also incurs expenses to further the election of one or more other individuals to Federal, State, or local elective public office, expenses incurred by such committee which are not specifically to further the election of such other individual or individuals shall be considered as incurred to further the election of such candidates for President and Vice President in such proportion as the Commission prescribes by rules or regulations.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<chapeau> The term “expenditure report period” with respect to any presidential election means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a major party, the period beginning with the first day of September before the election, or, if earlier, with the date on which such major party at its national convention nominated its candidate for election to the office of President of the United States, and ending 30 days after the date of the presidential election; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a party which is not a major party, the same period as the expenditure report period of the major party which has the shortest expenditure report period for such presidential election under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–178, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 563</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–443, title IV, § 404(c)(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="1974-10-15">Oct. 15, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1292</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–283, title I, § 115(c)(1)</ref>, title III, § 306(a)(1), <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 495</ref>, 499; <ref>Pub. L. 110–172, § 11(a)(42)(A)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-29">Dec. 29, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2488</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9003.</num>
<heading> Condition for eligibility for payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to be eligible to receive any payments under section 9006, the candidates of a political party in a presidential election shall, in writing—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> agree to obtain and furnish to the Commission such evidence as it may request of the qualified campaign expenses of such candidates,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> agree to keep and furnish to the Commission such records, books, and other information as it may request, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> agree to an audit and examination by the Commission under section 9007 and to pay any amounts required to be paid under such section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Major parties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to be eligible to receive any payments under section 9006, the candidates of a major party in a presidential election shall certify to the Commission, under penalty of perjury, that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> such candidates and their authorized committees will not incur qualified campaign expenses in excess of the aggregate payments to which they will be entitled under section 9004, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> no contributions to defray qualified campaign expenses have been or will be accepted by such candidates or any of their authorized committees except to the extent necessary to make up any deficiency in payments received out of the fund on account of the application of section 9006(c), and no contributions to defray expenses which would be qualified campaign expenses but for subparagraph (C) of section 9002(11) have been or will be accepted by such candidates or any of their authorized committees.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such certification shall be made within such time prior to the day of the presidential election as the Commission shall prescribe by rules or regulations.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minor and new parties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In order to be eligible to receive any payments under section 9006, the candidates of a minor or new party in a presidential election shall certify to the Commission, under penalty of perjury, that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> such candidates and their authorized committees will not incur qualified campaign expenses in excess of the aggregate payments to which the eligible candidates of a major party are entitled under section 9004, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such candidates and their authorized committees will accept and expend or retain contributions to defray qualified campaign expenses only to the extent that the qualified campaign expenses incurred by such candidates and their authorized committees certified to under paragraph (1) exceed the aggregate payments received by such candidates out of the fund pursuant to section 9006.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such certification shall be made within such time prior to the day of the presidential election as the Commission shall prescribe by rules or regulations.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withdrawal by candidate</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In any case in which an individual ceases to be a candidate as a result of the operation of the last sentence of section 9002(2), such individual—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> shall no longer be eligible to receive any payments under section 9006, except that such individual shall be eligible to receive payments under such section to defray qualified campaign expenses incurred while actively seeking election to the office of President of the United States or to the office of Vice President of the United States in more than one State; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> shall pay to the Secretary, as soon as practicable after the date upon which such individual ceases to be a candidate, an amount equal to the amount of payments received by such individual under section 9006 which are not used to defray qualified campaign expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Closed captioning requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No candidate for the office of President or Vice President may receive amounts from the Presidential Election Campaign Fund under this chapter or chapter 96 unless such candidate has certified that any television commercial prepared or distributed by the candidate will be prepared in a manner which ensures that the commercial contains or is accompanied by closed captioning of the oral content of the commercial to be broadcast in line 21 of the vertical blanking interval, or is capable of being viewed by deaf and hearing impaired individuals via any comparable successor technology to line 21 of the vertical blanking interval.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–178, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 564</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–53, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="1973-07-01">July 1, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 139</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–443, title IV</ref>, §§ 404(c)(4), (5), 405(b), <date date="1974-10-15">Oct. 15, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1292</ref>, 1294; <ref>Pub. L. 94–283, title III, § 306(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 500</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–393, title V, § 534(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 1764</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(338)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9004.</num>
<heading> Entitlement of eligible candidates to payments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subject to the provisions of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The eligible candidates of each major party in a presidential election shall be entitled to equal payments under section 9006 in an amount which, in the aggregate, shall not exceed the expenditure limitations applicable to such candidates under section 315(b)(1)(B) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The eligible candidates of a minor party in a presidential election shall be entitled to payments under section 9006 equal in the aggregate to an amount which bears the same ratio to the amount allowed under paragraph (1) for a major party as the number of popular votes received by the candidate for President of the minor party, as such candidate, in the preceding presidential election bears to the average number of popular votes received by the candidates for President of the major parties in the preceding presidential election.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If the candidate of one or more political parties (not including a major party) for the office of President was a candidate for such office in the preceding presidential election and received 5 percent or more but less than 25 percent of the total number of popular votes received by all candidates for such office, such candidate and his running mate for the office of Vice President, upon compliance with the provisions of section 9003(a) and (c), shall be treated as eligible candidates entitled to payments under section 9006 in an amount computed as provided in subparagraph (A) by taking into account all the popular votes received by such candidate for the office of President in the preceding presidential election. If eligible candidates of a minor party are entitled to payments under this subparagraph, such entitlement shall be reduced by the amount of the entitlement allowed under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The eligible candidates of a minor party or a new party in a presidential election whose candidate for President in such election receives, as such candidate, 5 percent or more of the total number of popular votes cast for the office of President in such election shall be entitled to payments under section 9006 equal in the aggregate to an amount which bears the same ratio to the amount allowed under paragraph (1) for a major party as the number of popular votes received by such candidate in such election bears to the average number of popular votes received in such election by the candidates for President of the major parties. In the case of eligible candidates entitled to payments under paragraph (2), the amount allowable under this paragraph shall be limited to the amount, if any, by which the entitlement under the preceding sentence exceeds the amount of the entitlement under paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The aggregate payments to which the eligible candidates of a political party shall be entitled under subsections (a)(2) and (3) with respect to a presidential election shall not exceed an amount equal to the lower of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the amount of qualified campaign expenses incurred by such eligible candidates and their authorized committees, reduced by the amount of contributions to defray qualified campaign expenses received and expended or retained by such eligible candidates and such committees, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the aggregate payments to which the eligible candidates of a major party are entitled under subsection (a)(1), reduced by the amount of contributions described in paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The eligible candidates of a political party shall be entitled to payments under subsection (a) only—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to defray qualified campaign expenses incurred by such eligible candidates or their authorized committees, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to repay loans the proceeds of which were used to defray such qualified campaign expenses, or otherwise to restore funds (other than contributions to defray qualified campaign expenses received and expended by such candidates or such committees) used to defray such qualified campaign expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expenditures from personal funds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In order to be eligible to receive any payment under section 9006, the candidate of a major, minor, or new party in an election for the office of President shall certify to the Commission, under penalty of perjury, that such candidate will not knowingly make expenditures from his personal funds, or the personal funds of his immediate family, in connection with his campaign for election to the office of President in excess of, in the aggregate, $50,000. For purposes of this subsection, expenditures from personal funds made by a candidate of a major, minor, or new party for the office of Vice President shall be considered to be expenditures by the candidate of such party for the office of President.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of immediate family</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (d), the term “immediate family” means a candidate’s spouse, and any child, parent, grandparent, brother, half-brother, sister, or half-sister of the candidate, and the spouses of such persons.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–178, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 565</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–443, title IV, § 404(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1974-10-15">Oct. 15, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1291</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–283, title III</ref>, §§ 301(a), 307(d), <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 497</ref>, 501; <ref>Pub. L. 110–172, § 11(a)(42)(B)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-29">Dec. 29, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2488</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9005.</num>
<heading> Certification by Commission</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial certifications</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 10 days after the candidates of a political party for President and Vice President of the United States have met all applicable conditions for eligibility to receive payments under this chapter set forth in section 9003, the Commission shall certify to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment to such eligible candidates under section 9006 payment in full of amounts to which such candidates are entitled under section 9004.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Finality of certifications and determinations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Initial certifications by the Commission under subsection (a), and all determinations made by it under this chapter, shall be final and conclusive, except to the extent that they are subject to examination and audit by the Commission under section 9007 and judicial review under section 9011.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–178, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 566</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–443, title IV</ref>, §§ 404(c)(6), (7), 405(a), <date date="1974-10-15">Oct. 15, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1292</ref>, 1293; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(C)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9006.</num>
<heading> Payments to eligible candidates</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of campaign fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby established on the books of the Treasury of the United States a special fund to be known as the “Presidential Election Campaign Fund”. The Secretary of the Treasury shall, from time to time, transfer to the fund an amount not in excess of the sum of the amounts designated (subsequent to the previous Presidential election) to the fund by individuals under section 6096. There is appropriated to the fund for each fiscal year, out of amounts in the general fund of the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, an amount equal to the amounts so designated during each fiscal year, which shall remain available to the fund without fiscal year limitation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments from the fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Upon receipt of a certification from the Commission under section 9005 for payment to the eligible candidates of a political party, the Secretary of the Treasury shall pay to such candidates out of the fund the amount certified by the Commission. Amounts paid to any such candidates shall be under the control of such candidates.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Insufficient amounts in fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If at the time of a certification by the Commission under section 9005 for payment to the eligible candidates of a political party, the Secretary determines that the moneys in the fund are not, or may not be, sufficient to satisfy the full entitlements of the eligible candidates of all political parties, he shall withhold from such payment such amount as he determines to be necessary to assure that the eligible candidates of each political party will receive their pro rata share of their full entitlement. Amounts withheld by reason of the preceding sentence shall be paid when the Secretary determines that there are sufficient moneys in the fund to pay such amounts, or portions thereof, to all eligible candidates from whom amounts have been withheld, but, if there are not sufficient moneys in the fund to satisfy the full entitlement of the eligible candidates of all political parties, the amounts so withheld shall be paid in such manner that the eligible candidates of each political party receive their pro rata share of their full entitlement. In any case in which the Secretary determines that there are insufficient moneys in the fund to make payments under subsection (b), section 9008(i)(2), and section 9037(b), moneys shall not be made available from any other source for the purpose of making such payments.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–178, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 567</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–53, § 6(b)</ref>, <date date="1973-07-01">July 1, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 138</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–443, title IV</ref>, §§ 403(a), 404(c)(8), <date date="1974-10-15">Oct. 15, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1291</ref>, 1292; <ref>Pub. L. 94–283, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX</ref>, §§ 1906(b)(13)(A), (B), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–172, § 11(a)(43)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-29">Dec. 29, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2488</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–94, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-04-03">Apr. 3, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1085</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9007.</num>
<heading> Examinations and audits; repayments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Examinations and audits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">After each presidential election, the Commission shall conduct a thorough examination and audit of the qualified campaign expenses of the candidates of each political party for President and Vice President.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repayments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> If the Commission determines that any portion of the payments made to the eligible candidates of a political party under section 9006 was in excess of the aggregate payments to which candidates were entitled under section 9004, it shall so notify such candidates, and such candidates shall pay to the Secretary of the Treasury an amount equal to such portion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the Commission determines that the eligible candidates of a political party and their authorized committees incurred qualified campaign expenses in excess of the aggregate payments to which the eligible candidates of a major party were entitled under section 9004, it shall notify such candidates of the amount of such excess and such candidates shall pay to the Secretary of the Treasury an amount equal to such amount.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> If the Commission determines that the eligible candidates of a major party or any authorized committee of such candidates accepted contributions (other than contributions to make up deficiencies in payments out of the fund on account of the application of section 9006(c)) to defray qualified campaign expenses (other than qualified campaign expenses with respect to which payment is required under paragraph (2)), it shall notify such candidates of the amount of the contributions so accepted, and such candidates shall pay to the Secretary of the Treasury an amount equal to such amount.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> If the Commission determines that any amount of any payment made to the eligible candidates of a political party under section 9006 was used for any purpose other than—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to defray the qualified campaign expenses with respect to which such payment was made, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to repay loans the proceeds of which were used, or otherwise to restore funds (other than contributions to defray qualified campaign expenses which were received and expended) which were used to defray such qualified campaign expenses,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">it shall notify such candidates of the amount so used, and such candidates shall pay to the Secretary of the Treasury an amount equal to such amount.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> No payment shall be required from the eligible candidates of a political party under this subsection to the extent that such payment, when added to other payments required from such candidates under this subsection, exceeds the amount of payments received by such candidates under section 9006.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No notification shall be made by the Commission under subsection (b) with respect to a presidential election more than 3 years after the day of such election.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit of repayments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All payments received by the Secretary of the Treasury under subsection (b) shall be deposited by him in the general fund of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–178, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 568</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–53, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="1973-07-01">July 1, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 139</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–443, title IV, § 404(c)(9)</ref>–(11), <date date="1974-10-15">Oct. 15, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1292</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–283, title III, § 307(e)</ref>, <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(B)</ref>, (C), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9008.</num>
<heading> Payments for presidential nominating conventions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of accounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall maintain in the fund, in addition to any account which he maintains under section 9006(a), a separate account for the national committee of each major party and minor party. The Secretary shall deposit in each such account an amount equal to the amount which each such committee may receive under subsection (b). Such deposits shall be drawn from amounts designated by individuals under section 6096 and shall be made before any transfer is made to any account for any eligible candidate under section 9006(a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Entitlement to payments from the fund</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Major parties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to the provisions of this section, the national committee of a major party shall be entitled to payments under paragraph (3), with respect to any presidential nominating convention, in amounts which, in the aggregate, shall not exceed $4,000,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minor parties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to the provisions of this section, the national committee of a minor party shall be entitled to payments under paragraph (3), with respect to any presidential nominating convention, in amounts which, in the aggregate, shall not exceed an amount which bears the same ratio to the amount the national committee of a major party is entitled to receive under paragraph (1) as the number of popular votes received by the candidate for President of the minor party, as such candidate, in the preceding presidential election bears to the average number of popular votes received by the candidates for President of the United States of the major parties in the preceding presidential election.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon receipt of certification from the Commission under subsection (g), the Secretary shall make payments from the appropriate account maintained under subsection (a) to the national committee of a major party or minor party which elects to receive its entitlement under this subsection. Such payments shall be available for use by such committee in accordance with the provisions of subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Payments to the national committee of a major party or minor party under this subsection, from the account designated for such committee shall be limited to the amounts in such account at the time of payment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment of entitlements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The entitlements established by this subsection shall be adjusted in the same manner as expenditure limitations established by section 315(b) and section 315(d) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 are adjusted pursuant to the provisions of section 315(c) of such Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No part of any payment made under subsection (b) shall be used to defray the expenses of any candidate or delegate who is participating in any presidential nominating convention. Such payments shall be used only—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to defray expenses incurred with respect to a presidential nominating convention (including the payment of deposits) by or on behalf of the national committee receiving such payments; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to repay loans the proceeds of which were used to defray such expenses, or otherwise to restore funds (other than contributions to defray such expenses received by such committee) used to defray such expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation of expenditures</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Major parties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided by paragraph (3), the national committee of a major party may not make expenditures with respect to a presidential nominating convention which, in the aggregate, exceed the amount of payments to which such committee is entitled under subsection (b)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minor parties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided by paragraph (3), the national committee of a minor party may not make expenditures with respect to a presidential nominating convention which, in the aggregate, exceed the amount of the entitlement of the national committee of a major party under subsection (b)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Commission may authorize the national committee of a major party or minor party to make expenditures which, in the aggregate, exceed the limitation established by paragraph (1) or paragraph (2) of this subsection. Such authorization shall be based upon a determination by the Commission that, due to extraordinary and unforeseen circumstances, such expenditures are necessary to assure the effective operation of the presidential nominating convention by such committee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision of legal or accounting services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the payment, by any person other than the national committee of a political party (unless the person paying for such services is a person other than the regular employer of the individual rendering such services) of compensation to any individual for legal or accounting services rendered to or on behalf of the national committee of a political party shall not be treated as an expenditure made by or on behalf of such committee with respect to its limitations on presidential nominating convention expenses.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The national committee of a major party or minor party may receive payments under subsection (b)(3) beginning on July 1 of the calendar year immediately preceding the calendar year in which a presidential nominating convention of the political party involved is held.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer to the fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If, after the close of a presidential nominating convention and after the national committee of the political party involved has been paid the amount which it is entitled to receive under this section, there are moneys remaining in the account of such national committee, the Secretary shall transfer the moneys so remaining to the fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certification by Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any major party or minor party may file a statement with the Commission in such form and manner and at such times as it may require, designating the national committee of such party. Such statement shall include the information required by section 303(b) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971, together with such additional information as the Commission may require. Upon receipt of a statement filed under the preceding sentences, the Commission promptly shall verify such statement according to such procedures and criteria as it may establish and shall certify to the Secretary for payment in full to any such committee of amounts to which such committee may be entitled under subsection (b). Such certifications shall be subject to an examination and audit which the Commission shall conduct no later than December 31, of the calendar year in which the presidential nominating convention involved is held.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repayments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission shall have the same authority to require repayments from the national committee of a major party or a minor party as it has with respect to repayments from any eligible candidate under section 9007(b). The provisions of section 9007(c) and section 9007(d) shall apply with respect to any repayment required by the Commission under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of payments for conventions; use of amounts for pediatric research initiative</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Effective on the date of the enactment of the Gabriella Miller Kids First Research Act—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the entitlement of any major party or minor party to a payment under this section shall terminate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> all amounts in each account maintained for the national committee of a major party or minor party under this section shall be transferred to a fund in the Treasury to be known as the “10-Year Pediatric Research Initiative Fund”, which shall be available only for the purpose provided in section 402A(a)(2) of the Public Health Service Act, and only to the extent and in such amounts as are provided in advance in appropriation Acts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–178, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 569</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–443, title IV, § 406(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-10-15">Oct. 15, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1294</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–283, title III</ref>, §§ 303, 307(a), <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 498</ref>, 501; <ref>Pub. L. 96–187, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1980-01-08">Jan. 8, 1980</date>, <ref>93 Stat. 1368</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–355, § 1(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1984-07-11">July 11, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 394</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–94, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-04-03">Apr. 3, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1085</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9009.</num>
<heading> Reports to Congress; regulations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall, as soon as practicable after each presidential election, submit a full report to the Senate and House of Representatives setting forth—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the qualified campaign expenses (shown in such detail as the Commission determines necessary) incurred by the candidates of each political party and their authorized committees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the amounts certified by it under section 9005 for payment to the eligible candidates of each political party; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the amount of payments, if any, required from such candidates under section 9007, and the reasons for each payment required.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Each report submitted pursuant to this section shall be printed as a Senate document.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission is authorized to prescribe such rules and regulations in accordance with the provisions of subsection (c), to conduct such examinations and audits (in addition to the examinations and audits required by section 9007(a)), to conduct such investigations, and to require the keeping and submission of such books, records, and information, as it deems necessary to carry out the functions and duties imposed on it by this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of regulations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Commission, before prescribing any rule or regulation under subsection (b), shall transmit a statement with respect to such rule or regulation to the Senate and to the House of Representatives, in accordance with the provisions of this subsection. Such statement shall set forth the proposed rule or regulation and shall contain a detailed explanation and justification of such rule or regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If either such House does not, through appropriate action, disapprove the proposed rule or regulation set forth in such statement no later than 30 legislative days after receipt of such statement, then the Commission may prescribe such rule or regulation. Whenever a committee of the House of Representatives reports any resolution relating to any such rule or regulation, it is at any time thereafter in order (even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to) to move to proceed to the consideration of the resolution. The motion is highly privileged and is not debatable. An amendment to the motion is not in order, and it is not in order to move to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to. The Commission may not prescribe any rule or regulation which is disapproved by either such House under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subsection, the term “legislative days” does not include any calendar day on which both Houses of the Congress are not in session.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subsection, the term “rule or regulation” means a provision or series of interrelated provisions stating a single separable rule of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–178, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 569</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–443, title IV</ref>, §§ 404(c)(12), (13), 406(b)(1), 409, <date date="1974-10-15">Oct. 15, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1292</ref>, 1293, 1296, 1303; <ref>Pub. L. 94–283, title III, § 304(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–94, § 2(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-04-03">Apr. 3, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1085</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9010.</num>
<heading> Participation by Commission in judicial proceedings</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appearance by counsel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission is authorized to appear in and defend against any action filed under section 9011, either by attorneys employed in its office or by counsel whom it may appoint without regard to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service, and whose compensation it may fix without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recovery of certain payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission is authorized through attorneys and counsel described in subsection (a) to appear in the district courts of the United States to seek recovery of any amounts determined to be payable to the Secretary of the Treasury as a result of examination and audit made pursuant to section 9007.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Declaratory and injunctive relief</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission is authorized through attorneys and counsel described in subsection (a) to petition the courts of the United States for declaratory or injunctive relief concerning any civil matter covered by the provisions of this subtitle or section 6096. Upon application of the Commission an action brought pursuant to this subsection shall be heard and determined by a court of three judges in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 2284 of title 28</ref>, United States Code, and any appeal shall lie to the Supreme Court.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appeal</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Commission is authorized on behalf of the United States to appeal from, and to petition the Supreme Court for certiorari to review, judgments or decrees entered with respect to actions in which it appears pursuant to the authority provided in this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–178, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 569</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–443, title IV, § 404(c)(14)</ref>–(18), <date date="1974-10-15">Oct. 15, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1293</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(C)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 402(28)(E)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3359</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9011.</num>
<heading> Judicial review</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review of certification, determination, or other action by the Commission</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any certification, determination, or other action by the Commission made or taken pursuant to the provisions of this chapter shall be subject to review by the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia upon petition filed in such Court by any interested person. Any petition filed pursuant to this section shall be filed within thirty days after the certification, determination, or other action by the Commission for which review is sought.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suits to implement chapter</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The Commission, the national committee of any political party, and individuals eligible to vote for President are authorized to institute such actions, including actions for declaratory judgment or injunctive relief, as may be appropriate to implement or construe any provision of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction of proceedings instituted pursuant to this subsection and shall exercise the same without regard to whether a person asserting rights under provisions of this subsection shall have exhausted any administrative or other remedies that may be provided at law. Such proceedings shall be heard and determined by a court of three judges in accordance with the provisions of <ref>section 2284 of title 28</ref>, United States Code, and any appeal shall lie to the Supreme Court.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–178, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 570</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–443, title IV, § 404(c)(19)</ref>–(21), <date date="1974-10-15">Oct. 15, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1293</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 402(28)(F)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 3359</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(339)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 9012.</num>
<heading> Criminal penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Excess expenses</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> It shall be unlawful for an eligible candidate of a political party for President and Vice President in a presidential election or any of his authorized committees knowingly and willfully to incur qualified campaign expenses in excess of the aggregate payments to which the eligible candidates of a major party are entitled under section 9004 with respect to such election.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any person who violates paragraph (1) shall be fined not more than $5,000, or imprisoned not more than one year or both. In the case of a violation by an authorized committee, any officer or member of such committee who knowingly and willfully consents to such violation shall be fined not more than $5,000, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contributions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> It shall be unlawful for an eligible candidate of a major party in a presidential election or any of his authorized committees knowingly and willfully to accept any contribution to defray qualified campaign expenses, except to the extent necessary to make up any deficiency in payments received out of the fund on account of the application of section 9006(c), or to defray expenses which would be qualified campaign expenses but for subparagraph (C) of section 9002(11).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> It shall be unlawful for an eligible candidate of a political party (other than a major party) in a presidential election or any of his authorized committees knowingly and willfully to accept and expend or retain contributions to defray qualified campaign expenses in an amount which exceeds the qualified campaign expenses incurred with respect to such election by such eligible candidate and his authorized committees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any person who violates paragraph (1) or (2) shall be fined not more than $5,000, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both. In the case of a violation by an authorized committee, any officer or member of such committee who knowingly and willfully consents to such violation shall be fined not more than $5,000, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unlawful use of payments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> It shall be unlawful for any person who receives any payment under section 9006, or to whom any portion of any payment received under such section is transferred, knowingly and willfully to use, or authorize the use of, such payment or such portion for any purpose other than—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to defray the qualified campaign expenses with respect to which such payment was made, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to repay loans the proceeds of which were used, or otherwise to restore funds (other than contributions to defray qualified campaign expenses which were received and expended) which were used, to defray such qualified campaign expenses.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any person who violates paragraph (1) shall be fined not more than $10,000, or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> False statements, etc.</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> It shall be unlawful for any person knowingly and willfully—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to furnish any false, fictitious, or fraudulent evidence, books, or information to the Commission under this subtitle, or to include in any evidence, books, or information so furnished any misrepresentation of a material fact, or to falsify or conceal any evidence, books, or information relevant to a certification by the Commission or an examination and audit by the Commission under this chapter; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to fail to furnish to the Commission any records, books, or information requested by it for purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any person who violates paragraph (1) shall be fined not more than $10,000, or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Kickbacks and illegal payments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> It shall be unlawful for any person knowingly and willfully to give or accept any kickback or any illegal payment in connection with any qualified campaign expense of eligible candidates or their authorized committees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any person who violates paragraph (1) shall be fined not more than $10,000, or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> In addition to the penalty provided by paragraph (2), any person who accepts any kickback or illegal payment in connection with any qualified campaign expense of eligible candidates or their authorized committees shall pay to the Secretary of the Treasury, for deposit in the general fund of the Treasury, an amount equal to 125 percent of the kickback or payment received.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unauthorized expenditures and contributions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), it shall be unlawful for any political committee which is not an authorized committee with respect to the eligible candidates of a political party for President and Vice President in a presidential election knowingly and willfully to incur expenditures to further the election of such candidates, which would constitute qualified campaign expenses if incurred by an authorized committee of such candidates, in an aggregate amount exceeding $1,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> This subsection shall not apply to (A) expenditures by a broadcaster regulated by the Federal Communications Commission, or by a periodical publication, in reporting the news or in taking editorial positions, or (B) expenditures by any organization described in section 501(c) which is exempt from tax under section 501(a) in communicating to its members the views of that organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any political committee which violates paragraph (1) shall be fined not more than $5,000, and any officer or member of such committee who knowingly and willfully consents to such violation and any other individual who knowingly and willfully violates paragraph (1) shall be fined not more than $5,000, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unauthorized disclosure of information</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> It shall be unlawful for any individual to disclose any information obtained under the provisions of this chapter except as may be required by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any person who violates paragraph (1) shall be fined not more than $5,000, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 92–178, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1971-12-10">Dec. 10, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 570</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 93–53, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="1973-07-01">July 1, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 139</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–443, title IV</ref>, §§ 404(c)(22), 406(b)(2)–(6), <date date="1974-10-15">Oct. 15, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1293</ref>, 1296; <ref>Pub. L. 94–283, title III, § 307(f)</ref>, <date date="1976-05-11">May 11, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 502</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(C)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–94, § 2(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-04-03">Apr. 3, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1086</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 9013.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(d)(8)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1212</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</chapter>