<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 21—</num>
<heading>FEDERAL INSURANCE CONTRIBUTIONS ACT</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter A—</num>
<heading>Tax on Employees</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3101.</num>
<heading> Rate of tax</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Old-age, survivors, and disability insurance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to other taxes, there is hereby imposed on the income of every individual a tax equal to 6.2 percent of the wages (as defined in section 3121(a)) received by the individual with respect to employment (as defined in section 3121(b)).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hospital insurance</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to the tax imposed by the preceding subsection, there is hereby imposed on the income of every individual a tax equal to 1.45 percent of the wages (as defined in section 3121(a)) received by him with respect to employment (as defined in section 3121(b)).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional tax</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In addition to the tax imposed by paragraph (1) and the preceding subsection, there is hereby imposed on every taxpayer (other than a corporation, estate, or trust) a tax equal to 0.9 percent of wages which are received with respect to employment (as defined in section 3121(b)) during any taxable year beginning after <date date="2012-12-31">December 31, 2012</date>, and which are in excess of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a joint return, $250,000,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a married taxpayer (as defined in section 7703) filing a separate return, ½ of the dollar amount determined under subparagraph (A), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in any other case, $200,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relief from taxes in cases covered by certain international agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">During any period in which there is in effect an agreement entered into pursuant to section 233 of the Social Security Act with any foreign country, wages received by or paid to an individual shall be exempt from the taxes imposed by this section to the extent that such wages are subject under such agreement exclusively to the laws applicable to the social security system of such foreign country.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 415</ref>; <ref>Sept. 1, 1954, ch. 1206</ref>, title II, § 208(b), <ref>68 Stat. 1094</ref>; <ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 836</ref>, title II, § 202(b), <ref>70 Stat. 845</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–840, title IV, § 401(b)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1041</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–64, title II, § 201(b)</ref>, <date date="1961-06-30">June 30, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 141</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–97, title I, § 111(c)(5)</ref>, title III, § 321(b), <date date="1965-07-30">July 30, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 342</ref>, 395; <ref>Pub. L. 90–248, title I, § 109(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(2), <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 836</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–5, title II, § 204(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1971-03-17">Mar. 17, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 11</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–336, § 204(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(2), <date date="1972-07-01">July 1, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 421</ref>, 422; <ref>Pub. L. 92–603, § 135(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(2), <date date="1972-10-30">Oct. 30, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1362</ref>, 1363; <ref>Pub. L. 93–233, § 6(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(2), <date date="1973-12-31">Dec. 31, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 954</ref>, 955; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1903(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1806</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–216, title I, § 101(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(1), title III, § 317(b)(2), <date date="1977-12-20">Dec. 20, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1510</ref>, 1511, 1540; <ref>Pub. L. 98–21, title I, § 123(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1983-04-20">Apr. 20, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 87</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–203, title IV, § 415</ref>, <date date="2004-03-02">Mar. 2, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 530</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–148, title IX, § 9015(a)(1)</ref>, title X, § 10906(a), <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 870</ref>, 1020; <ref>Pub. L. 111–152, title I, § 1402(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-30">Mar. 30, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1063</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(99)(A)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4051</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(207)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1194</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3102.</num>
<heading> Deduction of tax from wages</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The tax imposed by section 3101 shall be collected by the employer of the taxpayer, by deducting the amount of the tax from the wages as and when paid. An employer who in any calendar year pays to an employee cash remuneration to which paragraph (7)(B) of section 3121(a) is applicable may deduct an amount equivalent to such tax from any such payment of remuneration, even though at the time of payment the total amount of such remuneration paid to the employee by the employer in the calendar year is less than the applicable dollar threshold (as defined in section 3121(x)) for such year; and an employer who in any calendar year pays to an employee cash remuneration to which paragraph (7)(C) or (10) of section 3121(a) is applicable may deduct an amount equivalent to such tax from any such payment of remuneration, even though at the time of payment the total amount of such remuneration paid to the employee by the employer in the calendar year is less than $100; and an employer who in any calendar year pays to an employee cash remuneration to which paragraph (8)(B) of section 3121(a) is applicable may deduct an amount equivalent to such tax from any such payment of remuneration, even though at the time of payment the total amount of such remuneration paid to the employee by the employer in the calendar year is less than $150; and an employer who is furnished by an employee a written statement of tips (received in a calendar month) pursuant to section 6053(a) to which paragraph (12)(B) of section 3121(a) is applicable may deduct an amount equivalent to such tax with respect to such tips from any wages of the employee (exclusive of tips) under his control, even though at the time such statement is furnished the total amount of the tips included in statements furnished to the employer as having been received by the employee in such calendar month in the course of his employment by such employer is less than $20.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Indemnification of employer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every employer required so to deduct the tax shall be liable for the payment of such tax, and shall be indemnified against the claims and demands of any person for the amount of any such payment made by such employer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for tips</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> In the case of tips which constitute wages, subsection (a) shall be applicable only to such tips as are included in a written statement furnished to the employer pursuant to section 6053(a), and only to the extent that collection can be made by the employer, at or after the time such statement is so furnished and before the close of the 10th day following the calendar month (or, if paragraph (3) applies, the 30th day following the year) in which the tips were deemed paid, by deducting the amount of the tax from such wages of the employee (excluding tips, but including funds turned over by the employee to the employer pursuant to paragraph (2)) as are under control of the employer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> If the tax imposed by section 3101, with respect to tips which are included in written statements furnished in any month to the employer pursuant to section 6053(a), exceeds the wages of the employee (excluding tips) from which the employer is required to collect the tax under paragraph (1), the employee may furnish to the employer on or before the 10th day of the following month (or, if paragraph (3) applies, on or before the 30th day of the following year) an amount of money equal to the amount of the excess.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> The Secretary may, under regulations prescribed by him, authorize employers—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to estimate the amount of tips that will be reported by the employee pursuant to section 6053(a) in any calendar year,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to determine the amount to be deducted upon each payment of wages (exclusive of tips) during such year as if the tips so estimated constituted the actual tips so reported, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to deduct upon any payment of wages (other than tips, but including funds turned over by the employee to the employer pursuant to paragraph (2)) to such employee during such year (and within 30 days thereafter) such amount as may be necessary to adjust the amount actually deducted upon such wages of the employee during the year to the amount required to be deducted in respect of tips included in written statements furnished to the employer during the year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> If the tax imposed by section 3101 with respect to tips which constitute wages exceeds the portion of such tax which can be collected by the employer from the wages of the employee pursuant to paragraph (1) or paragraph (3), such excess shall be paid by the employee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for certain taxable group-term life insurance benefits</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of any payment for group-term life insurance to which this subsection applies—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subsection (a) shall not apply,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the employer shall separately include on the statement required under section 6051—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the portion of the wages which consists of payments for group-term life insurance to which this subsection applies, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the amount of the tax imposed by section 3101 on such payments, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the tax imposed by section 3101 on such payments shall be paid by the em­ployee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Benefits to which subsection applies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">This subsection shall apply to any payment for group-term life insurance to the extent—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such payment constitutes wages, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such payment is for coverage for periods during which an employment relationship no longer exists between the employee and the employer.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for certain transferred Federal employees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of any payments of wages for service performed in the employ of an international organization pursuant to a transfer to which the provisions of section 3121(y) are applicable—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> subsection (a) shall not apply,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the head of the Federal agency from which the transfer was made shall separately include on the statement required under section 6051—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the amount determined to be the amount of the wages for such service, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amount of the tax imposed by section 3101 on such payments, and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the tax imposed by section 3101 on such payments shall be paid by the employee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules for additional tax</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of any tax imposed by section 3101(b)(2), subsection (a) shall only apply to the extent to which the taxpayer receives wages from the employer in excess of $200,000, and the employer may disregard the amount of wages received by such taxpayer’s spouse.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collection of amounts not withheld</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To the extent that the amount of any tax imposed by section 3101(b)(2) is not collected by the employer, such tax shall be paid by the employee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax paid by recipient</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If an employer, in violation of this chapter, fails to deduct and withhold the tax imposed by section 3101(b)(2) and thereafter the tax is paid by the employee, the tax so required to be deducted and withheld shall not be collected from the employer, but this paragraph shall in no case relieve the employer from liability for any penalties or additions to tax otherwise applicable in respect of such failure to deduct and withhold.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 415</ref>; <ref>Sept. 1, 1954, ch. 1206</ref>, title II, § 205A, <ref>68 Stat. 1093</ref>; <ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 836</ref>, title II, § 201(h)(3), <ref>70 Stat. 841</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–97, title III, § 313(c)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1965-07-30">July 30, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 382</ref>, 383; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–216, title III, § 355(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1977-12-20">Dec. 20, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title V, § 5124(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–284</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–296, title III, § 319(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1534</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–387, § 2(a)(1)(D)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4072</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–203, title IV, § 424(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-03-02">Mar. 2, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 536</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–148, title IX, § 9015(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 871</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter B—</num>
<heading>Tax on Employers</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3111.</num>
<heading> Rate of tax</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Old-age, survivors, and disability insurance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to other taxes, there is hereby imposed on every employer an excise tax, with respect to having individuals in his employ, equal to 6.2 percent of the wages (as defined in section 3121(a)) paid by the employer with respect to employment (as defined in section 3121(b)).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Hospital insurance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In addition to the tax imposed by the preceding subsection, there is hereby imposed on every employer an excise tax, with respect to having individuals in his employ, equal to 1.45 percent of the wages (as defined in section 3121(a)) paid by the employer with respect to employment (as defined in section 3121(b)).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relief from taxes in cases covered by certain international agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">During any period in which there is in effect an agreement entered into pursuant to section 233 of the Social Security Act with any foreign country, wages received by or paid to an individual shall be exempt from the taxes imposed by this section to the extent that such wages are subject under such agreement exclusively to the laws applicable to the social security system of such foreign country.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">[(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(b)(34)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1204</ref>]</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Credit for employment of qualified veterans</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a qualified tax-exempt organization hires a qualified veteran with respect to whom a credit would be allowable under section 38 by reason of section 51 if the organization were not a qualified tax-exempt organization, then there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by subsection (a) on wages paid with respect to employment of all employees of the organization during the applicable period an amount equal to the credit determined under section 51 (after application of the modifications under paragraph (3)) with respect to wages paid to such qualified veteran during such period.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Overall limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The aggregate amount allowed as a credit under this subsection for all qualified veterans for any period with respect to which tax is imposed under subsection (a) shall not exceed the amount of the tax imposed by subsection (a) on wages paid with respect to employment of all employees of the organization during such period.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modifications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), section 51 shall be applied—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by substituting “26 percent” for “40 percent” in subsection (a) thereof,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by substituting “16.25 percent” for “25 percent” in subsection (i)(3)(A) thereof, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> by only taking into account wages paid to a qualified veteran for services in furtherance of the activities related to the purpose or function constituting the basis of the organization’s exemption under section 501.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “applicable period” means, with respect to any qualified veteran, the 1-year period beginning with the day such qualified veteran begins work for the organization.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “qualified tax-exempt organization” means an employer that is an organization described in section 501(c) and exempt from taxation under section 501(a), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “qualified veteran” has the meaning given such term by section 51(d)(3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Credit for research expenditures of qualified small businesses</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of a taxpayer who has made an election under section 41(h) for a taxable year—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by subsection (a) for the first calendar quarter which begins after the date on which the taxpayer files the return specified in section 41(h)(4)(A)(ii) an amount equal to so much of the payroll tax credit portion determined under section 41(h)(2) as does not exceed the limitation of subclause (I) of section 41(h)(4)(B)(i) (applied without regard to subclause (II) thereof), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by subsection (b) for the first calendar quarter which begins after the date on which the taxpayer files the return specified in section 41(h)(4)(A)(ii) an amount equal to so much of the payroll tax credit portion determined under section 41(h)(2) as is not allowed as a credit under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The credit allowed by paragraph (1)(A) shall not exceed the tax imposed by subsection (a) for any calendar quarter, and the credit allowed by paragraph (1)(B) shall not exceed the tax imposed by subsection (b) for any calendar quarter, on the wages paid with respect to the employment of all individuals in the employ of the employer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Carryover of unused credit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the amount of any credit under paragraph (1) exceeds the limitation of paragraph (2) for any calendar quarter, such excess shall be carried to the succeeding calendar quarter and allowed as a credit under paragraph (1) for such quarter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deduction allowed for credited amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The credits allowed under paragraph (1) shall not be taken into account for purposes of determining the amount of any deduction allowed under chapter 1 for taxes imposed under subsection (a) or (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 416</ref>; <ref>Sept. 1, 1954, ch. 1206</ref>, title II, § 208(c), <ref>68 Stat. 1094</ref>; <ref>Aug. 1, 1956. ch. 836</ref>, title II, § 202(c), <ref>70 Stat. 845</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–840, title IV, § 401(c)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1042</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–64, title II, § 201(c)</ref>, <date date="1961-06-30">June 30, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 141</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–97, title I, § 111(c)(6)</ref>, title III, § 321(c), <date date="1965-07-30">July 30, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 343</ref>, 396; <ref>Pub. L. 90–248, title I, § 109(a)(3)</ref>, (b)(3), <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 836</ref>, 837; <ref>Pub. L. 92–5, title II, § 204(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1971-03-17">Mar. 17, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 11</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–336, title II, § 204(a)(3)</ref>, (b)(3), <date date="1972-07-01">July 1, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 421</ref>, 422; <ref>Pub. L. 92–603, title I, § 135(a)(3)</ref>, (b)(3), <date date="1972-10-30">Oct. 30, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1363</ref>, 1364; <ref>Pub. L. 93–233, § 6(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(3), <date date="1973-12-31">Dec. 31, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 954</ref>, 955; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1903(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1806</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–216, title I, § 101(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(2), title III, §§ 315(b), 317(b)(2), <date date="1977-12-20">Dec. 20, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1511</ref>, 1512, 1537, 1540; <ref>Pub. L. 98–21, title I, § 123(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1983-04-20">Apr. 20, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 88</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–203, title IX, § 9006(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1330–289</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VIII, § 8016(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3793</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–203, title IV, § 415</ref>, <date date="2004-03-02">Mar. 2, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 530</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–147, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-18">Mar. 18, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 72</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–56, title II, § 261(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-11-21">Nov. 21, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 730</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(99)(B)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4051</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. Q, title I, § 121(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 3051</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(208)</ref>, (b)(34), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1194</ref>, 1204; <ref>Pub. L. 117–169, title I, § 13902(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-16">Aug. 16, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 2013</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3112.</num>
<heading> Instrumentalities of the United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (whether enacted before or after the enactment of this section) which grants to any instrumentality of the United States an exemption from taxation, such instrumentality shall not be exempt from the tax imposed by section 3111 unless such other provision of law grants a specific exemption, by reference to section 3111 (or the corresponding section of prior law), from the tax imposed by such section.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 416</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 3113.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1903(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1806</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter C—</num>
<heading>General Provisions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3121.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wages</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, the term “wages” means all remuneration for employment, including the cash value of all remuneration (including benefits) paid in any medium other than cash; except that such term shall not include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> in the case of the taxes imposed by sections 3101(a) and 3111(a) that part of the remuneration which, after remuneration (other than remuneration referred to in the succeeding paragraphs of this subsection) equal to the contribution and benefit base (as determined under section 230 of the Social Security Act) with respect to employment has been paid to an individual by an employer during the calendar year with respect to which such contribution and benefit base is effective, is paid to such individual by such employer during such calendar year. If an employer (hereinafter referred to as successor employer) during any calendar year acquires substantially all the property used in a trade or business of another employer (hereinafter referred to as a predecessor), or used in a separate unit of a trade or business of a predecessor, and immediately after the acquisition employs in his trade or business an individual who immediately prior to the acquisition was employed in the trade or business of such predecessor, then, for the purpose of determining whether the successor employer has paid remuneration (other than remuneration referred to in the succeeding paragraphs of this subsection) with respect to employment equal to the contribution and benefit base (as determined under section 230 of the Social Security Act) to such individual during such calendar year, any remuneration (other than remuneration referred to in the succeeding paragraphs of this subsection) with respect to employment paid (or considered under this paragraph as having been paid) to such individual by such predecessor during such calendar year and prior to such acquisition shall be considered as having been paid by such successor employer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the amount of any payment (including any amount paid by an employer for insurance or annuities, or into a fund, to provide for any such payment) made to, or on behalf of, an employee or any of his dependents under a plan or system established by an employer which makes provision for his employees generally (or for his employees generally and their dependents) or for a class or classes of his employees (or for a class or classes of his employees and their dependents), on account of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sickness or accident disability (but, in the case of payments made to an employee or any of his dependents, this subparagraph shall exclude from the term “wages” only payments which are received under a workman’s compensation law), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> medical or hospitalization expenses in connection with sickness or accident disability, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> death, except that this paragraph does not apply to a payment for group-term life insurance to the extent that such payment is includible in the gross income of the employee;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>[(3)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–21, title III, § 324(a)(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="1983-04-20">Apr. 20, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 123</ref>]</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any payment on account of sickness or accident disability, or medical or hospitalization expenses in connection with sickness or accident disability, made by an employer to, or on behalf of, an employee after the expiration of 6 calendar months following the last calendar month in which the employee worked for such employer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> any payment made to, or on behalf of, an employee or his beneficiary—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> from or to a trust described in section 401(a) which is exempt from tax under section 501(a) at the time of such payment unless such payment is made to an employee of the trust as remuneration for services rendered as such employee and not as a beneficiary of the trust,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> under or to an annuity plan which, at the time of such payment, is a plan described in section 403(a),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> under a simplified employee pension (as defined in section 408(k)(1)), other than any contributions described in section 408(k)(6),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> under or to an annuity contract described in section 403(b), other than a payment for the purchase of such contract which is made by reason of a salary reduction agreement (whether evidenced by a written instrument or otherwise),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> under or to an exempt governmental deferred compensation plan (as defined in subsection (v)(3)),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> to supplement pension benefits under a plan or trust described in any of the foregoing provisions of this paragraph to take into account some portion or all of the increase in the cost of living (as determined by the Secretary of Labor) since retirement but only if such supplemental payments are under a plan which is treated as a welfare plan under section 3(2)(B)(ii) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> under a cafeteria plan (within the meaning of section 125) if such payment would not be treated as wages without regard to such plan and it is reasonable to believe that (if section 125 applied for purposes of this section) section 125 would not treat any wages as constructively received,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> under an arrangement to which section 408(p) applies, other than any elective contributions under paragraph (2)(A)(i) thereof, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> under a plan described in section 457(e)(11)(A)(ii) and maintained by an eligible employer (as defined in section 457(e)(1));</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> the payment by an employer (without deduction from the remuneration of the employee)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> of the tax imposed upon an employee under section 3101, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> of any payment required from an employee under a State unemployment compensation law,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">with respect to remuneration paid to an employee for domestic service in a private home of the employer or for agricultural labor;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> remuneration paid in any medium other than cash to an employee for service not in the course of the employer’s trade or business or for domestic service in a private home of the employer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> cash remuneration paid by an employer in any calendar year to an employee for domestic service in a private home of the employer (including domestic service on a farm operated for profit), if the cash remuneration paid in such year by the employer to the employee for such service is less than the applicable dollar threshold (as defined in subsection (x)) for such year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> cash remuneration paid by an employer in any calendar year to an employee for service not in the course of the employer’s trade or business, if the cash remuneration paid in such year by the employer to the employee for such service is less than $100. As used in this subparagraph, the term “service not in the course of the employer’s trade or business” does not include domestic service in a private home of the employer and does not include service described in subsection (g)(5);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> remuneration paid in any medium other than cash for agricultural labor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> cash remuneration paid by an employer in any calendar year to an employee for agricultural labor unless—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the cash remuneration paid in such year by the employer to the employee for such labor is $150 or more, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the employer’s expenditures for agricultural labor in such year equal or exceed $2,500,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">except that clause (ii) shall not apply in determining whether remuneration paid to an employee constitutes “wages” under this section if such employee (I) is employed as a hand harvest laborer and is paid on a piece rate basis in an operation which has been, and is customarily and generally recognized as having been, paid on a piece rate basis in the region of employment, (II) commutes daily from his permanent residence to the farm on which he is so employed, and (III) has been employed in agriculture less than 13 weeks during the preceding calendar year;</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>[(9)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–21, title III, § 324(a)(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="1983-04-20">Apr. 20, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 123</ref>]</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<content> remuneration paid by an employer in any calendar year to an employee for service described in subsection (d)(3)(C) (relating to home workers), if the cash remuneration paid in such year by the employer to the employee for such service is less than $100;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> remuneration paid to or on behalf of an employee if (and to the extent that) at the time of the payment of such remuneration it is reasonable to believe that a corresponding deduction is allowable under section 217 (determined without regard to section 274(n));</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> tips paid in any medium other than cash;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> cash tips received by an employee in any calendar month in the course of his employment by an employer unless the amount of such cash tips is $20 or more;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<chapeau> any payment or series of payments by an employer to an employee or any of his dependents which is paid—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> upon or after the termination of an employee’s employment relationship because of (i) death, or (ii) retirement for disability, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> under a plan established by the employer which makes provision for his employees generally or a class or classes of his employees (or for such employees or class or classes of employees and their dependents),</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">other than any such payment or series of payments which would have been paid if the employee’s employment relationship had not been so terminated;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<content> any payment made by an employer to a survivor or the estate of a former employee after the calendar year in which such employee died;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> any payment made by an employer to an employee, if at the time such payment is made such employee is entitled to disability insurance benefits under section 223(a) of the Social Security Act and such entitlement commenced prior to the calendar year in which such payment is made, and if such employee did not perform any services for such employer during the period for which such payment is made;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<content> remuneration paid by an organization exempt from income tax under section 501(a) (other than an organization described in section 401(a)) or under section 521 in any calendar year to an employee for service rendered in the employ of such organization, if the remuneration paid in such year by the organization to the employee for such service is less than $100;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>[(17)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(19)(B)(iv)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4040</ref>]</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> any payment made, or benefit furnished, to or for the benefit of an employee if at the time of such payment or such furnishing it is reasonable to believe that the employee will be able to exclude such payment or benefit from income under section 127, 129, 134(b)(4), or 134(b)(5);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> the value of any meals or lodging furnished by or on behalf of the employer if at the time of such furnishing it is reasonable to believe that the employee will be able to exclude such items from income under section 119;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<content> any benefit provided to or on behalf of an employee if at the time such benefit is provided it is reasonable to believe that the employee will be able to exclude such benefit from income under section 74(c), 108(f)(4), 117, or 132;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<content> in the case of a member of an Indian tribe, any remuneration on which no tax is imposed by this chapter by reason of section 7873 (relating to income derived by Indians from exercise of fishing rights);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<chapeau> remuneration on account of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a transfer of a share of stock to any individual pursuant to an exercise of an incentive stock option (as defined in section 422(b)) or under an employee stock purchase plan (as defined in section 423(b)), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any disposition by the individual of such stock; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(23)</num>
<content> any benefit or payment which is excludable from the gross income of the employee under section section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002194">1</ref> 139B(a).</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Nothing in the regulations prescribed for purposes of chapter 24 (relating to income tax withholding) which provides an exclusion from “wages” as used in such chapter shall be construed to require a similar exclusion from “wages” in the regulations prescribed for purposes of this chapter. Except as otherwise provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary, any third party which makes a payment included in wages solely by reason of the parenthetical matter contained in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (2) shall be treated for purposes of this chapter and chapter 22 as the employer with respect to such wages.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, the term “employment” means any service, of whatever nature, performed (A) by an employee for the person employing him, irrespective of the citizenship or residence of either, (i) within the United States, or (ii) on or in connection with an American vessel or American aircraft under a contract of service which is entered into within the United States or during the performance of which and while the employee is employed on the vessel or aircraft it touches at a port in the United States, if the employee is employed on and in connection with such vessel or aircraft when outside the United States, or (B) outside the United States by a citizen or resident of the United States as an employee for an American employer (as defined in subsection (h)), or (C) if it is service, regardless of where or by whom performed, which is designated as employment or recognized as equivalent to employment under an agreement entered into under section 233 of the Social Security Act; except that such term shall not include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> service performed by foreign agricultural workers lawfully admitted to the United States from the Bahamas, Jamaica, and the other British West Indies, or from any other foreign country or possession thereof, on a temporary basis to perform agricultural labor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> domestic service performed in a local college club, or local chapter of a college fraternity or sorority, by a student who is enrolled and is regularly attending classes at a school, college, or university;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> service performed by a child under the age of 18 in the employ of his father or mother;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> service not in the course of the employer’s trade or business, or domestic service in a private home of the employer, performed by an individual under the age of 21 in the employ of his father or mother, or performed by an individual in the employ of his spouse or son or daughter; except that the provisions of this subparagraph shall not be applicable to such domestic service performed by an individual in the employ of his son or daughter if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the employer is a surviving spouse or a divorced individual and has not remarried, or has a spouse living in the home who has a mental or physical condition which results in such spouse’s being incapable of caring for a son, daughter, stepson, or stepdaughter (referred to in clause (ii)) for at least 4 continuous weeks in the calendar quarter in which the service is rendered, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a son, daughter, stepson, or stepdaughter of such employer is living in the home, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the son, daughter, stepson, or stepdaughter (referred to in clause (ii)) has not attained age 18 or has a mental or physical condition which requires the personal care and supervision of an adult for at least 4 continuous weeks in the calendar quarter in which the service is rendered;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> service performed by an individual on or in connection with a vessel not an American vessel, or on or in connection with an aircraft not an American aircraft, if (A) the individual is employed on and in connection with such vessel or aircraft, when outside the United States and (B)(i) such individual is not a citizen of the United States or (ii) the employer is not an American employer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> service performed in the employ of the United States or any instrumentality of the United States, if such service—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> would be excluded from the term “employment” for purposes of this title if the provisions of paragraphs (5) and (6) of this subsection as in effect in January 1983 had remained in effect, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> is performed by an individual who—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> has been continuously performing service described in subparagraph (A) since <date date="1983-12-31">December 31, 1983</date>, and for purposes of this clause—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> if an individual performing service described in subparagraph (A) returns to the performance of such service after being separated therefrom for a period of less than 366 consecutive days, regardless of whether the period began before, on, or after <date date="1983-12-31">December 31, 1983</date>, then such service shall be considered continuous,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> if an individual performing service described in subparagraph (A) returns to the performance of such service after being detailed or transferred to an international organization as described under section 3343 of subchapter III of chapter 33 of title 5, United States Code, or under section 3581 of chapter 35 of such title, then the service performed for that organization shall be considered service described in subparagraph (A),</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> if an individual performing service described in subparagraph (A) is reemployed or reinstated after being separated from such service for the purpose of accepting employment with the American Institute in Taiwan as provided under section 3310 of chapter 48 of title 22, United States Code, then the service performed for that Institute shall be considered service described in subparagraph (A),</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> if an individual performing service described in subparagraph (A) returns to the performance of such service after performing service as a member of a uniformed service (including, for purposes of this clause, service in the National Guard and temporary service in the Coast Guard Reserve) and after exercising restoration or reemployment rights as provided under chapter 43 of title 38, United States Code, then the service so performed as a member of a uniformed service shall be considered service described in subparagraph (A), and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> if an individual performing service described in subparagraph (A) returns to the performance of such service after employment (by a tribal organization) to which section 104(e)(2) of the Indian Self-Determination Act applies, then the service performed for that tribal organization shall be considered service described in subparagraph (A); or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is receiving an annuity from the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund, or benefits (for service as an employee) under another retirement system established by a law of the United States for employees of the Federal Government (other than for members of the uniformed service);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">except that this paragraph shall not apply with respect to any such service performed on or after any date on which such individual performs—</continuation>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> service performed as the President or Vice President of the United States,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> service performed—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in a position placed in the Executive Schedule under sections 5312 through 5317 of title 5, United States Code,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> as a noncareer appointee in the Senior Executive Service or a noncareer member of the Senior Foreign Service, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> in a position to which the individual is appointed by the President (or his designee) or the Vice President under section 105(a)(1), 106(a)(1), or 107 (a)(1) or (b)(1) of title 3, United States Code, if the maximum rate of basic pay for such position is at or above the rate for level V of the Executive Schedule,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> service performed as the Chief Justice of the United States, an Associate Justice of the Supreme Court, a judge of a United States court of appeals, a judge of a United States district court (including the district court of a territory), a judge of the United States Court of Federal Claims, a judge of the United States Court of International Trade, a judge or special trial judge of the United States Tax Court, a United States magistrate judge, or a referee in bankruptcy or United States bankruptcy judge,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> service performed as a Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner of or to the Congress,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<chapeau> any other service in the legislative branch of the Federal Government if such service—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is performed by an individual who was not subject to subchapter III of chapter 83 of title 5, United States Code, or to another retirement system established by a law of the United States for employees of the Federal Government (other than for members of the uniformed services), on <date date="1983-12-31">December 31, 1983</date>, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is performed by an individual who has, at any time after <date date="1983-12-31">December 31, 1983</date>, received a lump-sum payment under <ref>section 8342(a) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, or under the corresponding provision of the law establishing the other retirement system described in clause (i), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is performed by an individual after such individual has otherwise ceased to be subject to subchapter III of chapter 83 of title 5, United States Code (without having an application pending for coverage under such subchapter), while performing service in the legislative branch (determined without regard to the provisions of subparagraph (B) relating to continuity of employment), for any period of time after <date date="1983-12-31">December 31, 1983</date>,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">and for purposes of this subparagraph (G) an individual is subject to such subchapter III or to any such other retirement system at any time only if (a) such individual’s pay is subject to deductions, contributions, or similar payments (concurrent with the service being performed at that time) under section 8334(a) of such title 5 or the corresponding provision of the law establishing such other system, or (in a case to which section 8332(k)(1) of such title applies) such individual is making payments of amounts equivalent to such deductions, contributions, or similar payments while on leave without pay, or (b) such individual is receiving an annuity from the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund, or is receiving benefits (for service as an employee) under another retirement system established by a law of the United States for employees of the Federal Government (other than for members of the uniformed services), or</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<chapeau> service performed by an individual—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> on or after the effective date of an election by such individual, under section 301 of the Federal Employees’ Retirement System Act of 1986, section 307 of the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act (<ref>50 U.S.C. 2157</ref>), or the Federal Employees’ Retirement System Open Enrollment Act of 1997, to become subject to the Federal Employees’ Retirement System provided in chapter 84 of title 5, United States Code, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> on or after the effective date of an election by such individual, under regulations issued under section 860 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980, to become subject to the Foreign Service Pension System provided in subchapter II of chapter 8 of title I of such Act;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<chapeau> service performed in the employ of the United States or any instrumentality of the United States if such service is performed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in a penal institution of the United States by an inmate thereof;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by any individual as an employee included under <ref>section 5351(2) of title 5</ref>, United States Code (relating to certain interns, student nurses, and other student employees of hospitals of the Federal Government), other than as a medical or dental intern or a medical or dental resident in training; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> by any individual as an employee serving on a temporary basis in case of fire, storm, earthquake, flood, or other similar emergency;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<chapeau> service performed in the employ of a State, or any political subdivision thereof, or any instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing which is wholly owned thereby, except that this paragraph shall not apply in the case of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> service which, under subsection (j), constitutes covered transportation service,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> service in the employ of the Government of Guam or the Government of American Samoa or any political subdivision thereof, or of any instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing which is wholly owned thereby, performed by an officer or employee thereof (including a member of the legislature of any such Government or political subdivision), and, for purposes of this title with respect to the taxes imposed by this chapter—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any person whose service as such an officer or employee is not covered by a retirement system established by a law of the United States shall not, with respect to such service, be regarded as an employee of the United States or any agency or instrumentality thereof, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the remuneration for service described in clause (i) (including fees paid to a public official) shall be deemed to have been paid by the Government of Guam or the Government of American Samoa or by a political subdivision thereof or an instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing which is wholly owned thereby, whichever is appropriate,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> service performed in the employ of the District of Columbia or any instrumentality which is wholly owned thereby, if such service is not covered by a retirement system established by a law of the United States (other than the Federal Employees Retirement System provided in chapter 84 of title 5, United States Code); except that the provisions of this subparagraph shall not be applicable to service performed—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in a hospital or penal institution by a patient or inmate thereof;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> by any individual as an employee included under <ref>section 5351(2) of title 5</ref>, United States Code (relating to certain interns, student nurses, and other student employees of hospitals of the District of Columbia Government), other than as a medical or dental intern or as a medical or dental resident in training;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> by any individual as an employee serving on a temporary basis in case of fire, storm, snow, earthquake, flood or other similar emergency; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> by a member of a board, committee, or council of the District of Columbia, paid on a per diem, meeting, or other fee basis,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> service performed in the employ of the Government of Guam (or any instrumentality which is wholly owned by such Government) by an employee properly classified as a temporary or intermittent employee, if such service is not covered by a retirement system established by a law of Guam; except that (i) the provisions of this subparagraph shall not be applicable to services performed by an elected official or a member of the legislature or in a hospital or penal institution by a patient or inmate thereof, and (ii) for purposes of this subparagraph, clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (B) shall apply,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> service included under an agreement entered into pursuant to section 218 of the Social Security Act, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<chapeau> service in the employ of a State (other than the District of Columbia, Guam, or American Samoa), of any political subdivision thereof, or of any instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing which is wholly owned thereby, by an individual who is not a member of a retirement system of such State, political subdivision, or instrumentality, except that the provisions of this subparagraph shall not be applicable to service performed—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> by an individual who is employed to relieve such individual from unemployment;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in a hospital, home, or other institution by a patient or inmate thereof;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> by any individual as an employee serving on a temporary basis in case of fire, storm, snow, earthquake, flood, or other similar emergency;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> by an election official or election worker if the remuneration paid in a calendar year for such service is less than $1,000 with respect to service performed during any calendar year commencing on or after <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>, ending on or before <date date="1999-12-31">December 31, 1999</date>, and the adjusted amount determined under section 218(c)(8)(B) of the Social Security Act for any calendar year commencing on or after <date date="2000-01-01">January 1, 2000</date>, with respect to service performed during such calendar year; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> by an employee in a position compensated solely on a fee basis which is treated pursuant to section 1402(c)(2)(E) as a trade or business for purposes of inclusion of such fees in net earnings from self-employment;</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">for purposes of this subparagraph, except as provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the term “retirement system” has the meaning given such term by section 218(b)(4) of the Social Security Act;</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> service performed by a duly ordained, commissioned, or licensed minister of a church in the exercise of his ministry or by a member of a religious order in the exercise of duties required by such order, except that this subparagraph shall not apply to service performed by a member of such an order in the exercise of such duties, if an election of coverage under subsection (r) is in effect with respect to such order, or with respect to the autonomous subdivision thereof to which such member belongs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> service performed in the employ of a church or qualified church-controlled organization if such church or organization has in effect an election under subsection (w), other than service in an unrelated trade or business (within the meaning of section 513(a));</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(9)</num>
<content> service performed by an individual as an employee or employee representative as defined in section 3231;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(10)</num>
<chapeau> service performed in the employ of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a school, college, or university, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an organization described in section 509(a)(3) if the organization is organized, and at all times thereafter is operated, exclusively for the benefit of, to perform the functions of, or to carry out the purposes of a school, college, or university and is operated, supervised, or controlled by or in connection with such school, college, or university, unless it is a school, college, or university of a State or a political subdivision thereof and the services performed in its employ by a student referred to in section 218(c)(5) of the Social Security Act are covered under the agreement between the Commissioner of Social Security and such State entered into pursuant to section 218 of such Act;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">if such service is performed by a student who is enrolled and regularly attending classes at such school, college, or university;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(11)</num>
<content> service performed in the employ of a foreign government (including service as a consular or other officer or employee or a nondiplomatic representative);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(12)</num>
<chapeau> service performed in the employ of an instrumentality wholly owned by a foreign government—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> if the service is of a character similar to that performed in foreign countries by employees of the United States Government or of an instrumentality thereof; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> if the Secretary of State shall certify to the Secretary of the Treasury that the foreign government, with respect to whose instrumentality and employees thereof exemption is claimed, grants an equivalent exemption with respect to similar service performed in the foreign country by employees of the United States Government and of instrumentalities thereof;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(13)</num>
<content> service performed as a student nurse in the employ of a hospital or a nurses’ training school by an individual who is enrolled and is regularly attending classes in a nurses’ training school chartered or approved pursuant to State law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(14)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> service performed by an individual under the age of 18 in the delivery or distribution of newspapers or shopping news, not including delivery or distribution to any point for subsequent delivery or distribution;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> service performed by an individual in, and at the time of, the sale of newspapers or magazines to ultimate consumers, under an arrangement under which the newspapers or magazines are to be sold by him at a fixed price, his compensation being based on the retention of the excess of such price over the amount at which the newspapers or magazines are charged to him, whether or not he is guaranteed a minimum amount of compensation for such service, or is entitled to be credited with the unsold newspapers or magazines turned back;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(15)</num>
<content> service performed in the employ of an international organization, except service which constitutes “employment” under subsection (y);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(16)</num>
<chapeau> service performed by an individual under an arrangement with the owner or tenant of land pursuant to which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such individual undertakes to produce agricultural or horticultural commodities (including livestock, bees, poultry, and fur-bearing animals and wildlife) on such land,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the agricultural or horticultural commodities produced by such individual, or the proceeds therefrom, are to be divided between such individual and such owner or tenant, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the amount of such individual’s share depends on the amount of the agricultural or horticultural commodities produced;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>[(17)</num>
<content> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(99)(C)(i)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4052</ref>]</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(18)</num>
<content> service performed in Guam by a resident of the Republic of the Philippines while in Guam on a temporary basis as a nonimmigrant alien admitted to Guam pursuant to section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(H)(ii)</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(19)</num>
<content> Service which is performed by a nonresident alien individual for the period he is temporarily present in the United States as a nonimmigrant under subparagraph (F), (J), (M), or (Q) of section 101(a)(15) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as amended, and which is performed to carry out the purpose specified in subparagraph (F), (J), (M), or (Q), as the case may be;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(20)</num>
<chapeau> service (other than service described in paragraph (3)(A)) performed by an individual on a boat engaged in catching fish or other forms of aquatic animal life under an arrangement with the owner or operator of such boat pursuant to which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> such individual does not receive any cash remuneration other than as provided in subparagraph (B) and other than cash remuneration—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> which does not exceed $100 per trip;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> which is contingent on a minimum catch; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> which is paid solely for additional duties (such as mate, engineer, or cook) for which additional cash remuneration is traditional in the industry,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such individual receives a share of the boat’s (or the boats’ in the case of a fishing operation involving more than one boat) catch of fish or other forms of aquatic animal life or a share of the proceeds from the sale of such catch, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the amount of such individual’s share depends on the amount of the boat’s (or the boats’ in the case of a fishing operation involving more than one boat) catch of fish or other forms of aquatic animal life,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">but only if the operating crew of such boat (or each boat from which the individual receives a share in the case of a fishing operation involving more than one boat) is normally made up of fewer than 10 individuals;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(21)</num>
<chapeau> domestic service in a private home of the employer which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is performed in any year by an individual under the age of 18 during any portion of such year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is not the principal occupation of such employee; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(22)</num>
<content> service performed by members of Indian tribal councils as tribal council members in the employ of an Indian tribal government, except that this paragraph shall not apply in the case of service included under an agreement under section 218A of the Social Security Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of paragraph (20), the operating crew of a boat shall be treated as normally made up of fewer than 10 individuals if the average size of the operating crew on trips made during the preceding 4 calendar quarters consisted of fewer than 10 individuals.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Included and excluded service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, if the services performed during one-half or more of any pay period by an employee for the person employing him constitute employment, all the services of such employee for such period shall be deemed to be employment; but if the services performed during more than one-half of any such pay period by an employee for the person employing him do not constitute employment, then none of the services of such employee for such period shall be deemed to be employment. As used in this subsection, the term “pay period” means a period (of not more than 31 consecutive days) for which a payment of remuneration is ordinarily made to the employee by the person employing him. This subsection shall not be applicable with respect to services performed in a pay period by an employee for the person employing him, where any of such service is excepted by subsection (b)(9).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employee</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, the term “employee” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any officer of a corporation; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any individual who, under the usual common law rules applicable in determining the employer-employee relationship, has the status of an employee; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> any individual (other than an individual who is an employee under paragraph (1) or (2)) who performs services for remuneration for any person—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> as an agent-driver or commission-driver engaged in distributing meat products, vegetable products, fruit products, bakery products, beverages (other than milk), or laundry or dry-cleaning services, for his principal;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> as a full-time life insurance salesman;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> as a home worker performing work, according to specifications furnished by the person for whom the services are performed, on materials or goods furnished by such person which are required to be returned to such person or a person designated by him; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> as a traveling or city salesman, other than as an agent-driver or commission-driver, engaged upon a full-time basis in the solicitation on behalf of, and the transmission to, his principal (except for side-line sales activities on behalf of some other person) of orders from wholesalers, retailers, contractors, or operators of hotels, restaurants, or other similar establishments for merchandise for resale or supplies for use in their business operations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">if the contract of service contemplates that substantially all of such services are to be performed personally by such individual; except that an individual shall not be included in the term “employee” under the provisions of this paragraph if such individual has a substantial investment in facilities used in connection with the performance of such services (other than in facilities for transportation), or if the services are in the nature of a single transaction not part of a continuing relationship with the person for whom the services are performed; or</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> any individual who performs services that are included under an agreement entered into pursuant to section 218 or 218A of the Social Security Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State, United States, and citizen</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, and American Samoa.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “United States” when used in a geographical sense includes the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, and American Samoa.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">An individual who is a citizen of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico (but not otherwise a citizen of the United States) shall be considered, for purposes of this section, as a citizen of the United States.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> American vessel and aircraft</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, the term “American vessel” means any vessel documented or numbered under the laws of the United States; and includes any vessel which is neither documented or numbered under the laws of the United States nor documented under the laws of any foreign country, if its crew is employed solely by one or more citizens or residents of the United States or corporations organized under the laws of the United States or of any State; and the term “American aircraft” means an aircraft registered under the laws of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agricultural labor</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, the term “agricultural labor” includes all service performed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> on a farm, in the employ of any person, in connection with cultivating the soil, or in connection with raising or harvesting any agricultural or horticultural commodity, including the raising, shearing, feeding, caring for, training, and management of livestock, bees, poultry, and fur-bearing animals and wildlife;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the employ of the owner or tenant or other operator of a farm, in connection with the operation, management, conservation, improvement, or maintenance of such farm and its tools and equipment, or in salvaging timber or clearing land of brush and other debris left by a hurricane, if the major part of such service is performed on a farm;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in connection with the production or harvesting of any commodity defined as an agricultural commodity in section 15(g) of the Agricultural Marketing Act, as amended (<ref>12 U.S.C. 1141j</ref>), or in connection with the ginning of cotton, or in connection with the operation or maintenance of ditches, canals, reservoirs, or waterways, not owned or operated for profit, used exclusively for supplying and storing water for farming purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the employ of the operator of a farm in handling, planting, drying, packing, packaging, processing, freezing, grading, storing, or delivering to storage or to market or to a carrier for transportation to market, in its unmanufactured state, any agricultural or horticultural commodity; but only if such operator produced more than one-half of the commodity with respect to which such service is performed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the employ of a group of operators of farms (other than a cooperative organization) in the performance of service described in subparagraph (A), but only if such operators produced all of the commodity with respect to which such service is performed. For purposes of this subparagraph, any unincorporated group of operators shall be deemed a cooperative organization if the number of operators comprising such group is more than 20 at any time during the calendar year in which such service is performed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the provisions of subparagraphs (A) and (B) shall not be deemed to be applicable with respect to service performed in connection with commercial canning or commercial freezing or in connection with any agricultural or horticultural commodity after its delivery to a terminal market for distribution for consumption; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> on a farm operated for profit if such service is not in the course of the employer’s trade or business.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">As used in this subsection, the term “farm” includes stock, dairy, poultry, fruit, fur-bearing animal, and truck farms, plantations, ranches, nurseries, ranges, greenhouses or other similar structures used primarily for the raising of agricultural or horticultural commodities, and orchards.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> American employer</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, the term “American employer” means an employer which is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the United States or any instrumentality thereof,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an individual who is a resident of the United States,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a partnership, if two-thirds or more of the partners are residents of the United States,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a trust, if all of the trustees are residents of the United States, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a corporation organized under the laws of the United States or of any State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Computation of wages in certain cases</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Domestic service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this chapter, in the case of domestic service described in subsection (a)(7)(B), any payment of cash remuneration for such service which is more or less than a whole-dollar amount shall, under such conditions and to such extent as may be prescribed by regulations made under this chapter, be computed to the nearest dollar. For the purpose of the computation to the nearest dollar, the payment of a fractional part of a dollar shall be disregarded unless it amounts to one-half dollar or more, in which case it shall be increased to $1. The amount of any payment of cash remuneration so computed to the nearest dollar shall, in lieu of the amount actually paid, be deemed to constitute the amount of cash remuneration for purposes of subsection (a)(7)(B).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service in the uniformed services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this chapter, in the case of an individual performing service, as a member of a uniformed service, to which the provisions of subsection (m)(1) are applicable, the term “wages” shall, subject to the provisions of subsection (a)(1) of this section, include as such individual’s remuneration for such service only (A) his basic pay as described in chapter 3 and <ref>section 1009 of title 37</ref>, United States Code, in the case of an individual performing service to which subparagraph (A) of such subsection (m)(1) applies, or (B) his compensation for such service as determined under <ref>section 206(a) of title 37</ref>, United States Code, in the case of an individual performing service to which subparagraph (B) of such subsection (m)(1) applies.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Peace Corps volunteer service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this chapter, in the case of an individual performing service, as a volunteer or volunteer leader within the meaning of the Peace Corps Act, to which the provisions of section 3121(p) are applicable, the term “wages” shall, subject to the provisions of subsection (a)(1) of this section, include as such individual’s remuneration for such service only amounts paid pursuant to section 5(c) or 6(1) of the Peace Corps Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service performed by certain members of religious orders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this chapter, in any case where an individual is a member of a religious order (as defined in subsection (r)(2)) performing service in the exercise of duties required by such order, and an election of coverage under subsection (r) is in effect with respect to such order or with respect to the autonomous subdivision thereof to which such member belongs, the term “wages” shall, subject to the provisions of subsection (a)(1), include as such individual’s remuneration for such service the fair market value of any board, lodging, clothing, and other perquisites furnished to such member by such order or subdivision thereof or by any other person or organization pursuant to an agreement with such order or subdivision, except that the amount included as such individual’s remuneration under this paragraph shall not be less than $100 a month.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service performed by certain retired justices and judges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this chapter, in the case of an individual performing service under the provisions of <ref>section 294 of title 28</ref>, United States Code (relating to assignment of retired justices and judges to active duty), the term “wages” shall not include any payment under section 371(b) of such title 28 which is received during the period of such service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered transportation service</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing transportation systems—General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), all service performed in the employ of a State or political subdivision in connection with its operation of a public transportation system shall constitute covered transportation service if any part of the transportation system was acquired from private ownership after 1936 and prior to 1951.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Existing transportation systems—Cases in which no transportation employees, or only certain employees, are covered</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Service performed in the employ of a State or political subdivision in connection with the operation of its public transportation system shall not constitute covered transportation service if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any part of the transportation system was acquired from private ownership after 1936 and prior to 1951, and substantially all service in connection with the operation of the transportation system was, on <date date="1950-12-31">December 31, 1950</date>, covered under a general retirement system providing benefits which, by reason of a provision of the State constitution dealing specifically with retirement systems of the State or political subdivisions thereof, cannot be diminished or impaired; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> no part of the transportation system operated by the State or political subdivision on <date date="1950-12-31">December 31, 1950</date>, was acquired from private ownership after 1936 and prior to 1951;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">except that if such State or political subdivision makes an acquisition after 1950 from private ownership of any part of its transportation system, then, in the case of any employee who—</continuation>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> became an employee of such State or political subdivision in connection with and at the time of its acquisition after 1950 of such part, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> prior to such acquisition rendered service in employment (including as employment service covered by an agreement under section 218 of the Social Security Act) in connection with the operation of such part of the transportation system acquired by the State or political subdivision,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">the service of such employee in connection with the operation of the transportation system shall constitute covered transportation service, commencing with the first day of the third calendar quarter following the calendar quarter in which the acquisition of such part took place, unless on such first day such service of such employee is covered by a general retirement system which does not, with respect to such employee, contain special provisions applicable only to employees described in subparagraph (C).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transportation systems acquired after 1950</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">All service performed in the employ of a State or political subdivision thereof in connection with its operation of a public transportation system shall constitute covered transportation service if the transportation system was not operated by the State or political subdivision prior to 1951 and, at the time of its first acquisition (after 1950) from private ownership of any part of its transportation system, the State or political subdivision did not have a general retirement system covering substantially all service performed in connection with the operation of the transportation system.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The term “general retirement system” means any pension, annuity, retirement, or similar fund or system established by a State or by a political subdivision thereof for employees of the State, political subdivision, or both; but such term shall not include such a fund or system which covers only service performed in positions connected with the operation of its public transportation system.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A transportation system or a part thereof shall be considered to have been acquired by a State or political subdivision from private ownership if prior to the acquisition service performed by employees in connection with the operation of the system or part thereof acquired constituted employment under this chapter or subchapter A of chapter 9 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939 or was covered by an agreement made pursuant to section 218 of the Social Security Act and some of such employees became employees of the State or political subdivision in connection with and at the time of such acquisition.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> The term “political subdivision” includes an instrumentality of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a State,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> one or more political subdivisions of a State, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a State and one or more of its political subdivisions.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">[(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–21, title I, § 102(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1983-04-20">Apr. 20, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 71</ref>]</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreements entered into by American employers with respect to foreign affiliates</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreement with respect to certain employees of foreign affiliate</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall, at the American employer’s request, enter into an agreement (in such manner and form as may be prescribed by the Secretary) with any American employer (as defined in subsection (h)) who desires to have the insurance system established by title II of the Social Security Act extended to service performed outside the United States in the employ of any 1 or more of such employer’s foreign affiliates (as defined in paragraph (6)) by all employees who are citizens or residents of the United States, except that the agreement shall not apply to any service performed by, or remuneration paid to, an employee if such service or remuneration would be excluded from the term “employment” or “wages”, as defined in this section, had the service been performed in the United States. Such agreement may be amended at any time so as to be made applicable, in the same manner and under the same conditions, with respect to any other foreign affiliate of such American employer. Such agreement shall be applicable with respect to citizens or residents of the United States who, on or after the effective date of the agreement, are employees of and perform services outside the United States for any foreign affiliate specified in the agreement. Such agreement shall provide—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that the American employer shall pay to the Secretary, at such time or times as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe, amounts equivalent to the sum of the taxes which would be imposed by sections 3101 and 3111 (including amounts equivalent to the interest, additions to the taxes, additional amounts, and penalties which would be applicable) with respect to the remuneration which would be wages if the services covered by the agreement constituted employment as defined in this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that the American employer will comply with such regulations relating to payments and reports as the Secretary may prescribe to carry out the purposes of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective period of agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An agreement entered into pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be in effect for the period beginning with the first day of the calendar quarter in which such agreement is entered into or the first day of the succeeding calendar quarter, as may be specified in the agreement; except that in case such agreement is amended to include the services performed for any other affiliate and such amendment is executed after the first month following the first calendar quarter for which the agreement is in effect, the agreement shall be in effect with respect to service performed for such other affiliate only after the calendar quarter in which such amendment is executed. Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, the period for which any such agreement is effective with respect to any foreign entity shall terminate at the end of any calendar quarter in which the foreign entity, at any time in such quarter, ceases to be a foreign affiliate as defined in paragraph (6).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No termination of agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No agreement under this subsection may be terminated, either in its entirety or with respect to any foreign affiliate, on or after <date date="1989-06-15">June 15, 1989</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposits in trust funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of section 201 of the Social Security Act, relating to appropriations to the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund, such remuneration—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> paid for services covered by an agreement entered into pursuant to paragraph (1) as would be wages if the services constituted employment, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> as is reported to the Secretary pursuant to the provisions of such agreement or of the regulations issued under this subsection,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall be considered wages subject to the taxes imposed by this chapter.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Overpayments and underpayments</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> If more or less than the correct amount due under an agreement entered into pursuant to this subsection is paid with respect to any payment of remuneration, proper adjustments with respect to the amounts due under such agreement shall be made, without interest, in such manner and at such times as may be required by regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> If an overpayment cannot be adjusted under subparagraph (A), the amount thereof shall be paid by the Secretary, through the Fiscal Service of the Treasury Department, but only if a claim for such overpayment is filed with the Secretary within two years from the time such overpayment was made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign affiliate defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection and section 210(a) of the Social Security Act—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A foreign affiliate of an American employer is any foreign entity in which such American employer has not less than a 10-percent interest.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of 10-percent interest</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), an American employer has a 10-percent interest in any entity if such employer has such an interest directly (or through one or more entities)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of a corporation, in the voting stock thereof, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of any other entity, in the profits thereof.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> American employer as separate entity</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each American employer which enters into an agreement pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection shall, for purposes of this subsection and section 6413(c)(2)(C), relating to special refunds in the case of employees of certain foreign entities, be considered an employer in its capacity as a party to such agreement separate and distinct from its identity as a person employing individuals on its own account.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Regulations of the Secretary to carry out the purposes of this subsection shall be designed to make the requirements imposed on American employers with respect to services covered by an agreement entered into pursuant to this subsection the same, so far as practicable, as those imposed upon employers pursuant to this title with respect to the taxes imposed by this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(m)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service in the uniformed services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion of service</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “employment” shall, notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (b) of this section, include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> service performed by an individual as a member of a uniformed service on active duty, but such term shall not include any such service which is performed while on leave without pay, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> service performed by an individual as a member of a uniformed service on inactive duty training.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Active duty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “active duty” means “active duty” as described in paragraph (21) of <ref>section 101 of title 38</ref>, United States Code, except that it shall also include “active duty for training” as described in paragraph (22) of such section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inactive duty training</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “inactive duty training” means “inactive duty training” as described in paragraph (23) of such section 101.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(n)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Member of a uniformed service</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, the term “member of a uniformed service” means any person appointed, enlisted, or inducted in a component of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Coast Guard (including a reserve component as defined in <ref>section 101(27) of title 38</ref>, United States Code), or in one of those services without specification of component, or as a commissioned officer of the Coast and Geodetic Survey, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Corps, or the Regular or Reserve Corps <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002195">2</ref> of the Public Health Service, and any person serving in the Army or Air Force under call or conscription. The term includes—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a retired member of any of those services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a member of the Fleet Reserve or Fleet Marine Corps Reserve;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> a cadet at the United States Military Academy, a midshipman at the United States Naval Academy, and a cadet at the United States Coast Guard Academy or United States Air Force Academy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a member of the Reserve Officers’ Training Corps, the Naval Reserve Officers’ Training Corps, or the Air Force Reserve Officers’ Training Corps, when ordered to annual training duty for fourteen days or more, and while performing authorized travel to and from that duty; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<chapeau> any person while en route to or from, or at, a place for final acceptance or for entry upon active duty in the military, naval, or air service—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> who has been provisionally accepted for such duty; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> who, under the Military Selective Service Act, has been selected for active military, naval, or air service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">and has been ordered or directed to proceed to such place.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The term does not include a temporary member of the Coast Guard Reserve.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(o)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Crew leader</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, the term “crew leader” means an individual who furnishes individuals to perform agricultural labor for another person, if such individual pays (either on his own behalf or on behalf of such person) the individuals so furnished by him for the agricultural labor performed by them and if such individual has not entered into a written agreement with such person whereby such individual has been designated as an employee of such person; and such individuals furnished by the crew leader to perform agricultural labor for another person shall be deemed to be the employees of such crew leader. For purposes of this chapter and chapter 2, a crew leader shall, with respect to service performed in furnishing individuals to perform agricultural labor for another person and service performed as a member of the crew, be deemed not to be an employee of such other person.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(p)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Peace Corps volunteer service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, the term “employment” shall, notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (b) of this section, include service performed by an individual as a volunteer or volunteer leader within the meaning of the Peace Corps Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(q)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tips included for both employee and employer taxes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, tips received by an employee in the course of his employment shall be considered remuneration for such employment (and deemed to have been paid by the employer for purposes of subsections (a) and (b) of section 3111). Such remuneration shall be deemed to be paid at the time a written statement including such tips is furnished to the employer pursuant to section 6053(a) or (if no statement including such tips is so furnished) at the time received; except that, in determining the employer’s liability in connection with the taxes imposed by section 3111 with respect to such tips in any case where no statement including such tips was so furnished (or to the extent that the statement so furnished was inaccurate or incomplete), such remuneration shall be deemed for purposes of subtitle F to be paid on the date on which notice and demand for such taxes is made to the employer by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(r)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election of coverage by religious orders</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certificate of election by order</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A religious order whose members are required to take a vow of poverty, or any autonomous subdivision of such order, may file a certificate (in such form and manner, and with such official, as may be prescribed by regulations under this chapter) electing to have the insurance system established by title II of the Social Security Act extended to services performed by its members in the exercise of duties required by such order or such subdivision thereof. Such certificate of election shall provide that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such election of coverage by such order or subdivision shall be irrevocable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such election shall apply to all current and future members of such order, or in the case of a subdivision thereof to all current and future members of such order who belong to such subdivision;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> all services performed by a member of such an order or subdivision in the exercise of duties required by such order or subdivision shall be deemed to have been performed by such member as an employee of such order or subdivision; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the wages of each member, upon which such order or subdivision shall pay the taxes imposed by sections 3101 and 3111, will be determined as provided in subsection (i)(4).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition of member</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, a member of a religious order means any individual who is subject to a vow of poverty as a member of such order and who performs tasks usually required (and to the extent usually required) of an active member of such order and who is not considered retired because of old age or total disability.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date for election</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> A certificate of election of coverage shall be in effect, for purposes of subsection (b)(8) and for purposes of section 210(a)(8) of the Social Security Act, for the period beginning with whichever of the following may be designated by the order or subdivision thereof:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the first day of the calendar quarter in which the certificate is filed,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the first day of the calendar quarter succeeding such quarter, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the first day of any calendar quarter preceding the calendar quarter in which the certificate is filed, except that such date may not be earlier than the first day of the twentieth calendar quarter preceding the quarter in which such certificate is filed.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">Whenever a date is designated under clause (iii), the election shall apply to services performed before the quarter in which the certificate is filed only if the member performing such services was a member at the time such services were performed and is living on the first day of the quarter in which such certificate is filed.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> If a certificate of election filed pursuant to this subsection is effective for one or more calendar quarters prior to the quarter in which such certificate is filed, then—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for purposes of computing interest and for purposes of section 6651 (relating to addition to tax for failure to file tax return), the due date for the return and payment of the tax for such prior calendar quarters resulting from the filing of such certificate shall be the last day of the calendar month following the calendar quarter in which the certificate is filed; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the statutory period for the assessment of such tax shall not expire before the expiration of 3 years from such due date.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">[(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 98–21, title I, § 102(b)(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="1983-04-20">Apr. 20, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 71</ref>]</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(s)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Concurrent employment by two or more employers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of sections 3102, 3111, and 3121(a)(1), if two or more related corporations concurrently employ the same individual and compensate such individual through a common paymaster which is one of such corporations, each such corporation shall be considered to have paid as remuneration to such individual only the amounts actually disbursed by it to such individual and shall not be considered to have paid as remuneration to such individual amounts actually disbursed to such individual by another of such corporations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">[(t)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 100–203, title IX, § 9006(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1330–289</ref>]</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(u)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of hospital insurance tax to Federal, State, and local employment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal employment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of the taxes imposed by sections 3101(b) and 3111(b), subsection (b) shall be applied without regard to paragraph (5) thereof.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State and local employment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of the taxes imposed by sections 3101(b) and 3111(b)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C), subsection (b) shall be applied without regard to paragraph (7) thereof.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for certain services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Service shall not be treated as employment by reason of subparagraph (A) if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the service is included under an agreement under section 218 of the Social Security Act, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> the service is performed—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> by an individual who is employed by a State or political subdivision thereof to relieve him from unemployment,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> in a hospital, home, or other institution by a patient or inmate thereof as an employee of a State or political subdivision thereof or of the District of Columbia,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> by an individual, as an employee of a State or political subdivision thereof or of the District of Columbia, serving on a temporary basis in case of fire, storm, snow, earthquake, flood or other similar emergency,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> by any individual as an employee included under <ref>section 5351(2) of title 5</ref>, United States Code (relating to certain interns, student nurses, and other student employees of hospitals of the District of Columbia Government), other than as a medical or dental intern or a medical or dental resident in training,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> by an election official or election worker if the remuneration paid in a calendar year for such service is less than $1,000 with respect to service performed during any calendar year commencing on or after <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>, ending on or before <date date="1999-12-31">December 31, 1999</date>, and the adjusted amount determined under section 218(c)(8)(B) of the Social Security Act for any calendar year commencing on or after <date date="2000-01-01">January 1, 2000</date>, with respect to service performed during such calendar year, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(VI)</num>
<content> by an individual in a position described in section 1402(c)(2)(E).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">As used in this subparagraph, the terms “State” and “political subdivision” have the meanings given those terms in section 218(b) of the Social Security Act.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for current employment which continues</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Service performed for an employer shall not be treated as employment by reason of subparagraph (A) if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such service would be excluded from the term “employment” for purposes of this chapter if subparagraph (A) did not apply;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> such service is performed by an individual—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> who was performing substantial and regular service for remuneration for that employer before <date date="1986-04-01">April 1, 1986</date>,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> who is a bona fide employee of that employer on <date date="1986-03-31">March 31, 1986</date>, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> whose employment relationship with that employer was not entered into for purposes of meeting the requirements of this subparagraph; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the employment relationship with that employer has not been terminated after <date date="1986-03-31">March 31, 1986</date>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of agencies and instrumentalities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (C), under regulations—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> All agencies and instrumentalities of a State (as defined in section 218(b) of the Social Security Act) or of the District of Columbia shall be treated as a single employer.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> All agencies and instrumentalities of a political subdivision of a State (as so defined) shall be treated as a single employer and shall not be treated as described in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Medicare qualified government employment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this chapter, the term “medicare qualified government employment” means service which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is employment (as defined in subsection (b)) with the application of paragraphs (1) and (2), but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> would not be employment (as so defined) without the application of such paragraphs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(v)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of certain deferred compensation and salary reduction arrangements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain employer contributions treated as wages</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Nothing in any paragraph of subsection (a) (other than paragraph (1)) shall exclude from the term “wages”—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any employer contribution under a qualified cash or deferred arrangement (as defined in section 401(k)) to the extent not included in gross income by reason of section 402(e)(3) or consisting of designated Roth contributions (as defined in section 402A(c)), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any amount treated as an employer contribution under section 414(h)(2) where the pickup referred to in such section is pursuant to a salary reduction agreement (whether evidenced by a written instrument or otherwise).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of certain nonqualified deferred compensation plans</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Any amount deferred under a nonqualified deferred compensation plan shall be taken into account for purposes of this chapter as of the later of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> when the services are performed, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> when there is no substantial risk of forfeiture of the rights to such amount.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">The preceding sentence shall not apply to any excess parachute payment (as defined in section 280G(b)) or to any specified stock compensation (as defined in section 4985) on which tax is imposed by section 4985.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxed only once</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any amount taken into account as wages by reason of subparagraph (A) (and the income attributable thereto) shall not thereafter be treated as wages for purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonqualified deferred compensation plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “nonqualified deferred compensation plan” means any plan or other arrangement for deferral of compensation other than a plan described in subsection (a)(5).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exempt governmental deferred compensation plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of subsection (a)(5), the term “exempt governmental deferred compensation plan” means any plan providing for deferral of compensation established and maintained for its employees by the United States, by a State or political subdivision thereof, or by an agency or instrumentality of any of the foregoing. Such term shall not include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any plan to which section 83, 402(b), 403(c), 457(a), or 457(f)(1) applies,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any annuity contract described in section 403(b), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Thrift Savings Fund (within the meaning of subchapter III of chapter 84 of title 5, United States Code).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(w)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption of churches and qualified church-controlled organizations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any church or qualified church-controlled organization (as defined in paragraph (3)) may make an election within the time period described in paragraph (2), in accordance with such procedures as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, that services performed in the employ of such church or organization shall be excluded from employment for purposes of title II of the Social Security Act and this chapter. An election may be made under this subsection only if the church or qualified church-controlled organization states that such church or organization is opposed for religious reasons to the payment of the tax imposed under section 3111.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing and duration of election</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An election under this subsection must be made prior to the first date, more than 90 days after <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, on which a quarterly employment tax return for the tax imposed under section 3111 is due, or would be due but for the election, from such church or organization. An election under this subsection shall apply to current and future employees, and shall apply to service performed after <date date="1983-12-31">December 31, 1983</date>. The election may be revoked by the church or organization under regulations prescribed by the Secretary. The election shall be revoked by the Secretary if such church or organization fails to furnish the information required under section 6051 to the Secretary for a period of 2 years or more with respect to remuneration paid for such services by such church or organization, and, upon request by the Secretary, fails to furnish all such previously unfurnished information for the period covered by the election. Any revocation under the preceding sentence shall apply retroactively to the beginning of the 2-year period for which the information was not furnished.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subsection, the term “church” means a church, a convention or association of churches, or an elementary or secondary school which is controlled, operated, or principally supported by a church or by a convention or association of churches.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of this subsection, the term “qualified church-controlled organization” means any church-controlled tax-exempt organization described in section 501(c)(3), other than an organization which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> offers goods, services, or facilities for sale, other than on an incidental basis, to the general public, other than goods, services, or facilities which are sold at a nominal charge which is substantially less than the cost of providing such goods, services, or facilities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> normally receives more than 25 percent of its support from either (I) governmental sources, or (II) receipts from admissions, sales of merchandise, performance of services, or furnishing of facilities, in activities which are not unrelated trades or businesses, or both.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(x)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable dollar threshold</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a)(7)(B), the term “applicable dollar threshold” means $1,000. In the case of calendar years after 1995, the Commissioner of Social Security shall adjust such $1,000 amount at the same time and in the same manner as under section 215(a)(1)(B)(ii) of the Social Security Act with respect to the amounts referred to in section 215(a)(1)(B)(i) of such Act, except that, for purposes of this paragraph, 1993 shall be substituted for the calendar year referred to in section 215(a)(1)(B)(ii)(II) of such Act. If any amount as adjusted under the preceding sentence is not a multiple of $100, such amount shall be rounded to the next lowest multiple of $100.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(y)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Service in the employ of international organizations by certain transferred Federal employees</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this chapter, service performed in the employ of an international organization by an individual pursuant to a transfer of such individual to such international organization pursuant to <ref>section 3582 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, shall constitute “employment” if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> immediately before such transfer, such individual performed service with a Federal agency which constituted “employment” under subsection (b) for purposes of the taxes imposed by sections 3101(a) and 3111(a), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such individual would be entitled, upon separation from such international organization and proper application, to reemployment with such Federal agency under such section 3582.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal agency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “Federal agency” means an agency, as defined in <ref>section 3581(1) of title 5</ref>, United States Code.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “international organization” has the meaning provided such term by <ref>section 3581(3) of title 5</ref>, United States Code.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(z)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of certain foreign persons as American employers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If any employee of a foreign person is performing services in connection with a contract between the United States Government (or any instrumentality thereof) and any member of any domestically controlled group of entities which includes such foreign person, such foreign person shall be treated for purposes of this chapter as an American employer with respect to such services performed by such employee.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Domestically controlled group of entities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “domestically controlled group of entities” means a controlled group of entities the common parent of which is a domestic corporation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Controlled group of entities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “controlled group of entities” means a controlled group of corporations as defined in section 1563(a)(1), except that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> “more than 50 percent” shall be substituted for “at least 80 percent” each place it appears therein, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the determination shall be made without regard to subsections (a)(4) and (b)(2) of section 1563.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">A partnership or any other entity (other than a corporation) shall be treated as a member of a controlled group of entities if such entity is controlled (within the meaning of section 954(d)(3)) by members of such group (including any entity treated as a member of such group by reason of this sentence).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability of common parent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a foreign person who is a member of any domestically controlled group of entities, the common parent of such group shall be jointly and severally liable for any tax under this chapter for which such foreign person is liable by reason of this subsection, and for any penalty imposed on such person by this title with respect to any failure to pay such tax or to file any return or statement with respect to such tax or wages subject to such tax. No deduction shall be allowed under this title for any liability imposed by the preceding sentence.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provisions preventing double taxation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Agreements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to any services which are covered by an agreement under subsection (<i>l</i>).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Equivalent foreign taxation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to any services if the employer establishes to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the remuneration paid by such employer for such services is subject to a tax imposed by a foreign country which is substantially equivalent to the taxes imposed by this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cross reference</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2 fontsize7">For relief from taxes in cases covered by certain international agreements, see sections 3101(c) and 3111(c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 417</ref>; <ref>Sept. 1, 1954, ch. 1206</ref>, title II, §§ 204(a), (b), 205(a)–(e), 206(a), 207, 209, <ref>68 Stat. 1091–1094</ref>; <ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 836</ref>, title I, §§ 103(j), 121(d), title II, §§ 201(b)–(d), (e)(1), (h)(1), (2), (j)–(<i>l</i>), <ref>70 Stat. 824</ref>, 839–841, 843; <ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 837</ref>, title IV, §§ 410, 411(a), <ref>70 Stat. 878</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–840, title IV</ref>, §§ 402(b), 404(a), 405(a), (b), <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1042</ref>, 1044–1046; <ref>Pub. L. 85–866, title I, § 69</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1659</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–70, § 22(a)</ref>, <date date="1959-06-25">June 25, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 146</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–168, title I, § 104(h)</ref>, title II, § 202(a), <date date="1959-08-18">Aug. 18, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 387</ref>, 389; <ref>Pub. L. 86–624, § 18(c)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 416</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–778, title I</ref>, §§ 103(n)–(p), 104(b), 105(a), <date date="1960-09-13">Sept. 13, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 938</ref>, 939, 942; <ref>Pub. L. 87–256, § 110(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1961-09-21">Sept. 21, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 536</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–293, title II, § 202(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1961-09-22">Sept. 22, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 626</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–272, title II, § 220(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1964-02-26">Feb. 26, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 62</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–650, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1964-10-13">Oct. 13, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 1077</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–97, title III</ref>, §§ 311(b)(4), (5), 313(c)(3), (4), 316(a)(1), (b), 317(b), 320(b)(2), <date date="1965-07-30">July 30, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 381</ref>, 383, 386, 388, 393; <ref>Pub. L. 90–248, title I</ref>, §§ 108(b)(2), 123(b), title IV, § 403(i), title V, § 504(a), <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 835</ref>, 845, 932, 934; <ref>Pub. L. 91–172, title IX, § 943(c)(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 728</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–5, title II, § 203(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1971-03-17">Mar. 17, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 11</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–336, title II, § 203(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1972-07-01">July 1, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 419</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–603, title I</ref>, §§ 104(i), 122(b), 123(a)(2), (b), (c)(2), 128(b), 129(a)(2), 138(b), <date date="1972-10-30">Oct. 30, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 1341</ref>, 1354, 1356, 1358, 1359, 1365; <ref>Pub. L. 93–66, title II, § 203(b)(2)</ref>, (d), <date date="1973-07-09">July 9, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 153</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–233, § 5(b)(2)</ref>, (d), <date date="1973-12-31">Dec. 31, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 954</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XII, § 1207(e)(1)(A)</ref>, title XIX, §§ 1903(a)(3), 1906(b)(13)(A), (C), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1706</ref>, 1807, 1834; <ref>Pub. L. 94–563, § 1(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="1976-10-19">Oct. 19, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2655</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–216, title III</ref>, §§ 312(a), (b), (d), (f), (g), 314(a), 315(a), 356(a)–(d), <date date="1977-12-20">Dec. 20, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1532–1536</ref>, 1555; <ref>Pub. L. 95–472, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-17">Oct. 17, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1333</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–600, title I, § 164(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2814</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–222, title I, § 101(a)(10)(B)(i)</ref>, <date date="1980-04-01">Apr. 1, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 201</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–499, title XI, § 1141(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-05">Dec. 5, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2693</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–34, title I, § 124(e)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 200</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–123, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 1662</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–248, title II, § 278(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 559</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–21, title I</ref>, §§ 101(b), (c)(2), 102(b), title III, §§ 321(a), (e)(1), 322(a)(2), 323(a)(1), 324(a), 327(a)(1), (b)(1), 328(a), <date date="1983-04-20">Apr. 20, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 69</ref>, 70, 118, 119, 121, 122, 126–128; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title I, § 67(c)</ref>, title IV, § 491(d)(36), title V, § 531(d)(1)(A), div. B, title VI, §§ 2601(b), 2603(a)(2), (b), 2661(<i>o</i>)(3), 2663(i), (j)(5)(C), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 587</ref>, 851, 884, 1124, 1128, 1159, 1169, 1171; <ref>Pub. L. 99–221, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1985-12-26">Dec. 26, 1985</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1735</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–272, title XII, § 12112(b)</ref>, title XIII, §§ 13205(a)(1), 13303(c)(2), <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 288</ref>, 313, 327; <ref>Pub. L. 99–335, title III, § 304(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 606</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title IX, § 9002(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (2)(A), <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1971</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title I, § 122(e)(1)</ref>, title XI, §§ 1108(g)(7), 1147(b), 1151(d)(2)(A), title XVIII, §§ 1882(c), 1883(a)(11)(B), 1895(b)(18)(A), 1899A(38)–(40), <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2112</ref>, 2435, 2494, 2505, 2915, 2916, 2935, 2960; <ref>Pub. L. 100–203, title IX</ref>, §§ 9001(b), 9002(b), 9003(a)(2), 9004(b), 9005(b), 9006(a), (b)(2), 9023(d), <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1330–286</ref> to 1330–289, 1330–296; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title I</ref>, §§ 1001(d)(2)(C)(i), (g)(4)(B)(i), 1011(e)(8), 1011B(a)(22)(A), (23)(A), 1018(r)(2)(A), (u)(35), title III, § 3043(c)(2), title VIII, §§ 8015(b)(2), (c)(2), 8016(a)(3)(A), (4)(A), (C), 8017(b), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3351</ref>, 3352, 3461, 3485, 3486, 3586, 3592, 3642, 3791–3793; <ref>Pub. L. 101–140, title II, § 203(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-08">Nov. 8, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 830</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–239, title X, § 10201(a)</ref>, (b)(3), <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2472</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XI</ref>, §§ 11331(a), 11332(b), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–467</ref>, 1388–469; <ref>Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 5117</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–318, title V, § 521(b)(34)</ref>, <date date="1992-07-03">July 3, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 312</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–66, title XIII, § 13207(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 467</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–178, title II, § 204(c)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-03">Dec. 3, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 2033</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–296, title I, § 108(h)(2)</ref>, title III, §§ 303(a)(2), (b)(2), 319(a)(1), (5), 320(a)(1)(C), <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1487</ref>, 1519, 1533–1535; <ref>Pub. L. 103–387, § 2(a)(1)(A)</ref>–(C), <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 4071</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–188, title I</ref>, §§ 1116(a)(1)(A), (B), 1421(b)(8)(A), 1458(b)(1), <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1762</ref>, 1798, 1819; <ref>Pub. L. 105–33, title XI, § 11246(b)(2)(A)</ref>, as added <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(h) [title VIII, § 802(a)(2)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–480</ref>, 2681–532; <ref>Pub. L. 105–61, title VI, § 642(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1997-10-10">Oct. 10, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1319</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title VI, § 6023(13)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 825</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(7) [title III, § 319(15)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–647; <ref>Pub. L. 108–121, title I, § 106(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-11">Nov. 11, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1339</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–203, title IV, § 423(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="2004-03-02">Mar. 2, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 536</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–357, title II, § 251(a)(1)(A)</ref>, title III, § 320(b)(1), title VIII, § 802(c)(1), <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1458</ref>, 1473, 1568; <ref>Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 585(b)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1932</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–280, title VIII, § 854(c)(8)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1018</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–172, § 8(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-29">Dec. 29, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2483</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–245, title I, § 115(a)(1)</ref>, title III, § 302(a), <date date="2008-06-17">June 17, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1636</ref>, 1647; <ref>Pub. L. 110–458, title I, § 108(k)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 5110</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(19)(B)(iv)</ref>, (99)(C)(i), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4040</ref>, 4052; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(209)</ref>, (210), (325)(A), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1194</ref>, 1199; <ref>Pub. L. 115–243, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-09-20">Sept. 20, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 2895</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. O, title III, § 301(c)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3175</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. T, title VII, § 702(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5404</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3122.</num>
<heading> Federal service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of the taxes imposed by this chapter with respect to service performed in the employ of the United States or in the employ of any instrumentality which is wholly owned by the United States, including such service which is medicare qualified government employment (as defined in section 3121(u)(3)), including service, performed as a member of a uniformed service, to which the provisions of section 3121(m)(1) are applicable, and including service, performed as a volunteer or volunteer leader within the meaning of the Peace Corps Act, to which the provisions of section 3121(p) are applicable, the determination of the amount of remuneration for such service, and the return and payment of the taxes imposed by this chapter, shall be made by the head of the Federal agency or instrumentality having the control of such service, or by such agents as such head may designate. In the case of the taxes imposed by this chapter with respect to service performed in the employ of an international organization pursuant to a transfer to which the provisions of section 3121(y) are applicable, the determination of the amount of remuneration for such service, and the return and payment of the taxes imposed by this chapter, shall be made by the head of the Federal agency from which the transfer was made. Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to affect the Secretary’s authority to determine under subsections (a) and (b) of section 3121 whether any such service constitutes employment, the periods of such employment, and whether remuneration paid for any such service constitutes wages. The person making such return may, for convenience of administration, make payments of the tax imposed under section 3111 with respect to such service without regard to the contribution and benefit base limitation in section 3121(a)(1), and he shall not be required to obtain a refund of the tax paid under section 3111 on that part of the remuneration not included in wages by reason of section 3121(a)(1). Payments of the tax imposed under section 3111 with respect to service, performed by an individual as a member of a uniformed service, to which the provisions of section 3121(m)(1) are applicable, shall be made from appropriations available for the pay of members of such uniformed service. The provisions of this section shall be applicable in the case of service performed by a civilian employee, not compensated from funds appropriated by the Congress, in the Army and Air Force Exchange Service, Army and Air Force Motion Picture Service, Navy Exchanges, Marine Corps Exchanges, or other activities, conducted by an instrumentality of the United States subject to the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense, at installations of the Department of Defense for the comfort, pleasure, contentment, and mental and physical improvement of personnel of such Department; and for purposes of this section the Secretary of Defense shall be deemed to be the head of such instrumentality. The provisions of this section shall be applicable also in the case of service performed by a civilian employee, not compensated from funds appropriated by the Congress, in the Coast Guard Exchanges or other activities, conducted by an instrumentality of the United States subject to the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating, at installations of the Coast Guard for the comfort, pleasure, contentment, and mental and physical improvement of personnel of the Coast Guard; and for purposes of this section the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall be deemed to be the head of such instrumentality.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 428</ref>; <ref>Sept. 1, 1954, ch. 1206</ref>, title II, §§ 202(c), 203(a), <ref>68 Stat. 1090</ref>; <ref>Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 837</ref>, title IV, § 411(b), (c), <ref>70 Stat. 879</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–840, title IV, § 402(c)</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1042</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–866, title I, § 70</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1660</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–293, title II, § 202(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1961-09-22">Sept. 22, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 626</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–97, title III, § 320(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1965-07-30">July 30, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 393</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–248, title I, § 108(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 835</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–5, title II, § 203(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1971-03-17">Mar. 17, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 11</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–236, § 203(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1972-07-01">July 1, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 419</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–66, § 203(b)(3)</ref>, (d), <date date="1973-07-09">July 9, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 153</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–233, § 5(b)(3)</ref>, (d), <date date="1973-12-31">Dec. 31, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 954</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1903(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1807</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–248, title II, § 278(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 560</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–272, title XIII, § 13205(a)(2)(C)</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 315</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VIII, § 8015(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3791</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11331(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–468</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–66, title XIII, § 13207(d)(4)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 468</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–296, title III, § 319(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1534</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–241, title IX, § 902(i)</ref>, <date date="2006-07-11">July 11, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 567</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3123.</num>
<heading> Deductions as constructive payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever under this chapter or any act of Congress, or under the law of any State, an employer is required or permitted to deduct any amount from the remuneration of an employee and to pay the amount deducted to the United States, a State, or any political subdivision thereof, then for purposes of this chapter the amount so deducted shall be considered to have been paid to the employee at the time of such deduction.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 429</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3124.</num>
<heading> Estimate of revenue reduction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary at intervals of not longer than 3 years shall estimate the reduction in the amount of taxes collected under this chapter by reason of the operation of section 3121(b)(9) and shall include such estimate in his annual report.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 429</ref>; <ref>Sept. 1, 1954, ch. 1206</ref>, title II, § 205(b), <ref>68 Stat. 1091</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3125.</num>
<heading> Returns in the case of governmental employees in States, Guam, American Samoa, and the District of Columbia</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this section, in the case of the taxes imposed by sections 3101(b) and 3111(b) with respect to service performed in the employ of a State or any political subdivision thereof (or any instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing which is wholly owned thereby), the return and payment of such taxes may be made by the head of the agency or instrumentality having the control of such service, or by such agents as such head may designate. The person making such return may, for convenience of administration, make payments of the tax imposed under section 3111 with respect to the service of such individuals without regard to the contribution and benefit base limitation in section 3121(a)(1).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guam</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The return and payment of the taxes imposed by this chapter on the income of individuals who are officers or employees of the Government of Guam or any political subdivision thereof or of any instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing which is wholly owned thereby, and those imposed on such Government or political subdivision or instrumentality with respect to having such individuals in its employ, may be made by the Governor of Guam or by such agents as he may designate. The person making such return may, for convenience of administration, make payments of the tax imposed under section 3111 with respect to the service of such individuals without regard to the contribution and benefit base limitation in section 3121(a)(1).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> American Samoa</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The return and payment of the taxes imposed by this chapter on the income of individuals who are officers or employees of the Government of American Samoa or any political subdivision thereof or of any instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing which is wholly owned thereby, and those imposed on such Government or political subdivision or instrumentality with respect to having such individuals in its employ, may be made by the Governor of American Samoa or by such agents as he may designate. The person making such return may, for convenience of administration, make payments of the tax imposed under section 3111 with respect to the service of such individuals without regard to the contribution and benefit base limitation in section 3121(a)(1).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> District of Columbia</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of the taxes imposed by this chapter with respect to service performed in the employ of the District of Columbia or in the employ of any instrumentality which is wholly owned thereby, the return and payment of the taxes may be made by the Mayor of the District of Columbia or such agents as he may designate. The person making such return may, for convenience of administration, make payments of the tax imposed by section 3111 with respect to such service without regard to the contribution and benefit base limitation in section 3121(a)(1).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 86–778, title I, § 103(q)(1)</ref>, <date date="1960-09-13">Sept. 13, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 939</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 89–97, title III</ref>, §§ 317(c)(1), (2), 320(b)(4), <date date="1965-07-30">July 30, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 389</ref>, 393; <ref>Pub. L. 90–248, title I, § 108(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref>81 Stat. 835</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–5, title II, § 203(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="1971-03-17">Mar. 17, 1971</date>, <ref>85 Stat. 11</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 92–336, title II, § 203(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="1972-07-01">July 1, 1972</date>, <ref>86 Stat. 419</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–66, title II, § 203(b)(4)</ref>, (d), <date date="1973-07-09">July 9, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 153</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–233, § 5(b)(4)</ref>, (d), <date date="1973-12-31">Dec. 31, 1973</date>, <ref>87 Stat. 954</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1903(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1807</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–272, title XIII, § 13205(a)(2)(A)(i)</ref>, (ii), <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 315</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11331(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–468</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–66, title XIII, § 13207(d)(4)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 468</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3126.</num>
<heading> Return and payment by governmental em­ployer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the employer is a State or political subdivision thereof, or an agency or instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing, the return of the amount deducted and withheld upon any wages under section 3101 and the amount of the tax imposed by section 3111 may be made by any officer or employee of such State or political subdivision or such agency or instrumentality, as the case may be, having control of the payment of such wages, or appropriately designated for that purpose.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title IX, § 9002(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3127.</num>
<heading> Exemption for employers and their employees where both are members of religious faiths opposed to participation in Social Security Act programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter (and under regulations prescribed to carry out this section), in any case where—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an employer (or, if the employer is a partnership, each partner therein) is a member of a recognized religious sect or division thereof described in section 1402(g)(1) and an adherent of established tenets or teachings of such sect or division as described in such section, and has filed and had approved under subsection (b) an application (in such form and manner, and with such official, as may be prescribed by such regulations) for an exemption from the taxes imposed by section 3111, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an employee of such employer who is also a member of such a religious sect or division and an adherent of its established tenets or teachings has filed and had approved under subsection (b) an identical application for exemption from the taxes imposed by section 3101,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">such employer shall be exempt from the taxes imposed by section 3111 with respect to wages paid to each of the employees thereof who meets the requirements of paragraph (2) and each such employee shall be exempt from the taxes imposed by section 3101 with respect to such wages paid to him by such employer.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Approval of application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An application for exemption filed by an employer (or a partner) under subsection (a)(1) or by an employee under subsection (a)(2) shall be approved only if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> such application contains or is accompanied by the evidence described in section 1402(g)(1)(A) and a waiver described in section 1402(g)(1)(B),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the Commissioner of Social Security makes the findings (with respect to such sect or division) described in section 1402(g)(1)(C), (D), and (E), and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> no benefit or other payment referred to in section 1402(g)(1)(B) became payable (or, but for section 203 of the Social Security Act, would have become payable) to the individual filing the application at or before the time of such filing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective period of exemption</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">An exemption granted under this section to any employer with respect to wages paid to any of the employees thereof, or granted to any such employee, shall apply with respect to wages paid by such employer during the period—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> commencing with the first day of the first calendar quarter, after the quarter in which such application is filed, throughout which such employer (or, if the employer is a partnership, each partner therein) or employee meets the applicable requirements specified in subsections (a) and (b), and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> ending with the last day of the calendar quarter preceding the first calendar quarter thereafter in which (A) such employer (or, if the employer is a partnership, any partner therein) or the employee involved does not meet the applicable requirements of subsection (a), or (B) the sect or division thereof of which such employer (or, if the employer is a partnership, any partner therein) or employee is a member is found by the Commissioner of Social Security to have ceased to meet the requirements of subsection (b)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VIII, § 8007(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3781</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–239, title X, § 10204(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2474</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–296, title I, § 108(h)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1487</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(b)(35)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1204</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3128.</num>
<heading> Short title</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This chapter may be cited as the “Federal Insurance Contributions Act.”</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 429</ref>, § 3125; renumbered § 3126, <ref>Pub. L. 86–778, title I, § 103(q)(1)</ref>, <date date="1960-09-13">Sept. 13, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 939</ref>; renumbered § 3127, <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title IX, § 9002(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 1970</ref>; renumbered § 3128, <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VIII, § 8007(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3781</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter D—</num>
<heading>Credits</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 3131.</num>
<heading> Credit for paid sick leave</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of an employer, there shall be allowed as a credit against applicable employment taxes for each calendar quarter an amount equal to 100 percent of the qualified sick leave wages paid by such employer with respect to such calendar quarter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations and refundability</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wages taken into account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amount of qualified sick leave wages taken into account under subsection (a), plus any increases under subsection (e), with respect to any individual shall not exceed $200 ($511 in the case of any day any portion of which is paid sick time described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of section 5102(a) of the Emergency Paid Sick Leave Act, applied with the modification described in subsection (c)(2)(A)(i)) for any day (or portion thereof) for which the individual is paid qualified sick leave wages.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Overall limitation on number of days taken into account</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The aggregate number of days taken into account under paragraph (1) for any calendar quarter shall not exceed the excess (if any) of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 10, over</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the aggregate number of days so taken into account during preceding calendar quarters in such calendar year (other than the first quarter of calendar year 2021).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Credit limited to certain employment taxes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The credit allowed by subsection (a) with respect to any calendar quarter shall not exceed the applicable employment taxes for such calendar quarter on the wages paid with respect to the employment of all employees of the employer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refundability of excess credit</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Credit is refundable</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If the amount of the credit under subsection (a) exceeds the limitation of paragraph (3) for any calendar quarter, such excess shall be treated as an overpayment that shall be refunded under sections 6402(a) and 6413(b).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advancing credit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In anticipation of the credit, including the refundable portion under subparagraph (A), the credit shall be advanced, according to forms and instructions provided by the Secretary, up to an amount calculated under subsection (a), subject to the limits under paragraph (1) and (2), all calculated through the end of the most recent payroll period in the quarter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified sick leave wages</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “qualified sick leave wages” means wages paid by an employer which would be required to be paid by reason of the Emergency Paid Sick Leave Act as if such Act applied after <date date="2021-03-31">March 31, 2021</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules of application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of determining whether wages are qualified sick leave wages under paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Emergency Paid Sick Leave Act shall be applied—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> by inserting “, the employee is seeking or awaiting the results of a diagnostic test for, or a medical diagnosis of, COVID–19 and such employee has been exposed to COVID–19 or the employee’s employer has requested such test or diagnosis, or the employee is obtaining immunization related to COVID–19 or recovering from any injury, disability, illness, or condition related to such immunization” after “medical diagnosis” in section 5102(a)(3) thereof, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> by applying section 5102(b)(1) of such Act separately with respect to each calendar year after 2020 (and, in the case of calendar year 2021, without regard to the first quarter thereof).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Leave must meet requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If an employer fails to comply with any requirement of such Act (determined without regard to section 5109 thereof) with respect to paid sick time (as defined in section 5110 of such Act), amounts paid by such employer with respect to such paid sick time shall not be taken into account as qualified sick leave wages. For purposes of the preceding sentence, an employer which takes an action described in section 5104 of such Act shall be treated as failing to meet a requirement of such Act.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allowance of credit for certain health plan expenses</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amount of the credit allowed under subsection (a) shall be increased by so much of the employer’s qualified health plan expenses as are properly allocable to the qualified sick leave wages for which such credit is so allowed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified health plan expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “qualified health plan expenses” means amounts paid or incurred by the employer to provide and maintain a group health plan (as defined in section 5000(b)(1)), but only to the extent that such amounts are excluded from the gross income of employees by reason of section 106(a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation rules</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section, qualified health plan expenses shall be allocated to qualified sick leave wages in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe. Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, such allocation shall be treated as properly made if made on the basis of being pro rata among covered employees and pro rata on the basis of periods of coverage (relative to the time periods of leave to which such wages relate).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allowance of credit for amounts paid under certain collectively bargained agreements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The amount of the credit allowed under subsection (a) shall be increased by the sum of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> so much of the employer’s collectively bargained defined benefit pension plan contributions as are properly allocable to the qualified sick leave wages for which such credit is so allowed, plus</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> so much of the employer’s collectively bargained apprenticeship program contributions as are properly allocable to the qualified sick leave wages for which such credit is so allowed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collectively bargained defined benefit pension plan contributions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “collectively bargained defined benefit pension plan contributions” means, with respect to any calendar quarter, contributions which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are paid or incurred by an employer during the calendar quarter on behalf of its employees to a defined benefit plan (as defined in section 414(j)), which meets the requirements of section 401(a),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> are made based on a pension contribution rate, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> are required to be made pursuant to the terms of a collective bargaining agreement in effect with respect to such calendar quarter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pension contribution rate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “pension contribution rate” means the contribution rate that the employer is obligated to pay on behalf of its employees under the terms of a collective bargaining agreement for benefits under a defined benefit plan under such agreement, as such rate is applied to contribution base units (as defined by section 4001(a)(11) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 1301(a)(11)</ref>).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002196">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The amount of collectively bargained defined benefit pension plan contributions allocated to qualified sick leave wages for any calendar quarter shall be the product of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the pension contribution rate (expressed as an hourly rate), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the number of hours for which qualified sick leave wages were provided to employees covered under the collective bargaining agreement described in subparagraph (A)(iii) during the calendar quarter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collectively bargained apprenticeship program contributions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “collectively bargained apprenticeship program contributions” means, with respect to any calendar quarter, contributions which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> are paid or incurred by an employer on behalf of its employees with respect to the calendar quarter to a registered apprenticeship program,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> are made based on an apprenticeship program contribution rate, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> are required to be made pursuant to the terms of a collective bargaining agreement that is in effect with respect to such calendar quarter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Registered apprenticeship program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “registered apprenticeship program” means an apprenticeship registered under the Act of <date date="1937-08-16">August 16, 1937</date> (commonly known as the “National Apprenticeship Act”; <ref>50 Stat. 664</ref>, chapter 663; <ref>29 U.S.C. 50</ref> et seq.) that meets the standards of subpart A of part 29 and part 30 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Apprenticeship program contribution rate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “apprenticeship program contribution rate” means the contribution rate that the employer is obligated to pay on behalf of its employees under the terms of a collective bargaining agreement for benefits under a registered apprenticeship program under such agreement, as such rate is applied to contribution base units (as defined by section 4001(a)(11) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<ref>29 U.S.C. 1301(a)(11)</ref>).<sup>1</sup></p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The amount of collectively bargained apprenticeship program contributions allocated to qualified sick leave wages for any calendar quarter shall be the product of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the apprenticeship program contribution rate (expressed as an hourly rate), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the number of hours for which qualified sick leave wages were provided to employees covered under the collective bargaining agreement described in subparagraph (A)(iii) during the calendar quarter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions and special rules</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable employment taxes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “applicable employment taxes” means the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The taxes imposed under section 3111(b).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> So much of the taxes imposed under section 3221(a) as are attributable to the rate in effect under section 3111(b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wages</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “wages” means wages (as defined in section 3121(a), determined without regard to paragraphs (1) through (22) of section 3121(b)) and compensation (as defined in section 3231(e), determined without regard to the sentence in paragraph (1) thereof which begins “Such term does not include remuneration”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Denial of double benefit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of chapter 1, the gross income of the employer, for the taxable year which includes the last day of any calendar quarter with respect to which a credit is allowed under this section, shall be increased by the amount of such credit. Any wages taken into account in determining the credit allowed under this section shall not be taken into account for purposes of determining the credit allowed under sections 45A, 45P, 45S, 51, 3132, and 3134. In the case of any credit allowed under section 2301 of the CARES Act or section 41 with respect to wages taken into account under this section, the credit allowed under this section shall be reduced by the portion of the credit allowed under such section 2301 or section 41 which is attributable to such wages.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election to not take certain wages into account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This section shall not apply to so much of the qualified sick leave wages paid by an eligible employer as such employer elects (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe) to not take into account for purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain governmental employers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No credit shall be allowed under this section to the Government of the United States or to any agency or instrumentality thereof. The preceding sentence shall not apply to any organization described in section 501(c)(1) and exempt from tax under section 501(a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension of limitation on assessment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Notwithstanding section 6501, the limitation on the time period for the assessment of any amount attributable to a credit claimed under this section shall not expire before the date that is 5 years after the later of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the date on which the original return which includes the calendar quarter with respect to which such credit is determined is filed, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date on which such return is treated as filed under section 6501(b)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with certain programs</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">This section shall not apply to so much of the qualified sick leave wages paid by an eligible employer as are taken into account as payroll costs in connection with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a covered loan under section 7(a)(37) or 7A of the Small Business Act,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a grant under section 324 of the Economic Aid to Hard-Hit Small Businesses, Non-Profits, and Venues Act, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a restaurant revitalization grant under section 5003 of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application where PPP loans not forgiven</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall issue guidance providing that payroll costs paid during the covered period shall not fail to be treated as qualified sick leave wages under this section by reason of subparagraph (A)(i) to the extent that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a covered loan of the taxpayer under section 7(a)(37) of the Small Business Act is not forgiven by reason of a decision under section 7(a)(37)(J) of such Act, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a covered loan of the taxpayer under section 7A of the Small Business Act is not forgiven by reason of a decision under section 7A(g) of such Act.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">Terms used in the preceding sentence which are also used in section 7A(g) or 7(a)(37)(J) of the Small Business Act shall, when applied in connection with either such section, have the same meaning as when used in such section, respectively.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> regulations or other guidance to prevent the avoidance of the purposes of the limitations under this section,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> regulations or other guidance to minimize compliance and record-keeping burdens under this section,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> regulations or other guidance providing for waiver of penalties for failure to deposit amounts in anticipation of the allowance of the credit allowed under this section,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> regulations or other guidance for recapturing the benefit of credits determined under this section in cases where there is a subsequent adjustment to the credit determined under subsection (a),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> regulations or other guidance to ensure that the wages taken into account under this section conform with the paid sick time required to be provided under the Emergency Paid Sick Leave Act,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> regulations or other guidance to permit the advancement of the credit determined under subsection (a), and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> regulations or other guidance with respect to the allocation, reporting, and substantiation of collectively bargained defined benefit pension plan contributions and collectively bargained apprenticeship program contributions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of section</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply only to wages paid with respect to the period beginning on <date date="2021-04-01">April 1, 2021</date>, and ending on <date date="2021-09-30">September 30, 2021</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of deposits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall waive any penalty under section 6656 for any failure to make a deposit of applicable employment taxes if the Secretary determines that such failure was due to the anticipation of the credit allowed under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-discrimination requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No credit shall be allowed under this section to any employer for any calendar quarter if such employer, with respect to the availability of the provision of qualified sick leave wages to which this section otherwise applies for such calendar quarter, discriminates in favor of highly compensated employees (within the meaning of section 414(q)), full-time employees, or employees on the basis of employment tenure with such employer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–2, title IX, § 9641(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 161</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3132.</num>
<heading> Payroll credit for paid family leave</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of an employer, there shall be allowed as a credit against applicable employment taxes for each calendar quarter an amount equal to 100 percent of the qualified family leave wages paid by such employer with respect to such calendar quarter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations and refundability</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wages taken into account</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The amount of qualified family leave wages taken into account under subsection (a), plus any increases under subsection (e), with respect to any individual shall not exceed—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for any day (or portion thereof) for which the individual is paid qualified family leave wages, $200, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the aggregate with respect to all calendar quarters, $12,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Credit limited to certain employment taxes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The credit allowed by subsection (a) with respect to any calendar quarter shall not exceed the applicable employment taxes for such calendar quarter (reduced by any credits allowed under section 3131) on the wages paid with respect to the employment of all employees of the employer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refundability of excess credit</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Credit is refundable</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If the amount of the credit under subsection (a) exceeds the limitation of paragraph (2) for any calendar quarter, such excess shall be treated as an overpayment that shall be refunded under sections 6402(a) and 6413(b).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advancing credit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In anticipation of the credit, including the refundable portion under subparagraph (A), the credit shall be advanced, according to forms and instructions provided by the Secretary, up to an amount calculated under subsection (a), subject to the limits under paragraph (1) and (2), all calculated through the end of the most recent payroll period in the quarter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified family leave wages</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “qualified family leave wages” means wages paid by an employer which would be required to be paid by reason of the Emergency Family and Medical Leave Expansion Act (including the amendments made by such Act) as if such Act (and amendments made by such Act) applied after <date date="2021-03-31">March 31, 2021</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules of application</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of determining whether wages are qualified family leave wages under paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> section 110(a)(2)(A) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 shall be applied by inserting “or any reason for leave described in section 5102(a) of the Families First Coronavirus Response Act, or the employee is seeking or awaiting the results of a diagnostic test for, or a medical diagnosis of, COVID–19 and such employee has been exposed to COVID–19 or the employee’s employer has requested such test or diagnosis, or the employee is obtaining immunization related to COVID–19 or recovering from any injury, disability, illness, or condition related to such immunization” after “public health emergency”, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> section 110(b) of such Act shall be applied—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> without regard to paragraph (1) thereof,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> by striking “after taking leave after such section for 10 days” in paragraph (2)(A) thereof, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> by substituting “$12,000” for “$10,000” in paragraph (2)(B)(ii) thereof.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Leave must meet requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of determining whether wages would be required to be paid under paragraph (1), if an employer fails to comply with any requirement of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 or the Emergency Family and Medical Leave Expansion Act (determined without regard to any time limitation under section 102(a)(1)(F) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1994) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002197">1</ref> with respect to any leave provided for a qualifying need related to a public health emergency (as defined in section 110 of such Act, applied as described in subparagraph (A)(i)), amounts paid by such employer with respect to such leave shall not be taken into account as qualified family leave wages. For purposes of the preceding sentence, an employer which takes an action described in section 105 of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 shall be treated as failing to meet a requirement of such Act.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allowance of credit for certain health plan expenses</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amount of the credit allowed under subsection (a) shall be increased by so much of the employer’s qualified health plan expenses as are properly allocable to the qualified family leave wages for which such credit is so allowed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified health plan expenses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “qualified health plan expenses” means amounts paid or incurred by the employer to provide and maintain a group health plan (as defined in section 5000(b)(1)), but only to the extent that such amounts are excluded from the gross income of employees by reason of section 106(a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation rules</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section, qualified health plan expenses shall be allocated to qualified family leave wages in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe. Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, such allocation shall be treated as properly made if made on the basis of being pro rata among covered employees and pro rata on the basis of periods of coverage (relative to the time periods of leave to which such wages relate).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allowance of credit for amounts paid under certain collectively bargained agreements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The amount of the credit allowed under subsection (a) shall be increased by so much of the sum of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> so much of the employer’s collectively bargained defined benefit pension plan contributions as are properly allocable to the qualified family leave wages for which such credit is so allowed, plus</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> so much of the employer’s collectively bargained apprenticeship program contributions as are properly allocable to the qualified family leave wages for which such credit is so allowed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collectively bargained defined benefit pension plan contributions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “collectively bargained defined benefit pension plan contributions” has the meaning given such term under section 3131(e)(2).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The amount of collectively bargained defined benefit pension plan contributions allocated to qualified family leave wages for any calendar quarter shall be the product of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the pension contribution rate (as defined in section 3131(e)(2)), expressed as an hourly rate, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the number of hours for which qualified family leave wages were provided to employees covered under the collective bargaining agreement described in section 3131(e)(2)(A)(iii) during the calendar quarter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collectively bargained apprenticeship program contributions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “collectively bargained apprenticeship program contributions” has the meaning given such term under section 3131(e)(3).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of this section, the amount of collectively bargained apprenticeship program contributions allocated to qualified family leave wages for any calendar quarter shall be the product of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the apprenticeship contribution rate (as defined in section 3131(e)(3)), expressed as an hourly rate, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the number of hours for which qualified family leave wages were provided to employees covered under the collective bargaining agreement described in section 3131(e)(3)(A)(iii) during the calendar quarter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions and special rules</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable employment taxes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “applicable employment taxes” means the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The taxes imposed under section 3111(b).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> So much of the taxes imposed under section 3221(a) as are attributable to the rate in effect under section 3111(b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wages</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “wages” means wages (as defined in section 3121(a), determined without regard to paragraphs (1) through (22) of section 3121(b)) and compensation (as defined in section 3231(e), determined without regard to the sentence in paragraph (1) thereof which begins “Such term does not include remuneration”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Denial of double benefit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of chapter 1, the gross income of the employer, for the taxable year which includes the last day of any calendar quarter with respect to which a credit is allowed under this section, shall be increased by the amount of such credit. Any wages taken into account in determining the credit allowed under this section shall not be taken into account for purposes of determining the credit allowed under sections 45A, 45P, 45S, 51, 3131, and 3134. In the case of any credit allowed under section 2301 of the CARES Act or section 41 with respect to wages taken into account under this section, the credit allowed under this section shall be reduced by the portion of the credit allowed under such section 2301 or section 41 which is attributable to such wages.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election to not take certain wages into account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This section shall not apply to so much of the qualified family leave wages paid by an eligible employer as such employer elects (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe) to not take into account for purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain governmental employers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No credit shall be allowed under this section to the Government of the United States or to any agency or instrumentality thereof. The preceding sentence shall not apply to any organization described in section 501(c)(1) and exempt from tax under section 501(a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension of limitation on assessment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Notwithstanding section 6501, the limitation on the time period for the assessment of any amount attributable to a credit claimed under this section shall not expire before the date that is 5 years after the later of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the date on which the original return which includes the calendar quarter with respect to which such credit is determined is filed, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date on which such return is treated as filed under section 6501(b)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with certain programs</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">This section shall not apply to so much of the qualified family leave wages paid by an eligible employer as are taken into account as payroll costs in connection with—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a covered loan under section 7(a)(37) or 7A of the Small Business Act,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a grant under section 324 of the Economic Aid to Hard-Hit Small Businesses, Non-Profits, and Venues Act, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a restaurant revitalization grant under section 5003 of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application where PPP loans not forgiven</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall issue guidance providing that payroll costs paid during the covered period shall not fail to be treated as qualified family leave wages under this section by reason of subparagraph (A)(i) to the extent that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a covered loan of the taxpayer under section 7(a)(37) of the Small Business Act is not forgiven by reason of a decision under section 7(a)(37)(J) of such Act, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a covered loan of the taxpayer under section 7A of the Small Business Act is not forgiven by reason of a decision under section 7A(g) of such Act.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">Terms used in the preceding sentence which are also used in section 7A(g) or 7(a)(37)(J) of the Small Business Act shall, when applied in connection with either such section, have the same meaning as when used in such section, respectively.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section, including—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> regulations or other guidance to prevent the avoidance of the purposes of the limitations under this section,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> regulations or other guidance to minimize compliance and record-keeping burdens under this section,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> regulations or other guidance providing for waiver of penalties for failure to deposit amounts in anticipation of the allowance of the credit allowed under this section,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> regulations or other guidance for recapturing the benefit of credits determined under this section in cases where there is a subsequent adjustment to the credit determined under subsection (a),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> regulations or other guidance to ensure that the wages taken into account under this section conform with the paid leave required to be provided under the Emergency Family and Medical Leave Expansion Act (including the amendments made by such Act),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> regulations or other guidance to permit the advancement of the credit determined under subsection (a), and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> regulations or other guidance with respect to the allocation, reporting, and substantiation of collectively bargained defined benefit pension plan contributions and collectively bargained apprenticeship program contributions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of section</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply only to wages paid with respect to the period beginning on <date date="2021-04-01">April 1, 2021</date>, and ending on <date date="2021-09-30">September 30, 2021</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of deposits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall waive any penalty under section 6656 for any failure to make a deposit of applicable employment taxes if the Secretary determines that such failure was due to the anticipation of the credit allowed under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Non-discrimination requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No credit shall be allowed under this section to any employer for any calendar quarter if such employer, with respect to the availability of the provision of qualified family leave wages to which this section otherwise applies for such calendar quarter, discriminates in favor of highly compensated employees (within the meaning of section 414(q)), full-time employees, or employees on the basis of employment tenure with such employer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–2, title IX, § 9641(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 166</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3133.</num>
<heading> Special rule related to tax on employers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The credit allowed by section 3131 and the credit allowed by section 3132 shall each be increased by the amount of the taxes imposed by subsections (a) and (b) of section 3111 and section 3221(a) on qualified sick leave wages, or qualified family leave wages, for which credit is allowed under such section 3131 or 3132 (respectively).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Denial of double benefit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For denial of double benefit with respect to the credit increase under subsection (a), see sections 3131(f)(3) and 3132(f)(3).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–2, title IX, § 9641(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 171</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 3134.</num>
<heading> Employee retention credit for employers subject to closure due to COVID–19</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of an eligible employer, there shall be allowed as a credit against applicable employment taxes for each calendar quarter an amount equal to 70 percent of the qualified wages with respect to each employee of such employer for such calendar quarter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations and refundability</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wages taken into account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The amount of qualified wages with respect to any employee which may be taken into account under subsection (a) by the eligible employer for any calendar quarter shall not exceed $10,000.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recovery startup businesses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of an eligible employer which is a recovery startup business (as defined in subsection (c)(5)), the amount of the credit allowed under subsection (a) (after application of subparagraph (A)) for any calendar quarter shall not exceed $50,000.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Credit limited to employment taxes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The credit allowed by subsection (a) with respect to any calendar quarter shall not exceed the applicable employment taxes (reduced by any credits allowed under sections 3131 and 3132) on the wages paid with respect to the employment of all the employees of the eligible employer for such calendar quarter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refundability of excess credit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the amount of the credit under subsection (a) exceeds the limitation of paragraph (2) for any calendar quarter, such excess shall be treated as an overpayment that shall be refunded under sections 6402(a) and 6413(b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable employment taxes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “applicable employment taxes” means the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The taxes imposed under section 3111(b).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> So much of the taxes imposed under section 3221(a) as are attributable to the rate in effect under section 3111(b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible employer</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “eligible employer” means any employer—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> which was carrying on a trade or business during the calendar quarter for which the credit is determined under subsection (a), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to any calendar quarter, for which—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the operation of the trade or business described in clause (i) is fully or partially suspended during the calendar quarter due to orders from an appropriate governmental authority limiting commerce, travel, or group meetings (for commercial, social, religious, or other purposes) due to the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID–19),</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the gross receipts (within the meaning of section 448(c)) of such employer for such calendar quarter are less than 80 percent of the gross receipts of such employer for the same calendar quarter in calendar year 2019, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the employer is a recovery startup business (as defined in paragraph (5)).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent3 firstIndent-1">  With respect to any employer for any calendar quarter, if such employer was not in existence as of the beginning of the same calendar quarter in calendar year 2019, clause (ii)(II) shall be applied by substituting “2020” for “2019”.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election to use alternative quarter</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">At the election of the employer—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> subparagraph (A)(ii)(II) shall be applied—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> by substituting “for the immediately preceding calendar quarter” for “for such calendar quarter”, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> by substituting “the corresponding calendar quarter in calendar year 2019” for “the same calendar quarter in calendar year 2019”, and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the last sentence of subparagraph (A) shall be applied by substituting “the corresponding calendar quarter in calendar year 2019” for “the same calendar quarter in calendar year 2019”.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">An election under this subparagraph shall be made at such time and in such manner as the Secretary shall prescribe.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax-exempt organizations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In the case of an organization which is described in section 501(c) and exempt from tax under section 501(a)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> clauses (i) and (ii)(I) of subparagraph (A) shall apply to all operations of such organization, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any reference in this section to gross receipts shall be treated as a reference to gross receipts within the meaning of section 6033.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified wages</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “qualified wages” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of an eligible employer for which the average number of full-time employees (within the meaning of section 4980H) employed by such eligible employer during 2019 was greater than 500, wages paid by such eligible employer with respect to which an employee is not providing services due to circumstances described in subclause (I) or (II) of paragraph (2)(A)(ii), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of an eligible employer for which the average number of full-time employees (within the meaning of section 4980H) employed by such eligible employer during 2019 was not greater than 500—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> with respect to an eligible employer described in subclause (I) of paragraph (2)(A)(ii), wages paid by such eligible employer with respect to an employee during any period described in such clause, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> with respect to an eligible employer described in subclause (II) of such paragraph, wages paid by such eligible employer with respect to an employee during such quarter.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for employers not in existence in 2019</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of any employer that was not in existence in 2019, subparagraph (A) shall be applied by substituting “2020” for “2019” each place it appears.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Severely financially distressed employers</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Notwithstanding subparagraph (A)(i), in the case of a severely financially distressed employer, the term “qualified wages” means wages paid by such employer with respect to an employee during any calendar quarter.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The term “severely financially distressed employer” means an eligible employer as defined in paragraph (2), determined by substituting “less than 10 percent” for “less than 80 percent” in subparagraph (A)(ii)(II) thereof.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “qualified wages” shall not include any wages taken into account under sections 41, 45A, 45P, 45S, 51, 1396, 3131, and 3132.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Wages</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “wages” means wages (as defined in section 3121(a)) and compensation (as defined in section 3231(e)). For purposes of the preceding sentence, in the case of any organization or entity described in subsection (f)(2), wages as defined in section 3121(a) shall be determined without regard to paragraphs (5), (6), (7), (10), and (13) of section 3121(b) (except with respect to services performed in a penal institution by an inmate thereof).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allowance for certain health plan expenses</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Such term shall include amounts paid by the eligible employer to provide and maintain a group health plan (as defined in section 5000(b)(1)), but only to the extent that such amounts are excluded from the gross income of employees by reason of section 106(a).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allocation rules</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">For purposes of this section, amounts treated as wages under clause (i) shall be treated as paid with respect to any employee (and with respect to any period) to the extent that such amounts are properly allocable to such employee (and to such period) in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe. Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, such allocation shall be treated as properly made if made on the basis of being pro rata among periods of coverage.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recovery startup business</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “recovery startup business” means any employer—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> which began carrying on any trade or business after <date date="2020-02-15">February 15, 2020</date>, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for which the average annual gross receipts of such employer (as determined under rules similar to the rules under section 448(c)(3)) for the 3-taxable-year period ending with the taxable year which precedes the calendar quarter for which the credit is determined under subsection (a) does not exceed $1,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other terms</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any term used in this section which is also used in this chapter or chapter 22 shall have the same meaning as when used in such chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Aggregation rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">All persons treated as a single employer under subsection (a) or (b) of section 52, or subsection (m) or (<i>o</i>) of section 414, shall be treated as one employer for purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain rules to apply</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, rules similar to the rules of sections 51(i)(1) and 280C(a) shall apply.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain governmental employers</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This credit shall not apply to the Government of the United States, the government of any State or political subdivision thereof, or any agency or instrumentality of any of the foregoing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any organization described in section 501(c)(1) and exempt from tax under section 501(a), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> any entity described in paragraph (1) if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such entity is a college or university, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the principal purpose or function of such entity is providing medical or hospital care.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">In the case of any entity described in subparagraph (B), such entity shall be treated as satisfying the requirements of subsection (c)(2)(A)(i).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election to not take certain wages into account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply to so much of the qualified wages paid by an eligible employer as such employer elects (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe) to not take into account for purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with certain programs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">This section shall not apply to so much of the qualified wages paid by an eligible employer as are taken into account as payroll costs in connection with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a covered loan under section 7(a)(37) or 7A of the Small Business Act,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a grant under section 324 of the Economic Aid to Hard-Hit Small Businesses, Non-Profits, and Venues Act, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a restaurant revitalization grant under section 5003 of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application where PPP loans not forgiven</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall issue guidance providing that payroll costs paid during the covered period shall not fail to be treated as qualified wages under this section by reason of paragraph (1) to the extent that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a covered loan of the taxpayer under section 7(a)(37) of the Small Business Act is not forgiven by reason of a decision under section 7(a)(37)(J) of such Act, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a covered loan of the taxpayer under section 7A of the Small Business Act is not forgiven by reason of a decision under section 7A(g) of such Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">Terms used in the preceding sentence which are also used in section 7A(g) or 7(a)(37)(J) of the Small Business Act shall, when applied in connection with either such section, have the same meaning as when used in such section, respectively.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Third party payors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any credit allowed under this section shall be treated as a credit described in section 3511(d)(2).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advance payments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), no advance payment of the credit under subsection (a) shall be allowed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Advance payments to small employers</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Under rules provided by the Secretary, an eligible employer for which the average number of full-time employees (within the meaning of section 4980H) employed by such eligible employer during 2019 was not greater than 500 may elect for any calendar quarter to receive an advance payment of the credit under subsection (a) for such quarter in an amount not to exceed 70 percent of the average quarterly wages paid by the employer in calendar year 2019.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for seasonal employers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of any employer who employs seasonal workers (as defined in section 45R(d)(5)(B)), the employer may elect to apply subparagraph (A) by substituting “the wages for the calendar quarter in 2019 which corresponds to the calendar quarter to which the election relates” for “the average quarterly wages paid by the employer in calendar year 2019”.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for employers not in existence in 2019</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of any employer that was not in existence in 2019, subparagraphs (A) and (B) shall each be applied by substituting “2020” for “2019” each place it appears.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reconciliation of credit with advance payments</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The amount of credit which would (but for this subsection) be allowed under this section shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the aggregate payment allowed to the taxpayer under paragraph (2). Any failure to so reduce the credit shall be treated as arising out of a mathematical or clerical error and assessed according to section 6213(b)(1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Excess advance payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If the advance payments to a taxpayer under paragraph (2) for a calendar quarter exceed the credit allowed by this section (determined without regard to subparagraph (A)), the tax imposed under section 3111(b) or so much of the tax imposed under section 3221(a) as is attributable to the rate in effect under section 3111(b) (whichever is applicable) for the calendar quarter shall be increased by the amount of such excess.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of deposits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall waive any penalty under section 6656 for any failure to make a deposit of any applicable employment taxes if the Secretary determines that such failure was due to the reasonable anticipation of the credit allowed under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension of limitation on assessment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Notwithstanding section 6501, the limitation on the time period for the assessment of any amount attributable to a credit claimed under this section shall not expire before the date that is 5 years after the later of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the date on which the original return which includes the calendar quarter with respect to which such credit is determined is filed, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the date on which such return is treated as filed under section 6501(b)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(m)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations and guidance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall issue such forms, instructions, regulations, and other guidance as are necessary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to allow the advance payment of the credit under subsection (a) as provided in subsection (j)(2), subject to the limitations provided in this section, based on such information as the Secretary shall require,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with respect to the application of the credit under subsection (a) to third party payors (including professional employer organizations, certified professional employer organizations, or agents under section 3504), including regulations or guidance allowing such payors to submit documentation necessary to substantiate the eligible employer status of employers that use such payors, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to prevent the avoidance of the purposes of the limitations under this section, including through the leaseback of employees.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Any forms, instructions, regulations, or other guidance described in paragraph (2) shall require the customer to be responsible for the accounting of the credit and for any liability for improperly claimed credits and shall require the certified professional employer organization or other third party payor to accurately report such tax credits based on the information provided by the customer.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(n)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall only apply to wages paid after <date date="2021-06-30">June 30, 2021</date>, and before <date date="2021-10-01">October 1, 2021</date> (or, in the case of wages paid by an eligible employer which is a recovery startup business, <date date="2022-01-01">January 1, 2022</date>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–2, title IX, § 9651(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 177</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. H, title VI, § 80604(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1341</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>