<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 92—</num>
<heading>POWERS AND DUTIES OF THE JOINT COMMITTEE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 8021.</num>
<heading> Powers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> To obtain data and inspect income returns</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2 fontsize7">For powers of the Joint Committee to obtain and inspect income returns, see section 6103(f).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relating to hearings and sessions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Joint Committee, or any subcommittee thereof, is authorized—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> To hold</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To hold hearings and to sit and act at such places and times;</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> To require attendance of witnesses and production of books</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To require by subpoena (to be issued under the signature of the chairman or vice chairman) or otherwise the attendance of such witnesses and the production of such books, papers, and documents;</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> To administer oaths</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To administer such oaths; and</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> To take testimony</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To take such testimony;</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">as it deems advisable.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> To procure printing and binding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Joint Committee, or any subcommittee thereof, is authorized to have such printing and binding done as it deems advisable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> To make expenditures</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Joint Committee, or any subcommittee thereof, is authorized to make such expenditures as it deems advisable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Joint Committee shall review all requests (other than requests by the chairman or ranking member of a committee or subcommittee) for investigations of the Internal Revenue Service by the Government Accountability Office, and approve such requests when appropriate, with a view towards eliminating overlapping investigations, ensuring that the Government Accountability Office has the capacity to handle the investigation, and ensuring that investigations focus on areas of primary importance to tax administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 927</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1907(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1835</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1018(s)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3586</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title IV, § 4001(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 783</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–311, title III, § 321(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-04">Oct. 4, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1182</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–135, title IV, § 412(rr)(5)</ref>, <date date="2005-12-21">Dec. 21, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2640</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(b)(56)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8022.</num>
<heading> Duties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">It shall be the duty of the Joint Committee—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operation and effects of law</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To investigate the operation and effects of the Federal system of internal revenue taxes;</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administration</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To investigate the administration of such taxes by the Internal Revenue Service or any executive department, establishment, or agency charged with their administration; and</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other investigations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To make such other investigations in respect of such system of taxes as the Joint Committee may deem necessary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Simplification of law</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investigation of methods</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To investigate measures and methods for the simplification of such taxes, particularly the income tax; and</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publication of proposals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">To publish, from time to time, for public examination and analysis, proposed measures and methods for the simplification of such taxes.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> To report, from time to time, to the Committee on Finance and the Committee on Ways and Means, and, in its discretion, to the Senate or House of Representatives, or both, the results of its investigations, together with such recommendations as it may deem advisable.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Subject to amounts specifically appropriated to carry out this subparagraph, to report, at least once each Congress, to the Committee on Finance and the Committee on Ways and Means on the overall state of the Federal tax system, together with recommendations with respect to possible simplification proposals and other matters relating to the administration of the Federal tax system as it may deem advisable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cross reference</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2 fontsize7">For duties of the Joint Committee relating to refunds of income and estate taxes, see section 6405.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 927</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title IV, § 4002(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 784</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–311, title III, § 321(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-04">Oct. 4, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1182</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(b)(57)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 8023.</num>
<heading> Additional powers to obtain data</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Securing of data</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Joint Committee or the Chief of Staff of the Joint Committee, upon approval of the Chairman or Vice Chairman, is authorized to secure directly from the Internal Revenue Service, or the office of the Chief Counsel for the Internal Revenue Service, or directly from any executive department, board, bureau, agency, independent establishment, or instrumentality of the Government, information, suggestions, rulings, data, estimates, and statistics, for the purpose of making investigations, reports, and studies relating to internal revenue taxation. In the investigation by the Joint Committee on Taxation of the administration of the internal revenue taxes by the Internal Revenue Service, the Chief of Staff of the Joint Committee on Taxation is authorized to secure directly from the Internal Revenue Service such tax returns, or copies of tax returns, and other relevant information, as the Chief of Staff deems necessary for such investigation, and the Internal Revenue Service is authorized and directed to furnish such tax returns and information to the Chief of Staff together with a brief report, with respect to each return, as to any action taken or proposed to be taken by the Service as a result of any audit of the return.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Furnishing of data</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Internal Revenue Service, the office of the Chief Counsel for the Internal Revenue Service, executive departments, boards, bureaus, agencies, independent establishments, and instrumentalities are authorized and directed to furnish such information, suggestions, rulings, data, estimates, and statistics directly to the Joint Committee or to the Chief of Staff of the Joint Committee, upon request made pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of subsections (a) and (b)</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsections (a) and (b) shall be applied in accordance with their provisions without regard to any reorganization plan becoming effective on, before, or after the date of the enactment of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 928</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–368, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1959-09-22">Sept. 22, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 648</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XII, § 1210(c)</ref>, title XIX, § 1907(a)(4), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1711</ref>, 1835.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>