<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 63—</num>
<heading>ASSESSMENT</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter A—</num>
<heading>In General</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6201.</num>
<heading> Assessment authority</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized and required to make the inquiries, determinations, and assessments of all taxes (including interest, additional amounts, additions to the tax, and assessable penalties) imposed by this title, or accruing under any former internal revenue law, which have not been duly paid by stamp at the time and in the manner provided by law. Such authority shall extend to and include the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxes shown on return</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall assess all taxes determined by the taxpayer or by the Secretary as to which returns or lists (or payments under section 6225(c)(2)(B)(i)) are made under this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Unpaid taxes payable by stamp</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted stamps</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Whenever any article upon which a tax is required to be paid by means of a stamp is sold or removed for sale or use by the manufacturer thereof or whenever any transaction or act upon which a tax is required to be paid by means of a stamp occurs without the use of the proper stamp, it shall be the duty of the Secretary, upon such information as he can obtain, to estimate the amount of tax which has been omitted to be paid and to make assessment therefor upon the person or persons the Secretary determines to be liable for such tax.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Check or money order not duly paid</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In any case in which a check or money order received under authority of section 6311 as payment for stamps is not duly paid, the unpaid amount may be immediately assessed as if it were a tax imposed by this title, due at the time of such receipt, from the person who tendered such check or money order.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Erroneous income tax prepayment credits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If on any return or claim for refund of income taxes under subtitle A there is an overstatement of the credit for income tax withheld at the source, or of the amount paid as estimated income tax, the amount so overstated which is allowed against the tax shown on the return or which is allowed as a credit or refund may be assessed by the Secretary in the same manner as in the case of a mathematical or clerical error appearing upon the return, except that the provisions of section 6213(b)(2) (relating to abatement of mathematical or clerical error assessments) shall not apply with regard to any assessment under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain orders of criminal restitution</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall assess and collect the amount of restitution under an order pursuant to <ref>section 3556 of title 18</ref>, United States Code, for failure to pay any tax imposed under this title in the same manner as if such amount were such tax.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time of assessment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An assessment of an amount of restitution under an order described in subparagraph (A) shall not be made before all appeals of such order are concluded and the right to make all such appeals has expired.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restriction on challenge of assessment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The amount of such restitution may not be challenged by the person against whom assessed on the basis of the existence or amount of the underlying tax liability in any proceeding authorized under this title (including in any suit or proceeding in court permitted under section 7422).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount not to be assessed</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Estimated income tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No unpaid amount of estimated income tax required to be paid under section 6654 or 6655 shall be assessed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal unemployment tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No unpaid amount of Federal unemployment tax for any calendar quarter or other period of a calendar year, computed as provided in section 6157, shall be assessed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Compensation of child</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any income tax under chapter 1 assessed against a child, to the extent attributable to amounts includible in the gross income of the child, and not of the parent, solely by reason of section 73(a), shall, if not paid by the child, for all purposes be considered as having also been properly assessed against the parent.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required reasonable verification of information returns</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any court proceeding, if a taxpayer asserts a reasonable dispute with respect to any item of income reported on an information return filed with the Secretary under subpart B or C of part III of subchapter A of chapter 61 by a third party and the taxpayer has fully cooperated with the Secretary (including providing, within a reasonable period of time, access to and inspection of all witnesses, information, and documents within the control of the taxpayer as reasonably requested by the Secretary), the Secretary shall have the burden of producing reasonable and probative information concerning such deficiency in addition to such information return.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deficiency proceedings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2 fontsize7">For special rules applicable to deficiencies of income, estate, gift, and certain excise taxes, see subchapter B.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 767</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–44, title VIII, § 809(d)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="1965-06-21">June 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 168</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–53, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1969-08-07">Aug. 7, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 92</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–172, title I, § 101(j)(38)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 530</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–258, title II, § 207(d)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1970-05-21">May 21, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 248</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–406, title II, § 1016(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 929</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–12, title II, § 204(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1975-03-29">Mar. 29, 1975</date>, <ref>89 Stat. 31</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XII, § 1206(c)(2)</ref>, title XIII, § 1307(d)(2)(D), title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1704</ref>, 1727, 1834; <ref>Pub. L. 97–424, title V, § 515(b)(6)(E)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-06">Jan. 6, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2182</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–76, title II, § 231(b)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1983-08-12">Aug. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>97 Stat. 429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title IV</ref>, §§ 412(b)(5), 474(r)(32), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 792</ref>, 845; <ref>Pub. L. 100–203, title X, § 10301(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1330–429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1015(r)(1)</ref>, title VII, § 7106(c)(2), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3572</ref>, 3773; <ref>Pub. L. 104–168, title VI, § 602(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-07-30">July 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1463</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–237, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-08-16">Aug. 16, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2497</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title II, § 203(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1176</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6202.</num>
<heading> Establishment by regulations of mode or time of assessment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the mode or time for the assessment of any internal revenue tax (including interest, additional amounts, additions to the tax, and assessable penalties) is not otherwise provided for, the Secretary may establish the same by regulations.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 768</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6203.</num>
<heading> Method of assessment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The assessment shall be made by recording the liability of the taxpayer in the office of the Secretary in accordance with rules or regulations prescribed by the Secretary. Upon request of the taxpayer, the Secretary shall furnish the taxpayer a copy of the record of the assessment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 768</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6204.</num>
<heading> Supplemental assessments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may, at any time within the period prescribed for assessment, make a supplemental assessment whenever it is ascertained that any assessment is imperfect or incomplete in any material respect.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions on assessment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2 fontsize7">For restrictions on assessment of deficiencies in income, estate, gift, and certain excise taxes, see section 6213.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 768</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–406, title II, § 1016(a)(27)</ref>, <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 932</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6205.</num>
<heading> Special rules applicable to certain employment taxes</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment of tax</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If less than the correct amount of tax imposed by section 3101, 3111, 3201, 3221, or 3402 is paid with respect to any payment of wages or compensation, proper adjustments, with respect to both the tax and the amount to be deducted, shall be made, without interest, in such manner and at such times as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States as employer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, in the case of remuneration received from the United States or a wholly-owned instrumentality thereof during any calendar year, each head of a Federal agency or instrumentality who makes a return pursuant to section 3122 and each agent, designated by the head of a Federal agency or instrumentality, who makes a return pursuant to such section shall be deemed a separate employer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guam or American Samoa as employer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, in the case of remuneration received during any calendar year from the Government of Guam, the Government of American Samoa, a political subdivision of either, or any instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing which is wholly owned thereby, the Governor of Guam, the Governor of American Samoa, and each agent designated by either who makes a return pursuant to section 3125 shall be deemed a separate employer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> District of Columbia as employer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, in the case of remuneration received during any calendar year from the District of Columbia or any instrumentality which is wholly owned thereby, the Mayor of the District of Columbia and each agent designated by him who makes a return pursuant to section 3125 shall be deemed a separate employer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> States and political subdivisions as employer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, in the case of remuneration received from a State or any political subdivision thereof (or any instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing which is wholly owned thereby) during any calendar year, each head of an agency or instrumentality, and each agent designated by either, who makes a return pursuant to section 3125 shall be deemed a separate employer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Underpayments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If less than the correct amount of tax imposed by section 3101, 3111, 3201, 3221, or 3402 is paid or deducted with respect to any payment of wages or compensation and the underpayment cannot be adjusted under subsection (a) of this section, the amount of the underpayment shall be assessed and collected in such manner and at such times (subject to the statute of limitations properly applicable thereto) as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 768</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–778, title I, § 103(r)(1)</ref>, <date date="1960-09-13">Sept. 13, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 940</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–97, title III, § 317(d)</ref>, <date date="1965-07-30">July 30, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 389</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(a)(13)</ref>, (b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1825</ref>, 1834; <ref>Pub. L. 99–272, title XIII, § 13205(a)(2)(D)</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 315</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6206.</num>
<heading> Special rules applicable to excessive claims under certain sections</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any portion of a refund made under section 6416(a)(4) and any portion of a payment made under section 6420, 6421, or 6427 which constitutes an excessive amount (as defined in section 6675(b)), and any civil penalty provided by section 6675, may be assessed and collected as if it were a tax imposed by section 4081 (with respect to refunds under section 6416(a)(4) and payments under sections 6420 and 6421), or 4041 or 4081 (with respect to payments under section 6427) and as if the person who made the claim were liable for such tax. The period for assessing any such portion, and for assessing any such penalty, shall be 3 years from the last day prescribed for the filing of the claim under section 6416(a)(4), 6420, 6421, or 6427, as the case may be.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Apr. 2, 1956, ch. 160, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 90</ref>; amended <ref>June 29, 1956, ch. 462</ref>, title II, § 208(d)(1), <ref>70 Stat. 396</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–44, title II, § 202(c)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="1965-06-21">June 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 139</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–258, title II, § 207(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="1970-05-21">May 21, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 248</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–424, title V, § 515(b)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-06">Jan. 6, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2181</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–203, title X, § 10502(d)(5)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1330–444</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–66, title XIII, § 13242(d)(14)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 524</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–357, title VIII, § 853(d)(2)(F)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1613</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–59, title XI, § 11163(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1974</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6207.</num>
<heading> Cross references</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For prohibition of suits to restrain assessment of any tax, see section 7421.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For prohibition of assessment of taxes against insolvent banks, see section 7507.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For assessment where property subject to tax has been sold in a distraint proceeding without the tax having been assessed prior to such sale, see section 6342.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For assessment with respect to taxes required to be paid by chapter 52, see section 5703.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> For assessment in case of distilled spirits removed from place where distilled and not deposited in bonded warehouse, see section 5006(c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> For period of limitation upon assessment, see chapter 66.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 769</ref>, § 6206; renumbered § 6207, <ref>Apr. 2, 1956, ch. 160, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 90</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 85–859, title II, § 204(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1428</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(a)(14)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1825</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter B—</num>
<heading>Deficiency Procedures in the Case of Income, Estate, Gift, and Certain Excise Taxes</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6211.</num>
<heading> Definition of a deficiency</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this title in the case of income, estate, and gift taxes imposed by subtitles A and B and excise taxes imposed by chapters 41, 42, 43, and 44 the term “deficiency” means the amount by which the tax imposed by subtitle A or B, or chapter 41, 42, 43, or 44 exceeds the excess of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the sum of</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the amount shown as the tax by the taxpayer upon his return, if a return was made by the taxpayer and an amount was shown as the tax by the taxpayer thereon, plus</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amounts previously assessed (or collected without assessment) as a deficiency, over—</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the amount of rebates, as defined in subsection (b)(2), made.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules for application of subsection (a)</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The tax imposed by subtitle A and the tax shown on the return shall both be determined without regard to payments on account of estimated tax, without regard to the credit under section 31, without regard to the credit under section 33, and without regard to any credits resulting from the collection of amounts assessed under section 6851 or 6852 (relating to termination assessments).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The term “rebate” means so much of an abatement, credit, refund, or other repayment, as was made on the ground that the tax imposed by subtitle A or B or chapter 41, 42, 43, or 44 was less than the excess of the amount specified in subsection (a)(1) over the rebates previously made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The computation by the Secretary, pursuant to section 6014, of the tax imposed by chapter 1 shall be considered as having been made by the taxpayer and the tax so computed considered as shown by the taxpayer upon his return.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> For purposes of subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any excess of the sum of the credits allowable under sections 21 by reason of subsection (g) thereof, 24 by reason of subsections (d) and (i)(1) thereof, 25A by reason of subsection (i) thereof, 32, 34, 35, 36, 36B, 6428, 6428A, 6428B, and 7527A over the tax imposed by subtitle A (determined without regard to such credits), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any excess of the sum of such credits as shown by the taxpayer on his return over the amount shown as the tax by the taxpayer on such return (determined without regard to such credits),</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall be taken into account as negative amounts of tax.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with subchapter C</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In determining the amount of any deficiency for purposes of this subchapter, adjustments to partnership-related items shall be made only as provided in subchapter C.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 770</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–44, title VIII, § 809(d)(5)(A)</ref>, <date date="1965-06-21">June 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 168</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–368, title I, § 102(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="1966-03-15">Mar. 15, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 64</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–172, title I, § 101(f)(1)</ref>, (j)(39), <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 524</ref>, 530; <ref>Pub. L. 93–406, title II, § 1016(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 929</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XII, § 1204(c)(4)</ref>, title XIII, § 1307(d)(2)(E), (F)(i), title XVI, § 1605(b)(4), title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1698</ref>, 1728, 1754, 1834; <ref>Pub. L. 96–223, title I, § 101(f)(1)(A)</ref>, (B), (2), (3), <date date="1980-04-02">Apr. 2, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 252</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title IV, § 474(r)(33)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 845</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–203, title X, § 10713(b)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1330–470</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1941(b)(2)(B)(i)</ref>, (ii), (C), (D), <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1323</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1015(r)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3572</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–34, title XII, § 1231(b)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1023</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title VI, § 6012(f)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 819</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(7) [title III, § 314(a)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–643; <ref>Pub. L. 109–432, div. A, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 2954</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–172, § 11(a)(35)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-29">Dec. 29, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2487</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–185, title I, § 101(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-02-13">Feb. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 615</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–289, div. C, title I, § 3011(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2891</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–5, div. B, title I</ref>, §§ 1001(e)(1), 1004(b)(7), 1201(a)(3)(B), (b)(2), 1531(c)(4), <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 312</ref>, 314, 334, 360; <ref>Pub. L. 111–148, title I, § 1401(d)(3)</ref>, as added title X, §§ 10105(d), 10909(b)(2)(N), (c), <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 906</ref>, 1023; <ref>Pub. L. 111–312, title I, § 101(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-17">Dec. 17, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3298</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(5)(B)</ref>, (8)(B), (112)(B), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4037</ref>, 4038, 4054; <ref>Pub. L. 115–97, title I, § 13404(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 2138</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title I</ref>, §§ 101(<i>l</i>)(17), 106(a), title II, § 201(c)(1), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1165</ref>, 1170, 1172; <ref>Pub. L. 116–136, div. A, title II, § 2201(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2020-03-27">Mar. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 337</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. N, title II, § 272(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1971</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–2, title IX</ref>, §§ 9601(c)(1), 9611(b)(4)(B), 9631(c)(1), <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 143</ref>, 150, 160; <ref>Pub. L. 117–328, div. T, title I, § 103(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 5285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6212.</num>
<heading> Notice of deficiency</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary determines that there is a deficiency in respect of any tax imposed by subtitles A or B or chapter 41, 42, 43, or 44 he is authorized to send notice of such deficiency to the taxpayer by certified mail or registered mail. Such notice shall include a notice to the taxpayer of the taxpayer’s right to contact a local office of the taxpayer advocate and the location and phone number of the appropriate office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Address for notice of deficiency</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Income and gift taxes and certain excise taxes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the absence of notice to the Secretary under section 6903 of the existence of a fiduciary relationship, notice of a deficiency in respect of a tax imposed by subtitle A, chapter 12, chapter 41, chapter 42, chapter 43, or chapter 44 if mailed to the taxpayer at his last known address, shall be sufficient for purposes of subtitle A, chapter 12, chapter 41, chapter 42, chapter 43, chapter 44, and this chapter even if such taxpayer is deceased, or is under a legal disability, or, in the case of a corporation, has terminated its existence.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint income tax return</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a joint income tax return filed by husband and wife, such notice of deficiency may be a single joint notice, except that if the Secretary has been notified by either spouse that separate residences have been established, then, in lieu of the single joint notice, a duplicate original of the joint notice shall be sent by certified mail or registered mail to each spouse at his last known address.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Estate tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the absence of notice to the Secretary under section 6903 of the existence of a fiduciary relationship, notice of a deficiency in respect of a tax imposed by chapter 11, if addressed in the name of the decedent or other person subject to liability and mailed to his last known address, shall be sufficient for purposes of chapter 11 and of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Further deficiency letters restricted</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Secretary has mailed to the taxpayer a notice of deficiency as provided in subsection (a), and the taxpayer files a petition with the Tax Court within the time prescribed in section 6213(a), the Secretary shall have no right to determine any additional deficiency of income tax for the same taxable year, of gift tax for the same calendar year, of estate tax in respect of the taxable estate of the same decedent, of chapter 41 tax for the same taxable year, of chapter 43 tax for the same taxable year, of chapter 44 tax for the same taxable year, of section 4940 tax for the same taxable year, or of chapter 42 tax, (other than under section 4940) with respect to any act (or failure to act) to which such petition relates, except in the case of fraud, and except as provided in section 6214(a) (relating to assertion of greater deficiencies before the Tax Court), in section 6213(b)(1) (relating to mathematical or clerical errors), in section 6851 or 6852 (relating to termination assessments), or in section 6861(c) (relating to the making of jeopardy assessments).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cross references</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2 fontsize7">For assessment as a deficiency notwithstanding the prohibition of further deficiency letters, in the case of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent3 fontsize7">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Deficiency attributable to change of treatment with respect to itemized deductions, see section 63(e)(3).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 fontsize7">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Deficiency attributable to gain on involuntary conversion, see section 1033(a)(2)(C) and (D).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 fontsize7">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Deficiency attributable to activities not engaged in for profit, see section 183(e)(4).</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent2 fontsize7">For provisions allowing determination of tax in title 11 cases, see <ref>section 505(a) of title 11</ref> of the United States Code.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to rescind notice of deficiency with taxpayer’s consent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may, with the consent of the taxpayer, rescind any notice of deficiency mailed to the taxpayer. Any notice so rescinded shall not be treated as a notice of deficiency for purposes of subsection (c)(1) (relating to further deficiency letters restricted), section 6213(a) (relating to restrictions applicable to deficiencies; petition to Tax Court), and section 6512(a) (relating to limitations in case of petition to Tax Court), and the taxpayer shall have no right to file a petition with the Tax Court based on such notice. Nothing in this subsection shall affect any suspension of the running of any period of limitations during any period during which the rescinded notice was outstanding.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 770</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–866, title I</ref>, §§ 76, 89(b), <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1661</ref>, 1665; <ref>Pub. L. 88–272, title I, § 112(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1964-02-26">Feb. 26, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 24</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–172, title I, § 101(f)(2)</ref>, (j)(40), (41), <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 524</ref>, 530; <ref>Pub. L. 91–614, title I, § 102(d)(5)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1842</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–406, title II, § 1016(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 930</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title II, § 214(b)</ref>, title XII, §§ 1204(c)(5), 1206(c)(3), title XIII, § 1307(d)(2)(F)(ii), (G), title XVI, § 1605(b)(5), title XIX, §§ 1901(b)(31)(C), (37)(C), 1906(b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1549</ref>, 1698, 1704, 1728, 1754, 1800, 1803, 1834; <ref>Pub. L. 95–30, title I, § 101(d)(15)</ref>, <date date="1977-05-23">May 23, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 134</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–600, title IV, § 405(c)(5)</ref>, title VII, § 701(t)(3)(C), <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2871</ref>, 2912; <ref>Pub. L. 96–223, title I, § 101(f)(1)(C)</ref>, (4), (5), <date date="1980-04-02">Apr. 2, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 252</ref>, 253; <ref>Pub. L. 96–589, § 6(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3408</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–34, title IV, § 442(d)(4)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 323</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title I, § 104(b)(17)</ref>, title XV, § 1562(a), <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2106</ref>, 2761; <ref>Pub. L. 100–203, title X, § 10713(b)(2)(C)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1330–470</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1941(b)(2)(B)(iii)</ref>, (E), (F), <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1323</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1015(m)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3572</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–34, title III, § 312(d)(12)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 840</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title I, § 1102(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 703</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6213.</num>
<heading> Restrictions applicable to deficiencies; petition to Tax Court</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time for filing petition and restriction on assessment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Within 90 days, or 150 days if the notice is addressed to a person outside the United States, after the notice of deficiency authorized in section 6212 is mailed (not counting Saturday, Sunday, or a legal holiday in the District of Columbia as the last day), the taxpayer may file a petition with the Tax Court for a redetermination of the deficiency. Except as otherwise provided in section 6851, 6852, or 6861 no assessment of a deficiency in respect of any tax imposed by subtitle A, or B, chapter 41, 42, 43, or 44 and no levy or proceeding in court for its collection shall be made, begun, or prosecuted until such notice has been mailed to the taxpayer, nor until the expiration of such 90-day or 150-day period, as the case may be, nor, if a petition has been filed with the Tax Court, until the decision of the Tax Court has become final. Notwithstanding the provisions of section 7421(a), the making of such assessment or the beginning of such proceeding or levy during the time such prohibition is in force may be enjoined by a proceeding in the proper court, including the Tax Court, and a refund may be ordered by such court of any amount collected within the period during which the Secretary is prohibited from collecting by levy or through a proceeding in court under the provisions of this subsection. The Tax Court shall have no jurisdiction to enjoin any action or proceeding or order any refund under this subsection unless a timely petition for a redetermination of the deficiency has been filed and then only in respect of the deficiency that is the subject of such petition. Any petition filed with the Tax Court on or before the last date specified for filing such petition by the Secretary in the notice of deficiency shall be treated as timely filed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions to restrictions on assessment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessments arising out of mathematical or clerical errors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the taxpayer is notified that, on account of a mathematical or clerical error appearing on the return, an amount of tax in excess of that shown on the return is due, and that an assessment of the tax has been or will be made on the basis of what would have been the correct amount of tax but for the mathematical or clerical error, such notice shall not be considered as a notice of deficiency for the purposes of subsection (a) (prohibiting assessment and collection until notice of the deficiency has been mailed), or of section 6212(c)(1) (restricting further deficiency letters), or of section 6512(a) (prohibiting credits or refunds after petition to the Tax Court), and the taxpayer shall have no right to file a petition with the Tax Court based on such notice, nor shall such assessment or collection be prohibited by the provisions of subsection (a) of this section. Each notice under this paragraph shall set forth the error alleged and an explanation thereof.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Abatement of assessment of mathematical or clerical errors</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Request for abatement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding section 6404(b), a taxpayer may file with the Secretary within 60 days after notice is sent under paragraph (1) a request for an abatement of any assessment specified in such notice, and upon receipt of such request, the Secretary shall abate the assessment. Any reassessment of the tax with respect to which an abatement is made under this subparagraph shall be subject to the deficiency procedures prescribed by this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Stay of collection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of any assessment referred to in paragraph (1), notwithstanding paragraph (1), no levy or proceeding in court for the collection of such assessment shall be made, begun, or prosecuted during the period in which such assessment may be abated under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessments arising out of tentative carryback or refund adjustments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Secretary determines that the amount applied, credited, or refunded under section 6411 is in excess of the overassessment attributable to the carryback or the amount described in section 1341(b)(1) with respect to which such amount was applied, credited, or refunded, he may assess without regard to the provisions of paragraph (2) the amount of the excess as a deficiency as if it were due to a mathematical or clerical error appearing on the return.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assessment of amount paid</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any amount paid as a tax or in respect of a tax may be assessed upon the receipt of such payment notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a). In any case where such amount is paid after the mailing of a notice of deficiency under section 6212, such payment shall not deprive the Tax Court of jurisdiction over such deficiency determined under section 6211 without regard to such assessment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain orders of criminal restitution</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If the taxpayer is notified that an assessment has been or will be made pursuant to section 6201(a)(4)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such notice shall not be considered as a notice of deficiency for the purposes of subsection (a) (prohibiting assessment and collection until notice of the deficiency has been mailed), section 6212(c)(1) (restricting further deficiency letters), or section 6512(a) (prohibiting credits or refunds after petition to the Tax Court), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to the amount of such assessment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to file petition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the taxpayer does not file a petition with the Tax Court within the time prescribed in subsection (a), the deficiency, notice of which has been mailed to the taxpayer, shall be assessed, and shall be paid upon notice and demand from the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver of restrictions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The taxpayer shall at any time (whether or not a notice of deficiency has been issued) have the right, by a signed notice in writing filed with the Secretary, to waive the restrictions provided in subsection (a) on the assessment and collection of the whole or any part of the deficiency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of filing period for certain excise taxes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The running of the time prescribed by subsection (a) for filing a petition in the Tax Court with respect to the taxes imposed by section 4941 (relating to taxes on self-dealing), 4942 (relating to taxes on failure to distribute income), 4943 (relating to taxes on excess business holdings), 4944 (relating to investments which jeopardize charitable purpose), 4945 (relating to taxes on taxable expenditures), 4951 (relating to taxes on self-dealing), or 4952 (relating to taxes on taxable expenditures), 4955 (relating to taxes on political expenditures), 4958 (relating to private excess benefit), 4971 (relating to excise taxes on failure to meet minimum funding standard), 4975 (relating to excise taxes on prohibited transactions) shall be suspended for any period during which the Secretary has extended the time allowed for making correction under section 4963(e).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with title 11</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of running of period for filing petition in title 11 cases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case under title 11 of the United States Code, the running of the time prescribed by subsection (a) for filing a petition in the Tax Court with respect to any deficiency shall be suspended for the period during which the debtor is prohibited by reason of such case from filing a petition in the Tax Court with respect to such deficiency, and for 60 days thereafter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain action not taken into account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of the second and third sentences of subsection (a), the filing of a proof of claim or request for payment (or the taking of any other action) in a case under title 11 of the United States Code shall not be treated as action prohibited by such second sentence.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Return</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “return” includes any return, statement, schedule, or list, and any amendment or supplement thereto, filed with respect to any tax imposed by subtitle A or B, or chapter 41, 42, 43, or 44.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mathematical or clerical error</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “mathematical or clerical error” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an error in addition, subtraction, multiplication, or division shown on any return,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an incorrect use of any table provided by the Internal Revenue Service with respect to any return if such incorrect use is apparent from the existence of other information on the return,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> an entry on a return of an item which is inconsistent with another entry of the same or another item on such return,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an omission of information which is required to be supplied on the return to substantiate an entry on the return,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<chapeau> an entry on a return of a deduction or credit in an amount which exceeds a statutory limit imposed by subtitle A or B, or chapter 41, 42, 43, or 44, if such limit is expressed—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> as a specified monetary amount, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> as a percentage, ratio, or fraction,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">and if the items entering into the application of such limit appear on such return,</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> an omission of a correct taxpayer identification number required under section 32 (relating to the earned income credit) to be included on a return,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> an entry on a return claiming the credit under section 32 with respect to net earnings from self-employment described in section 32(c)(2)(A) to the extent the tax imposed by section 1401 (relating to self-employment tax) on such net earnings has not been paid,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> an omission of a correct TIN required under section 21 (relating to expenses for household and dependent care services necessary for gainful employment) or section 151 (relating to allowance of deductions for personal exemptions),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> an omission of a correct TIN required under section 24(e) (relating to child tax credit) to be included on a return,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> an omission of a correct TIN required under section 25A(g)(1) (relating to higher education tuition and related expenses) to be included on a return,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> an omission of information required by section 32(k)(2) (relating to taxpayers making improper prior claims of earned income credit) or an entry on the return claiming the credit under section 32 for a taxable year for which the credit is disallowed under subsection (k)(1) thereof,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<chapeau> the inclusion on a return of a TIN required to be included on the return under section 21, 24, 32, 6428, or 6428A if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such TIN is of an individual whose age affects the amount of the credit under such section, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the computation of the credit on the return reflects the treatment of such individual as being of an age different from the individual’s age based on such TIN,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(M)</num>
<content> the entry on the return claiming the credit under section 32 with respect to a child if, according to the Federal Case Registry of Child Support Orders established under section 453(h) of the Social Security Act, the taxpayer is a noncustodial parent of such child,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(N)</num>
<content> an omission of any increase required under section 36(f) with respect to the recapture of a credit allowed under section 36,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(O)</num>
<content> the inclusion on a return of an individual taxpayer identification number issued under section 6109(i) which has expired, been revoked by the Secretary, or is otherwise invalid,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(P)</num>
<content> an omission of information required by section 24(g)(2) or an entry on the return claiming the credit under section 24 for a taxable year for which the credit is disallowed under subsection (g)(1) thereof,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(Q)</num>
<content> an omission of information required by section 25A(b)(4)(B) or an entry on the return claiming the American Opportunity Tax Credit for a taxable year for which such credit is disallowed under section 25A(b)(4)(A),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(R)</num>
<content> an omission of information or documentation required under section 25C(b)(6)(B) (relating to home energy audits) to be included on a return,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(S)</num>
<content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002284">1</ref> an omission of a correct product identification number required under section 25C(h) (relating to credit for nonbusiness energy property) to be included on a return,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(T)</num>
<content> an omission of a correct vehicle identification number required under section 30D(f)(9) (relating to credit for new clean vehicles) to be included on a return,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(U)</num>
<content> an omission of a correct vehicle identification number required under section 25E(d) (relating to credit for previously-owned clean vehicles) to be included on a return, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(V)</num>
<content> an omission of a correct vehicle identification number required under section 45W(e) (relating to commercial clean vehicle credit) to be included on a return.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">A taxpayer shall be treated as having omitted a correct TIN for purposes of the preceding sentence if information provided by the taxpayer on the return with respect to the individual whose TIN was provided differs from the information the Secretary obtains from the person issuing the TIN.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cross references</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For assessment as if a mathematical error on the return, in the case of erroneous claims for income tax prepayment credits, see section 6201(a)(3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> For assessments without regard to restrictions imposed by this section in the case of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent3 fontsize7">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Recovery of foreign income taxes, see section 905(c).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 fontsize7">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Recovery of foreign estate tax, see section 2016.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For provisions relating to application of this subchapter in the case of certain partnership items, etc., see section 6230(a).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002285">2</ref></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 771</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–44, title VIII, § 809(d)(4)(B)</ref>, <date date="1965-06-21">June 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 168</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–172, title I, § 101(f)(3)</ref>, (j)(42), <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 524</ref>, 530; <ref>Pub. L. 93–406, title II, § 1016(a)(11)</ref>, <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 930</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XII</ref>, §§ 1204(c)(6), 1206(a)–(c)(1), title XIII, § 1307(d)(2)(F)(iii), title XVI, § 1605(b)(6), title XIX, §§ 1906(a)(15), (b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1698</ref>, 1703, 1704, 1728, 1755, 1825, 1834; <ref>Pub. L. 95–227, § 4(d)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1978-02-10">Feb. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 23</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–600, title V, § 504(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2881</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–223, title I, § 101(f)(1)(D)</ref>, (E), <date date="1980-04-02">Apr. 2, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 252</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–589, § 6(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3407</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–596, § 2(a)(4)(C)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3472</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–248, title IV, § 402(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 667</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, title III, § 305(b)(4)</ref>, title IV, § 474(r)(34), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 784</ref>, 845; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title XVIII, § 1875(d)(2)(B)(i)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2896</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–203, title X</ref>, §§ 10712(c)(1), 10713(b)(2)(D), <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1330–467</ref>, 1330–470; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1941(b)(2)(B)(iv)</ref>, (v), <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1323</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1015(r)(3)</ref>, title VI, § 6243(a), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3573</ref>, 3749; <ref>Pub. L. 101–239, title VII, § 7811(k)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2412</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–168, title XIII, § 1311(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-07-30">July 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1478</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–188, title I, § 1615(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1853</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–193, title IV, § 451(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2277</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–34, title I, § 101(d)(2)</ref>, title II, § 201(b), title X, § 1085(a)(3), <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 799</ref>, 803, 956; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title III</ref>, §§ 3463(b), 3464(a), title VI, § 6010(p)(3), <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 767</ref>, 817; <ref>Pub. L. 105–277, div. J, title III, § 3003(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 2681–905</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–16, title III, § 303(g)</ref>, <date date="2001-06-07">June 7, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 56</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–185, title I, § 101(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-02-13">Feb. 13, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 616</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–5, div. B, title I, § 1001(d)</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 312</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–92</ref>, §§ 11(h), 12(d), <date date="2009-11-06">Nov. 6, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2991</ref>, 2992; <ref>Pub. L. 111–237, § 3(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-08-16">Aug. 16, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2498</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II</ref>, §§ 214(a), 221(a)(4), (5)(C), (112)(C), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4034</ref>, 4037, 4038, 4054; <ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. Q, title II</ref>, §§ 203(e), 208(b), <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 3080</ref>, 3084; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title I, § 101</ref>(<i>l</i>)(18), title IV, § 401(a)(277), (278), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1165</ref>, 1197; <ref>Pub. L. 116–136, div. A, title II, § 2201(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2020-03-27">Mar. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 337</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–260, div. N, title II, § 272(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 1971</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–169, title I</ref>, §§ 13301(f)(4), (g)(2), 13401(i)(4), 13402(c), 13403(b)(2), <date date="2022-08-16">Aug. 16, 2022</date>, <ref>136 Stat. 1945</ref>, 1946, 1961, 1964, 1966.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6214.</num>
<heading> Determinations by Tax Court</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction as to increase of deficiency, additional amounts, or additions to the tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided by section 7463, the Tax Court shall have jurisdiction to redetermine the correct amount of the deficiency even if the amount so redetermined is greater than the amount of the deficiency, notice of which has been mailed to the taxpayer, and to determine whether any additional amount, or any addition to the tax should be assessed, if claim therefor is asserted by the Secretary at or before the hearing or a rehearing.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction over other years and quarters</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Tax Court in redetermining a deficiency of income tax for any taxable year or of gift tax for any calendar year or calendar quarter shall consider such facts with relation to the taxes for other years or calendar quarters as may be necessary correctly to redetermine the amount of such deficiency, but in so doing shall have no jurisdiction to determine whether or not the tax for any other year or calendar quarter has been overpaid or underpaid. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, the Tax Court may apply the doctrine of equitable recoupment to the same extent that it is available in civil tax cases before the district courts of the United States and the United States Court of Federal Claims.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxes imposed by section 507 or chapter 41, 42, 43, or 44</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Tax Court, in redetermining a deficiency of any tax imposed by section 507 or chapter 41, 42, 43, or 44 for any period, act, or failure to act, shall consider such facts with relation to the taxes under chapter 41, 42, 43, or 44 for other periods, acts, or failures to act as may be necessary correctly to redetermine the amount of such deficiency, but in so doing shall have no jurisdiction to determine whether or not the taxes under chapter 41, 42, 43, or 44 for any other period, act, or failure to act have been overpaid or underpaid. The Tax Court, in redetermining a deficiency of any second tier tax (as defined in section 4963(b)), shall make a determination with respect to whether the taxable event has been corrected.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final decisions of Tax Court</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, chapter 41, 42, 43, or 44, and subtitles A or B the date on which a decision of the Tax Court becomes final shall be determined according to the provisions of section 7481.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cross reference</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2 fontsize7">For provision giving Tax Court jurisdiction to order a refund of an overpayment and to award sanctions, see section 6512(b)(2).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 773</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–172, title I, § 101(j)(43)</ref>, (44), title IX, § 960(a), <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 530</ref>, 531, 734; <ref>Pub. L. 91–614, title I, § 102(d)(6)</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1842</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–406, title II, § 1016(a)(12)</ref>, <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 930</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIII, § 1307(d)(2)(F)(iv)</ref>, (H), title XVI, § 1605(b)(7), title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1728</ref>, 1755, 1834; <ref>Pub. L. 96–223, title I, § 101(f)(1)(F)</ref>, (G), <date date="1980-04-02">Apr. 2, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 252</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–596, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3472</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title I, § 144(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 683</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title XV</ref>, §§ 1511(c)(8), 1554(a), title XVIII, § 1833, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2745</ref>, 2754, 2852; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1941(b)(2)(B)(vi)</ref>, (vii), <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1323</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VI, § 6244(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3750</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–188, title I, § 1704(t)(16)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1888</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–280, title VIII, § 858(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1020</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6215.</num>
<heading> Assessment of deficiency found by Tax Court</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the taxpayer files a petition with the Tax Court, the entire amount redetermined as the deficiency by the decision of the Tax Court which has become final shall be assessed and shall be paid upon notice and demand from the Secretary. No part of the amount determined as a deficiency by the Secretary but disallowed as such by the decision of the Tax Court which has become final shall be assessed or be collected by levy or by proceeding in court with or without assessment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cross references</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For assessment or collection of the amount of the deficiency determined by the Tax Court pending appellate court review, see section 7485.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For dismissal of petition by Tax Court as affirmation of deficiency as determined by the Secretary, see section 7459(d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For decision of Tax Court that tax is barred by limitation as its decision that there is no deficiency, see section 7459(e).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For assessment of damages awarded by Tax Court for instituting proceedings merely for delay, see section 6673.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> For rules applicable to Tax Court proceedings, see generally subchapter C of chapter 76.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> For extension of time for paying amount determined as deficiency, see section 6161(b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 773</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(a)(16)</ref>, (b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1825</ref>, 1834; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title XIV, § 1404(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2714</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(b)(46)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1204</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6216.</num>
<heading> Cross references</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> For procedures relating to receivership proceedings, see subchapter B of chapter 70.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> For procedures relating to jeopardy assessments, see subchapter A of chapter 70.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> For procedures relating to claims against transferees and fiduciaries, see chapter 71.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 fontsize7">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> For procedures relating to partnership items, see subchapter C.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 773</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–589, § 6(i)(9)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3411</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–248, title IV, § 402(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 667</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter C—</num>
<heading>Treatment of Partnerships</heading>
<part>
<num>PART I—</num>
<heading>IN GENERAL</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6221.</num>
<heading> Determination at partnership level</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any adjustment to a partnership-related item shall be determined, and any tax attributable thereto shall be assessed and collected, and the applicability of any penalty, addition to tax, or additional amount which relates to an adjustment to any such item shall be determined, at the partnership level, except to the extent otherwise provided in this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Election out for certain partnerships with 100 or fewer partners, etc.</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">This subchapter shall not apply with respect to any partnership for any taxable year if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the partnership elects the application of this subsection for such taxable year,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for such taxable year the partnership is required to furnish 100 or fewer statements under section 6031(b) with respect to its partners,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> each of the partners of such partnership is an individual, a C corporation, any foreign entity that would be treated as a C corporation were it domestic, an S corporation, or an estate of a deceased partner,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<chapeau> the election—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is made with a timely filed return for such taxable year, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> includes (in the manner prescribed by the Secretary) a disclosure of the name and taxpayer identification number of each partner of such partnership, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the partnership notifies each such partner of such election in the manner prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules relating to certain partners</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> S corporation partners</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In the case of a partner that is an S corporation—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the partnership shall only be treated as meeting the requirements of paragraph (1)(C) with respect to such partner if such partnership includes (in the manner prescribed by the Secretary) a disclosure of the name and taxpayer identification number of each person with respect to whom such S corporation is required to furnish a statement under section 6037(b) for the taxable year of the S corporation ending with or within the partnership taxable year for which the application of this subsection is elected, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the statements such S corporation is required to so furnish shall be treated as statements furnished by the partnership for purposes of paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign partners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of paragraph (1)(D)(ii), the Secretary may provide for alternative identification of any foreign partners.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other partners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may by regulation or other guidance prescribe rules similar to the rules of subparagraph (A) with respect to any partners not described in such subparagraph or paragraph (1)(C).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–74, title XI, § 1101(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 625</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title II, § 201(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1173</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6222.</num>
<heading> Partner’s return must be consistent with partnership return</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A partner shall, on the partner’s return, treat any partnership-related item in a manner which is consistent with the treatment of such item on the partnership return.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Underpayment due to inconsistent treatment assessed as math error</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any underpayment of tax by a partner by reason of failing to comply with the requirements of subsection (a) shall be assessed and collected in the same manner as if such underpayment were on account of a mathematical or clerical error appearing on the partner’s return. Paragraph (2) of section 6213(b) shall not apply to any assessment of an underpayment referred to in the preceding sentence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for notification of inconsistent treatment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of any item referred to in subsection (a), if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the partnership has filed a return but the partner’s treatment on the partner’s return is (or may be) inconsistent with the treatment of the item on the partnership return, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the partnership has not filed a return, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the partner files with the Secretary a statement identifying the inconsistency,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply to such item.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partner receiving incorrect information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A partner shall be treated as having complied with subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1) with respect to an item if the partner—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the treatment of the item on the partner’s return is consistent with the treatment of the item on the statement furnished to the partner by the partnership, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> elects to have this paragraph apply with respect to that item.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Final decision on certain positions not binding on partnership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any final decision with respect to an inconsistent position identified under subsection (c) in a proceeding to which the partnership is not a party shall not be binding on the partnership.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Addition to tax for failure to comply with section</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For addition to tax in the case of a partner’s disregard of the requirements of this section, see part II of subchapter A of chapter 68.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–74, title XI, § 1101(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 626</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title II, § 201(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1173</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6223.</num>
<heading> Partners bound by actions of partnership</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designation of partnership representative</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each partnership shall designate (in the manner prescribed by the Secretary) a partner (or other person) with a substantial presence in the United States as the partnership representative who shall have the sole authority to act on behalf of the partnership under this subchapter. In any case in which such a designation is not in effect, the Secretary may select any person as the partnership representative.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Binding effect</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A partnership and all partners of such partnership shall be bound—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by actions taken under this subchapter by the partnership, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by any final decision in a proceeding brought under this subchapter with respect to the partnership.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–74, title XI, § 1101(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 627</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num>PART II—</num>
<heading>PARTNERSHIP ADJUSTMENTS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6225.</num>
<heading> Partnership adjustment by Secretary</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of any adjustments by the Secretary to any partnership-related items with respect to any reviewed year of a partnership—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> if such adjustments result in an imputed underpayment, the partnership shall pay an amount equal to such imputed underpayment in the adjustment year as provided in section 6232, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if such adjustments do not result in an imputed underpayment, such adjustments shall be taken into account by the partnership in the adjustment year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of imputed underpayments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as otherwise provided in this section, any imputed underpayment with respect to any reviewed year shall be determined by the Secretary by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> appropriately netting all partnership adjustments with respect to such reviewed year, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> applying the highest rate of tax in effect for the reviewed year under section 1 or 11.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustments to distributive shares of partners not netted</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of any adjustment which reallocates the distributive share of any item from one partner to another, such adjustment shall be taken into account by disregarding so much of such adjustment as results in a decrease in the amount of the imputed underpayment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustments separately netted by category</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1)(A), partnership adjustments for any reviewed year shall first be separately determined (and netted as appropriate) within each category of items that are required to be taken into account separately under section 702(a) or other provision of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on adjustments that may be taken into account</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If any adjustment would (but for this paragraph)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> result in a decrease in the amount of the imputed underpayment, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> could be subject to any additional limitation under the provisions of this title (or not allowed, in whole or in part, against ordinary income) if such adjustment were taken into account by any person,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">such adjustment shall not be taken into account under paragraph (1)(A) except to the extent otherwise provided by the Secretary.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification of imputed underpayments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish procedures under which the imputed underpayment amount may be modified consistent with the requirements of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Procedures for partners to take adjustments into account</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amended returns of partners</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Such procedures shall provide that if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> one or more partners file returns for the taxable year of the partners which includes the end of the reviewed year of the partnership (and for any taxable year with respect to which any tax attribute is affected by reason of any adjustment referred to in clause (ii)),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> such returns take into account all adjustments under subsection (a) properly allocable to such partners (and the effect of such adjustments on any tax attributes), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> payment of any tax due is included with such returns,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">then the imputed underpayment amount shall be determined without regard to the portion of the adjustments so taken into account.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alternative procedure to filing amended returns</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Such procedures shall provide that, with respect to any partner referred to in subparagraph (A), the requirements of subparagraph (A) shall be treated as satisfied with respect to adjustments properly allocable to such partner if, in lieu of filing the returns described in such subparagraph—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the amounts described in subparagraph (A)(iii) are paid by the partner,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the partner agrees to take into account, in the form and manner prescribed by the Secretary, the adjustments to the tax attributes of such partner referred to in subparagraph (A)(ii), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> such partner provides, in the form and manner specified by the Secretary (including, if the Secretary so specifies, in the same form as on an amended return), such information as the Secretary may require to carry out this subparagraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reallocation of distributive share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of any adjustment which reallocates the distributive share of any item from one partner to another, this paragraph shall apply with respect to any such partner only if the requirements of subparagraph (A) or (B) are satisfied with respect to all partners affected by such adjustment.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of statute of limitations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of adjustments referred to in subparagraph (A)(ii), sections 6501 and 6511 shall not apply with respect to any return filed for purposes of subparagraph (A)(i) or any amount paid under subparagraph (A)(iii) or (B)(i).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustments to tax attributes binding for affected taxable years of partner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The adjustments to the tax attributes of any partner provided for in subparagraph (A)(ii) or (B)(ii) shall be binding with respect to the taxable year of the partner which includes the end of the reviewed year of the partnership and any taxable years for which any tax attribute is affected by such adjustment. Any failure to so treat any such tax attribute shall be treated for purposes of this title in the same manner as a failure to treat a partnership-related item in a manner which is consistent with the treatment of such item on the partnership return within the meaning of section 6222.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002287">1</ref> Application to partnerships and S corporations in tiered structures</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">In the case of any partnership any partner of which is a partnership, subparagraph (A) or (B) may apply with respect to any partner (hereafter in this subparagraph referred to as the “relevant partner”) in the chain of ownership of such partnerships if—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> such information as the Secretary may require is furnished to the Secretary for purposes of carrying out this paragraph with respect to such partnerships (including any information the Secretary may require with respect to any chain of ownership of the relevant partner), and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> to such extent as the Secretary may require, each partnership in the chain of ownership between the relevant partner and the audited partnership satisfies the requirements of subparagraph (A) or (B).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of S corporations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">For purposes of clause (i), an S corporation and its shareholders shall be treated in the same manner as a partnership and its partners.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(F)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <sup>1</sup> Adjustments not treated as amended return</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An administrative adjustment request under section 6227 and a partnership adjustment tracking report under section 6226(b)(4)(A) shall not be treated as a return for purposes of this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax-exempt partners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Such procedures shall provide for determining the imputed underpayment without regard to the portion of the adjustment that the partnership demonstrates is allocable to a partner that would not owe tax by reason of its status as a tax-exempt entity (as defined in section 168(h)(2)).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification of applicable highest tax rates</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Such procedures shall provide for taking into account a rate of tax lower than the rate of tax described in subsection (b)(1)(A) with respect to any portion of the adjustment that the partnership demonstrates is allocable to a partner which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is a C corporation, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of a capital gain or qualified dividend, is an individual.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">In no event shall the lower rate determined under the preceding sentence be less than the highest rate in effect with respect to the income and taxpayer described in clause (i) or clause (ii), as the case may be. For purposes of clause (ii), an S corporation shall be treated as an individual.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Portion of imputed underpayment to which lower rate applies</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Except as provided in clause (ii), the portion of the imputed underpayment to which the lower rate applies with respect to a partner under subparagraph (A) shall be determined by reference to the partners’ distributive share of items to which the imputed underpayment relates.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rule in case of varied treatment of items among partners</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">If the imputed underpayment is attributable to the adjustment of more than 1 item, and any partner’s distributive share of such items is not the same with respect to all such items, then the portion of the imputed underpayment to which the lower rate applies with respect to a partner under subparagraph (A) shall be determined by reference to the amount which would have been the partner’s distributive share of net gain or loss if the partnership had sold all of its assets at their fair market value as of the close of the reviewed year of the partnership.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain passive losses of publicly traded partnerships</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In the case of a publicly traded partnership (as defined in section 469(k)(2)), such procedures shall provide—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for determining the imputed underpayment without regard to the portion of the adjustment that the partnership demonstrates is attributable to a net decrease in a specified passive activity loss which is allocable to a specified partner, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for the partnership to take such net decrease into account as an adjustment in the adjustment year with respect to the specified partners to which such net decrease relates.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specified passive activity loss</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “specified passive activity loss” means, with respect to any specified partner of such publicly traded partnership, the lesser of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the passive activity loss of such partner which is separately determined with respect to such partnership under section 469(k) with respect to such partner’s taxable year in which or with which the reviewed year of such partnership ends, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> such passive activity loss so determined with respect to such partner’s taxable year in which or with which the adjustment year of such partnership ends.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specified partner</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “specified partner” means any person if such person—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is a partner of the publicly traded partnership referred to in subparagraph (A),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is described in section 469(a)(2), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> has a specified passive activity loss with respect to such publicly traded partnership,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">with respect to each taxable year of such person which is during the period beginning with the taxable year of such person in which or with which the reviewed year of such publicly traded partnership ends and ending with the taxable year of such person in which or with which the adjustment year of such publicly traded partnership ends.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other procedures for modification of imputed underpayment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may by regulations or guidance provide for additional procedures to modify imputed underpayment amounts on the basis of such other factors as the Secretary determines are necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Year and day for submission to Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Anything required to be filed or submitted under this subsection shall be submitted to the Secretary not later than the close of the 270-day period beginning on the date on which the notice of a proposed partnership adjustment is mailed under section 6231 unless such period is extended with the consent of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Decision of Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any modification of the imputed underpayment amount under this subsection shall be made only upon approval of such modification by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modification of adjustments not resulting in an imputed underpayment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish procedures under which the adjustments described in subsection (a)(2) may be modified in such manner as the Secretary determines appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reviewed year</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “reviewed year” means the partnership taxable year to which the item being adjusted relates.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment year</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “adjustment year” means the partnership taxable year in which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of an adjustment pursuant to the decision of a court in a proceeding brought under section 6234, such decision becomes final,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of an administrative adjustment request under section 6227, such administrative adjustment request is made, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in any other case, notice of the final partnership adjustment is mailed under section 6231.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–74, title XI, § 1101(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 628</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. Q, title IV, § 411(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 3121</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title II</ref>, §§ 202, 203(a), 206(b), (p)(1), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1173</ref>, 1174, 1178, 1182.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6226.</num>
<heading> Alternative to payment of imputed underpayment by partnership</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the partnership—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> not later than 45 days after the date of the notice of final partnership adjustment, elects the application of this section with respect to an imputed underpayment, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may provide, furnishes to each partner of the partnership for the reviewed year and to the Secretary a statement of the partner’s share of any adjustment to a partnership-related item (as determined in the notice of final partnership adjustment),</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">section 6225 shall not apply with respect to such underpayment (and no assessment of tax, levy, or proceeding in any court for the collection of such underpayment shall be made against such partnership) and each such partner shall take such adjustment into account as provided in subsection (b). The election under paragraph (1) shall be made in such manner as the Secretary may provide and, once made, shall be revocable only with the consent of the Secretary.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustments taken into account by partner</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax imposed in year of statement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (4), each partner’s tax imposed by chapter 1 for the taxable year which includes the date the statement was furnished under subsection (a) shall be adjusted by the aggregate of the correction amounts determined under paragraph (2) for the taxable years referred to therein.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Correction amounts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The correction amounts determined under this paragraph are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of the taxable year of the partner which includes the end of the reviewed year, the amount by which the tax imposed under chapter 1 would increase or decrease if the partner’s share of the adjustments described in subsection (a) were taken into account for such taxable year, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of any taxable year after the taxable year referred to in subparagraph (A) and before the taxable year referred to in paragraph (1), the amount by which the tax imposed under chapter 1 would increase or decrease by reason of the adjustment to tax attributes under paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment of tax attributes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any tax attribute which would have been affected if the adjustments described in subsection (a) were taken into account for the taxable year referred to in paragraph (2)(A) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of any taxable year referred to in paragraph (2)(B), be appropriately adjusted for purposes of applying such paragraph, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of any subsequent taxable year, be appropriately adjusted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of partnerships and S corporations in tiered structures</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If a partner which receives a statement under subsection (a)(2) is a partnership or an S corporation, such partner shall, with respect to the partner’s share of the adjustment—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> file with the Secretary a partnership adjustment tracking report which includes such information as the Secretary may require, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> furnish statements under rules similar to the rules of subsection (a)(2), or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> if no such statements are furnished, compute and pay an imputed underpayment under rules similar to the rules of section 6225 (other than paragraphs (2), (7), and (9) of subsection (c) thereof).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Due date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), with respect to a partner’s share of the adjustment, the partnership adjustment tracking report shall be filed, and the imputed underpayment shall be paid or statements shall be furnished, not later than the due date for the return for the adjustment year of the audited partnership.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partnership payment of tax if elected out of subchapter</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of a partnership which has elected the application of section 6221(b) with respect to the taxable year of the partnership which includes the end of the reviewed year of the audited partnership, this paragraph shall apply notwithstanding such election.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Audited partnership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “audited partnership” means, with respect to any partner described in subparagraph (A), the partnership in the chain of ownership originally electing the application of this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of trusts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall prescribe such rules as may be necessary with respect to trusts which receive a statement under subsection (a)(2).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties and interest</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b), any penalties, additions to tax, or additional amount shall be determined as provided under section 6221 and the partners of the partnership for the reviewed year shall be liable for any such penalty, addition to tax, or additional amount.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of an imputed underpayment with respect to which the application of this section is elected, or which is described in subsection (b)(4)(A)(ii)(I), interest shall be determined—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> at the partner level,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> from the due date of the return for the taxable year to which the increase is attributable (determined by taking into account any increases attributable to a change in tax attributes for a taxable year under subsection (b)(2)), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> at the underpayment rate under section 6621(a)(2), determined by substituting “5 percentage points” for “3 percentage points” in subparagraph (B) thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For the time period within which a partnership may file a petition for a readjustment, see section 6234(a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–74, title XI, § 1101(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 630</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. Q, title IV, § 411(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 3122</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title II</ref>, §§ 201(c)(4), 204, 206(d), (e), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1173</ref>, 1176, 1178.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6227.</num>
<heading> Administrative adjustment request by partnership</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A partnership may file a request for an administrative adjustment in the amount of one or more partnership-related items for any partnership taxable year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any such adjustment under subsection (a) shall be determined and taken into account for the partnership taxable year in which the administrative adjustment request is filed—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by the partnership under rules similar to the rules of section 6225 (other than paragraphs (2), (7), and (9) of subsection (c) thereof) for the partnership taxable year in which the administrative adjustment request is filed, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by the partnership and partners under rules similar to the rules of section 6226 (determined without regard to the substitution described in subsection (c)(2)(C) thereof).</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">In the case of an adjustment that would not result in an imputed underpayment, paragraph (1) shall not apply and paragraph (2) shall apply with appropriate adjustments.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Period of limitations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A partnership may not file such a request more than 3 years after the later of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the date on which the partnership return for such year is filed, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the last day for filing the partnership return for such year (determined without regard to extensions).</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">In no event may a partnership file such a request after a notice of an administrative proceeding with respect to the taxable year is mailed under section 6231.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with adjustments related to foreign tax credits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall issue regulations or other guidance which provide for the proper coordination of this section and section 905(c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–74, title XI, § 1101(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 631</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title II</ref>, §§ 201(c)(5), 206(f), (p)(2), (3), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1173</ref>, 1179, 1182.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num>PART III—</num>
<heading>PROCEDURE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6231.</num>
<heading> Notice of proceedings and adjustment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall mail to the partnership and the partnership representative—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> notice of any administrative proceeding initiated at the partnership level with respect to an adjustment of any partnership-related item for any partnership taxable year, or any partner’s distributive share thereof,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> notice of any proposed partnership adjustment resulting from such proceeding, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> notice of any final partnership adjustment resulting from such proceeding.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Any notice of a final partnership adjustment shall be sufficient if mailed to the last known address of the partnership representative or the partnership (even if the partnership has terminated its existence). The first sentence shall apply to any proceeding with respect to an administrative adjustment request filed by a partnership under section 6227.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing of notices</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice of proposed partnership adjustment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any notice of a proposed partnership adjustment shall not be mailed later than the date determined under section 6235 (determined without regard to paragraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (a) thereof).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice of final partnership adjustment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except to the extent that the partnership elects to waive the application of this subparagraph, any notice of a final partnership adjustment shall not be mailed earlier than 270 days after the date on which the notice of the proposed partnership adjustment is mailed.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statute of limitations on adjustment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For the period of limitations on making adjustments, see section 6235.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Further notices restricted</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary mails a notice of a final partnership adjustment to any partnership for any partnership taxable year and the partnership files a petition under section 6234 with respect to such notice, in the absence of a showing of fraud, malfeasance, or misrepresentation of a material fact, the Secretary shall not mail another such notice to such partnership with respect to such taxable year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to rescind notice with partnership consent</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may, with the consent of the partnership, rescind any notice of a partnership adjustment mailed to such partnership. Any notice so rescinded shall not be treated as a notice of a partnership adjustment for purposes of this subchapter, and the taxpayer shall have no right to bring a proceeding under section 6234 with respect to such notice.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–74, title XI, § 1101(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 632</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title II</ref>, §§ 201(c)(6), 206(h), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1173</ref>, 1179.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6232.</num>
<heading> Assessment, collection, and payment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Any imputed underpayment shall be assessed and collected in the same manner as if it were a tax imposed for the adjustment year by subtitle A, except that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> subchapter B of chapter 63 shall not apply, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of an administrative adjustment request to which section 6227(b)(1) applies, the underpayment shall be paid and may be assessed when the request is filed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on assessment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle (other than subchapter B of this chapter), no assessment of an imputed underpayment may be made (and no levy or proceeding in any court for the collection of any amount resulting from such adjustment may be made, begun or prosecuted) before—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the close of the 90th day after the day on which a notice of a final partnership adjustment was mailed, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if a petition is filed under section 6234 with respect to such notice, the decision of the court has become final.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The preceding sentence shall not apply in the case of a specified similar amount (as defined in subsection (f)(2)).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Premature action may be enjoined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding section 7421(a), any action which violates subsection (b) may be enjoined in the proper court, including the Tax Court. The Tax Court shall have no jurisdiction to enjoin any action under this subsection unless a timely petition has been filed under section 6234 and then only in respect of the adjustments that are the subject of such petition.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions to restrictions on adjustments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustments arising out of math or clerical errors</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2"> If the partnership is notified that, on account of a mathematical or clerical error appearing on the partnership return, an adjustment to an item is required, rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 6213(b) shall apply to such adjustment.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If a partnership is a partner in another partnership, any adjustment on account of such partnership’s failure to comply with the requirements of section 6222(a) with respect to its interest in such other partnership shall be treated as an adjustment referred to in subparagraph (A), except that paragraph (2) of section 6213(b) shall not apply to such adjustment.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partnership may waive restrictions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The partnership may at any time (whether or not any notice of partnership adjustment has been issued), by a signed notice in writing filed with the Secretary, waive the restrictions provided in subsection (b) on the making of any partnership adjustment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limit where no proceeding begun</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If no proceeding under section 6234 is begun with respect to any notice of a final partnership adjustment during the 90-day period described in subsection (b), the amount for which the partnership is liable under section 6225 shall not exceed the amount determined in accordance with such notice.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Failure to pay imputed underpayment</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If any amount of any imputed underpayment to which section 6225 applies or any specified similar amount (or any interest or penalties with respect to any such amount) has not been paid by the date which is 10 days after the date on which the Secretary provides notice and demand for such payment—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> section 6621(a)(2)(B) shall be applied by substituting “5 percentage points” for “3 percentage points” with respect to such amount, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the Secretary may assess upon each partner of the partnership (determined as of the close of the adjustment year or, if the partnership has ceased to exist as of such time, the former partners of the partnership as determined for purposes of section 6241(7)) a tax equal to such partner’s proportionate share of such amount (including any such interest or penalties, determined after application of subparagraph (A)).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specified similar amount</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “specified similar amount” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the amount described in subclause (II) of section 6226(b)(4)(A)(ii) (including any failure to satisfy the requirement of subclause (I) of such section which is treated as a failure to pay such amount under section 6651(i)), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any amount assessed under paragraph (1)(B) upon a partner which is a partnership.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proportionate share</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), a partner’s proportionate share is such percentage as the Secretary may determine on the basis of such partner’s distributive share. The Secretary shall make determinations under the preceding sentence such that the aggregate proportionate shares so determined total 100 percent.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with partnership liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The liability of the partnership for any amount with respect to which a partner is made liable under paragraph (1) shall be reduced upon payment by the partner of such amount. Paragraph (1)(B) shall not apply with respect to any amount after the date on which such amount is paid by the partnership.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> S corporations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, an S corporation and its shareholders shall be treated in the same manner as a partnership and its partners.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules related to assessment and collection</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deficiency procedures not applicable</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subchapter B shall not apply to any assessment or collection under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on assessment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, no assessment may be made (or proceeding in court begun without assessment) with respect to any partner with respect to an amount under paragraph (1) after the date which is 2 years after the date on which the Secretary provides the notice and demand referred to in paragraph (1) with respect to such amount.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–74, title XI, § 1101(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 632</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title II</ref>, §§ 205(a), 206(g), (p)(4)–(6), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1177</ref>, 1179, 1182.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6233.</num>
<heading> Interest and penalties</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest and penalties determined from reviewed year</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except to the extent provided in section 6226(c), in the case of a partnership adjustment for a reviewed year—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> interest shall be computed under paragraph (2), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the partnership shall be liable for any penalty, addition to tax, or additional amount as provided in paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of amount of interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The interest computed under this paragraph with respect to any partnership adjustment is the interest which would be determined under chapter 67 for the period beginning on the day after the return due date for the reviewed year and ending on the return due date for the adjustment year (or, if earlier, the date payment of the imputed underpayment is made). Proper adjustments in the amount determined under the preceding sentence shall be made for adjustments required for partnership taxable years after the reviewed year and before the adjustment year by reason of such partnership adjustment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any penalty, addition to tax, or additional amount shall be determined at the partnership level as if such partnership had been an individual subject to tax under chapter 1 for the reviewed year and the imputed underpayment were an actual underpayment (or understatement) for such year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest and penalties with respect to adjustment year return</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of any failure to pay an imputed underpayment on the date prescribed therefor, the partnership shall be liable—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for interest as determined under paragraph (2), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for any penalty, addition to tax, or additional amount as determined under paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Interest determined under this paragraph is the interest that would be determined by treating the imputed underpayment as an underpayment of tax imposed in the adjustment year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Penalties, additions to tax, or additional amounts determined under this paragraph are the penalties, additions to tax, or additional amounts that would be determined—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> by applying section 6651(a)(2) to such failure to pay, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> by treating the imputed underpayment as an underpayment of tax for purposes of part II of subchapter A of chapter 68.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deposit to suspend interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For rules allowing deposits to suspend running of interest on potential underpayments, see section 6603.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–74, title XI, § 1101(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 633</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title II, § 206(i)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6234.</num>
<heading> Judicial review of partnership adjustment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Within 90 days after the date on which a notice of a final partnership adjustment is mailed under section 6231 with respect to any partnership taxable year, the partnership may file a petition for a readjustment for such taxable year with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the Tax Court,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the district court of the United States for the district in which the partnership’s principal place of business is located, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the Court of Federal Claims.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jurisdictional requirement for bringing action in district court or Court of Federal Claims</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A readjustment petition under this section may be filed in a district court of the United States or the Court of Federal Claims only if the partnership filing the petition deposits with the Secretary, on or before the date the petition is filed, the amount of (as of the date of the filing of the petition) the imputed underpayment, penalties, additions to tax, and additional amounts with respect to such imputed underpayment if the partnership adjustment was made as provided by the notice of final partnership adjustment. The court may by order provide that the jurisdictional requirements of this paragraph are satisfied where there has been a good faith attempt to satisfy such requirement and any shortfall of the amount required to be deposited is timely corrected.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest payable</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any amount deposited under paragraph (1), while deposited, shall not be treated as a payment of tax for purposes of this title (other than chapter 67).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Scope of judicial review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A court with which a petition is filed in accordance with this section shall have jurisdiction to determine all partnership-related items for the partnership taxable year to which the notice of final partnership adjustment relates, the proper allocation of such items among the partners, and the applicability of any penalty, addition to tax, or additional amount for which the partnership may be liable under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of court reviewable</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any determination by a court under this section shall have the force and effect of a decision of the Tax Court or a final judgment or decree of the district court or the Court of Federal Claims, as the case may be, and shall be reviewable as such. The date of any such determination shall be treated as being the date of the court’s order entering the decision.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of decision dismissing action</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If an action brought under this section is dismissed other than by reason of a rescission under section 6231(c),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002288">1</ref> the decision of the court dismissing the action shall be considered as its decision that the notice of final partnership adjustment is correct, and an appropriate order shall be entered in the records of the court.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–74, title XI, § 1101(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 634</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. Q, title IV, § 411(b)(2)</ref>, (3), <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 3122</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title II</ref>, §§ 201(c)(7), 206(j), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1173</ref>, 1180.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 6235.</num>
<heading> Period of limitations on making adjustments</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this section or section 905(c), no adjustment under this subchapter for any partnership taxable year may be made after the later of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the date which is 3 years after the latest of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the date on which the partnership return for such taxable year was filed,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the return due date for the taxable year, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the date on which the partnership filed an administrative adjustment request with respect to such year under section 6227, or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of any modification of an imputed underpayment under section 6225(c), the date that is 270 days (plus the number of days of any extension consented to by the Secretary under paragraph (7) thereof) after the date on which everything required to be submitted to the Secretary pursuant to such section is so submitted, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> in the case of any notice of a proposed partnership adjustment under section 6231(a)(2), the date that is 330 days (plus the number of days of any extension consented to by the Secretary under section 6225(c)(7)) after the date of such notice.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension by agreement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The period described in subsection (a) (including an extension period under this subsection) may be extended by an agreement entered into by the Secretary and the partnership before the expiration of such period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule in case of fraud, etc.</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> False return</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a false or fraudulent partnership return with intent to evade tax, the adjustment may be made at any time.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Substantial omission of income</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If any partnership omits from gross income an amount properly includible therein and such amount is described in subparagraph (A) or (C) of section 6501(e)(1), subsection (a) shall be applied by substituting “6 years” for “3 years”.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No return</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a failure by a partnership to file a return for any taxable year, the adjustment may be made at any time.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Return filed by Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section, a return executed by the Secretary under subsection (b) of section 6020 on behalf of the partnership shall not be treated as a return of the partnership.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information required to be reported</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a partnership that is required to report any information described in section 6501(c)(8), the time for making any adjustment under this subchapter with respect to any tax return, event, or period to which such information relates shall not expire before the date that is determined under section 6501(c)(8).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Listed transactions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a partnership fails to include on any return or statement any information with respect to a listed transaction as described in section 6501(c)(10), the time for making any adjustment under this subchapter with respect to such transaction shall not expire before the date that is determined under section 6501(c)(10).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–74, title XI, § 1101(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 635</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. Q, title IV, § 411(c)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 3122</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title II, § 206(k)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num>PART IV—</num>
<heading>DEFINITIONS AND SPECIAL RULES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 6241.</num>
<heading> Definitions and special rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partnership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “partnership” means any partnership required to file a return under section 6031(a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partnership adjustment</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “partnership adjustment” means any adjustment to a partnership-related item.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partnership-related item</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “partnership-related item” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any item or amount with respect to the partnership (without regard to whether or not such item or amount appears on the partnership’s return and including an imputed underpayment and any item or amount relating to any transaction with, basis in, or liability of, the partnership) which is relevant (determined without regard to this subchapter) in determining the tax liability of any person under chapter 1, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any partner’s distributive share of any item or amount described in clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Return due date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “return due date” means, with respect to the taxable year, the date prescribed for filing the partnership return for such taxable year (determined without regard to extensions).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments nondeductible</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No deduction shall be allowed under subtitle A for any payment required to be made by a partnership under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partnerships having principal place of business outside United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of section 6234, a principal place of business located outside the United States shall be treated as located in the District of Columbia.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partnerships in cases under title 11 of United States Code</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of period of limitations on making adjustment, assessment, or collection</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The running of any period of limitations provided in this subchapter on making a partnership adjustment (or provided by section 6501 or 6502 on the assessment or collection of any imputed underpayment determined under this subchapter) shall, in a case under title 11 of the United States Code, be suspended during the period during which the Secretary is prohibited by reason of such case from making the adjustment (or assessment or collection) and—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for adjustment or assessment, 60 days thereafter, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for collection, 6 months thereafter.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">A rule similar to the rule of section 6213(f)(2) shall apply for purposes of section 6232(b).</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of period of limitation for filing for judicial review</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The running of the period specified in section 6234 shall, in a case under title 11 of the United States Code, be suspended during the period during which the partnership is prohibited by reason of such case from filing a petition under section 6234 and for 60 days thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment where partnership ceases to exist</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a partnership ceases to exist before a partnership adjustment under this subchapter takes effect, such adjustment shall be taken into account by the former partners of such partnership under regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Extension to entities filing partnership return</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a partnership return is filed by an entity for a taxable year but it is determined that the entity is not a partnership (or that there is no entity) for such year, then, to the extent provided in regulations, the provisions of this subchapter are hereby extended in respect of such year to such entity and its items and to persons holding an interest in such entity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(9)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with other chapters</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">This subchapter shall not apply with respect to any tax imposed (including any amount required to be deducted or withheld) under chapter 2, 2A, 3, or 4, except that any partnership adjustment determined under this subchapter for purposes of chapter 1 shall be taken into account for purposes of determining any such tax to the extent that such adjustment is relevant to such determination.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing of withholding</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In the case of any tax imposed (including any amount required to be deducted or withheld) under chapter 3 or 4, which is determined with respect to an adjustment described in subparagraph (A), such tax—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> shall be so determined with respect to the reviewed year, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> shall be so imposed (or so required to be deducted or withheld) with respect to the adjustment year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Statute of limitation on assessment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For special rule with respect to limitation on assessment of taxes under chapter 2 or 2A which are attributable to any partnership adjustment, see section 6501(c)(12).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(10)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to require electronic filing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding section 6011(e), the Secretary may require that anything required to be filed or submitted under section 6225(c), or to be furnished to or filed with the Secretary under section 6226, be so filed, submitted, or furnished by magnetic media or in other machine-readable form.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(11)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of special enforcement matters</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In the case of partnership-related items which involve special enforcement matters, the Secretary may prescribe regulations pursuant to which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> this subchapter (or any portion thereof) does not apply to such items, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> such items are subject to such special rules (including rules related to assessment and collection) as the Secretary determines to be necessary for the effective and efficient enforcement of this title.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special enforcement matters</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “special enforcement matters” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> failure to comply with the requirements of section 6226(b)(4)(A)(ii),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> assessments under section 6851 (relating to termination assessments of income tax) or section 6861 (relating to jeopardy assessments of income, estate, gift, and certain excise taxes),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> criminal investigations,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> indirect methods of proof of income,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> foreign partners or partnerships, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> other matters that the Secretary determines by regulation present special enforcement considerations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(12)</num>
<heading class="bold"> United States shareholders and certain other persons treated as partners</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, in the case of any controlled foreign corporation (as defined in section 957 or 953(c)(1)) which is a partner of a partnership, each United States shareholder (as defined in section 951(b) or 953(c)(1)) with respect to such controlled foreign corporation shall be treated for purposes of this subchapter as a partner of such partnership. For purposes of the preceding sentence, any distributive share of any such United States shareholder with respect to such partnership shall, except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, be equal to such United States shareholder’s pro rata share with respect to such controlled foreign corporation (determined under rules similar to the rules of section 951(a)(2)).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Passive foreign investment companies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), in the case of a passive foreign investment company (as defined in section 1297), each taxpayer that makes an election under section 1295 with respect to such company shall be treated in the same manner as United States shareholders under subparagraph (A), except that such taxpayer’s pro rata share with respect to the passive foreign investment company shall be determined under rules similar to the rules of section 1293(b).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations or other guidance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as is necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this paragraph, including regulations which apply the rules of subparagraph (A) in similar circumstances or with respect to similarly situated persons.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 114–74, title XI, § 1101(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-02">Nov. 2, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 636</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title II</ref>, §§ 201(a), (b)(1), 206(c), (<i>l</i>), (m), (p)(7), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1171</ref>, 1172, 1178, 1180–1182.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
</chapter>