<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 33—</num>
<heading>FACILITIES AND SERVICES</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>[Subchapter A—</num>
<heading>Repealed]</heading>
<section>
<num>[§§ 4231 to 4234.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 89–44, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1965-06-21">June 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 145</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 4241 to 4243.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 89–44, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1965-06-21">June 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 145</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter B—</num>
<heading>Communications</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4251.</num>
<heading> Imposition of tax</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax imposed</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is hereby imposed on amounts paid for communications services a tax equal to the applicable percentage of amounts so paid.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment of tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The tax imposed by this section shall be paid by the person paying for such services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Communications services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “communications services” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> local telephone service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> toll telephone service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> teletypewriter exchange service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable percentage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “applicable percentage” means 3 percent.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of subsections (a) and (b), in the case of communications services rendered before November 1 of a calendar year for which a bill has not been rendered before the close of such year, a bill shall be treated as having been first rendered on December 31 of such year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of prepaid telephone cards</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subchapter, in the case of communications services acquired by means of a prepaid telephone card—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the face amount of such card shall be treated as the amount paid for such communications services, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> that amount shall be treated as paid when the card is transferred by any telecommunications carrier to any person who is not such a carrier.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of face amount in absence of specified dollar amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of any prepaid telephone card which entitles the user other than to a specified dollar amount of use, the face amount shall be determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prepaid telephone card</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “prepaid telephone card” means any card or any other similar arrangement which permits its holder to obtain communications services and pay for such services in advance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 503</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–859, title I, § 133(a)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1289</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–75, § 5</ref>, <date date="1959-06-30">June 30, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 158</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–564, title II, § 202(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1960-06-30">June 30, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 290</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–72, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1961-06-30">June 30, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 193</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–508, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1962-06-28">June 28, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 114</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–52, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1963-06-29">June 29, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 72</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–348, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1964-06-30">June 30, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 237</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–44, title III, § 302</ref>, title VII, § 701(b)(2)(B), <date date="1965-06-21">June 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 145</ref>, 156; <ref>Pub. L. 89–368, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-03-15">Mar. 15, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 66</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–285, § 1(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1968-04-12">Apr. 12, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 92</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–364, title I, § 105(b)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1968-06-28">June 28, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 265</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–172, title VII, § 702(b)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 660</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–614, title II, § 201(b)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 1843</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–499, title XI, § 1151</ref>, <date date="1980-12-05">Dec. 5, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 2694</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–34, title VIII, § 821</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–248, title II, § 282(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 568</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title I, § 26</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 507</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title XVIII, § 1801(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2785</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–203, title X, § 10501</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1330–438</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11217(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–437</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–34, title X, § 1034(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 937</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title VI, § 6010(i)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 815</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4252.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Local telephone service</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “local telephone service” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the access to a local telephone system, and the privilege of telephonic quality communication with substantially all persons having telephone or radio telephone stations constituting a part of such local telephone system, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any facility or service provided in connection with a service described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">The term “local telephone service” does not include any service which is a “toll telephone service” or a “private communication service” as defined in subsections (b) and (d).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Toll telephone service</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “toll telephone service” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a telephonic quality communication for which (A) there is a toll charge which varies in amount with the distance and elapsed transmission time of each individual communication and (B) the charge is paid within the United States, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a service which entitles the subscriber, upon payment of a periodic charge (determined as a flat amount or upon the basis of total elapsed transmission time), to the privilege of an unlimited number of telephonic communications to or from all or a substantial portion of the persons having telephone or radio telephone stations in a specified area which is outside the local telephone system area in which the station provided with this service is located.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Teletypewriter exchange service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “teletypewriter exchange service” means the access from a teletypewriter or other data station to the teletypewriter exchange system of which such station is a part, and the privilege of intercommunication by such station with substantially all persons having teletypewriter or other data stations constituting a part of the same teletypewriter exchange system, to which the subscriber is entitled upon payment of a charge or charges (whether such charge or charges are determined as a flat periodic amount, on the basis of distance and elapsed transmission time, or in some other manner). The term “teletypewriter exchange service” does not include any service which is “local telephone service” as defined in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Private communication service</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “private communication service” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the communication service furnished to a subscriber which entitles the subscriber—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to exclusive or priority use of any communication channel or groups of channels, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to the use of an intercommunication system for the subscriber’s stations,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">regardless of whether such channel, groups of channels, or intercommunication system may be connected through switching with a service described in subsection (a), (b), or (c),</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> switching capacity, extension lines and stations, or other associated services which are provided in connection with, and are necessary or unique to the use of, channels or systems described in paragraph (1), and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the channel mileage which connects a telephone station located outside a local telephone system area with a central office in such local telephone system,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">except that such term does not include any communication service unless a separate charge is made for such service.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 503</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–859, title I, § 133(a)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1290</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–508, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1962-06-28">June 28, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–44, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1965-06-21">June 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 145</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4253.</num>
<heading> Exemptions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain coin-operated service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Service paid for by inserting coins in coin-operated telephones available to the public shall not be subject to the tax imposed by section 4251 with respect to local telephone service, or with respect to toll telephone service if the charge for such toll telephone service is less than 25 cents; except that where such coin-operated telephone service is furnished for a guaranteed amount, the amounts paid under such guarantee plus any fixed monthly or other periodic charge shall be subject to the tax.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> News services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No tax shall be imposed under section 4251, except with respect to local telephone service, on any payment received from any person for services used in the collection of news for the public press, or a news ticker service furnishing a general news service similar to that of the public press, or radio broadcasting, or in the dissemination of news through the public press, or a news ticker service furnishing a general news service similar to that of the public press, or by means of radio broadcasting, if the charge for such service is billed in writing to such person.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International, etc., organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on any payment received for services furnished to an international organization, or to the American National Red Cross.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Servicemen in combat zone</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on any payment received for any toll telephone service which originates within a combat zone, as defined in section 112, from a member of the Armed Forces of the United States performing service in such combat zone, as determined under such section, provided a certificate, setting forth such facts as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe, is furnished to the person receiving such payment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Items otherwise taxed</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Only one payment of tax under section 4251 shall be required with respect to the tax on any service, notwithstanding the lines or stations of one or more persons are used in furnishing such service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Common carriers and communications companies</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on the amount paid for any toll telephone service described in section 4252(b)(2) to the extent that the amount so paid is for use by a common carrier, telephone or telegraph company, or radio broadcasting station or network in the conduct of its business as such.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Installation charges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on so much of any amount paid for the installation of any instrument, wire, pole, switchboard, apparatus, or equipment as is properly attributable to such installation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonprofit hospitals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on any amount paid by a nonprofit hospital for services furnished to such organization. For purposes of this subsection, the term “nonprofit hospital” means a hospital referred to in section 170(b)(1)(A)(iii) which is exempt from income tax under section 501(a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State and local governmental exemption</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, no tax shall be imposed under section 4251 upon any payment received for services or facilities furnished to the government of any State, or any political subdivision thereof, or the District of Columbia.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption for nonprofit educational organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, no tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on any amount paid by a nonprofit educational organization for services or facilities furnished to such organization. For purposes of this subsection, the term “nonprofit educational organization” means an educational organization described in section 170(b)(1)(A)(ii) which is exempt from income tax under section 501(a). The term also includes a school operated as an activity of an organization described in section 501(c)(3) which is exempt from income tax under section 501(a), if such school normally maintains a regular faculty and curriculum and normally has a regularly enrolled body of pupils or students in attendance at the place where its educational activities are regularly carried on.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption for qualified blood collector organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Under regulations provided by the Secretary, no tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on any amount paid by a qualified blood collector organization (as defined in section 7701(a)(49)) for services or facilities furnished to such organization.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(l)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Filing of exemption certificates</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In order to claim an exemption under subsection (c), (h), (i), (j), or (k), a person shall provide to the provider of communications services a statement (in such form and manner as the Secretary may provide) certifying that such person is entitled to such exemption.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration of certificate</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any statement provided under paragraph (1) shall remain in effect until—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the provider of communications services has actual knowledge that the information provided in such statement is false, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such provider is notified by the Secretary that the provider of the statement is no longer entitled to an exemption described in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">If any information provided in such statement is no longer accurate, the person providing such statement shall inform the provider of communications services within 30 days of any change of information.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 504</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–859, title I, § 133(a)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1290</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–344, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1959-09-21">Sept. 21, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 619</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–508, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1962-06-28">June 28, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–44, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1965-06-21">June 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 146</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–368, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-03-15">Mar. 15, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 66</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–172, title I, § 101(j)(27)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 529</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX</ref>, §§ 1904(a)(6), 1906(b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1811</ref>, 1834; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11217(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–438</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–280, title XII, § 1207(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1070</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4254.</num>
<heading> Computation of tax</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If a bill is rendered the taxpayer for local telephone service or toll telephone service—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the amount on which the tax with respect to such services shall be based shall be the sum of all charges for such services included in the bill; except that</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> if the person who renders the bill groups individual items for purposes of rendering the bill and computing the tax, then (A) the amount on which the tax with respect to each such group shall be based shall be the sum of all items within that group, and (B) the tax on the remaining items not included in any such group shall be based on the charge for each item separately.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Where payment is made for toll telephone service in coin-operated telephones</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the tax imposed by section 4251 with respect to toll telephone service is paid by inserting coins in coin-operated telephones, tax shall be computed to the nearest multiple of 5 cents, except that, where the tax is midway between multiples of 5 cents, the next higher multiple shall apply.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain State and local taxes not included</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, in determining the amounts paid for communications services, there shall not be included the amount of any State or local tax imposed on the furnishing or sale of such services, if the amount of such tax is separately stated in the bill.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 504</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–859, title I, § 133(a)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1291</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–44, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1965-06-21">June 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 147</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–172, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-11-12">Nov. 12, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1358</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter C—</num>
<heading>Transportation by Air</heading>
<part>
<num>PART I—</num>
<heading>PERSONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4261.</num>
<heading> Imposition of tax</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby imposed on the amount paid for taxable transportation of any person a tax equal to 7.5 percent of the amount so paid.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Domestic segments of taxable transportation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is hereby imposed on the amount paid for each domestic segment of taxable transportation by air a tax in the amount of $3.00.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Domestic segment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “domestic segment” means any segment consisting of 1 takeoff and 1 landing and which is taxable transportation described in section 4262(a)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Changes in segments by reason of rerouting</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> transportation is purchased between 2 locations on specified flights, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> there is a change in the route taken between such 2 locations which changes the number of domestic segments, but there is no change in the amount charged for such transportation,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">the tax imposed by paragraph (1) shall be determined without regard to such change in route.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of international travel facilities</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is hereby imposed a tax of $12.00 on any amount paid (whether within or without the United States) for any transportation of any person by air, if such transportation begins or ends in the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for transportation entirely taxable under subsection (a)</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">This subsection shall not apply to any transportation all of which is taxable under subsection (a) (determined without regard to sections 4281 and 4282).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for Alaska and Hawaii</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which the tax imposed by paragraph (1) applies to a domestic segment beginning or ending in Alaska or Hawaii, such tax shall apply only to departures and shall be at the rate of $6.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> By whom paid</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as provided in section 4263(a), the taxes imposed by this section shall be paid by the person making the payment subject to the tax.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Segments to and from rural airports</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception from segment tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The tax imposed by subsection (b)(1) shall not apply to any domestic segment beginning or ending at an airport which is a rural airport for the calendar year in which such segment begins or ends (as the case may be).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rural airport</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “rural airport” means, with respect to any calendar year, any airport if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> there were fewer than 100,000 commercial passengers departing by air (in the case of any airport described in clause (ii)(III), on flight segments of at least 100 miles) during the second preceding calendar year from such airport, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> such airport—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> is not located within 75 miles of another airport which is not described in clause (i),</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> is receiving essential air service subsidies as of the date of the enactment of this paragraph, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> is not connected by paved roads to another airport.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amounts paid outside the United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of amounts paid outside the United States for taxable transportation, the taxes imposed by subsections (a) and (b) shall apply only if such transportation begins and ends in the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amounts paid for right to award free or reduced rate air transportation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any amount paid (and the value of any other benefit provided) to an air carrier (or any related person) for the right to provide mileage awards for (or other reductions in the cost of) any transportation of persons by air shall be treated for purposes of subsection (a) as an amount paid for taxable transportation, and such amount shall be taxable under subsection (a) without regard to any other provision of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Controlled group</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), a corporation and all wholly owned subsidiaries of such corporation shall be treated as 1 corporation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall prescribe rules which reallocate items of income, deduction, credit, exclusion, or other allowance to the extent necessary to prevent the avoidance of tax imposed by reason of this paragraph. The Secretary may prescribe rules which exclude from the tax imposed by subsection (a) amounts attributable to mileage awards which are used other than for transportation of persons by air.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inflation adjustment of dollar rates of tax</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In the case of taxable events in a calendar year after the last nonindexed year, the $3.00 amount contained in subsection (b) and each dollar amount contained in subsection (c) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such dollar amount, multiplied by</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for such calendar year by substituting the year before the last nonindexed year for “calendar year 2016” in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">If any increase determined under the preceding sentence is not a multiple of 10 cents, such increase shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of 10 cents.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Last nonindexed year</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the last nonindexed year is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 2002 in the case of the $3.00 amount contained in subsection (b), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 1998 in the case of the dollar amounts contained in subsection (c).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxable event</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), in the case of the tax imposed by subsection (b), the beginning of the domestic segment shall be treated as the taxable event.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for amounts paid for domestic segments beginning after 2002</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If an amount is paid during a calendar year for a domestic segment beginning in a later calendar year, then the rate of tax under subsection (b) on such amount shall be the rate in effect for the calendar year in which such amount is paid.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amounts paid for aircraft management services</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">No tax shall be imposed by this section or section 4271 on any amounts paid by an aircraft owner for aircraft management services related to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> maintenance and support of the aircraft owner’s aircraft, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> flights on the aircraft owner’s aircraft.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Aircraft management services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “aircraft management services” includes—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> assisting an aircraft owner with administrative and support services, such as scheduling, flight planning, and weather forecasting,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> obtaining insurance,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> maintenance, storage and fueling of aircraft,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> hiring, training, and provision of pilots and crew,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> establishing and complying with safety standards, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> such other services as are necessary to support flights operated by an aircraft owner.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lessee treated as aircraft owner</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “aircraft owner” includes a person who leases the aircraft other than under a disqualified lease.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disqualified lease</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">For purposes of clause (i), the term “disqualified lease” means a lease from a person providing aircraft management services with respect to such aircraft (or a related person (within the meaning of section 465(b)(3)(C)) to the person providing such services), if such lease is for a term of 31 days or less.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pro rata allocation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of amounts paid to any person which (but for this subsection) are subject to the tax imposed by subsection (a), a portion of which consists of amounts described in subparagraph (A), this paragraph shall apply on a pro rata basis only to the portion which consists of amounts described in such subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption for certain uses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No tax shall be imposed under subsection (a) or (b) on air transportation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by helicopter for the purpose of transporting individuals, equipment, or supplies in the exploration for, or the development or removal of, hard minerals, oil, or gas, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by helicopter or by fixed-wing aircraft for the purpose of the planting, cultivation, cutting, or transportation of, or caring for, trees (including logging operations),</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">but only if the helicopter or fixed-wing aircraft does not take off from, or land at, a facility eligible for assistance under the Airport and Airway Development Act of 1970, or otherwise use services provided pursuant to section 44509 or 44913(b) or subchapter I of chapter 471 of title 49, United States Code, during such use. In the case of helicopter transportation described in paragraph (1), this subsection shall be applied by treating each flight segment as a distinct flight.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption for air ambulances providing certain emergency medical transportation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No tax shall be imposed under this section or section 4271 on any air transportation for the purpose of providing emergency medical services—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> by helicopter, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by a fixed-wing aircraft equipped for and exclusively dedicated on that flight to acute care emergency medical services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption for skydiving uses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No tax shall be imposed by this section or section 4271 on any air transportation exclusively for the purpose of skydiving.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption for seaplanes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No tax shall be imposed by this section or section 4271 on any air transportation by a seaplane with respect to any segment consisting of a takeoff from, and a landing on, water, but only if the places at which such takeoff and landing occur have not received and are not receiving financial assistance from the Airport and Airways Trust Fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption for aircraft in fractional ownership aircraft programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No tax shall be imposed by this section or section 4271 on any air transportation if tax is imposed under section 4043 with respect to the fuel used in such transportation. This subsection shall not apply after <date date="2028-09-30">September 30, 2028</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(k)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of taxes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The taxes imposed by this section shall apply to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> transportation beginning during the period—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> beginning on the 7th day after the date of the enactment of the Airport and Airway Trust Fund Tax Reinstatement Act of 1997, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> ending on <date date="2028-09-30">September 30, 2028</date>, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> amounts paid during such period for transportation beginning after such period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refunds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If, as of the date any transportation begins, the taxes imposed by this section would not have applied to such transportation if paid for on such date, any tax paid under paragraph (1)(B) with respect to such transportation shall be treated as an overpayment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 506</ref>; <ref>July 25, 1956, ch. 725</ref>, §§ 1, 4(b), <ref>70 Stat. 644</ref>, 646; <ref>Pub. L. 86–75, § 4</ref>, <date date="1959-06-30">June 30, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 158</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–564, title II, § 202(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1960-06-30">June 30, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 290</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–72, § 3(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1961-06-30">June 30, 1961</date>, <ref>75 Stat. 193</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–508, § 5(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1962-06-28">June 28, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–52, § 3(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1963-06-29">June 29, 1963</date>, <ref>77 Stat. 72</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 88–348, § 2(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1964-06-30">June 30, 1964</date>, <ref>78 Stat. 237</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–44, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-06-21">June 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 148</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–258, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-05-21">May 21, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1904(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1812</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–298, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-07-01">July 1, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 829</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–248, title II, § 280(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 564</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title X, § 1018(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 1021</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title XVIII, § 1878(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2903</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–223, title IV</ref>, §§ 402(a)(1), 404(a), (c), <date date="1987-12-30">Dec. 30, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1532</ref>, 1533; <ref>Pub. L. 101–239, title VII, § 7503(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2362</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11213(a)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–432</ref>, 1388–435; <ref>Pub. L. 103–272, § 5(g)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref>108 Stat. 1374</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–188, title I, § 1609(b)</ref>, (d), (e), <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1841</ref>, 1842; <ref>Pub. L. 105–2, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-02-28">Feb. 28, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 5</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–34, title X, § 1031(b)(1)</ref>, (c)(1), (2), title XIV, § 1435(a), title XVI, § 1601(f)(4)(D), <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 929</ref>, 930, 1052, 1091; <ref>Pub. L. 108–176, title IX, § 902(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-12">Dec. 12, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2598</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–59, title XI</ref>, §§ 11121(c), 11122(a), 11123(a), <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1951</ref>, 1952; <ref>Pub. L. 109–135, title IV, § 412(vv)</ref>, <date date="2005-12-21">Dec. 21, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2640</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. K, title I, § 116(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2381</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–190, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-02-28">Feb. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 643</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–253, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-06-30">June 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2417</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–330, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-09-30">Sept. 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3717</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–12, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1457</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–69, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-01">Oct. 1, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2054</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–116, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2009-12-16">Dec. 16, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 3031</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–153, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-31">Mar. 31, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1084</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–161, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-04-30">Apr. 30, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1126</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–197, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-02">July 2, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1353</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–216, title I, § 101(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-08-01">Aug. 1, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2349</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–249, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-09-30">Sept. 30, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2627</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–329, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3566</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–7, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-03-31">Mar. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 31</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–16, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-05-31">May 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 218</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–21, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-06-29">June 29, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 233</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–27, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-08-05">Aug. 5, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 270</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–30, title II, § 202(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 357</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–91, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2012-01-31">Jan. 31, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 3</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–95, title XI</ref>, §§ 1101(b)(1), 1103(c), <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 148</ref>, 151; <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(104)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4053</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–55, title II, § 202(b)(1)</ref>, (c)(2), <date date="2015-09-30">Sept. 30, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 525</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–141, title II, § 202(b)(1)</ref>, (c)(2), <date date="2016-03-30">Mar. 30, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 324</ref>, 325; <ref>Pub. L. 114–190, title I, § 1202(b)(1)</ref>, (c)(2), <date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 619</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–63, title II, § 202(b)(1)</ref>, (c)(2), <date date="2017-09-29">Sept. 29, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1171</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–97, title I</ref>, §§ 11002(d)(1)(FF), 13822(a), <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 2060</ref>, 2182; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. M, title I, § 202(b)(1)</ref>, (c)(2), div. U, title IV, § 401(b)(42), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1048</ref>, 1049, 1204; <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title VIII, § 802(b)(1)</ref>, (c)(3), <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–15, div. B, title II, § 2212(b)(1)</ref>, (c)(3), <date date="2023-09-30">Sept. 30, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 85</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–34, title II, § 202(b)(1)</ref>, (c)(3), <date date="2023-12-26">Dec. 26, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 1115</ref>, 1116; <ref>Pub. L. 118–41, title II, § 202(b)(1)</ref>, (c)(3), <date date="2024-03-08">Mar. 8, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 23</ref>, 24; <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title XIII, § 1302(b)(1)</ref>, (c)(3), <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1433</ref>, 1434.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4262.</num>
<heading> Definition of taxable transportation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxable transportation; in general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this part, except as provided in subsection (b), the term “taxable transportation” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> transportation by air which begins in the United States or in the 225–mile zone and ends in the United States or in the 225–mile zone; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of transportation by air other than transportation described in paragraph (1), that portion of such transportation which is directly or indirectly from one port or station in the United States to another port or station in the United States, but only if such portion is not a part of uninterrupted international air transportation (within the meaning of subsection (c)(3)).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exclusion of certain travel</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this part, the term “taxable transportation” does not include that portion of any transportation by air which meets all 4 of the following requirements:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> such portion is outside the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> neither such portion nor any segment thereof is directly or indirectly—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> between (i) a point where the route of the transportation leaves or enters the continental United States, or (ii) a port or station in the 225-mile zone, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a port or station in the 225-mile zone;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> such portion—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> begins at either (i) the point where the route of the transportation leaves the United States, or (ii) a port or station in the 225-mile zone, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ends at either (i) the point where the route of the transportation enters the United States, or (ii) a port or station in the 225-mile zone; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a direct line from the point (or the port or station) specified in paragraph (3)(A), to the point (or the port or station) specified in paragraph (3)(B), passes through or over a point which is not within 225 miles of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Continental United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “continental United States” means the District of Columbia and the States other than Alaska and Hawaii.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 225-mile zone</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “225-mile zone” means that portion of Canada and Mexico which is not more than 225 miles from the nearest point in the continental United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Uninterrupted international air transportation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “uninterrupted international air transportation” means any transportation by air which is not transportation described in subsection (a)(1) and in which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the scheduled interval between (i) the beginning or end of the portion of such transportation which is directly or indirectly from one port or station in the United States to another port or station in the United States and (ii) the end or beginning of the other portion of such transportation is not more than 12 hours, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the scheduled interval between the beginning or end and the end or beginning of any two segments of the portion of such transportation referred to in subparagraph (A)(i) is not more than 12 hours.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of this paragraph, in the case of personnel of the United States Army, Air Force, Navy, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard traveling in uniform at their own expense when on official leave, furlough, or pass, the scheduled interval described in subparagraph (A) shall be deemed to be not more than 12 hours if a ticket for the subsequent portion of such transportation is purchased within 12 hours after the end of the earlier portion of such transportation and the purchaser accepts and utilizes the first accommodations actually available to him for such subsequent portion.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transportation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this part, the term “transportation” includes layover or waiting time and movement of the aircraft in deadhead service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to waive 225-mile zone provisions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If the Secretary of the Treasury determines that Canada or Mexico has entered into a qualified agreement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary shall publish a notice of such determination in the Federal Register, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> effective with respect to transportation beginning after the date specified in such notice, to the extent provided in the agreement, the term “225-mile zone” shall not include part or all of the country with respect to which such determination is made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of waiver</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If a determination was made under paragraph (1) with respect to any country and the Secretary of the Treasury subsequently determines that the agreement is no longer in effect or that the agreement is no longer a qualified agreement—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the Secretary shall publish a notice of such determination in the Federal Register, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1) shall cease to apply with respect to transportation beginning after the date specified in such notice.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified agreement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “qualified agreement” means an agreement between the United States and Canada or Mexico (as the case may be)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> setting forth that portion of such country which is not to be treated as within the 225-mile zone, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> providing that the tax imposed by such country on transportation described in subparagraph (A) will be at a level which the Secretary of the Treasury determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement that agreement be submitted to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No notice may be published under paragraph (1)(A) with respect to any qualified agreement before the date 90 days after the date on which a copy of such agreement was furnished to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>July 25, 1956, ch. 725, § 3</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 644</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 86–70, § 22(b)</ref>, <date date="1959-06-25">June 25, 1959</date>, <ref>73 Stat. 146</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 86–624, § 18(a)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref>74 Stat. 416</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 87–508, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="1962-06-28">June 28, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 116</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–44, title VIII, § 803(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-06-21">June 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 160</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–258, title II, § 203(b)</ref>, <date date="1970-05-21">May 21, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–248, title II, § 281A(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 566</ref>, 567.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4263.</num>
<heading> Special rules</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments made outside the United States for prepaid orders</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the payment upon which tax is imposed by section 4261 is made outside the United States for a prepaid order, exchange order, or similar order, the person furnishing the initial transportation pursuant to such order shall collect the amount of the tax.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax deducted upon refunds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Every person who refunds any amount with respect to a ticket or order which was purchased without payment of the tax imposed by section 4261 shall deduct from the amount refundable, to the extent available, any tax due under such section as a result of the use of a portion of the transportation purchased in connection with such ticket or order, and shall report to the Secretary the amount of any such tax remaining uncollected.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment of tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Where any tax imposed by section 4261 is not paid at the time payment for transportation is made, then, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, to the extent that such tax is not collected under any other provision of this subchapter, such tax shall be paid by the carrier providing the initial segment of such transportation which begins or ends in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The tax imposed by section 4261 shall apply to any amount paid within the United States for transportation of any person by air unless the taxpayer establishes, pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary, at the time of payment for the transportation, that the transportation is not transportation in respect of which tax is imposed by section 4261.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Round trips</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In applying this subchapter to a round trip, such round trip shall be considered to consist of transportation from the point of departure to the destination, and of separate transportation thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transportation outside the northern portion of the Western Hemisphere</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In applying this subchapter to transportation any part of which is outside the northern portion of the Western Hemisphere, if the route of such transportation leaves and reenters the northern portion of the Western Hemisphere, such transportation shall be considered to consist of transportation to a point outside such northern portion, and of separate transportation thereafter. For purposes of this subsection, the term “northern portion of the Western Hemisphere” means the area lying west of the 30th meridian west of Greenwich, east of the international dateline, and north of the Equator, but not including any country of South America.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>July 25, 1956, ch. 725, § 4(a)</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 645</ref>, § 4264; amended <ref>Pub. L. 87–508, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="1962-06-28">June 28, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 117</ref>; renumbered § 4263, <ref>Pub. L. 91–258, title II, § 205(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1970-05-21">May 21, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 242</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–34, title X, § 1031(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 932</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num>PART II—</num>
<heading>PROPERTY</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4271.</num>
<heading> Imposition of tax</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby imposed upon the amount paid within or without the United States for the taxable transportation (as defined in section 4272) of property a tax equal to 6.25 percent of the amount so paid for such transportation. The tax imposed by this subsection shall apply only to amounts paid to a person engaged in the business of transporting property by air for hire.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> By whom paid</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided by paragraph (2), the tax imposed by subsection (a) shall be paid by the person making the payment subject to tax.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments made outside the United States</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If a payment subject to tax under subsection (a) is made outside the United States and the person making such payment does not pay such tax, such tax—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be paid by the person to whom the property is delivered in the United States by the person furnishing the last segment of the taxable transportation in respect of which such tax is imposed, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall be collected by the person furnishing the last segment of such taxable transportation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of amounts paid in certain cases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, in any case in which a person engaged in the business of transporting property by air for hire and one or more other persons not so engaged jointly provide services which include taxable transportation of property, and the person so engaged receives, for the furnishing of such taxable transportation, a portion of the receipts from the joint providing of such services, the amount paid for the taxable transportation shall be treated as being the sum of (1) the portion of the receipts so received, and (2) any expenses incurred by any of the persons not so engaged which are properly attributable to such taxable transportation and which are taken into account in determining the portion of the receipts so received.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of tax</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The tax imposed by subsection (a) shall apply to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> transportation beginning during the period—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> beginning on the 7th day after the date of the enactment of the Airport and Airway Trust Fund Tax Reinstatement Act of 1997, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> ending on <date date="2028-09-30">September 30, 2028</date>, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> amounts paid during such period for transportation beginning after such period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refunds</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If, as of the date any transportation begins, the taxes imposed by this section would not have applied to such transportation if paid for on such date, any tax paid under paragraph (1)(B) with respect to such transportation shall be treated as an overpayment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–258, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1970-05-21">May 21, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 239</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1904(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1812</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–298, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-07-01">July 1, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 829</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–248, title II, § 280(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 564</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–223, title IV, § 402(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-30">Dec. 30, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1532</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11213(a)(2)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–432</ref>, 1388–435; <ref>Pub. L. 104–188, title I, § 1609(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1841</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–2, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1997-02-28">Feb. 28, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 5</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–34, title X, § 1031(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 929</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–161, div. K, title I, § 116(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2381</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–190, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-02-28">Feb. 28, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 643</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–253, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-06-30">June 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 2417</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–330, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-09-30">Sept. 30, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3717</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–12, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2009-03-30">Mar. 30, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 1457</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–69, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-01">Oct. 1, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 2054</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–116, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2009-12-16">Dec. 16, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 3031</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–153, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-31">Mar. 31, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1084</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–161, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-04-30">Apr. 30, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1126</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–197, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-02">July 2, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 1353</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–216, title I, § 101(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-08-01">Aug. 1, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2349</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–249, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-09-30">Sept. 30, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 2627</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–329, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-22">Dec. 22, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3566</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–7, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-03-31">Mar. 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 31</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–16, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-05-31">May 31, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 218</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–21, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-06-29">June 29, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 233</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–27, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-08-05">Aug. 5, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 270</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–30, title II, § 202(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-16">Sept. 16, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 357</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–91, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2012-01-31">Jan. 31, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 3</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–95, title XI, § 1101(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 148</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–55, title II, § 202(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2015-09-30">Sept. 30, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 525</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–141, title II, § 202(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-03-30">Mar. 30, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 324</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–190, title I, § 1202(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 619</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–63, title II, § 202(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2017-09-29">Sept. 29, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 1171</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. M, title I, § 202(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1048</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title VIII, § 802(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 3429</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–15, div. B, title II, § 2212(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2023-09-30">Sept. 30, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 85</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–34, title II, § 202(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-26">Dec. 26, 2023</date>, <ref>137 Stat. 1115</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–41, title II, § 202(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2024-03-08">Mar. 8, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 23</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 118–63, title XIII, § 1302(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2024-05-16">May 16, 2024</date>, <ref>138 Stat. 1433</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4272.</num>
<heading> Definition of taxable transportation, etc.</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this part, except as provided in subsection (b), the term “taxable transportation” means transportation by air which begins and ends in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this part, the term “taxable transportation” does not include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> that portion of any transportation which meets the requirements of paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4) of section 4262(b), or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, transportation of property in the course of exportation (including shipment to a possession of the United States) by continuous movement, and in due course so exported.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Excess baggage of passengers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this part, the term “property” does not include excess baggage accompanying a passenger traveling on an aircraft operated on an established line.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transportation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this part, the term “transportation” includes layover or waiting time and movement of the aircraft in deadhead service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–258, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1970-05-21">May 21, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 240</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</part>
<part>
<num>PART III—</num>
<heading>SPECIAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO TAXES ON TRANSPORTATION BY AIR</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4281.</num>
<heading> Small aircraft on nonestablished lines</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The taxes imposed by sections 4261 and 4271 shall not apply to transportation by an aircraft having a maximum certificated takeoff weight of 6,000 pounds or less, except when such aircraft is operated on an established line or when such aircraft is a jet aircraft.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Maximum certificated takeoff weight</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “maximum certificated takeoff weight” means the maximum such weight contained in the type certificate or airworthiness certificate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sightseeing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, an aircraft shall not be considered as operated on an established line at any time during which such aircraft is being operated on a flight the sole purpose of which is sightseeing.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jet aircraft</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “jet aircraft” shall not include any aircraft which is a rotorcraft or propeller aircraft.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–258, title II, § 205(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1970-05-21">May 21, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 241</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 97–248, title II, § 280(c)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 564</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–59, title XI, § 11124(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-10">Aug. 10, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 1952</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–95, title XI, § 1107(a)</ref>, <date date="2012-02-14">Feb. 14, 2012</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 154</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 204(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4025</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4282.</num>
<heading> Transportation by air for other members of affiliated group</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> one member of an affiliated group is the owner or lessee of an aircraft, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such aircraft is not available for hire by persons who are not members of such group,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">no tax shall be imposed under section 4261 or 4271 upon any payment received by one member of the affiliated group from another member of such group for services furnished to such other member in connection with the use of such aircraft.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability for hire</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a), the determination of whether an aircraft is available for hire by persons who are not members of an affiliated group shall be made on a flight-by-flight basis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Affiliated group</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a), the term “affiliated group” has the meaning assigned to such term by section 1504(a), except that all corporations shall be treated as includible corporations (without any exclusion under section 1504(b)).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–258, title II, § 205(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1970-05-21">May 21, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 241</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–188, title I, § 1609(f)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-20">Aug. 20, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1842</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 4283.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11213(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–436</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</part>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>[Subchapter D—</num>
<heading>Repealed]</heading>
<section>
<num>[§§ 4286, 4287.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 89–44, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1965-06-21">June 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 148</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter E—</num>
<heading>Special Provisions Applicable to Services and Facilities Taxes</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4291.</num>
<heading> Cases where persons receiving payment must collect tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in section 4263(a), every person receiving any payment for facilities or services on which a tax is imposed upon the payor thereof under this chapter shall collect the amount of the tax from the person making such payment.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 511</ref>; <ref>July 25, 1956, ch. 725, § 4(c)</ref>, <ref>70 Stat. 646</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–859, title I, § 131(g)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1287</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–44, title III, § 305(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-06-21">June 21, 1965</date>, <ref>79 Stat. 148</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–258, title II, § 205(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1970-05-21">May 21, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 242</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 4292.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1904(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1812</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4293.</num>
<heading> Exemption for United States and possessions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury may authorize exemption from the taxes imposed by section 4041, section 4051, chapter 32 (other than the taxes imposed by sections 4064 and 4121) and subchapter B of chapter 33, as to any particular article, or service or class of articles or services, to be purchased for the exclusive use of the United States, if he determines that the imposition of such taxes with respect to such articles or services, or class of articles or services will cause substantial burden or expense which can be avoided by granting tax exemption and that full benefit of such exemption, if granted, will accrue to the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 511</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 91–258, title II, § 205(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1970-05-21">May 21, 1970</date>, <ref>84 Stat. 241</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(B)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–227, § 2(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1978-02-10">Feb. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 12</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–502, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 1697</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–618, title II, § 201(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 3184</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VI, § 6103(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3711</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11221(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–444</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(103)(B)(iii)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4053</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§§ 4294, 4295.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1904(a)(10)</ref>, (11), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1812</ref>]</heading>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>