<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 47—</num>
<heading>CERTAIN GROUP HEALTH PLANS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5000.</num>
<heading> Certain group health plans</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Imposition of tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby imposed on any employer (including a self-employed person) or employee organization that contributes to a nonconforming group health plan a tax equal to 25 percent of the employer’s or employee organization’s expenses incurred during the calendar year for each group health plan to which the employer or employee organization contributes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Group health plan and large group health plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Group health plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “group health plan” means a plan (including a self-insured plan) of, or contributed to by, an employer (including a self-employed person) or employee organization to provide health care (directly or otherwise) to the employees, former employees, the employer, others associated or formerly associated with the employer in a business relationship, or their families.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Large group health plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “large group health plan” means a plan of, or contributed to by, an employer or employee organization (including a self-insured plan) to provide health care (directly or otherwise) to the employees, former employees, the employer, others associated or formerly associated with the employer in a business relationship, or their families, that covers employees of at least one employer that normally employed at least 100 employees on a typical business day during the previous calendar year. For purposes of the preceding sentence—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all employers treated as a single employer under subsection (a) or (b) of section 52 shall be treated as a single employer,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> all employees of the members of an affiliated service group (as defined in section 414(m)) shall be treated as employed by a single employer, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> leased employees (as defined in section 414(n)(2)) shall be treated as employees of the person for whom they perform services to the extent they are so treated under section 414(n).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonconforming group health plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “nonconforming group health plan” means a group health plan or large group health plan that at any time during a calendar year does not comply with the requirements of subparagraphs (A) and (C) or subparagraph (B), respectively, of paragraph (1), or with the requirements of paragraph (2), of section 1862(b) of the Social Security Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Government entities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “employer” does not include a Federal or other governmental entity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–509, title IX, § 9319(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2012</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 101–239, title VI, § 6202(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2233</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 103–66, title XIII, § 13561(d)(2)</ref>, (e)(2)(A), <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref>107 Stat. 594</ref>, 595.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>