<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 42—</num>
<heading>PRIVATE FOUNDATIONS; AND CERTAIN OTHER TAX-EXEMPT ORGANIZATIONS</heading>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter A—</num>
<heading>Private Foundations</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4940.</num>
<heading> Excise tax based on investment income</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax-exempt foundations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby imposed on each private foundation which is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) for the taxable year, with respect to the carrying on of its activities, a tax equal to 1.39 percent of the net investment income of such foundation for the taxable year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxable foundations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is hereby imposed on each private foundation which is not exempt from taxation under section 501(a) for the taxable year, with respect to the carrying on of its activities, a tax equal to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the amount (if any) by which the sum of (A) the tax imposed under subsection (a) (computed as if such subsection applied to such private foundation for the taxable year), plus (B) the amount of the tax which would have been imposed under section 511 for the taxable year if such private foundation had been exempt from taxation under section 501(a), exceeds</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the tax imposed under subtitle A on such private foundation for the taxable year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Net investment income defined</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of subsection (a), the net investment income is the amount by which (A) the sum of the gross investment income and the capital gain net income exceeds (B) the deductions allowed by paragraph (3). Except to the extent inconsistent with the provisions of this section, net investment income shall be determined under the principles of subtitle A.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Gross investment income</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), the term “gross investment income” means the gross amount of income from interest, dividends, rents, payments with respect to securities loans (as defined in section 512(a)(5)), and royalties, but not including any such income to the extent included in computing the tax imposed by section 511. Such term shall also include income from sources similar to those in the preceding sentence.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deductions</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of paragraph (1), there shall be allowed as a deduction all the ordinary and necessary expenses paid or incurred for the production or collection of gross investment income or for the management, conservation, or maintenance of property held for the production of such income, determined with the modifications set forth in subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modifications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The deduction provided by section 167 shall be allowed, but only on the basis of the straight line method of depreciation.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The deduction for depletion provided by section 611 shall be allowed, but such deduction shall be determined without regard to section 613 (relating to percentage depletion).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Capital gains and losses</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1) in determining capital gain net income—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> There shall not be taken into account any gain or loss from the sale or other disposition of property to the extent that such gain or loss is taken into account for purposes of computing the tax imposed by section 511.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The basis for determining gain in the case of property held by the private foundation on <date date="1969-12-31">December 31, 1969</date>, and continuously thereafter to the date of its disposition shall be deemed to be not less than the fair market value of such property on <date date="1969-12-31">December 31, 1969</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Losses from sales or other dispositions of property shall be allowed only to the extent of gains from such sales or other dispositions, and there shall be no capital loss carryovers or carrybacks.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Except to the extent provided by regulation, under rules similar to the rules of section 1031 (including the exception under subsection (a)(2) thereof), no gain or loss shall be taken into account with respect to any portion of property used for a period of not less than 1 year for a purpose or function constituting the basis of the private foundation’s exemption if the entire property is exchanged immediately following such period solely for property of like kind which is to be used primarily for a purpose or function constituting the basis for such foundation’s exemption.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax-exempt income</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section, net investment income shall be determined by applying section 103 (relating to State and local bonds) and section 265 (relating to expenses and interest relating to tax-exempt income).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption for certain operating foundations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">No tax shall be imposed by this section on any private foundation which is an exempt operating foundation for the taxable year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exempt operating foundation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “exempt operating foundation” means, with respect to any taxable year, any private foundation if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such foundation is an operating foundation (as defined in section 4942(j)(3)),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such foundation has been publicly supported for at least 10 taxable years,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> at all times during the taxable year, the governing body of such foundation—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> consists of individuals at least 75 percent of whom are not disqualified individuals, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is broadly representative of the general public, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> at no time during the taxable year does such foundation have an officer who is a disqualified individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Publicly supported</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A private foundation is publicly supported for a taxable year if it meets the requirements of section 170(b)(1)(A)(vi) or 509(a)(2) for such taxable year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disqualified individual</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “disqualified individual” means, with respect to any private foundation, an individual who is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a substantial contributor to the foundation,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> an owner of more than 20 percent of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the total combined voting power of a corporation,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the profits interest of a partnership, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the beneficial interest of a trust or unincorporated enterprise,</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent3 firstIndent-1"> which is a substantial contributor to the foundation, or</continuation>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a member of the family of any individual described in clause (i) or (ii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Substantial contributor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “substantial contributor” means a person who is described in section 507(d)(2).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Family</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “family” has the meaning given to such term by section 4946(d).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Constructive ownership</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The rules of paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 4946(a) shall apply for purposes of subparagraph (B)(ii).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–172, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 498</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1901(b)(33)(N)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1802</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–345, § 2(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1978-08-15">Aug. 15, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 481</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 95–600, title V, § 520(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2884</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title III</ref>, §§ 302(a), 303(a), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 779</ref>, 781; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title XIII, § 1301(j)(6)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1832, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2658</ref>, 2851; <ref>Pub. L. 109–280, title XII, § 1221(a)(1)</ref>, (b), <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1089</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–172, § 3(f)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-29">Dec. 29, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2475</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. Q, title II, § 206(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3246</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4941.</num>
<heading> Taxes on self-dealing</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial taxes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On self-dealer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is hereby imposed a tax on each act of self-dealing between a disqualified person and a private foundation. The rate of tax shall be equal to 10 percent of the amount involved with respect to the act of self-dealing for each year (or part thereof) in the taxable period. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any disqualified person (other than a foundation manager acting only as such) who participates in the act of self-dealing. In the case of a government official (as defined in section 4946(c)), a tax shall be imposed by this paragraph only if such disqualified person participates in the act of self-dealing knowing that it is such an act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On foundation manager</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which a tax is imposed by paragraph (1), there is hereby imposed on the participation of any foundation manager in an act of self-dealing between a disqualified person and a private foundation, knowing that it is such an act, a tax equal to 5 percent of the amount involved with respect to the act of self-dealing for each year (or part thereof) in the taxable period, unless such participation is not willful and is due to reasonable cause. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any foundation manager who participated in the act of self-dealing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional taxes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On self-dealer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which an initial tax is imposed by subsection (a)(1) on an act of self-dealing by a disqualified person with a private foundation and the act is not corrected within the taxable period, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 200 percent of the amount involved. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any disqualified person (other than a foundation manager acting only as such) who participated in the act of self-dealing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On foundation manager</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which an additional tax is imposed by paragraph (1), if a foundation manager refused to agree to part or all of the correction, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 50 percent of the amount involved. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any foundation manager who refused to agree to part or all of the correction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsections (a) and (b)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint and several liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If more than one person is liable under any paragraph of subsection (a) or (b) with respect to any one act of self-dealing, all such persons shall be jointly and severally liable under such paragraph with respect to such act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> $20,000 limit for management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to any one act of self-dealing, the maximum amount of the tax imposed by subsection (a)(2) shall not exceed $20,000, and the maximum amount of the tax imposed by subsection (b)(2) shall not exceed $20,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Self-dealing</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “self-dealing” means any direct or indirect—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sale or exchange, or leasing, of property between a private foundation and a disqualified person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> lending of money or other extension of credit between a private foundation and a disqualified person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> furnishing of goods, services, or facilities between a private foundation and a disqualified person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> payment of compensation (or payment or reimbursement of expenses) by a private foundation to a disqualified person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> transfer to, or use by or for the benefit of, a disqualified person of the income or assets of a private foundation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> agreement by a private foundation to make any payment of money or other property to a government official (as defined in section 4946(c)), other than an agreement to employ such individual for any period after the termination of his government service if such individual is terminating his government service within a 90-day period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the transfer of real or personal property by a disqualified person to a private foundation shall be treated as a sale or exchange if the property is subject to a mortgage or similar lien which the foundation assumes or if it is subject to a mortgage or similar lien which a disqualified person placed on the property within the 10-year period ending on the date of the transfer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the lending of money by a disqualified person to a private foundation shall not be an act of self-dealing if the loan is without interest or other charge (determined without regard to section 7872) and if the proceeds of the loan are used exclusively for purposes specified in section 501(c)(3);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the furnishing of goods, services, or facilities by a disqualified person to a private foundation shall not be an act of self-dealing if the furnishing is without charge and if the goods, services, or facilities so furnished are used exclusively for purposes specified in section 501(c)(3);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the furnishing of goods, services, or facilities by a private foundation to a disqualified person shall not be an act of self-dealing if such furnishing is made on a basis no more favorable than that on which such goods, services, or facilities are made available to the general public;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> except in the case of a government official (as defined in section 4946(c)), the payment of compensation (and the payment or reimbursement of expenses) by a private foundation to a disqualified person for personal services which are reasonable and necessary to carrying out the exempt purpose of the private foundation shall not be an act of self-dealing if the compensation (or payment or reimbursement) is not excessive;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> any transaction between a private foundation and a corporation which is a disqualified person (as defined in section 4946(a)), pursuant to any liquidation, merger, redemption, recapitalization, or other corporate adjustment, organization, or reorganization, shall not be an act of self-dealing if all of the securities of the same class as that held by the foundation are subject to the same terms and such terms provide for receipt by the foundation of no less than fair market value;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of a government official (as defined in section 4946(c)), paragraph (1) shall in addition not apply to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> prizes and awards which are subject to the provisions of section 74(b) (without regard to paragraph (3) thereof), if the recipients of such prizes and awards are selected from the general public,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> scholarships and fellowship grants which would be subject to the provisions of section 117(a) (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Tax Reform Act of 1986) and are to be used for study at an educational organization described in section 170(b)(1)(A)(ii),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any annuity or other payment (forming part of a stock-bonus, pension, or profit-sharing plan) by a trust which is a qualified trust under section 401,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any annuity or other payment under a plan which meets the requirements of section 404(a)(2),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> any contribution or gift (other than a contribution or gift of money) to, or services or facilities made available to, any such individual, if the aggregate value of such contributions, gifts, services, and facilities to, or made available to, such individual during any calendar year does not exceed $25,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> any payment made under chapter 41 of title 5, United States Code, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> any payment or reimbursement of traveling expenses for travel solely from one point in the United States to another point in the United States, but only if such payment or reimbursement does not exceed the actual cost of the transportation involved plus an amount for all other traveling expenses not in excess of 125 percent of the maximum amount payable under <ref>section 5702 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, for like travel by employees of the United States; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<chapeau> the leasing by a disqualified person to a private foundation of office space for use by the foundation in a building with other tenants who are not disqualified persons shall not be treated as an act of self-dealing if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such leasing of office space is pursuant to a binding lease which was in effect on <date date="1969-10-09">October 9, 1969</date>, or pursuant to renewals of such a lease;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the execution of such lease was not a prohibited transaction (within the meaning of section 503(b) or any corresponding provision of prior law) at the time of such execution; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the terms of the lease (or any renewal) reflect an arm’s-length transaction.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxable period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “taxable period” means, with respect to any act of self-dealing, the period beginning with the date on which the act of self-dealing occurs and ending on the earliest of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the date of mailing a notice of deficiency with respect to the tax imposed by subsection (a)(1) under section 6212,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date on which the tax imposed by subsection (a)(1) is assessed, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the date on which correction of the act of self-dealing is completed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount involved</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “amount involved” means, with respect to any act of self-dealing, the greater of the amount of money and the fair market value of the other property given or the amount of money and the fair market value of the other property received; except that, in the case of services described in subsection (d)(2)(E), the amount involved shall be only the excess compensation. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the fair market value—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of the taxes imposed by subsection (a), shall be determined as of the date on which the act of self-dealing occurs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of the taxes imposed by subsection (b), shall be the highest fair market value during the taxable period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Correction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “correction” and “correct” mean, with respect to any act of self-dealing, undoing the transaction to the extent possible, but in any case placing the private foundation in a financial position not worse than that in which it would be if the disqualified person were dealing under the highest fiduciary standards.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–172, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 499</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX</ref>, §§ 1901(b)(8)(H), 1906(b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1795</ref>, 1834; <ref>Pub. L. 96–596, § 2(a)(1)(A)</ref>, (B), (2)(A), (3)(A), <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3469</ref>, 3471; <ref>Pub. L. 96–608, § 5</ref>, <date date="1980-12-28">Dec. 28, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3553</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–234, title I, § 107(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-01-02">Jan. 2, 1986</date>, <ref>99 Stat. 1759</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title I, § 122(a)(2)(A)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1812(b)(1), <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2110</ref>, 2833; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1001(d)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3350</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–280, title XII, § 1212(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1074</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4942.</num>
<heading> Taxes on failure to distribute income</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial tax</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is hereby imposed on the undistributed income of a private foundation for any taxable year, which has not been distributed before the first day of the second (or any succeeding) taxable year following such taxable year (if such first day falls within the taxable period), a tax equal to 30 percent of the amount of such income remaining undistributed at the beginning of such second (or succeeding) taxable year. The tax imposed by this subsection shall not apply to the undistributed income of a private foundation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> for any taxable year for which it is an operating foundation (as defined in subsection (j)(3)), or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> to the extent that the foundation failed to distribute any amount solely because of an incorrect valuation of assets under subsection (e), if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the failure to value the assets properly was not willful and was due to reasonable cause,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such amount is distributed as qualifying distributions (within the meaning of subsection (g)) by the foundation during the allowable distribution period (as defined in subsection (j)(2)),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the foundation notifies the Secretary that such amount has been distributed (within the meaning of subparagraph (B)) to correct such failure, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> such distribution is treated under subsection (h)(2) as made out of the undistributed income for the taxable year for which a tax would (except for this paragraph) have been imposed under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any case in which an initial tax is imposed under subsection (a) on the undistributed income of a private foundation for any taxable year, if any portion of such income remains undistributed at the close of the taxable period, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 100 percent of the amount remaining undistributed at such time.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Undistributed income</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “undistributed income” means, with respect to any private foundation for any taxable year as of any time, the amount by which—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the distributable amount for such taxable year, exceeds</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the qualifying distributions made before such time out of such distributable amount.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Distributable amount</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “distrib­utable amount” means, with respect to any foundation for any taxable year, an amount equal to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the sum of the minimum investment return plus the amounts described in subsection (f)(2)(C), reduced by</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the sum of the taxes imposed on such private foundation for the taxable year under subtitle A and section 4940.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Minimum investment return</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of subsection (d), the minimum investment return for any private foundation for any taxable year is 5 percent of the excess of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the aggregate fair market value of all assets of the foundation other than those which are used (or held for use) directly in carrying out the foundation’s exempt purpose, over</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the acquisition indebtedness with respect to such assets (determined under section 514(c)(1) without regard to the taxable year in which the indebtedness was incurred).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Valuation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of paragraph (1)(A), the fair market value of securities for which market quotations are readily available shall be determined on a monthly basis. For all other assets, the fair market value shall be determined at such times and in such manner as the Secretary shall by regulations prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reductions in value for blockage or similar factors</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In determining the value of any securities under this paragraph, the fair market value of such securities (determined without regard to any reduction in value) shall not be reduced unless, and only to the extent that, the private foundation establishes that as a result of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the size of the block of such securities,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the fact that the securities held are securities in a closely held corporation, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the fact that the sale of such securities would result in a forced or distress sale,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">the securities could not be liquidated within a reasonable period of time except at a price less than such fair market value. Any reduction in value allowable under this subparagraph shall not exceed 10 percent of such fair market value.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjusted net income</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Defined</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of subsection (j), the term “adjusted net income” means the excess (if any) of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the gross income for the taxable year (determined with the income modifications provided by paragraph (2)), over</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the sum of the deductions (determined with the deduction modifications provided by paragraph (3)) which would be allowed to a corporation subject to the tax imposed by section 11 for the taxable year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Income modifications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The income modifications referred to in paragraph (1)(A) are as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> section 103 (relating to State and local bonds) shall not apply,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> capital gains and losses from the sale or other disposition of property shall be taken into account only in an amount equal to any net short-term capital gain for the taxable year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> there shall be taken into account—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> amounts received or accrued as repayments of amounts which were taken into account as a qualifying distribution within the meaning of subsection (g)(1)(A) for any taxable year;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> notwithstanding subparagraph (B), amounts received or accrued from the sale or other disposition of property to the extent that the acquisition of such property was taken into account as a qualifying distribution (within the meaning of subsection (g)(1)(B)) for any taxable year; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any amount set aside under subsection (g)(2) to the extent it is determined that such amount is not necessary for the purposes for which it was set aside; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> section 483 (relating to imputed interest) shall not apply in the case of a binding contract made in a taxable year beginning before <date date="1970-01-01">January 1, 1970</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deduction modifications</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The deduction modifications referred to in paragraph (1)(B) are as follows:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> no deduction shall be allowed other than all the ordinary and necessary expenses paid or incurred for the production or collection of gross income or for the management, conservation, or maintenance of property held for the production of such income and the allowances for depreciation and depletion determined under section 4940(c)(3)(B), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> section 265 (relating to expenses and interest relating to tax-exempt interest) shall not apply.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transitional rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (2)(B), the basis (for purposes of determining gain) of property held by a private foundation on <date date="1969-12-31">December 31, 1969</date>, and continuously thereafter to the date of its disposition, shall be deemed to be not less than the fair market value of such property on <date date="1969-12-31">December 31, 1969</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualifying distributions defined</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “qualifying distribution” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any amount (including that portion of reasonable and necessary administrative expenses) paid to accomplish one or more purposes described in section 170(c)(2)(B), other than any contribution to (i) an organization controlled (directly or indirectly) by the foundation or one or more disqualified persons (as defined in section 4946) with respect to the foundation, except as provided in paragraph (3), or (ii) a private foundation which is not an operating foundation (as defined in subsection (j)(3)), except as provided in paragraph (3), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any amount paid to acquire an asset used (or held for use) directly in carrying out one or more purposes described in section 170(c)(2)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain set-asides</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Subject to such terms and conditions as may be prescribed by the Secretary, an amount set aside for a specific project which comes within one or more purposes described in section 170(c)(2)(B) may be treated as a qualifying distribution if it meets the requirements of subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">An amount set aside for a specific project shall meet the requirements of this subparagraph if at the time of the set-aside the foundation establishes to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the amount will be paid for the specific project within 5 years, and either—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> at the time of the set-aside the private foundation establishes to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the project is one which can better be accomplished by such set-aside than by immediate payment of funds, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the project will not be completed before the end of the taxable year of the foundation in which the set-aside is made,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the private foundation in each taxable year beginning after <date date="1975-12-31">December 31, 1975</date> (or after the end of the fourth taxable year following the year of its creation, whichever is later), distributes amounts, in cash or its equivalent, equal to not less than the distributable amount determined under subsection (d) (without regard to subsection (i)) for purposes described in section 170(c)(2)(B) (including but not limited to payments with respect to set-asides which were treated as qualifying distributions in one or more prior years), and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the private foundation has distributed (including but not limited to payments with respect to set-asides which were treated as qualifying distributions in one or more prior years) during the four taxable years immediately preceding its first taxable year beginning after <date date="1975-12-31">December 31, 1975</date>, or the fifth taxable year following the year of its creation, whichever is later, an aggregate amount, in cash or its equivalent, of not less than the sum of the following: 80 percent of the first preceding taxable year’s distributable amount; 60 percent of the second preceding taxable year’s distributable amount; 40 percent of the third preceding taxable year’s distributable amount; and 20 percent of the fourth preceding taxable year’s distributable amount.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain failures to distribute</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If, for any taxable year to which clause (ii)(II) of subparagraph (B) applies, the private foundation fails to distribute in cash or its equivalent amounts not less than those required by such clause and—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the failure to distribute such amounts was not willful and was due to reasonable cause, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the foundation distributes an amount in cash or its equivalent which is not less than the difference between the amounts required to be distributed under clause (ii)(II) of subparagraph (B) and the amounts actually distributed in cash or its equivalent during that taxable year within the correction period (as defined in section 4963(e)),</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">such distribution in cash or its equivalent shall be treated for the purposes of this subparagraph as made during such year.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction in distribution amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If, during the taxable years in the adjustment period for which the organization is a private foundation, the foundation distributes amounts in cash or its equivalent which exceed the amount required to be distributed under clause (ii)(II) of subparagraph (B) (including but not limited to payments with respect to set-asides which were treated as qualifying distributions in prior years), then for purposes of this subsection the distribution required under clause (ii)(II) of subparagraph (B) for the taxable year shall be reduced by an amount equal to such excess.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (D), with respect to any taxable year of a private foundation, the taxable years in the adjustment period are the taxable years (not exceeding 5) beginning after <date date="1975-12-31">December 31, 1975</date>, and immediately preceding the taxable year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">In the case of a set-aside which satisfies the requirements of clause (i) of subparagraph (B), for good cause shown, the period for paying the amount set aside may be extended by the Secretary.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain contributions to section 501(c)(3) organizations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “qualifying distribution” includes a contribution to a section 501(c)(3) organization described in paragraph (1)(A)(i) or (ii) if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> not later than the close of the first taxable year after its taxable year in which such contribution is received, such organization makes a distribution equal to the amount of such contribution and such distribution is a qualifying distribution (within the meaning of paragraph (1) or (2), without regard to this paragraph) which is treated under subsection (h) as a distribution out of corpus (or would be so treated if such section 501(c)(3) organization were a private foundation which is not an operating foundation), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the private foundation making the contribution obtains adequate records or other sufficient evidence from such organization showing that the qualifying distribution described in subparagraph (A) has been made by such organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on distributions by nonoperating private foundations to supporting organizations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of this section, the term “qualifying distribution” shall not include any amount paid by a private foundation which is not an operating foundation to—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any type III supporting organization (as defined in section 4943(f)(5)(A)) which is not a functionally integrated type III supporting organization (as defined in section 4943(f)(5)(B)), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> any organization which is described in subparagraph (B) or (C) if—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a disqualified person of the private foundation directly or indirectly controls such organization or a supported organization (as defined in section 509(f)(3)) of such organization, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines by regulations that a distribution to such organization otherwise is inappropriate.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Type I and type II supporting organizations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">An organization is described in this subparagraph if the organization meets the requirements of subparagraphs (A) and (C) of section 509(a)(3) and is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> operated, supervised, or controlled by one or more organizations described in paragraph (1) or (2) of section 509(a), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> supervised or controlled in connection with one or more such organizations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functionally integrated type III supporting organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An organization is described in this subparagraph if the organization is a functionally integrated type III supporting organization (as defined under section 4943(f)(5)(B)).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of qualifying distributions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), any qualifying distribution made during a taxable year shall be treated as made—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> first out of the undistributed income of the immediately preceding taxable year (if the private foundation was subject to the tax imposed by this section for such preceding taxable year) to the extent thereof,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> second out of the undistributed income for the taxable year to the extent thereof, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> then out of corpus.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of this paragraph, distributions shall be taken into account in the order of time in which made.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Correction of deficient distributions for prior taxable years, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of any qualifying distribution which (under paragraph (1)) is not treated as made out of the undistributed income of the immediately preceding taxable year, the foundation may elect to treat any portion of such distribution as made out of the undistributed income of a designated prior taxable year or out of corpus. The election shall be made by the foundation at such time and in such manner as the Secretary shall by regulations prescribe.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment of distributable amount where distributions during prior years have exceeded income</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If, for the taxable years in the adjustment period for which an organization is a private foundation—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the aggregate qualifying distributions treated (under subsection (h)) as made out of the undistributed income for such taxable year or as made out of corpus (except to the extent subsection (g)(3) with respect to the recipient private foundation or section 170(b)(1)(F)(ii) applies) during such taxable years, exceed</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the distributable amounts for such taxable years (determined without regard to this subsection),</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">then, for purposes of this section (other than subsection (h)), the distributable amount for the taxable year shall be reduced by an amount equal to such excess.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxable years in adjustment period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), with respect to any taxable year of a private foundation the taxable years in the adjustment period are the taxable years (not exceeding 5) immediately preceding the taxable year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(j)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxable period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “taxable period” means, with respect to the undistributed income for any taxable year, the period beginning with the first day of the taxable year and ending on the earlier of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the date of mailing of a notice of deficiency with respect to the tax imposed by subsection (a) under section 6212, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date on which the tax imposed by subsection (a) is assessed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Allowable distribution period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “allowable distribution period” means, with respect to any private foundation, the period beginning with the first day of the first taxable year following the taxable year in which the incorrect valuation (described in subsection (a)(2)) occurred and ending 90 days after the date of mailing of a notice of deficiency (with respect to the tax imposed by subsection (a)) under section 6212 extended by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any period in which a deficiency cannot be assessed under section 6213(a), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other period which the Secretary determines is reasonable and necessary to permit a distribution of undistributed income under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operating foundation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “operating foundation” means any organization—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> which makes qualifying distributions (within the meaning of paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (g)) directly for the active conduct of the activities constituting the purpose or function for which it is organized and operated equal to substantially all of the lesser of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> its adjusted net income (as defined in subsection (f)), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> its minimum investment return; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> substantially more than half of the assets of which are devoted directly to such activities or to functionally related businesses (as defined in paragraph (4)), or to both, or are stock of a corporation which is controlled by the foundation and substantially all of the assets of which are so devoted,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> which normally makes qualifying distributions (within the meaning of paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (g)) directly for the active conduct of the activities constituting the purpose or function for which it is organized and operated in an amount not less than two-thirds of its minimum investment return (as defined in subsection (e)), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> substantially all of the support (other than gross investment income as defined in section 509(e)) of which is normally received from the general public and from 5 or more exempt organizations which are not described in section 4946(a)(1)(H) with respect to each other or the recipient foundation; not more than 25 percent of the support (other than gross investment income) of which is normally received from any one such exempt organization; and not more than half of the support of which is normally received from gross investment income.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">Notwithstanding the provisions of subparagraph (A), if the qualifying distributions (within the meaning of paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (g)) of an organization for the taxable year exceed the minimum investment return for the taxable year, clause (ii) of subparagraph (A) shall not apply unless substantially all of such qualifying distributions are made directly for the active conduct of the activities constituting the purpose or function for which it is organized and operated.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functionally related business</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “functionally related business” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a trade or business which is not an unrelated trade or business (as defined in section 513), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an activity which is carried on within a larger aggregate of similar activities or within a larger complex of other endeavors which is related (aside from the need of the organization for income or funds or the use it makes of the profits derived) to the exempt purposes of the organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain elderly care facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section (but no other provisions of this title), the term “operating foundation” includes any organization which, on <date date="1969-05-26">May 26, 1969</date>, and at all times thereafter before the close of the taxable year, operated and maintained as its principal functional purpose facilities for the long-term care, comfort, maintenance, or education of permanently and totally disabled persons, elderly persons, needy widows, or children but only if such organization meets the requirements of paragraph (3)(B)(ii).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–172, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 502</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIII</ref>, §§ 1302(a), 1303(a), 1310(a), title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1713</ref>, 1715, 1729, 1834; <ref>Pub. L. 95–600, title V, § 522(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 2885</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–596, § 2(a)(1)(C)</ref>, (2)(B), (3)(B), (4)(A), <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3469–3472</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–34, title VIII, § 823(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref>95 Stat. 351</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–448, title I, § 108(b)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2391</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title III</ref>, §§ 304(a), (b), 305(b)(4), 314(a)(1), (2), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 782–784</ref>, 787; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title XIII, § 1301(j)(6)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2658</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–280, title XII</ref>, §§ 1212(b), 1244(a), <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1074</ref>, 1107; <ref>Pub. L. 110–172, § 11(a)(14)(D)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-29">Dec. 29, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2485</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(105)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4053</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4943.</num>
<heading> Taxes on excess business holdings</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial tax</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Imposition</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is hereby imposed on the excess business holdings of any private foundation in a business enterprise during any taxable year which ends during the taxable period a tax equal to 10 percent of the value of such holdings.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The tax imposed by paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be imposed on the last day of the taxable year, but</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with respect to the private foundation’s holdings in any business enterprise, shall be determined as of that day during the taxable year when the foundation’s excess holdings in such enterprise were the greatest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any case in which an initial tax is imposed under subsection (a) with respect to the holdings of a private foundation in any business enterprise, if, at the close of the taxable period with respect to such holdings, the foundation still has excess business holdings in such enterprise, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 200 percent of such excess business holdings.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Excess business holdings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “excess business holdings” means, with respect to the holdings of any private foundation in any business enterprise, the amount of stock or other interest in the enterprise which the foundation would have to dispose of to a person other than a disqualified person in order for the remaining holdings of the foundation in such enterprise to be permitted holdings.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permitted holdings in a corporation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The permitted holdings of any private foundation in an incorporated business enterprise are—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 20 percent of the voting stock, reduced by</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the percentage of the voting stock owned by all disqualified persons.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">In any case in which all disqualified persons together do not own more than 20 percent of the voting stock of an incorporated business enterprise, nonvoting stock held by the private foundation shall also be treated as permitted holdings.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 35 percent rule where third person has effective control of enterprise</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the private foundation and all disqualified persons together do not own more than 35 percent of the voting stock of an incorporated business enterprise, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> it is established to the satisfaction of the Secretary that effective control of the corporation is in one or more persons who are not disqualified persons with respect to the foundation,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">then subparagraph (A) shall be applied by substituting 35 percent for 20 percent.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 2 percent de minimis rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">A private foundation shall not be treated as having excess business holdings in any corporation in which it (together with all other private foundations which are described in section 4946(a)(1)(H)) owns not more than 2 percent of the voting stock and not more than 2 percent in value of all outstanding shares of all classes of stock.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Permitted holdings in partnerships, etc.</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The permitted holdings of a private foundation in any business enterprise which is not incorporated shall be determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary. Such regulations shall be consistent in principle with paragraphs (2) and (4), except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a partnership or joint venture, “profits interest” shall be substituted for “voting stock”, and “capital interest” shall be substituted for “nonvoting stock”,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of a proprietorship, there shall be no permitted holdings, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in any other case, “beneficial interest” shall be substituted for “voting stock”.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Present holdings</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> In applying this section with respect to the holdings of any private foundation in a business enterprise, if such foundation and all disqualified persons together have holdings in such enterprise in excess of 20 percent of the voting stock on <date date="1969-05-26">May 26, 1969</date>, the percentage of such holdings shall be substituted for “20 percent,” and for “35 percent” (if the percentage of such holdings is greater than 35 percent), wherever it appears in paragraph (2), but in no event shall the percentage so substituted be more than 50 percent.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> If the percentage of the holdings of any private foundation and all disqualified persons together in a business enterprise (or if the percentage of the holdings of the private foundation in such enterprise) decreases for any reason, clause (i) and subparagraph (D) shall, except as provided in the next sentence, be applied for all periods after such decrease by substituting such decreased percentage for the percentage held on <date date="1969-05-26">May 26, 1969</date>, but in no event shall the percentage substituted be less than 20 percent. For purposes of the preceding sentence, any decrease in percentage holdings attributable to issuances of stock (or to issuances of stock coupled with redemptions of stock) shall be disregarded so long as—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the net percentage decrease disregarded under this sentence does not exceed 2 percent, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent2">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the number of shares held by the foundation is not affected by any such issuance or redemption.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The percentage substituted under clause (i), and any percentage substituted under subparagraph (D), shall be applied both with respect to the voting stock and, separately, with respect to the value of all outstanding shares of all classes of stock.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> In the case of any merger, recapitalization, or other reorganization involving one or more business enterprises, the application of clauses (i), (ii), and (iii) shall be determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Any interest in a business enterprise which a private foundation holds on <date date="1969-05-26">May 26, 1969</date>, if the private foundation on such date has excess business holdings, shall (while held by the foundation) be treated as held by a disqualified person (rather than by the private foundation)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> during the 20-year period beginning on such date, if the private foundation and all disqualified persons have more than a 95 percent voting stock interest on such date,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> except as provided in clause (i), during the 15-year period beginning on such date, if the foundation and all disqualified persons have more than a 75 percent voting stock interest (or more than a 75 percent profits or beneficial interest in the case of any unincorporated enterprise) on such date or more than a 75 percent interest in the value of all outstanding shares of all classes of stock (or more than a 75 percent capital interest in the case of a partnership or joint venture) on such date, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> during the 10–year period beginning on such date, in any other case.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The 20-year, 15-year, and 10-year periods described in subparagraph (B) for the disposition of excess business holdings shall be suspended during the pendency of any judicial proceeding by the private foundation which is necessary to reform, or to excuse such foundation from compliance with, its governing instrument or any other instrument (as in effect on <date date="1969-05-26">May 26, 1969</date>) in order to allow disposition of such holdings.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> If, at any time during the second phase, all disqualified persons together have holdings in a business enterprise in excess of 2 percent of the voting stock of such enterprise, then subparagraph (A)(i) shall be applied by substituting for “50 percent” the following: “50 percent, of which not more than 25 percent shall be voting stock held by the private foundation”.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> If, immediately before the close of the second phase, clause (i) of this subparagraph did not apply with respect to a business enterprise, then for all periods after the close of the second phase subparagraph (A)(i) shall be applied by substituting for “50 percent” the following: “35 percent, or if at any time after the close of the second phase all disqualified persons together have had holdings in such enterprise which exceed 2 percent of the voting stock, 35 percent, of which not more than 25 percent shall be voting stock held by the private foundation”.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent1">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> For purposes of this subparagraph, the term “second phase” means the 15-year period immediately following the 20-year, 15-year, or 10-year period described in subparagraph (B), whichever applies, as modified by subparagraph (C).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Clause (ii) of subparagraph (B) shall not apply with respect to any business enterprise if before <date date="1971-01-01">January 1, 1971</date>, one or more individuals who are substantial contributors (or members of the family (within the meaning of section 4946(d)) of one or more substantial contributors) to the private foundation and who on <date date="1969-05-26">May 26, 1969</date>, held more than 15 percent of the voting stock of the enterprise elect, in such manner as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe, not to have such clause (ii) apply with respect to such enterprise.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Holdings acquired by trust or will</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Paragraph (4) (other than subparagraph (B)(i)) shall apply to any interest in a business enterprise which a private foundation acquires under the terms of a trust which was irrevocable on <date date="1969-05-26">May 26, 1969</date>, or under the terms of a will executed on or before such date, which are in effect on such date and at all times thereafter, as if such interest were held on <date date="1969-05-26">May 26, 1969</date>, except that the 15-year and 10-year periods prescribed in clauses (ii) and (iii) of paragraph (4)(B) shall commence with respect to such interest on the date of distribution under the trust or will in lieu of <date date="1969-05-26">May 26, 1969</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 5-year period to dispose of gifts, bequests, etc.</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (5), if, after <date date="1969-05-26">May 26, 1969</date>, there is a change in the holdings in a business enterprise (other than by purchase by the private foundation or by a disqualified person) which causes the private foundation to have—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> excess business holdings in such enterprise, the interest of the foundation in such enterprise (immediately after such change) shall (while held by the foundation) be treated as held by a disqualified person (rather than by the foundation) during the 5-year period beginning on the date of such change in holdings; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an increase in excess business holdings in such enterprise (determined without regard to subparagraph (A)), subparagraph (A) shall apply, except that the excess holdings immediately preceding the increase therein shall not be treated, solely because of such increase, as held by a disqualified person (rather than by the foundation).</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">In any case where an acquisition by a disqualified person would result in a substitution under clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (D) of paragraph (4), the preceding sentence shall be applied with respect to such acquisition as if it did not contain the phrase “or by a disqualified person” in the material preceding subparagraph (A).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 5-year extension of period to dispose of certain large gifts and bequests</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary may extend for an additional 5-year period the period under paragraph (6) for disposing of excess business holdings in the case of an unusually large gift or bequest of diverse business holdings or holdings with complex corporate structures if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the foundation establishes that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> diligent efforts to dispose of such holdings have been made within the initial 5-year period, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> disposition within the initial 5-year period has not been possible (except at a price substantially below fair market value) by reason of such size and complexity or diversity of such holdings,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> before the close of the initial 5-year period—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the private foundation submits to the Secretary a plan for disposing of all of the excess business holdings involved in the extension, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the private foundation submits the plan described in clause (i) to the Attorney General (or other appropriate State official) having administrative or supervisory authority or responsibility with respect to the foundation’s disposition of the excess business holdings involved and submits to the Secretary any response received by the private foundation from the Attorney General (or other appropriate State official) to such plan during such 5-year period, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines that such plan can reasonably be expected to be carried out before the close of the extension period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions; special rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Business holdings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In computing the holdings of a private foundation, or a disqualified person (as defined in section 4946) with respect thereto, in any business enterprise, any stock or other interest owned, directly or indirectly, by or for a corporation, partnership, estate, or trust shall be considered as being owned proportionately by or for its shareholders, partners, or beneficiaries. The preceding sentence shall not apply with respect to an income or remainder interest of a private foundation in a trust described in section 4947(a)(2), but only if, in the case of property transferred in trust after <date date="1969-05-26">May 26, 1969</date>, such foundation holds only an income interest or only a remainder interest in such trust.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxable period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “taxable period” means, with respect to any excess business holdings of a private foundation in a business enterprise, the period beginning on the first day on which there are excess holdings and ending on the earlier of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the date of mailing of a notice of deficiency with respect to the tax imposed by subsection (a) under section 6212 in respect of such holdings, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date on which the tax imposed by subsection (a) in respect of such holdings is assessed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Business enterprise</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “business enterprise” does not include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a functionally related business (as defined in section 4942(j)(4)), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a trade or business at least 95 percent of the gross income of which is derived from passive sources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of subparagraph (B), gross income from passive sources includes the items excluded by section 512(b)(1), (2), (3), and (5), and income from the sale of goods (including charges or costs passed on at cost to purchasers of such goods or income received in settlement of a dispute concerning or in lieu of the exercise of the right to sell such goods) if the seller does not manufacture, produce, physically receive or deliver, negotiate sales of, or maintain inventories in such goods.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disqualified person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “disqualified person” (as defined in section 4946(a)) does not include a plan described in section 4975(e)(7) with respect to the holdings of a private foundation described in paragraphs (4) and (5) of subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of tax to donor advised funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section, a donor advised fund (as defined in section 4966(d)(2)) shall be treated as a private foundation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disqualified person</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In applying this section to any donor advised fund (as so defined), the term “disqualified person” means, with respect to the donor advised fund, any person who is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> described in section 4966(d)(2)(A)(iii),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a member of the family of an individual described in subparagraph (A), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a 35-percent controlled entity (as defined in section 4958(f)(3) by substituting “persons described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 4943(e)(2)” for “persons described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1)” in subparagraph (A)(i) thereof).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Present holdings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (4), (5), and (6) of subsection (c) shall apply to donor advised funds (as so defined), except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> “the date of the enactment of this subsection” shall be substituted for “<date date="1969-05-26">May 26, 1969</date>” each place it appears in paragraphs (4), (5), and (6), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> “<date date="2007-01-01">January 1, 2007</date>” shall be substituted for “<date date="1971-01-01">January 1, 1971</date>” in paragraph (4)(E).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of tax to supporting organizations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section, an organization which is described in paragraph (3) shall be treated as a private foundation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may exempt the excess business holdings of any organization from the application of this subsection if the Secretary determines that such holdings are consistent with the purpose or function constituting the basis for its exemption under section 501.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Organizations described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An organization is described in this paragraph if such organization is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a type III supporting organization (other than a functionally integrated type III supporting organization), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an organization which meets the requirements of subparagraphs (A) and (C) of section 509(a)(3) and which is supervised or controlled in connection with one or more organizations described in paragraph (1) or (2) of section 509(a), but only if such organization accepts any gift or contribution from any person described in section 509(f)(2)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disqualified person</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In applying this section to any organization described in paragraph (3), the term “disqualified person” means, with respect to the organization—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any person who was, at any time during the 5-year period ending on the date described in subsection (a)(2)(A), in a position to exercise substantial influence over the affairs of the organization,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any member of the family (determined under section 4958(f)(4)) of an individual described in clause (i),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> any 35-percent controlled entity (as defined in section 4958(f)(3) by substituting “persons described in clause (i) or (ii) of section 4943(f)(4)(A)” for “persons described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1)” in subparagraph (A)(i) thereof),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> any person described in section 4958(c)(3)(B), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<chapeau> any organization—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> which is effectively controlled (directly or indirectly) by the same person or persons who control the organization in question, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> substantially all of the contributions to which were made (directly or indirectly) by the same person or persons described in subparagraph (B) or a member of the family (within the meaning of section 4946(d)) of such a person.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Persons described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A person is described in this subparagraph if such person is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a substantial contributor to the organization (as defined in section 4958(c)(3)(C)),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an officer, director, or trustee of the organization (or an individual having powers or responsibilities similar to those of the officers, directors, or trustees of the organization), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> an owner of more than 20 percent of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the total combined voting power of a corporation,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the profits interest of a partnership, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> the beneficial interest of a trust or unincorporated enterprise,</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent3 firstIndent-1"> which is a substantial contributor (as so defined) to the organization.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Type III supporting organization; functionally integrated type III supporting organization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Type III supporting organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “type III supporting organization” means an organization which meets the requirements of subparagraphs (A) and (C) of section 509(a)(3) and which is operated in connection with one or more organizations described in paragraph (1) or (2) of section 509(a).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functionally integrated type III supporting organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “functionally integrated type III supporting organization” means a type III supporting organization which is not required under regulations established by the Secretary to make payments to supported organizations (as defined under section 509(f)(3)) due to the activities of the organization related to performing the functions of, or carrying out the purposes of, such supported organizations.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for certain holdings of type III supporting organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “excess business holdings” shall not include any holdings of a type III supporting organization in any business enterprise if, as of <date date="2005-11-18">November 18, 2005</date>, the holdings were held (and at all times thereafter, are held) for the benefit of the community pursuant to the direction of a State attorney general or a State official with jurisdiction over such organization.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Present holdings</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (4), (5), and (6) of subsection (c) shall apply to organizations described in section 509(a)(3), except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> “the date of the enactment of this subsection” shall be substituted for “<date date="1969-05-26">May 26, 1969</date>” each place it appears in paragraphs (4), (5), and (6), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> “<date date="2007-01-01">January 1, 2007</date>” shall be substituted for “<date date="1971-01-01">January 1, 1971</date>” in paragraph (4)(E).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for certain holdings limited to independently-operated philanthropic business</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to the holdings of a private foundation in any business enterprise which meets the requirements of paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) for the taxable year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ownership</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The requirements of this paragraph are met if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> 100 percent of the voting stock in the business enterprise is held by the private foundation at all times during the taxable year, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> all the private foundation’s ownership interests in the business enterprise were acquired by means other than by purchase.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> All profits to charity</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The requirements of this paragraph are met if the business enterprise, not later than 120 days after the close of the taxable year, distributes an amount equal to its net operating income for such taxable year to the private foundation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Net operating income</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, the net operating income of any business enterprise for any taxable year is an amount equal to the gross income of the business enterprise for the taxable year, reduced by the sum of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the deductions allowed by chapter 1 for the taxable year which are directly connected with the production of such income,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the tax imposed by chapter 1 on the business enterprise for the taxable year, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> an amount for a reasonable reserve for working capital and other business needs of the business enterprise.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Independent operation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The requirements of this paragraph are met if, at all times during the taxable year—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> no substantial contributor (as defined in section 4958(c)(3)(C)) to the private foundation or family member (as determined under section 4958(f)(4)) of such a contributor is a director, officer, trustee, manager, employee, or contractor of the business enterprise (or an individual having powers or responsibilities similar to any of the foregoing),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> at least a majority of the board of directors of the private foundation are persons who are not—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> directors or officers of the business enterprise, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> family members (as so determined) of a substantial contributor (as so defined) to the private foundation, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> there is no loan outstanding from the business enterprise to a substantial contributor (as so defined) to the private foundation or to any family member of such a contributor (as so determined).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain deemed private foundations excluded</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">This subsection shall not apply to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any fund or organization treated as a private foundation for purposes of this section by reason of subsection (e) or (f),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any trust described in section 4947(a)(1) (relating to charitable trusts), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any trust described in section 4947(a)(2) (relating to split-interest trusts).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–172, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 507</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–596, § 2(a)(1)(D)</ref>, (2)(C), (3)(C), (4)(B), <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3469–3472</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title III</ref>, §§ 307(a), 308(a), 309(a), 310(a), 314(c)(1), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 784</ref>, 785, 787; <ref>Pub. L. 109–280, title XII</ref>, §§ 1212(c), 1233(a), 1243(a), <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1074</ref>, 1099, 1105; <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 220(r)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4036</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–123, div. D, title II, § 41110(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-02-09">Feb. 9, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 159</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4944.</num>
<heading> Taxes on investments which jeopardize charitable purpose</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial taxes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the private foundation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If a private foundation invests any amount in such a manner as to jeopardize the carrying out of any of its exempt purposes, there is hereby imposed on the making of such investment a tax equal to 10 percent of the amount so invested for each year (or part thereof) in the taxable period. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by the private foundation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which a tax is imposed by paragraph (1), there is hereby imposed on the participation of any foundation manager in the making of the investment, knowing that it is jeopardizing the carrying out of any of the foundation’s exempt purposes, a tax equal to 10 percent of the amount so invested for each year (or part thereof) in the taxable period, unless such participation is not willful and is due to reasonable cause. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any foundation manager who participated in the making of the investment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional taxes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the foundation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which an initial tax is imposed by subsection (a)(1) on the making of an investment and such investment is not removed from jeopardy within the taxable period, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 25 percent of the amount of the investment. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by the private foundation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which an additional tax is imposed by paragraph (1), if a foundation manager refused to agree to part or all of the removal from jeopardy, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 5 percent of the amount of the investment. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any foundation manager who refused to agree to part or all of the removal from jeopardy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for program-related investments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, investments, the primary purpose of which is to accomplish one or more of the purposes described in section 170(c)(2)(B), and no significant purpose of which is the production of income or the appreciation of property, shall not be considered as investments which jeopardize the carrying out of exempt purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsections (a) and (b)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint and several liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If more than one person is liable under subsection (a)(2) or (b)(2) with respect to any one investment, all such persons shall be jointly and severally liable under such paragraph with respect to such investment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limit for management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to any one investment, the maximum amount of the tax imposed by subsection (a)(2) shall not exceed $10,000, and the maximum amount of the tax imposed by subsection (b)(2) shall not exceed $20,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxable period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “taxable period” means, with respect to any investment which jeopardizes the carrying out of exempt purposes, the period beginning with the date on which the amount is so invested and ending on the earliest of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the date of mailing of a notice of deficiency with respect to the tax imposed by subsection (a)(1) under section 6212,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date on which the tax imposed by subsection (a)(1) is assessed, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the date on which the amount so invested is removed from jeopardy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Removal from jeopardy</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">An investment which jeopardizes the carrying out of exempt purposes shall be considered to be removed from jeopardy when such investment is sold or otherwise disposed of, and the proceeds of such sale or other disposition are not investments which jeopardize the carrying out of exempt purposes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–172, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 511</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–596, § 2(a)(1)(E)</ref>, (2)(D), (3)(D), <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3469–3471</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–280, title XII, § 1212(d)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1074</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4945.</num>
<heading> Taxes on taxable expenditures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial taxes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the foundation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is hereby imposed on each taxable expenditure (as defined in subsection (d)) a tax equal to 20 percent of the amount thereof. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by the private foundation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is hereby imposed on the agreement of any foundation manager to the making of an expenditure, knowing that it is a taxable expenditure, a tax equal to 5 percent of the amount thereof, unless such agreement is not willful and is due to reasonable cause. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any foundation manager who agreed to the making of the expenditure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional taxes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the foundation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which an initial tax is imposed by subsection (a)(1) on a taxable expenditure and such expenditure is not corrected within the taxable period, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 100 percent of the amount of the expenditure. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by the private foundation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which an additional tax is imposed by paragraph (1), if a foundation manager refused to agree to part or all of the correction, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 50 percent of the amount of the taxable expenditure. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any foundation manager who refused to agree to part or all of the correction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsections (a) and (b)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint and several liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If more than one person is liable under subsection (a)(2) or (b)(2) with respect to the making of a taxable expenditure, all such persons shall be jointly and severally liable under such paragraph with respect to such expenditure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limit for management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to any one taxable expenditure, the maximum amount of the tax imposed by subsection (a)(2) shall not exceed $10,000, and the maximum amount of the tax imposed by subsection (b)(2) shall not exceed $20,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxable expenditure</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “taxable expenditure” means any amount paid or incurred by a private foundation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to carry on propaganda, or otherwise to attempt, to influence legislation, within the meaning of subsection (e),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> except as provided in subsection (f), to influence the outcome of any specific public election, or to carry on, directly or indirectly, any voter registration drive,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> as a grant to an individual for travel, study, or other similar purposes by such individual, unless such grant satisfies the requirements of subsection (g),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<chapeau> as a grant to an organization unless—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> such organization—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is described in paragraph (1) or (2) of section 509(a),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is an organization described in section 509(a)(3) (other than an organization described in clause (i) or (ii) of section 4942(g)(4)(A)), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is an exempt operating foundation (as defined in section 4940(d)(2)), or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the private foundation exercises expenditure responsibility with respect to such grant in accordance with subsection (h), or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> for any purpose other than one specified in section 170(c)(2)(B).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Activities within subsection (d)(1)</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (d)(1), the term “taxable expenditure” means any amount paid or incurred by a private foundation for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any attempt to influence any legislation through an attempt to affect the opinion of the general public or any segment thereof, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any attempt to influence legislation through communication with any member or employee of a legislative body, or with any other government official or employee who may participate in the formulation of the legislation (except technical advice or assistance provided to a governmental body or to a committee or other subdivision thereof in response to a written request by such body or subdivision, as the case may be),</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">other than through making available the results of nonpartisan analysis, study, or research. Paragraph (2) of this subsection shall not apply to any amount paid or incurred in connection with an appearance before, or communication to, any legislative body with respect to a possible decision of such body which might affect the existence of the private foundation, its powers and duties, its tax-exempt status, or the deduction of contributions to such foundation.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonpartisan activities carried on by certain organizations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subsection (d)(2) shall not apply to any amount paid or incurred by any organization—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> which is described in section 501(c)(3) and exempt from taxation under section 501(a),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the activities of which are nonpartisan, are not confined to one specific election period, and are carried on in 5 or more States,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> substantially all of the income of which is expended directly for the active conduct of the activities constituting the purpose or function for which it is organized and operated,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> substantially all of the support (other than gross investment income as defined in section 509(e)) of which is received from exempt organizations, the general public, governmental units described in section 170(c)(1), or any combination of the foregoing; not more than 25 percent of such support is received from any one exempt organization (for this purpose treating private foundations which are described in section 4946(a)(1)(H) with respect to each other as one exempt organization); and not more than half of the support of which is received from gross investment income, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> contributions to which for voter registration drives are not subject to conditions that they may be used only in specified States, possessions of the United States, or political subdivisions or other areas of any of the foregoing, or the District of Columbia, or that they may be used in only one specific election period.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">In determining whether the organization meets the requirements of paragraph (4) for any taxable year of such organization, there shall be taken into account the support received by such organization during such taxable year and during the immediately preceding 4 taxable years of such organization. Subsection (d)(4) shall not apply to any grant to an organization which meets the requirements of this subsection.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Individual grants</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subsection (d)(3) shall not apply to an individual grant awarded on an objective and nondiscriminatory basis pursuant to a procedure approved in advance by the Secretary, if it is demonstrated to the satisfaction of the Secretary that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the grant constitutes a scholarship or fellowship grant which would be subject to the provisions of section 117(a) (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Tax Reform Act of 1986) and is to be used for study at an educational organization described in section 170(b)(1)(A)(ii),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the grant constitutes a prize or award which is subject to the provisions of section 74(b) (without regard to paragraph (3) thereof), if the recipient of such prize or award is selected from the general public, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the purpose of the grant is to achieve a specific objective, produce a report or other similar product, or improve or enhance a literary, artistic, musical, scientific, teaching, or other similar capacity, skill, or talent of the grantee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expenditure responsibility</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The expenditure responsibility referred to in subsection (d)(4) means that the private foundation is responsible to exert all reasonable efforts and to establish adequate procedures—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to see that the grant is spent solely for the purpose for which made,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to obtain full and complete reports from the grantee on how the funds are spent, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to make full and detailed reports with respect to such expenditures to the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Correction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “correction” and “correct” mean, with respect to any taxable expenditure, (A) recovering part or all of the expenditure to the extent recovery is possible, and where full recovery is not possible such additional corrective action as is prescribed by the Secretary by regulations, or (B) in the case of a failure to comply with subsection (h)(2) or (h)(3), obtaining or making the report in question.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxable period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “taxable period” means, with respect to any taxable expenditure, the period beginning with the date on which the taxable expenditure occurs and ending on the earlier of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the date of mailing a notice of deficiency with respect to the tax imposed by subsection (a)(1) under section 6212, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date on which the tax imposed by subsection (a)(1) is assessed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–172, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 512</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX</ref>, §§ 1901(b)(8)(H), 1906(b)(13(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1795</ref>, 1834; <ref>Pub. L. 96–596, § 2(a)(1)(F)</ref>, (2)(E), <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3469</ref>, 3470; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title III, § 302(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 780</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title I, § 122(a)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2110</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1001(d)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3350</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–280, title XII</ref>, §§ 1212(e), 1244(b), <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1074</ref>, 1107; <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(106)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4053</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4946.</num>
<heading> Definitions and special rules</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disqualified person</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “disqualified person” means, with respect to a private foundation, a person who is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a substantial contributor to the foundation,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a foundation manager (within the meaning of subsection (b)(1)),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> an owner of more than 20 percent of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the total combined voting power of a corporation,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the profits interest of a partnership, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the beneficial interest of a trust or unincorporated enterprise,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">which is a substantial contributor to the foundation,</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> a member of the family (as defined in subsection (d)) of any individual described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> a corporation of which persons described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) own more than 35 percent of the total combined voting power,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a partnership in which persons described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) own more than 35 percent of the profits interest,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> a trust or estate in which persons described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) hold more than 35 percent of the beneficial interest,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<chapeau> only for purposes of section 4943, a private foundation—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> which is effectively controlled (directly or indirectly) by the same person or persons who control the private foundation in question, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> substantially all of the contributions to which were made (directly or indirectly) by the same person or persons described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C), or members of their families (within the meaning of subsection (d)), who made (directly or indirectly) substantially all of the contributions to the private foundation in question, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> only for purposes of section 4941, a government official (as defined in subsection (c)).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Substantial contributors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), the term “substantial contributor” means a person who is described in section 507(d)(2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Stockholdings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of paragraphs (1)(C)(i) and (1)(E), there shall be taken into account indirect stockholdings which would be taken into account under section 267(c), except that, for purposes of this paragraph, section 267(c)(4) shall be treated as providing that the members of the family of an individual are the members within the meaning of subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partnerships; trusts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of paragraphs (1)(C)(ii) and (iii), (1)(F), and (1)(G), the ownership of profits or beneficial interests shall be determined in accordance with the rules for constructive ownership of stock provided in section 267(c) (other than paragraph (3) thereof), except that section 267(c)(4) shall be treated as providing that the members of the family of an individual are the members within the meaning of subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foundation manager</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “foundation manager” means, with respect to any private foundation—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an officer, director, or trustee of a foundation (or an individual having powers or responsibilities similar to those of officers, directors, or trustees of the foundation), and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> with respect to any act (or failure to act), the employees of the foundation having authority or responsibility with respect to such act (or failure to act).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Government official</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a)(1)(I) and section 4941, the term “government official” means, with respect to an act of self-dealing described in section 4941, an individual who, at the time of such act, holds any of the following offices or positions (other than as a “special Government employee”, as defined in <ref>section 202(a) of title 18</ref>, United States Code):</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an elective public office in the executive or legislative branch of the Government of the United States,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> an office in the executive or judicial branch of the Government of the United States, appointment to which was made by the President,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<chapeau> a position in the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of the Government of the United States—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> which is listed in schedule C of rule VI of the Civil Service Rules, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the compensation for which is equal to or greater than the lowest rate of basic pay for the Senior Executive Service under <ref>section 5382 of title 5</ref>, United States Code,</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> a position under the House of Representatives or the Senate of the United States held by an individual receiving gross compensation at an annual rate of $15,000 or more,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> an elective or appointive public office in the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of the government of a State, possession of the United States, or political subdivision or other area of any of the foregoing, or of the District of Columbia, held by an individual receiving gross compensation at an annual rate of $20,000 or more,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> a position as personal or executive assistant or secretary to any of the foregoing, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> a member of the Internal Revenue Service Oversight Board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Members of family</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a)(1), the family of any individual shall include only his spouse, ancestors, children, grandchildren, great grandchildren, and the spouses of children, grandchildren, and great grandchildren.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–172, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 515</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 95–227, § 4(c)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1978-02-10">Feb. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 22</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title III, § 306(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 784</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title XVI, § 1606(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2771</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title I, § 1101(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 696</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(7) [title III, § 319(16)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref>114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–647.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4947.</num>
<heading> Application of taxes to certain nonexempt trusts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of tax</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Charitable trusts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of part II of subchapter F of chapter 1 (other than section 508(a), (b), and (c)) and for purposes of this chapter, a trust which is not exempt from taxation under section 501(a), all of the unexpired interests in which are devoted to one or more of the purposes described in section 170(c)(2)(B), and for which a deduction was allowed under section 170, 545(b)(2), 642(c), 2055, 2106(a)(2), or 2522 (or the corresponding provisions of prior law), shall be treated as an organization described in section 501(c)(3). For purposes of section 509(a)(3)(A), such a trust shall be treated as if organized on the day on which it first becomes subject to this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Split-interest trusts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of a trust which is not exempt from tax under section 501(a), not all of the unexpired interests in which are devoted to one or more of the purposes described in section 170(c)(2)(B), and which has amounts in trust for which a deduction was allowed under section 170, 545(b)(2), 642(c), 2055, 2106(a)(2), or 2522, section 507 (relating to termination of private foundation status), section 508(e) (relating to governing instruments) to the extent applicable to a trust described in this paragraph, section 4941 (relating to taxes on self-dealing), section 4943 (relating to taxes on excess business holdings) except as provided in subsection (b)(3), section 4944 (relating to investments which jeopardize charitable purpose) except as provided in subsection (b)(3), and section 4945 (relating to taxes on taxable expenditures) shall apply as if such trust were a private foundation. This paragraph shall not apply with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any amounts payable under the terms of such trust to income beneficiaries, unless a deduction was allowed under section 170(f)(2)(B), 2055(e)(2)(B), or 2522(c)(2)(B),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any amounts in trust other than amounts for which a deduction was allowed under section 170, 545(b)(2), 642(c), 2055, 2106(a)(2), or 2522, if such other amounts are segregated from amounts for which no deduction was allowable, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any amounts transferred in trust before <date date="1969-05-27">May 27, 1969</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Segregated amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (2)(B), a trust with respect to which amounts are segregated shall separately account for the various income, deduction, and other items properly attributable to each of such segregated amounts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limit to segregated amounts</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If any amounts in the trust are segregated within the meaning of subsection (a)(2)(B) of this section, the value of the net assets for purposes of subsections (c)(2) and (g) of section 507 shall be limited to such segregated amounts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sections 4943 and 4944</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Sections 4943 and 4944 shall not apply to a trust which is described in subsection (a)(2) if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> all the income interest (and none of the remainder interest) of such trust is devoted solely to one or more of the purposes described in section 170(c)(2)(B), and all amounts in such trust for which a deduction was allowed under section 170, 545(b)(2), 642(c), 2055, 2106(a)(2), or 2522 have an aggregate value not more than 60 percent of the aggregate fair market value of all amounts in such trusts, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a deduction was allowed under section 170, 545(b)(2), 642(c), 2055, 2106(a)(2), or 2522 for amounts payable under the terms of such trust to every remainder beneficiary but not to any income beneficiary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Section 507</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The provisions of section 507(a) shall not apply to a trust which is described in subsection (a)(2) by reason of a distribution of qualified employer securities (as defined in section 664(g)(4)) to an employee stock ownership plan (as defined in section 4975(e)(7)) in a qualified gratuitous transfer (as defined by section 664(g)).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–172, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 517</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–34, title XV, § 1530(c)(9)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1079</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–16, title V, § 542(e)(4)</ref>, <date date="2001-06-07">June 7, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 85</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–357, title IV, § 413(c)(30)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1509</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–312, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-12-17">Dec. 17, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3300</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4948.</num>
<heading> Application of taxes and denial of exemption with respect to certain foreign organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax on income of certain foreign organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In lieu of the tax imposed by section 4940, there is hereby imposed for each taxable year on the gross investment income (within the meaning of section 4940(c)(2)) derived from sources within the United States (within the meaning of section 861) by every foreign organization which is a private foundation for the taxable year a tax equal to 4 percent of such income.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain sections inapplicable</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Section 507 (relating to termination of private foundation status), section 508 (relating to special rules with respect to section 501(c)(3) organizations), and this chapter (other than this section) shall not apply to any foreign organization which has received substantially all of its support (other than gross investment income) from sources outside the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Denial of exemption to foreign organizations engaged in prohibited transactions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A foreign organization described in subsection (b) shall not be exempt from taxation under section 501(a) if it has engaged in a prohibited transaction after <date date="1969-12-31">December 31, 1969</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibited transactions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “prohibited transaction” means any act or failure to act (other than with respect to section 4942(e)) which would subject a foreign organization described in subsection (b), or a disqualified person (as defined in section 4946) with respect thereto, to liability for a penalty under section 6684 or a tax under section 507 if such foreign organization were a domestic organization.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxable years affected</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a foreign organization described in subsection (b) shall be denied exemption from taxation under section 501(a) by reason of paragraph (1) for all taxable years beginning with the taxable year during which it is notified by the Secretary that it has engaged in a prohibited transaction. The Secretary shall publish such notice in the Federal Register on the day on which he so notifies such foreign organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, any foreign organization described in subsection (b) which is denied exemption from taxation under section 501(a) by reason of paragraph (1) may, with respect to the second taxable year following the taxable year in which notice is given under subparagraph (A) (or any taxable year thereafter), file claim for exemption from taxation under section 501(a). If the Secretary is satisfied that such organization will not knowingly again engage in a prohibited transaction, such organization shall not, with respect to taxable years beginning with the taxable year with respect to which such claim is filed, be denied exemption from taxation under section 501(a) by reason of any prohibited transaction which was engaged in before the date on which such notice was given under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disallowance of certain charitable deductions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">No gift or bequest shall be allowed as a deduction under section 170, 545(b)(2), 642(c), 2055, 2106(a)(2), or 2522, if made—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to a foreign organization described in subsection (b) after the date on which the Secretary publishes notice under paragraph (3)(A) that he has notified such organization that it has engaged in a prohibited transaction, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in a taxable year of such organization for which it is not exempt from taxation under section 501(a) by reason of paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 91–172, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref>83 Stat. 518</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–357, title IV, § 413(c)(30)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1509</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter B—</num>
<heading>Black Lung Benefit Trusts</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4951.</num>
<heading> Taxes on self-dealing</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial taxes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On self-dealer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is hereby imposed a tax on each act of self-dealing between a disqualified person and a trust described in section 501(c)(21). The rate of tax shall be equal to 10 percent of the amount involved with respect to the act of self-dealing for each year (or part thereof) in the taxable period. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any disqualified person (other than a trustee acting only as a trustee of the trust) who participates in the act of self-dealing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On trustee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which a tax is imposed by paragraph (1), there is hereby imposed on the participation of any trustee of such a trust in an act of self-dealing between a disqualified person and the trust, knowing that it is such an act, a tax equal to 2½ percent of the amount involved with respect to the act of self-dealing for each year (or part thereof) in the taxable period, unless such participation is not willful and is due to reasonable cause. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any such trustee who participated in the act of self-dealing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional taxes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On self-dealer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which an initial tax is imposed by subsection (a)(1) on an act of self-dealing by a disqualified person with a trust described in section 501(c)(21) and in which the act is not corrected within the taxable period, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 100 percent of the amount involved. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any disqualified person (other than a trustee acting only as a trustee of such a trust) who participated in the act of self-dealing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On trustee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which an additional tax is imposed by paragraph (1), if a trustee of such a trust refused to agree to part or all of the correction, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 50 percent of the amount involved. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any such trustee who refused to agree to part or all of the correction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint and several liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If more than one person is liable under any paragraph of subsection (a) or (b) with respect to any one act of self-dealing, all such persons shall be jointly and severally liable under such paragraph with respect to such act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Self-dealing</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “self-dealing” means any direct or indirect—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> sale, exchange, or leasing of real or personal property between a trust described in section 501(c)(21) and a disqualified person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> lending of money or other extension of credit between such a trust and a disqualified person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> furnishing of goods, services, or facilities between such a trust and a disqualified person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> payment of compensation (or payment or reimbursement of expenses) by such a trust to a disqualified person; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> transfer to, or use by or for the benefit of, a disqualified person of the income or assets of such a trust.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the transfer of personal property by a disqualified person to such a trust shall be treated as a sale or exchange if the property is subject to a mortgage or similar lien;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the furnishing of goods, services, or facilities by a disqualified person to such a trust shall not be an act of self-dealing if the furnishing is without charge and if the goods, services, or facilities so furnished are used exclusively for the purposes specified in section 501(c)(21)(A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the payment of compensation (and the payment or reimbursement of expenses) by such a trust to a disqualified person for personal services which are reasonable and necessary to carrying out the exempt purpose of the trust shall not be an act of self-dealing if the compensation (or payment or reimbursement) is not excessive.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxable period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “taxable period” means, with respect to any act of self-dealing, the period beginning with the date on which the act of self-dealing occurs and ending on the earliest of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the date of mailing a notice of deficiency with respect to the tax imposed by subsection (a)(1) under section 6212,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date on which the tax imposed by subsection (a)(1) is assessed, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the date on which correction of the act of self-dealing is completed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount involved</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “amount involved” means, with respect to any act of self-dealing, the greater of the amount of money and the fair market value of the other property given or the amount of money and the fair market value of the other property received; except that in the case of services described in subsection (d)(2)(C), the amount involved shall be only the excess compensation. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the fair market value—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of the taxes imposed by subsection (a), shall be determined as of the date on which the act of self-dealing occurs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of taxes imposed by subsection (b), shall be the highest fair market value during the taxable period.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Correction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “correction” and “correct” mean, with respect to any act of self-dealing, undoing the transaction to the extent possible, but in any case placing the trust in a financial position not worse than that in which it would be if the disqualified person were dealing under the highest fiduciary standards.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disqualified person</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “disqualified person” means, with respect to a trust described in section 501(c)(21), a person who is—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a contributor to the trust,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a trustee of the trust,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> an owner of more than 10 percent of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the total combined voting power of a corporation,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the profits interest of a partnership, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> the beneficial interest of a trust or unincorporated enterprise,</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">which is a contributor to the trust,</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> an officer, director, or employee of a person who is a contributor to the trust,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the spouse, ancestor, lineal descend­ant, or spouse of a lineal descendant of an individual described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> a corporation of which persons described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), or (E) own more than 35 percent of the total combined voting power,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> a partnership in which persons described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), or (E), own more than 35 percent of the profits interest, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> a trust or estate in which persons described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), or (E), hold more than 35 percent of the beneficial interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of subparagraphs (C)(i) and (F), there shall be taken into account indirect stockholdings which would be taken into account under section 267(c), except that, for purposes of this paragraph, section 267(c)(4) shall be treated as providing that the members of the family of an individual are only those individuals described in subparagraph (E) of this paragraph. For purposes of subparagraphs (C) (ii) and (iii), (G), and (H), the ownership of profits or beneficial interests shall be determined in accordance with the rules for constructive ownership of stock provided in section 267(c) (other than paragraph (3) thereof), except that section 267(c)(4) shall be treated as providing that the members of the family of an individual are only those individuals described in subparagraph (E) of this paragraph.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payments of benefits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, a payment, out of assets or income of a trust described in section 501(c)(21), for the purposes described in subclause (I) or (IV) of section 501(c)(21)(A)(i) shall not be considered an act of self-dealing.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–227, § 4(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-02-10">Feb. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 18</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–596, § 2(a)(1)(G)</ref>, (H), (2)(F), (3)(E), <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3469–3471</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–486, title XIX, § 1940(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref>106 Stat. 3035</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4952.</num>
<heading> Taxes on taxable expenditures</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax imposed</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is hereby imposed on each taxable expenditure (as defined in subsection (d)) from the assets or income of a trust described in section 501(c)(21) a tax equal to 10 percent of the amount thereof. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by the trustee out of the assets of the trust.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the trustee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is hereby imposed on the agreement of any trustee of such a trust to the making of an expenditure, knowing that it is a taxable expenditure, a tax equal to 2½ percent of the amount thereof, unless such agreement is not willful and is due to reasonable cause. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by the trustee who agreed to the making of the expenditure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional taxes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which an initial tax is imposed by subsection (a)(1) on a taxable expenditure and such expenditure is not corrected within the taxable period, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 100 percent of the amount of the expenditure. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by the trustee out of the assets of the trust.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the trustee</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which an additional tax is imposed by paragraph (1), if a trustee refused to agree to a part or all of the correction, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 50 percent of the amount of the taxable expenditure. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any trustee who refused to agree to part or all of the correction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint and several liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of subsections (a) and (b), if more than one person is liable under subsection (a)(2) or (b)(2) with respect to the making of a taxable expenditure, all such persons shall be jointly and severally liable under such paragraph with respect to such expenditure.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxable expenditure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “taxable expenditure” means any amount paid or incurred by a trust described in section 501(c)(21) other than for a purpose specified in such section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Correction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “correction” and “correct” mean, with respect to any taxable expenditure, recovering part or all of the expenditure to the extent recovery is possible, and where full recovery is not possible, contributions by the person or persons whose liabilities for black lung benefit claims (as defined in section 192(e)) are to be paid out of the trust to the extent necessary to place the trust in a financial position not worse than that in which it would be if the taxable expenditure had not been made.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxable period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “taxable period” means, with respect to any taxable expenditure, the period beginning with the date on which the taxable expenditure occurs and ending on the earlier of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the date of mailing a notice of deficiency with respect to the tax imposed by subsection (a)(1) under section 6212, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date on which the tax imposed by subsection (a)(1) is assessed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–227, § 4(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-02-10">Feb. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 21</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 96–596, § 2(a)(1)(I)</ref>, (2)(G), <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3469</ref>, 3471.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4953.</num>
<heading> Tax on excess contributions to black lung benefit trusts</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax imposed</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby imposed for each taxable year a tax in an amount equal to 5 percent of the amount of the excess contributions made by a person to or under a trust or trusts described in section 501(c)(21). The tax imposed by this subsection shall be paid by the person making the excess contribution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Excess contribution</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “excess contribution” means the sum of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the amount by which the amount contributed for the taxable year to a trust or trusts described in section 501(c)(21) exceeds the amount of the deduction allowable to such person for such contributions for the taxable year under section 192, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> the amount determined under this subsection for the preceding taxable year, reduced by the sum of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the excess of the maximum amount allowable as a deduction under section 192 for the taxable year over the amount contributed to the trust or trusts for the taxable year, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> amounts distributed from the trust to the contributor which were excess contributions for the preceding taxable year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of withdrawal of excess contributions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Amounts distributed during the taxable year from a trust described in section 501(c)(21) to the contributor thereof the sum of which does not exceed the amount of the excess contribution made by the contributor shall not be treated as—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an act of self-dealing (within the meaning of section 4951),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a taxable expenditure (within the meaning of section 4952), or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an act contrary to the purposes for which the trust is exempt from taxation under section 501(a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 95–227, § 4(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-02-10">Feb. 10, 1978</date>, <ref>92 Stat. 22</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter C—</num>
<heading>Political Expenditures of Section 501(c)(3) Organizations</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4955.</num>
<heading> Taxes on political expenditures of section 501(c)(3) organizations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial taxes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is hereby imposed on each political expenditure by a section 501(c)(3) organization a tax equal to 10 percent of the amount thereof. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by the organization.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is hereby imposed on the agreement of any organization manager to the making of any expenditure, knowing that it is a political expenditure, a tax equal to 2½ percent of the amount thereof, unless such agreement is not willful and is due to reasonable cause. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any organization manager who agreed to the making of the expenditure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional taxes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which an initial tax is imposed by subsection (a)(1) on a political expenditure and such expenditure is not corrected within the taxable period, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 100 percent of the amount of the expenditure. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by the organization.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which an additional tax is imposed by paragraph (1), if an organization manager refused to agree to part or all of the correction, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 50 percent of the amount of the political expenditure. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any organization manager who refused to agree to part or all of the correction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsections (a) and (b)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint and several liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If more than 1 person is liable under subsection (a)(2) or (b)(2) with respect to the making of a political expenditure, all such persons shall be jointly and severally liable under such subsection with respect to such expenditure.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limit for management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to any 1 political expenditure, the maximum amount of the tax imposed by subsection (a)(2) shall not exceed $5,000, and the maximum amount of the tax imposed by subsection (b)(2) shall not exceed $10,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Political expenditure</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “political expenditure” means any amount paid or incurred by a section 501(c)(3) organization in any participation in, or intervention in (including the publication or distribution of statements), any political campaign on behalf of (or in opposition to) any candidate for public office.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain other expenditures included</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of an organization which is formed primarily for purposes of promoting the candidacy (or prospective candidacy) of an individual for public office (or which is effectively controlled by a candidate or prospective candidate and which is availed of primarily for such purposes), the term “political expenditure” includes any of the following amounts paid or incurred by the organization:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Amounts paid or incurred to such individual for speeches or other services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Travel expenses of such individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Expenses of conducting polls, surveys, or other studies, or preparing papers or other materials, for use by such individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Expenses of advertising, publicity, and fundraising for such individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Any other expense which has the primary effect of promoting public recognition, or otherwise primarily accruing to the benefit, of such individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with sections 4945 and 4958</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If tax is imposed under this section with respect to any political expenditure, such expenditure shall not be treated as a taxable expenditure for purposes of section 4945 or an excess benefit for purposes of section 4958.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Section 501(c)(3) organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “section 501(c)(3) organization” means any organization which (without regard to any political expenditure) would be described in section 501(c)(3) and exempt from taxation under section 501(a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Organization manager</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “organization manager” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any officer, director, or trustee of the organization (or individual having powers or responsibilities similar to those of officers, directors, or trustees of the organization), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with respect to any expenditure, any employee of the organization having authority or responsibility with respect to such expenditure.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Correction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “correction” and “correct” mean, with respect to any political expenditure, recovering part or all of the expenditure to the extent recovery is possible, establishment of safeguards to prevent future political expenditures, and where full recovery is not possible, such additional corrective action as is prescribed by the Secretary by regulations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxable period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “taxable period” means, with respect to any political expenditure, the period beginning with the date on which the political expenditure occurs and ending on the earlier of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the date of mailing a notice of deficiency under section 6212 with respect to the tax imposed by subsection (a)(1), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date on which tax imposed by subsection (a)(1) is assessed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–203, title X, § 10712(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1330–465</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–168, title XIII, § 1311(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-07-30">July 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1478</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter D—</num>
<heading>Failure by Certain Charitable Organizations To Meet Certain Qualification Requirements</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4958.</num>
<heading> Taxes on excess benefit transactions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial taxes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the disqualified person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is hereby imposed on each excess benefit transaction a tax equal to 25 percent of the excess benefit. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any disqualified person referred to in subsection (f)(1) with respect to such transaction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In any case in which a tax is imposed by paragraph (1), there is hereby imposed on the participation of any organization manager in the excess benefit transaction, knowing that it is such a transaction, a tax equal to 10 percent of the excess benefit, unless such participation is not willful and is due to reasonable cause. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any organization manager who participated in the excess benefit transaction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional tax on the disqualified person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In any case in which an initial tax is imposed by subsection (a)(1) on an excess benefit transaction and the excess benefit involved in such transaction is not corrected within the taxable period, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 200 percent of the excess benefit involved. The tax imposed by this subsection shall be paid by any disqualified person referred to in subsection (f)(1) with respect to such transaction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Excess benefit transaction; excess benefit</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Excess benefit transaction</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “excess benefit transaction” means any transaction in which an economic benefit is provided by an applicable tax-exempt organization directly or indirectly to or for the use of any disqualified person if the value of the economic benefit provided exceeds the value of the consideration (including the performance of services) received for providing such benefit. For purposes of the preceding sentence, an economic benefit shall not be treated as consideration for the performance of services unless such organization clearly indicated its intent to so treat such benefit.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Excess benefit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “excess benefit” means the excess referred to in subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules for donor advised funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of any donor advised fund (as defined in section 4966(d)(2))—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the term “excess benefit transaction” includes any grant, loan, compensation, or other similar payment from such fund to a person described in subsection (f)(7) with respect to such fund, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the term “excess benefit” includes, with respect to any transaction described in subparagraph (A), the amount of any such grant, loan, compensation, or other similar payment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules for supporting organizations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In the case of any organization described in section 509(a)(3)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the term “excess benefit transaction” includes—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> any grant, loan, compensation, or other similar payment provided by such organization to a person described in subparagraph (B), and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> any loan provided by such organization to a disqualified person (other than an organization described in subparagraph (C)(ii)), and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the term “excess benefit” includes, with respect to any transaction described in clause (i), the amount of any such grant, loan, compensation, or other similar payment.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Person described</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A person is described in this subparagraph if such person is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a substantial contributor to such organization,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a member of the family (determined under section 4958(f)(4)) of an individual described in clause (i), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a 35-percent controlled entity (as defined in section 4958(f)(3) by substituting “persons described in clause (i) or (ii) of section 4958(c)(3)(B)” for “persons described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1)” in subparagraph (A)(i) thereof).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Substantial contributor</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The term “substantial contributor” means any person who contributed or bequeathed an aggregate amount of more than $5,000 to the organization, if such amount is more than 2 percent of the total contributions and bequests received by the organization before the close of the taxable year of the organization in which the contribution or bequest is received by the organization from such person. In the case of a trust, such term also means the creator of the trust. Rules similar to the rules of subparagraphs (B) and (C) of section 507(d)(2) shall apply for purposes of this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Such term shall not include—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> any organization described in paragraph (1), (2), or (4) of section 509(a), and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> any organization which is treated as described in such paragraph (2) by reason of the last sentence of section 509(a) and which is a supported organization (as defined in section 509(f)(3)) of the organization to which subparagraph (A) applies.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to include certain other private inurement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To the extent provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the term “excess benefit transaction” includes any transaction in which the amount of any economic benefit provided to or for the use of a disqualified person is determined in whole or in part by the revenues of 1 or more activities of the organization but only if such transaction results in inurement not permitted under paragraph (3) or (4) of section 501(c), as the case may be. In the case of any such transaction, the excess benefit shall be the amount of the inurement not so permitted.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint and several liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If more than 1 person is liable for any tax imposed by subsection (a) or subsection (b), all such persons shall be jointly and severally liable for such tax.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limit for management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to any 1 excess benefit transaction, the maximum amount of the tax imposed by subsection (a)(2) shall not exceed $20,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable tax-exempt organization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “applicable tax-exempt organization” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any organization which (without regard to any excess benefit) would be described in paragraph (3), (4), or (29) of section 501(c) and exempt from tax under section 501(a), and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any organization which was described in paragraph (1) at any time during the 5-year period ending on the date of the transaction.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Such term shall not include a private foundation (as defined in section 509(a)).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disqualified person</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “disqualified person” means, with respect to any transaction—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any person who was, at any time during the 5-year period ending on the date of such transaction, in a position to exercise substantial influence over the affairs of the organization,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a member of the family of an individual described in subparagraph (A),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a 35-percent controlled entity,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any person who is described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) with respect to an organization described in section 509(a)(3) and organized and operated exclusively for the benefit of, to perform the functions of, or to carry out the purposes of the applicable tax-exempt organization,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> which involves a donor advised fund (as defined in section 4966(d)(2)), any person who is described in paragraph (7) with respect to such donor advised fund (as so defined), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> which involves a sponsoring organization (as defined in section 4966(d)(1)), any person who is described in paragraph (8) with respect to such sponsoring organization (as so defined).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Organization manager</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “organization manager” means, with respect to any applicable tax-exempt organization, any officer, director, or trustee of such organization (or any individual having powers or responsibilities similar to those of officers, directors, or trustees of the organization).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> 35-percent controlled entity</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “35-percent controlled entity” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a corporation in which persons described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) own more than 35 percent of the total combined voting power,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> a partnership in which such persons own more than 35 percent of the profits interest, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> a trust or estate in which such persons own more than 35 percent of the beneficial interest.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Constructive ownership rules</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 4946(a) shall apply for purposes of this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Family members</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The members of an individual’s family shall be determined under section 4946(d); except that such members also shall include the brothers and sisters (whether by the whole or half blood) of the individual and their spouses.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxable period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “taxable period” means, with respect to any excess benefit transaction, the period beginning with the date on which the transaction occurs and ending on the earliest of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the date of mailing a notice of deficiency under section 6212 with respect to the tax imposed by subsection (a)(1), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date on which the tax imposed by subsection (a)(1) is assessed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Correction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The terms “correction” and “correct” mean, with respect to any excess benefit transaction, undoing the excess benefit to the extent possible, and taking any additional measures necessary to place the organization in a financial position not worse than that in which it would be if the disqualified person were dealing under the highest fiduciary standards, except that in the case of any correction of an excess benefit transaction described in subsection (c)(2), no amount repaid in a manner prescribed by the Secretary may be held in any donor advised fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Donors and donor advisors</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1)(E), a person is described in this paragraph if such person—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is described in section 4966(d)(2)(A)(iii),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is a member of the family of an individual described in subparagraph (A), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is a 35-percent controlled entity (as defined in paragraph (3) by substituting “persons described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (7)” for “persons described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1)” in subparagraph (A)(i) thereof).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(8)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investment advisors</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1)(F)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A person is described in this paragraph if such person—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is an investment advisor,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is a member of the family of an individual described in clause (i), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is a 35-percent controlled entity (as defined in paragraph (3) by substituting “persons described in clause (i) or (ii) of paragraph (8)(A)” for “persons described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1)” in subparagraph (A)(i) thereof).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investment advisor defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “investment advisor” means, with respect to any sponsoring organization (as defined in section 4966(d)(1)), any person (other than an employee of such organization) compensated by such organization for managing the investment of, or providing investment advice with respect to, assets maintained in donor advised funds (as defined in section 4966(d)(2)) owned by such organization.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–168, title XIII, § 1311(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-07-30">July 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1475</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 109–280, title XII</ref>, §§ 1212(a)(3), 1232(a), (b), 1242(a), (b), <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1074</ref>, 1098, 1099, 1104; <ref>Pub. L. 110–172, § 3(i)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-29">Dec. 29, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2475</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 111–148, title I, § 1322(h)(3)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 192</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(224)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1194</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4959.</num>
<heading> Taxes on failures by hospital organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If a hospital organization to which section 501(r) applies fails to meet the requirement of section 501(r)(3) for any taxable year, there is imposed on the organization a tax equal to $50,000.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–148, title IX, § 9007(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 857</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4960.</num>
<heading> Tax on excess tax-exempt organization executive compensation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax imposed</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There is hereby imposed a tax equal to the product of the rate of tax under section 11 and the sum of—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> so much of the remuneration paid (other than any excess parachute payment) by an applicable tax-exempt organization for the taxable year with respect to employment of any covered employee in excess of $1,000,000, plus</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any excess parachute payment paid by such an organization to any covered employee.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of the preceding sentence, remuneration shall be treated as paid when there is no substantial risk of forfeiture (within the meaning of section 457(f)(3)(B)) of the rights to such remuneration.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability for tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The employer shall be liable for the tax imposed under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions and special rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable tax-exempt organization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “applicable tax-exempt organization” means any organization which for the taxable year—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is exempt from taxation under section 501(a),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is a farmers’ cooperative organization described in section 521(b)(1),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> has income excluded from taxation under section 115(1), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> is a political organization described in section 527(e)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Covered employee</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “covered employee” means any employee (including any former employee) of an applicable tax-exempt organization if the employee—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is one of the 5 highest compensated employees of the organization for the taxable year, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> was a covered employee of the organization (or any predecessor) for any preceding taxable year beginning after <date date="2016-12-31">December 31, 2016</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remuneration</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “remuneration” means wages (as defined in section 3401(a)), except that such term shall not include any designated Roth contribution (as defined in section 402A(c)) and shall include amounts required to be included in gross income under section 457(f).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception for remuneration for medical services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “remuneration” shall not include the portion of any remuneration paid to a licensed medical professional (including a veterinarian) which is for the performance of medical or veterinary services by such professional.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Remuneration from related organizations</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Remuneration of a covered employee by an applicable tax-exempt organization shall include any remuneration paid with respect to employment of such employee by any related person or governmental entity.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Related organizations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A person or governmental entity shall be treated as related to an applicable tax-exempt organization if such person or governmental entity—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> controls, or is controlled by, the organization,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is controlled by one or more persons which control the organization,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is a supported organization (as defined in section 509(f)(3)) during the taxable year with respect to the organization,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> is a supporting organization described in section 509(a)(3) during the taxable year with respect to the organization, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> in the case of an organization which is a voluntary employees’ beneficiary association described in section 501(c)(9), establishes, maintains, or makes contributions to such voluntary employees’ beneficiary association.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Liability for tax</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In any case in which remuneration from more than one employer is taken into account under this paragraph in determining the tax imposed by subsection (a), each such employer shall be liable for such tax in an amount which bears the same ratio to the total tax determined under subsection (a) with respect to such remuneration as—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the amount of remuneration paid by such employer with respect to such employee, bears to</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the amount of remuneration paid by all such employers to such employee.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Excess parachute payment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of determining the tax imposed by subsection (a)(2)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “excess parachute payment” means an amount equal to the excess of any parachute payment over the portion of the base amount allocated to such payment.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Parachute payment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “parachute payment” means any payment in the nature of compensation to (or for the benefit of) a covered employee if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such payment is contingent on such employee’s separation from employment with the employer, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the aggregate present value of the payments in the nature of compensation to (or for the benefit of) such individual which are contingent on such separation equals or exceeds an amount equal to 3 times the base amount.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Such term does not include any payment—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> described in section 280G(b)(6) (relating to exemption for payments under qualified plans),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> made under or to an annuity contract described in section 403(b) or a plan described in section 457(b),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> to a licensed medical professional (including a veterinarian) to the extent that such payment is for the performance of medical or veterinary services by such professional, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> to an individual who is not a highly compensated employee as defined in section 414(q).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Base amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Rules similar to the rules of 280G(b)(3) shall apply for purposes of determining the base amount.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Property transfers; present value</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 280G(d) shall apply.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with deduction limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Remuneration the deduction for which is not allowed by reason of section 162(m) shall not be taken into account for purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to prevent avoidance of the tax under this section, including regulations to prevent avoidance of such tax through the performance of services other than as an employee or by providing compensation through a pass-through or other entity to avoid such tax.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–97, title I, § 13602(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 2157</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter E—</num>
<heading>Abatement of First and Second Tier Taxes in Certain Cases</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4961.</num>
<heading> Abatement of second tier taxes where there is correction</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If any taxable event is corrected during the correction period for such event, then any second tier tax imposed with respect to such event (including interest, additions to the tax, and additional amounts) shall not be assessed, and if assessed the assessment shall be abated, and if collected shall be credited or refunded as an overpayment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Supplemental proceeding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the determination by a court that the taxpayer is liable for a second tier tax has become final, such court shall have jurisdiction to conduct any necessary supplemental proceeding to determine whether the taxable event was corrected during the correction period. Such a supplemental proceeding may be begun only during the period which ends on the 90th day after the last day of the correction period. Where such a supplemental proceeding has begun, the reference in the second sentence of section 6213(a) to a final decision of the Tax Court shall be treated as including a final decision in such supplemental proceeding.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of period of collection for second tier tax</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Proceeding in District Court or United States Court of Federal Claims</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If, not later than 90 days after the day on which the second tier tax is assessed, the first tier tax is paid in full and a claim for refund of the amount so paid is filed, no levy or proceeding in court for the collection of the second tier tax shall be made, begun, or prosecuted until a final resolution of a proceeding begun as provided in paragraph (2) (and of any supplemental proceeding with respect thereto under subsection (b)). Notwithstanding section 7421(a), the collection by levy or proceeding may be enjoined during the time such prohibition is in force by a proceeding in the proper court.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suit must be brought to determine liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If, within 90 days after the day on which his claim for refund is denied, the person against whom the second tier tax was assessed fails to begin a proceeding described in section 7422 for the determination of his liability for such tax, paragraph (1) shall cease to apply with respect to such tax, effective on the day following the close of the 90-day period referred to in this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Suspension of running of period of limitations on collection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The running of the period of limitations provided in section 6502 on the collection by levy or by a proceeding in court with respect to any second tier tax described in paragraph (1) shall be suspended for the period during which the Secretary is prohibited from collecting by levy or a proceeding in court.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Jeopardy collection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the Secretary makes a finding that the collection of the second tier tax is in jeopardy, nothing in this subsection shall prevent the immediate collection of such tax.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–596, § 2(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3472</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title XVIII, § 1899A(50)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2961</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(325)(C)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1200</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4962.</num>
<heading> Abatement of first tier taxes in certain cases</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If it is established to the satisfaction of the Secretary that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a taxable event was due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> such event was corrected within the correction period for such event,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">then any qualified first tier tax imposed with respect to such event (including interest) shall not be assessed and, if assessed, the assessment shall be abated and, if collected, shall be credited or refunded as an overpayment.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified first tier tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “qualified first tier tax” means any first tier tax imposed by subchapter A, C, D, or G of this chapter, except that such term shall not include the tax imposed by section 4941(a) (relating to initial tax on self-dealing).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for tax on political expenditures of section 501(c)(3) organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of the tax imposed by section 4955(a), subsection (a)(1) shall be applied by substituting “not willful and flagrant” for “due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title III, § 305(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 783</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–203, title X, § 10712(b)(1)</ref>, (2), (4), <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1330–467</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–34, title XVI, § 1603(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1096</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–172, § 3(h)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-29">Dec. 29, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2475</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4963.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> First tier tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “first tier tax” means any tax imposed by subsection (a) of section 4941, 4942, 4943, 4944, 4945, 4951, 4952, 4955, 4958, 4966, 4967, 4971, or 4975.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Second tier tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “second tier tax” means any tax imposed by subsection (b) of section 4941, 4942, 4943, 4944, 4945, 4951, 4952, 4955, 4958, 4971, or 4975.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxable event</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter, the term “taxable event” means any act (or failure to act) giving rise to liability for tax under section 4941, 4942, 4943, 4944, 4945, 4951, 4952, 4955, 4958, 4966, 4967, 4971, or 4975.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Correct</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the term “correct” has the same meaning as when used in the section which imposes the second tier tax.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “correct” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of the second tier tax imposed by section 4942(b), reducing the amount of the undistributed income to zero,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of the second tier tax imposed by section 4943(b), reducing the amount of the excess business holdings to zero, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of the second tier tax imposed by section 4944, removing the investment from jeopardy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Correction period</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “correction period” means, with respect to any taxable event, the period beginning on the date on which such event occurs and ending 90 days after the date of mailing under section 6212 of a notice of deficiency with respect to the second tier tax imposed on such taxable event, extended by—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any period in which a deficiency cannot be assessed under section 6213(a) (determined without regard to the last sentence of section 4961(b)), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any other period which the Secretary determines is reasonable and necessary to bring about correction of the taxable event.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules for when taxable event occurs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), the taxable event shall be treated as occurring—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of section 4942, on the first day of the taxable year for which there was a failure to distribute income,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of section 4943, on the first day on which there are excess business holdings,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of section 4971, on the last day of the plan year in which there is an accumulated funding deficiency, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> in any other case, the date on which such event occurred.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 96–596, § 2(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3473</ref>, § 4962; renumbered § 4963, <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title III, § 305(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 783</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–203, title X, § 10712(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1330–467</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–168, title XIII, § 1311(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-07-30">July 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1478</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–280, title XII, § 1231(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1098</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter F—</num>
<heading>Tax Shelter Transactions</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4965.</num>
<heading> Excise tax on certain tax-exempt entities entering into prohibited tax shelter transactions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Being a party to and approval of prohibited transactions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax-exempt entity</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If a transaction is a prohibited tax shelter transaction at the time any tax-exempt entity described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (c) becomes a party to the transaction, such entity shall pay a tax for the taxable year in which the entity becomes such a party and any subsequent taxable year in the amount determined under subsection (b)(1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Post-transaction determination</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If any tax-exempt entity described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (c) is a party to a subsequently listed transaction at any time during a taxable year, such entity shall pay a tax for such taxable year in the amount determined under subsection (b)(1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Entity manager</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If any entity manager of a tax-exempt entity approves such entity as (or otherwise causes such entity to be) a party to a prohibited tax shelter transaction at any time during the taxable year and knows or has reason to know that the transaction is a prohibited tax shelter transaction, such manager shall pay a tax for such taxable year in the amount determined under subsection (b)(2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount of tax</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Entity</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of a tax-exempt entity—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the amount of the tax imposed under subsection (a)(1) with respect to any transaction for a taxable year shall be an amount equal to the product of the highest rate of tax under section 11, and the greater of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the entity’s net income (after taking into account any tax imposed by this subtitle (other than by this section) with respect to such transaction) for such taxable year which—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> in the case of a prohibited tax shelter transaction (other than a subsequently listed transaction), is attributable to such transaction, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> in the case of a subsequently listed transaction, is attributable to such transaction and which is properly allocable to the period beginning on the later of the date such transaction is identified by guidance as a listed transaction by the Secretary or the first day of the taxable year, or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> 75 percent of the proceeds received by the entity for the taxable year which—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> in the case of a prohibited tax shelter transaction (other than a subsequently listed transaction), are attributable to such transaction, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> in the case of a subsequently listed transaction, are attributable to such transaction and which are properly allocable to the period beginning on the later of the date such transaction is identified by guidance as a listed transaction by the Secretary or the first day of the taxable year.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Increase in tax for certain knowing transactions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In the case of a tax-exempt entity which knew, or had reason to know, a transaction was a prohibited tax shelter transaction at the time the entity became a party to the transaction, the amount of the tax imposed under subsection (a)(1)(A) with respect to any transaction for a taxable year shall be the greater of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> 100 percent of the entity’s net income (after taking into account any tax imposed by this subtitle (other than by this section) with respect to the prohibited tax shelter transaction) for such taxable year which is attributable to the prohibited tax shelter transaction, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> 75 percent of the proceeds received by the entity for the taxable year which are attributable to the prohibited tax shelter transaction.</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">This subparagraph shall not apply to any prohibited tax shelter transaction to which a tax-exempt entity became a party on or before the date of the enactment of this section.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Entity manager</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of each entity manager, the amount of the tax imposed under subsection (a)(2) shall be $20,000 for each approval (or other act causing participation) described in subsection (a)(2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax-exempt entity</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “tax-exempt entity” means an entity which is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> described in section 501(c) or 501(d),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> described in section 170(c) (other than the United States),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> an Indian tribal government (within the meaning of section 7701(a)(40)),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of section 4979(e),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(5)</num>
<content> a program described in section 529,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(6)</num>
<content> an eligible deferred compensation plan described in section 457(b) which is maintained by an employer described in section 457(e)(1)(A),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(7)</num>
<content> an arrangement described in section 4973(a), or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(8)</num>
<content> a program described in section 529A.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Entity manager</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “entity manager” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of an entity described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (c)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the person with authority or responsibility similar to that exercised by an officer, director, or trustee of an organization, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with respect to any act, the person having authority or responsibility with respect to such act, and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in the case of an entity described in paragraph (4), (5), (6), or (7) of subsection (c), the person who approves or otherwise causes the entity to be a party to the prohibited tax shelter transaction.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibited tax shelter transaction; subsequently listed transaction</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibited tax shelter transaction</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “prohibited tax shelter transaction” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any listed transaction, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any prohibited reportable transaction.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Listed transaction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “listed transaction” has the meaning given such term by section 6707A(c)(2).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Prohibited reportable transaction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “prohibited reportable transaction” means any confidential transaction or any transaction with contractual protection (as defined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary) which is a reportable transaction (as defined in section 6707A(c)(1)).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Subsequently listed transaction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “subsequently listed transaction” means any transaction to which a tax-exempt entity is a party and which is determined by the Secretary to be a listed transaction at any time after the entity has become a party to the transaction. Such term shall not include a transaction which is a prohibited reportable transaction at the time the entity became a party to the transaction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulatory authority</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to promulgate regulations which provide guidance regarding the determination of the allocation of net income or proceeds of a tax-exempt entity attributable to a transaction to various periods, including before and after the listing of the transaction or the date which is 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with other taxes and penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The tax imposed by this section is in addition to any other tax, addition to tax, or penalty imposed under this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–222, title V, § 516(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-05-17">May 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 368</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 110–172, § 11(a)(30)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-29">Dec. 29, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 2487</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. B, title I, § 102(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4062</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter G—</num>
<heading>Donor Advised Funds</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4966.</num>
<heading> Taxes on taxable distributions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Imposition of taxes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the sponsoring organization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is hereby imposed on each taxable distribution a tax equal to 20 percent of the amount thereof. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by the sponsoring organization with respect to the donor advised fund.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the fund management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is hereby imposed on the agreement of any fund manager to the making of a distribution, knowing that it is a taxable distribution, a tax equal to 5 percent of the amount thereof. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any fund manager who agreed to the making of the distribution.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint and several liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If more than one person is liable under subsection (a)(2) with respect to the making of a taxable distribution, all such persons shall be jointly and severally liable under such paragraph with respect to such distribution.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limit for management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to any one taxable distribution, the maximum amount of the tax imposed by subsection (a)(2) shall not exceed $10,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Taxable distribution</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “taxable distribution” means any distribution from a donor advised fund—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to any natural person, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> to any other person if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such distribution is for any purpose other than one specified in section 170(c)(2)(B), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the sponsoring organization does not exercise expenditure responsibility with respect to such distribution in accordance with section 4945(h).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Such term shall not include any distribution from a donor advised fund—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to any organization described in section 170(b)(1)(A) (other than a disqualified supporting organization),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to the sponsoring organization of such donor advised fund, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to any other donor advised fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sponsoring organization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “sponsoring organization” means any organization which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is described in section 170(c) (other than in paragraph (1) thereof, and without regard to paragraph (2)(A) thereof),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is not a private foundation (as defined in section 509(a)), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> maintains 1 or more donor advised funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Donor advised fund</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Except as provided in subparagraph (B) or (C), the term “donor advised fund” means a fund or account—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> which is separately identified by reference to contributions of a donor or donors,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> which is owned and controlled by a sponsoring organization, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> with respect to which a donor (or any person appointed or designated by such donor) has, or reasonably expects to have, advisory privileges with respect to the distribution or investment of amounts held in such fund or account by reason of the donor’s status as a donor.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “donor advised fund” shall not include any fund or account—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> which makes distributions only to a single identified organization or governmental entity, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> with respect to which a person described in subparagraph (A)(iii) advises as to which individuals receive grants for travel, study, or other similar purposes, if—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> such person’s advisory privileges are performed exclusively by such person in the person’s capacity as a member of a committee all of the members of which are appointed by the sponsoring organization,</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> no combination of persons described in subparagraph (A)(iii) (or persons related to such persons) control, directly or indirectly, such committee, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> all grants from such fund or account are awarded on an objective and nondiscriminatory basis pursuant to a procedure approved in advance by the board of directors of the sponsoring organization, and such procedure is designed to ensure that all such grants meet the requirements of paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of section 4945(g).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Secretarial authority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary may exempt a fund or account not described in subparagraph (B) from treatment as a donor advised fund—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> if such fund or account is advised by a committee not directly or indirectly controlled by the donor or any person appointed or designated by the donor for the purpose of advising with respect to distributions from such fund (and any related parties), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> if such fund benefits a single identified charitable purpose.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fund manager</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “fund manager” means, with respect to any sponsoring organization—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an officer, director, or trustee of such sponsoring organization (or an individual having powers or responsibilities similar to those of officers, directors, or trustees of the sponsoring organization), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> with respect to any act (or failure to act), the employees of the sponsoring organization having authority or responsibility with respect to such act (or failure to act).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disqualified supporting organization</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “disqualified supporting organization” means, with respect to any distribution—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any type III supporting organization (as defined in section 4943(f)(5)(A)) which is not a functionally integrated type III supporting organization (as defined in section 4943(f)(5)(B)), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<chapeau> any organization which is described in subparagraph (B) or (C) if—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the donor or any person designated by the donor for the purpose of advising with respect to distributions from a donor advised fund (and any related parties) directly or indirectly controls a supported organization (as defined in section 509(f)(3)) of such organization, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the Secretary determines by regulations that a distribution to such organization otherwise is inappropriate.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Type I and type II supporting organizations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">An organization is described in this subparagraph if the organization meets the requirements of subparagraphs (A) and (C) of section 509(a)(3) and is—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> operated, supervised, or controlled by one or more organizations described in paragraph (1) or (2) of section 509(a), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> supervised or controlled in connection with one or more such organizations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functionally integrated type III supporting organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">An organization is described in this subparagraph if the organization is a functionally integrated type III supporting organization (as defined under section 4943(f)(5)(B)).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–280, title XII, § 1231(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1095</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 4967.</num>
<heading> Taxes on prohibited benefits</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Imposition of taxes</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the donor, donor advisor, or related person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is hereby imposed on the advice of any person described in subsection (d) to have a sponsoring organization make a distribution from a donor advised fund which results in such person or any other person described in subsection (d) receiving, directly or indirectly, a more than incidental benefit as a result of such distribution, a tax equal to 125 percent of such benefit. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any person described in subsection (d) who advises as to the distribution or who receives such a benefit as a result of the distribution.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On the fund management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There is hereby imposed on the agreement of any fund manager to the making of a distribution, knowing that such distribution would confer a benefit described in paragraph (1), a tax equal to 10 percent of the amount of such benefit. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any fund manager who agreed to the making of the distribution.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No tax shall be imposed under this section with respect to any distribution if a tax has been imposed with respect to such distribution under section 4958.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Joint and several liability</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If more than one person is liable under paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a) with respect to a distribution described in subsection (a), all such persons shall be jointly and severally liable under such paragraph with respect to such distribution.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limit for management</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to any one distribution described in subsection (a), the maximum amount of the tax imposed by subsection (a)(2) shall not exceed $10,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Person described</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">A person is described in this subsection if such person is described in section 4958(f)(7) with respect to a donor advised fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 109–280, title XII, § 1231(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-08-17">Aug. 17, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1097</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>Subchapter H—</num>
<heading>Excise Tax Based on Investment Income of Private Colleges and Universities</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4968.</num>
<heading> Excise tax based on investment income of private colleges and universities</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax imposed</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby imposed on each applicable educational institution for the taxable year a tax equal to 1.4 percent of the net investment income of such institution for the taxable year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable educational institution</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this subchapter—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “applicable educational institution” means an eligible educational institution (as defined in section 25A(f)(2))—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> which had at least 500 tuition-paying students during the preceding taxable year,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> more than 50 percent of the tuition-paying students of which are located in the United States,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> which is not described in the first sentence of section 511(a)(2)(B) (relating to State colleges and universities), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the aggregate fair market value of the assets of which at the end of the preceding taxable year (other than those assets which are used directly in carrying out the institution’s exempt purpose) is at least $500,000 per student of the institution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Students</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), the number of students of an institution (including for purposes of determining the number of students at a particular location) shall be based on the daily average number of full-time students attending such institution (with part-time students taken into account on a full-time student equivalent basis).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Net investment income</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, net investment income shall be determined under rules similar to the rules of section 4940(c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assets and net investment income of related organizations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of subsections (b)(1)(C) and (c), assets and net investment income of any related organization with respect to an educational institution shall be treated as assets and net investment income, respectively, of the educational institution, except that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> no such amount shall be taken into account with respect to more than 1 educational institution, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> unless such organization is controlled by such institution or is described in section 509(a)(3) with respect to such institution for the taxable year, assets and net investment income which are not intended or available for the use or benefit of the educational institution shall not be taken into account.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Related organization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “related organization” means, with respect to an educational institution, any organization which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> controls, or is controlled by, such institution,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is controlled by 1 or more persons which also control such institution, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> is a supported organization (as defined in section 509(f)(3)), or an organization described in section 509(a)(3), during the taxable year with respect to such institution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 115–97, title I, § 13701(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 2167</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–123, div. D, title II, § 41109(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-02-09">Feb. 9, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 159</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>