<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 77—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 7501.</num>
<heading> Liability for taxes withheld or collected</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever any person is required to collect or withhold any internal revenue tax from any other person and to pay over such tax to the United States, the amount of tax so collected or withheld shall be held to be a special fund in trust for the United States. The amount of such fund shall be assessed, collected, and paid in the same manner and subject to the same provisions and limitations (including penalties) as are applicable with respect to the taxes from which such fund arose.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2 fontsize7">For penalties applicable to violations of this section, see sections 6672 and 7202.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 895</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7502.</num>
<heading> Timely mailing treated as timely filing and paying</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Date of delivery</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If any return, claim, statement, or other document required to be filed, or any payment required to be made, within a prescribed period or on or before a prescribed date under authority of any provision of the internal revenue laws is, after such period or such date, delivered by United States mail to the agency, officer, or office with which such return, claim, statement, or other document is required to be filed, or to which such payment is required to be made, the date of the United States postmark stamped on the cover in which such return, claim, statement, or other document, or payment, is mailed shall be deemed to be the date of delivery or the date of payment, as the case may be.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mailing requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">This subsection shall apply only if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the postmark date falls within the prescribed period or on or before the prescribed date—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> for the filing (including any extension granted for such filing) of the return, claim, statement, or other document, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> for making the payment (including any extension granted for making such payment), and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the return, claim, statement, or other document, or payment was, within the time prescribed in subparagraph (A), deposited in the mail in the United States in an envelope or other appropriate wrapper, postage prepaid, properly addressed to the agency, officer, or office with which the return, claim, statement, or other document is required to be filed, or to which such payment is required to be made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Postmarks</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall apply in the case of postmarks not made by the United States Postal Service only if and to the extent provided by regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Registered and certified mailing; electronic filing</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Registered mail</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section, if any return, claim, statement, or other document, or payment, is sent by United States registered mail—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such registration shall be prima facie evidence that the return, claim, statement, or other document was delivered to the agency, officer, or office to which addressed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the date of registration shall be deemed the postmark date.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certified mail; electronic filing</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary is authorized to provide by regulations the extent to which the provisions of paragraph (1) with respect to prima facie evidence of delivery and the postmark date shall apply to certified mail and electronic filing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This section shall not apply with respect to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the filing of a document in, or the making of a payment to, any court other than the Tax Court,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> currency or other medium of payment unless actually received and accounted for, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> returns, claims, statements, or other documents, or payments, which are required under any provision of the internal revenue laws or the regulations thereunder to be delivered by any method other than by mailing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mailing of deposits</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Date of deposit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If any deposit required to be made (pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary under section 6302(c)) on or before a prescribed date is, after such date, delivered by the United States mail to the bank, trust company, domestic building and loan association, or credit union authorized to receive such deposit, such deposit shall be deemed received by such bank, trust company, domestic building and loan association, or credit union on the date the deposit was mailed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mailing requirements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall apply only if the person required to make the deposit establishes that—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the date of mailing falls on or before the second day before the prescribed date for making the deposit (including any extension of time granted for making such deposit), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the deposit was, on or before such second day, mailed in the United States in an envelope or other appropriate wrapper, postage prepaid, properly addressed to the bank, trust company, domestic building and loan association, or credit union authorized to receive such deposit.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">In applying subsection (c) for purposes of this subsection, the term “payment” includes “deposit”, and the reference to the postmark date refers to the date of mailing.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> No application to certain deposits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to any deposit of $20,000 or more by any person who is required to deposit any tax more than once a month.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of private delivery services</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any reference in this section to the United States mail shall be treated as including a reference to any designated delivery service, and any reference in this section to a postmark by the United States Postal Service shall be treated as including a reference to any date recorded or marked as described in paragraph (2)(C) by any designated delivery service.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Designated delivery service</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “designated delivery service” means any delivery service provided by a trade or business if such service is designated by the Secretary for purposes of this section. The Secretary may designate a delivery service under the preceding sentence only if the Secretary determines that such service—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is available to the general public,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> is at least as timely and reliable on a regular basis as the United States mail,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> records electronically to its data base, kept in the regular course of its business, or marks on the cover in which any item referred to in this section is to be delivered, the date on which such item was given to such trade or business for delivery, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> meets such other criteria as the Secretary may prescribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Equivalents of registered and certified mail</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may provide a rule similar to the rule of paragraph (1) with respect to any service provided by a designated delivery service which is substantially equivalent to United States registered or certified mail.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 895</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 85–866, title I, § 89(a)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1665</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–713, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1110</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 90–364, title I, § 106(a)</ref>, <date date="1968-06-28">June 28, 1968</date>, <ref>82 Stat. 266</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX</ref>, §§ 1906(a)(49), (b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1831</ref>, 1834; <ref>Pub. L. 95–147, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1977-10-28">Oct. 28, 1977</date>, <ref>91 Stat. 1228</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title I, § 157(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref>98 Stat. 695</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title XVIII, § 1811(e)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2833</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 104–168, title XII, § 1210</ref>, <date date="1996-07-30">July 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1474</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title II, § 2003(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 725</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7503.</num>
<heading> Time for performance of acts where last day falls on Saturday, Sunday, or legal holiday</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">When the last day prescribed under authority of the internal revenue laws for performing any act falls on Saturday, Sunday, or a legal holiday, the performance of such act shall be considered timely if it is performed on the next succeeding day which is not a Saturday, Sunday, or a legal holiday. For purposes of this section, the last day for the performance of any act shall be determined by including any authorized extension of time; the term “legal holiday” means a legal holiday in the District of Columbia; and in the case of any return, statement, or other document required to be filed, or any other act required under authority of the internal revenue laws to be performed, at any office of the Secretary or at any other office of the United States or any agency thereof, located outside the District of Columbia but within an internal revenue district, the term “legal holiday” also means a Statewide legal holiday in the State where such office is located.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 896</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7504.</num>
<heading> Fractional parts of a dollar</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may by regulations provide that in the allowance of any amount as a credit or refund, or in the collection of any amount as a deficiency or underpayment, of any tax imposed by this title, a fractional part of a dollar shall be disregarded, unless it amounts to 50 cents or more, in which case it shall be increased to 1 dollar.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 896</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7505.</num>
<heading> Sale of personal property acquired by the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any personal property acquired by the United States in payment of or as security for debts arising under the internal revenue laws may be sold by the Secretary in accordance with such regulations as may be prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Accounting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In case of the resale of such property, the proceeds of the sale shall be paid into the Treasury as internal revenue collections, and there shall be rendered a distinct account of all charges incurred in such sales.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 896</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–719, title I, § 111(a)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1145</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7506.</num>
<heading> Administration of real estate acquired by the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Person charged with</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall have charge of all real estate which is or shall become the property of the United States by judgment of forfeiture under the internal revenue laws, or which has been or shall be assigned, set off, or conveyed by purchase or otherwise to the United States in payment of debts or penalties arising under the laws relating to internal revenue, or which has been or shall be vested in the United States by mortgage or other security for the payment of such debts, or which has been redeemed by the United States, and of all trusts created for the use of the United States in payment of such debts due them.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Sale</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary, may, at public sale, and upon not less than 20 days’ notice, sell and dispose of any real estate owned or held by the United States as aforesaid.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Lease</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Until such sale, the Secretary may lease such real estate owned as aforesaid on such terms and for such period as the Secretary shall deem proper.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Release to debtor</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In cases where real estate has or may become the property of the United States by conveyance or otherwise, in payment of or as security for a debt arising under the laws relating to internal revenue, and such debt shall have been paid, together with the interest thereon, at the rate of 1 percent per month, to the United States, within 2 years from the date of the acquisition of such real estate, it shall be lawful for the Secretary to release by deed or otherwise convey such real estate to the debtor from whom it was taken, or to his heirs or other legal representatives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 896</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 89–719, title I, § 111(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref>80 Stat. 1145</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7507.</num>
<heading> Exemption of insolvent banks from tax</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assets in general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever and after any bank or trust company, a substantial portion of the business of which consists of receiving deposits and making loans and discounts, has ceased to do business by reason of insolvency or bankruptcy, no tax shall be assessed or collected, or paid into the Treasury of the United States, on account of such bank or trust company, which shall diminish the assets thereof necessary for the full payment of all its depositors; and such tax shall be abated from such national banks as are found by the Comptroller of the Currency to be insolvent; and the Secretary, when the facts shall appear to him, is authorized to remit so much of the said tax against any such insolvent banks and trust companies organized under State law as shall be found to affect the claims of their depositors.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Segregated assets; earnings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever any bank or trust company, a substantial portion of the business of which consists of receiving deposits and making loans and discounts, has been released or discharged from its liability to its depositors for any part of their claims against it, and such depositors have accepted, in lieu thereof, a lien upon subsequent earnings of such bank or trust company, or claims against assets segregated by such bank or trust company or against assets transferred from it to an individual or corporate trustee or agent, no tax shall be assessed or collected, or paid into the Treasury of the United States, on account of such bank or trust company, such individual or corporate trustee or such agent, which shall diminish the assets thereof which are available for the payment of such depositor claims and which are necessary for the full payment thereof. The term “agent”, as used in this subsection, shall be deemed to include a corporation acting as a liquidating agent.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refund; reassessment; statutes of limitation</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Any such tax collected shall be deemed to be erroneously collected, and shall be refunded subject to all provisions and limitations of law, so far as applicable, relating to the refunding of taxes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Any tax, the assessment, collection, or payment of which is barred under subsection (a), or any such tax which has been abated or remitted shall be assessed or reassessed whenever it shall appear that payment of the tax will not diminish the assets as aforesaid.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any tax, the assessment, collection, or payment of which is barred under subsection (b), or any such tax which has been refunded shall be assessed or reassessed after full payment of such claims of depositors to the extent of the remaining assets segregated or transferred as described in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> The running of the statute of limitations on the making of assessment and collection shall be suspended during, and for 90 days beyond, the period for which, pursuant to this section, assessment or collection may not be made, and a tax may be reassessed as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection and collected, during the time within which, had there been no abatement, collection might have been made.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception of employment taxes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply to any tax imposed by chapter 21 or chapter 23.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 897</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(a)(50)</ref>, (b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1831</ref>, 1834.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7508.</num>
<heading> Time for performing certain acts postponed by reason of service in combat zone or contingency operation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Time to be disregarded</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of an individual serving in the Armed Forces of the United States, or serving in support of such Armed Forces, in an area designated by the President of the United States by Executive order as a “combat zone” for purposes of section 112, or when deployed outside the United States away from the individual’s permanent duty station while participating in an operation designated by the Secretary of Defense as a contingency operation (as defined in <ref>section 101(a)(13) of title 10</ref>, United States Code) or which became such a contingency operation by operation of law, at any time during the period designated by the President by Executive order as the period of combatant activities in such zone for purposes of such section or at any time during the period of such contingency operation, or hospitalized as a result of injury received while serving in such an area or operation during such time, the period of service in such area or operation, plus the period of continuous qualified hospitalization attributable to such injury, and the next 180 days thereafter, shall be disregarded in determining, under the internal revenue laws, in respect of any tax liability (including any interest, penalty, additional amount, or addition to the tax) of such individual—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> Whether any of the following acts was performed within the time prescribed therefor:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Filing any return of income, estate, gift, employment, or excise tax;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Payment of any income, estate, gift, employment, or excise tax or any installment thereof or of any other liability to the United States in respect thereof;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Filing a petition with the Tax Court, or filing a notice of appeal from a decision of the Tax Court;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Allowance of a credit or refund of any tax;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Filing a claim for credit or refund of any tax;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Bringing suit upon any such claim for credit or refund;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> Assessment of any tax;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> Giving or making any notice or demand for the payment of any tax, or with respect to any liability to the United States in respect of any tax;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> Collection, by the Secretary, by levy or otherwise, of the amount of any liability in respect of any tax;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> Bringing suit by the United States, or any officer on its behalf, in respect of any liability in respect of any tax or in respect of any erroneous refund; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> Any other act required or permitted under the internal revenue laws specified by the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The amount of any credit or refund; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> Any certification of a seriously delinquent tax debt under section 7345.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rule for overpayments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subsection (a) shall not apply for purposes of determining the amount of interest on any overpayment of tax.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If an individual is entitled to the benefits of subsection (a) with respect to any return and such return is timely filed (determined after the application of such subsection), subsections (b)(3) and (e) of section 6611 shall not apply.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application to spouse</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall apply to the spouse of any individual entitled to the benefits of subsection (a). Except in the case of the combat zone designated for purposes of the Vietnam conflict, the preceding sentence shall not cause this section to apply for any spouse for any taxable year beginning more than 2 years after the date designated under section 112 as the date of termination of combatant activities in a combat zone.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Missing status</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The period of service in the area or contingency operation referred to in subsection (a) shall include the period during which an individual entitled to benefits under subsection (a) is in a missing status, within the meaning of section 6013(f)(3).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax in jeopardy; cases under title 11 of the United States Code and receiverships; and transferred assets</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a), any action or proceeding authorized by section 6851 (regardless of the taxable year for which the tax arose), chapter 70, or 71, as well as any other action or proceeding authorized by law in connection therewith, may be taken, begun, or prosecuted. In any other case in which the Secretary determines that collection of the amount of any assessment would be jeopardized by delay, the provisions of subsection (a) shall not operate to stay collection of such amount by levy or otherwise as authorized by law. There shall be excluded from any amount assessed or collected pursuant to this paragraph the amount of interest, penalty, additional amount, and addition to the tax, if any, in respect of the period disregarded under subsection (a). In any case to which this paragraph relates, if the Secretary is required to give any notice to or make any demand upon any person, such requirement shall be deemed to be satisfied if the notice or demand is prepared and signed, in any case in which the address of such person last known to the Secretary is in an area for which United States post offices under instructions of the Postmaster General are not, by reason of the combatant activities, accepting mail for delivery at the time the notice or demand is signed. In such case the notice or demand shall be deemed to have been given or made upon the date it is signed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Action taken before ascertainment of right to benefits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The assessment or collection of any internal revenue tax or of any liability to the United States in respect of any internal revenue tax, or any action or proceeding by or on behalf of the United States in connection therewith, may be made, taken, begun, or prosecuted in accordance with law, without regard to the provisions of subsection (a), unless prior to such assessment collection, action, or proceeding it is ascertained that the person concerned is entitled to the benefits of subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Collection period after assessment not extended as a result of hospitalization</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to any period of continuous qualified hospitalization described in subsection (a) and the next 180 days thereafter, subsection (a) shall not apply in the application of section 6502.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of individuals performing Desert Shield services</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any individual who performed Desert Shield services (and the spouse of such individual) shall be entitled to the benefits of this section in the same manner as if such services were services referred to in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Desert Shield services</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “Desert Shield services” means any services in the Armed Forces of the United States or in support of such Armed Forces if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such services are performed in the area designated by the President pursuant to this subparagraph as the “Persian Gulf Desert Shield area”, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> such services are performed during the period beginning on <date date="1990-08-02">August 2, 1990</date>, and ending on the date on which any portion of the area referred to in subparagraph (A) is designated by the President as a combat zone pursuant to section 112.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified hospitalization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a), the term “qualified hospitalization” means—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any hospitalization outside the United States, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any hospitalization inside the United States, except that not more than 5 years of hospitalization may be taken into account under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">Paragraph (2) shall not apply for purposes of applying this section with respect to the spouse of an individual entitled to the benefits of subsection (a).</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 898</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 93–597, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-02">Jan. 2, 1975</date>, <ref>88 Stat. 1952</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(a)(51)</ref>, (b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1831</ref>, 1834; <ref>Pub. L. 94–569, § 3(e)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-20">Oct. 20, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 2700</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–589, § 6(i)(14)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 3411</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 97–448, title III, § 307(d)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref>96 Stat. 2407</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title XVII, § 1708(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2782</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 102–2, § 1(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1991-01-30">Jan. 30, 1991</date>, <ref>105 Stat. 5</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–134, title I, § 112(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-23">Jan. 23, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2434</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–121, title I, § 104(a)</ref>–(b)(2), <date date="2003-11-11">Nov. 11, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1338</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–73, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-09-23">Sept. 23, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 2027</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–94, div. C, title XXXII, § 32101(d)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-04">Dec. 4, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 1732</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. Q, title III, § 309(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 3089</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. H, title V, § 80502(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1335</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7508A.</num>
<heading> Authority to postpone certain deadlines by reason of Federally declared disaster, significant fire, or terroristic or military actions</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of a taxpayer determined by the Secretary to be affected by a federally declared disaster (as defined by section 165(i)(5)(A)), a significant fire, or a terroristic or military action (as defined in section 692(c)(2)), the Secretary may specify a period of up to 1 year that may be disregarded in determining, under the internal revenue laws, in respect of any tax liability of such taxpayer—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> whether any of the acts described in paragraph (1) of section 7508(a) were performed within the time prescribed therefor (determined without regard to extension under any other provision of this subtitle for periods after the date (determined by the Secretary) of such disaster, fire, or action),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the amount of any interest, penalty, additional amount, or addition to the tax for periods after such date, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the amount of any credit or refund.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules regarding pensions, etc.</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">In the case of a pension or other employee benefit plan, or any sponsor, administrator, participant, beneficiary, or other person with respect to such plan, affected by a disaster, fire, or action described in subsection (a), the Secretary may specify a period of up to 1 year which may be disregarded in determining the date by which any action is required or permitted to be completed under this title. No plan shall be treated as failing to be operated in accordance with the terms of the plan solely as the result of disregarding any period by reason of the preceding sentence.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules for overpayments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The rules of section 7508(b) shall apply for purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mandatory 60-day extension</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of any qualified taxpayer, the period—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> beginning on the earliest incident date specified in the declaration to which the disaster area referred to in paragraph (2) relates, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> ending on the date which is 60 days after the later of such earliest incident date described in subparagraph (A) or the date such declaration was issued,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">shall be disregarded in determining, under the internal revenue laws, in respect of any tax liability of such qualified taxpayer, whether any of the acts described in subparagraphs (A) through (F) of section 7508(a)(1) were performed within the time prescribed therefor (determined without regard to extension under any other provision of this subtitle for periods after the date determined under subparagraph (B)).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified taxpayer</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “qualified taxpayer” means—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any individual whose principal residence (for purposes of section 1033(h)(4)) is located in a disaster area,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any taxpayer if the taxpayer’s principal place of business (other than the business of performing services as an employee) is located in a disaster area,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any individual who is a relief worker affiliated with a recognized government or philanthropic organization and who is assisting in a disaster area,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any taxpayer whose records necessary to meet a deadline for an act described in section 7508(a)(1) are maintained in a disaster area,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any individual visiting a disaster area who was killed or injured as a result of the disaster, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> solely with respect to a joint return, any spouse of an individual described in any preceding subparagraph of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disaster area</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, the term “disaster area” means an area in which a major disaster for which the President provides financial assistance under section 408 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref>42 U.S.C. 5174</ref>) occurs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application to rules regarding pensions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of any person described in subsection (b), a rule similar to the rule of paragraph (1) shall apply for purposes of subsection (b) with respect to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> making contributions to a qualified retirement plan (within the meaning of section 4974(c)) under section 219(f)(3), 404(a)(6), 404(h)(1)(B), or 404(m)(2),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> making distributions under section 408(d)(4),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> recharacterizing contributions under section 408A(d)(6), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> making a rollover under section 402(c), 403(a)(4), 403(b)(8), or 408(d)(3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with periods specified by the Secretary</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any period described in paragraph (1) with respect to any person (including by reason of the application of paragraph (4)) shall be in addition to (or concurrent with, as the case may be) any period specified under subsection (a) or (b) with respect to such person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multiple declarations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), in the case of multiple declarations relating to a disaster area which are issued within a 60-day period, a separate period shall be determined under such paragraph with respect to each such declaration.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Significant fire</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “significant fire” means any fire with respect to which assistance is provided under section 420 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–34, title IX, § 911(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 877</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 107–16, title VIII, § 802(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-06-07">June 7, 2001</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 149</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–134, title I, § 112(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-23">Jan. 23, 2002</date>, <ref>115 Stat. 2433</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–343, div. C, title VII, § 706(a)(2)(D)(vii)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-03">Oct. 3, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 3922</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(b)(10)(B)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1202</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–94, div. Q, title II, § 205(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 3245</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 117–58, div. H, title V</ref>, §§ 80501(a), 80504(a), (b)(1), <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 1335</ref>, 1336.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7509.</num>
<heading> Expenditures incurred by the United States Postal Service</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Postmaster General or his delegate shall at least once a month transfer to the Treasury of the United States a statement of the additional expenditures in the District of Columbia and elsewhere incurred by the United States Postal Service in performing the duties, if any, imposed upon such Service with respect to chapter 21, relating to the tax under the Federal Insurance Contributions Act, and the Secretary shall be authorized and directed to advance from time to time to the credit of the United States Postal Service, from appropriations made for the collection of the taxes imposed by chapter 21, such sums as may be required for such additional expenditures incurred by the United States Postal Service.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 899</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(a)(52)</ref>, (b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1832</ref>, 1834.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7510.</num>
<heading> Exemption from tax of domestic goods purchased for the United States</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The privilege existing by provision of law on <date date="1873-12-01">December 1, 1873</date>, or thereafter of purchasing supplies of goods imported from foreign countries for the use of the United States, duty free, shall be extended, under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, to all articles of domestic production which are subject to tax by the provisions of this title.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref>68A Stat. 900</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 7511.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 87–456, title III, § 302(d)</ref>, <date date="1962-05-24">May 24, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 77</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7512.</num>
<heading> Separate accounting for certain collected taxes, etc.</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Whenever any person who is required to collect, account for, and pay over any tax imposed by subtitle C or chapter 33—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> at the time and in the manner prescribed by law or regulations (A) fails to collect, truthfully account for, or pay over such tax, or (B) fails to make deposits, payments, or returns of such tax, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is notified, by notice delivered in hand to such person, of any such failure,</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">then all the requirements of subsection (b) shall be complied with. In the case of a corporation, partnership, or trust, notice delivered in hand to an officer, partner, or trustee, shall, for purposes of this section, be deemed to be notice delivered in hand to such corporation, partnership, or trust and to all officers, partners, trustees, and employees thereof.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any person who is required to collect, account for, and pay over any tax imposed by subtitle C or chapter 33, if notice has been delivered to such person in accordance with subsection (a), shall collect the taxes imposed by subtitle C or chapter 33 which become collectible after delivery of such notice, shall (not later than the end of the second banking day after any amount of such taxes is collected) deposit such amount in a separate account in a bank (as defined in section 581), and shall keep the amount of such taxes in such account until payment over to the United States. Any such account shall be designated as a special fund in trust for the United States, payable to the United States by such person as trustee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relief from further compliance with subsection (b)</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Whenever the Secretary is satisfied, with respect to any notification made under subsection (a), that all requirements of law and regulations with respect to the taxes imposed by subtitle C or chapter 33, as the case may be, will henceforth be complied with, he may cancel such notification. Such cancellation shall take effect at such time as is specified in the notice of such cancellation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–321, § 1</ref>, <date date="1958-02-11">Feb. 11, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 5</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 96–223, title I, § 101(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1980-04-02">Apr. 2, 1980</date>, <ref>94 Stat. 251</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1941(b)(2)(O)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 1324</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7513.</num>
<heading> Reproduction of returns and other documents</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to have any Federal agency or any person process films or other photoimpressions of any return, document, or other matter, and make reproductions from films or photoimpressions of any return, document, or other matter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall prescribe regulations which shall provide such safeguards as in the opinion of the Secretary are necessary or appropriate to protect the film, photoimpressions, and reproductions made therefrom, against any unauthorized use, and to protect the information contained therein against any unauthorized disclosure.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalty</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2 fontsize7">For penalty for violation of regulations for safeguarding against unauthorized use of any film or photoimpression, or reproduction made therefrom, and against unauthorized disclosure of information contained therein, see section 7213.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–866, title I, § 90(a)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1666</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XII, § 1202(f)</ref>, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1687</ref>, 1834.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7514.</num>
<heading> Authority to prescribe or modify seals</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to prescribe or modify seals of office for the district directors of internal revenue and other officers or employees of the Treasury Department to whom any of the functions of the Secretary of the Treasury shall have been or may be delegated. Each seal so prescribed shall contain such device as the Secretary may select. Each seal shall remain in the custody of any officer or employee whom the Secretary may designate, and, in accordance with the regulations approved by the Secretary, may be affixed in lieu of the seal of the Treasury Department to any certificate or attestation (except for material to be published in the Federal Register) that may be required of such officer or employee. Judicial notice shall be taken of any seal prescribed in accordance with this authority, a facsimile of which has been published in the Federal Register together with the regulations prescribing such seal and the affixation thereof.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 85–866, title I, § 91(a)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref>72 Stat. 1667</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, (M), <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>, 1835.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>[§ 7515.</num>
<heading> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XII, § 1202(h)(4)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1688</ref>]</heading>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7516.</num>
<heading> Supplying training and training aids on request</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized within his discretion, upon written request, to admit employees and officials of any State, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, any possession of the United States, any political subdivision or instrumentality of any of the foregoing, the District of Columbia, or any foreign government to training courses conducted by the Internal Revenue Service, and to supply them with texts and other training aids. The Secretary may require payment from the party or parties making the request of a reasonable fee not to exceed the cost of the training and training aids supplied pursuant to such request.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 87–870, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-23">Oct. 23, 1962</date>, <ref>76 Stat. 1160</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7517.</num>
<heading> Furnishing on request of statement explaining estate or gift valuation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">If the Secretary makes a determination or a proposed determination of the value of an item of property for purposes of the tax imposed under chapter 11, 12, or 13, he shall furnish, on the written request of the executor, donor, or the person required to make the return of the tax imposed by chapter 13 (as the case may be), to such executor, donor, or person a written statement containing the material required by subsection (b). Such statement shall be furnished not later than 45 days after the later of the date of such request or the date of such determination or proposed determination.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Contents of statement</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">A statement required to be furnished under subsection (a) with respect to the value of an item of property shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> explain the basis on which the valuation was determined or proposed,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> set forth any computation used in arriving at such value, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> contain a copy of any expert appraisal made by or for the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of statement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except to the extent otherwise provided by law, the value determined or proposed by the Secretary with respect to which a statement is furnished under this section, and the method used in arriving at such value, shall not be binding on the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 94–455, title XX, § 2008(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-04">Oct. 4, 1976</date>, <ref>90 Stat. 1891</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7518.</num>
<heading> Tax incentives relating to merchant marine capital construction funds</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ceiling on deposits</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The amount deposited in a fund established under chapter 535 of title 46 of the United States Code (hereinafter in this section referred to as a “capital construction fund”) shall not exceed for any taxable year the sum of:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> that portion of the taxable income of the owner or lessee for such year (computed as provided in chapter 1 but without regard to the carryback of any net operating loss or net capital loss and without regard to this section) which is attributable to the operation of the agreement vessels in the foreign or domestic commerce of the United States or in the fisheries of the United States,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the amount allowable as a deduction under section 167 for such year with respect to the agreement vessels,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> if the transaction is not taken into account for purposes of subparagraph (A), the net proceeds (as defined in joint regulations) from—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the sale or other disposition of any agreement vessel, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> insurance or indemnity attributable to any agreement vessel, and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the receipts from the investment or reinvestment of amounts held in such fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations on deposits by lessees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the case of a lessee, the maximum amount which may be deposited with respect to an agreement vessel by reason of paragraph (1)(B) for any period shall be reduced by any amount which, under an agreement entered into under chapter 535 of title 46, United States Code, the owner is required or permitted to deposit for such period with respect to such vessel by reason of paragraph (1)(B).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain barges and containers included</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1), the term “agreement vessel” includes barges and containers which are part of the complement of such vessel and which are provided for in the agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements as to investments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts in any capital construction fund shall be kept in the depository or depositories specified in the agreement and shall be subject to such trustee and other fiduciary requirements as may be specified by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on fund investments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Amounts in any capital construction fund may be invested only in interest-bearing securities approved by the Secretary; except that, if such Secretary consents thereto, an agreed percentage (not in excess of 60 percent) of the assets of the fund may be invested in the stock of domestic corporations. Such stock must be currently fully listed and registered on an exchange registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission as a national securities exchange, and must be stock which would be acquired by prudent men of discretion and intelligence in such matters who are seeking a reasonable income and the preservation of their capital. If at any time the fair market value of the stock in the fund is more than the agreed percentage of the assets in the fund, any subsequent investment of amounts deposited in the fund, and any subsequent withdrawal from the fund, shall be made in such a way as to tend to restore the fund to a situation in which the fair market value of the stock does not exceed such agreed percentage.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Investment in certain preferred stock permitted</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection, if the common stock of a corporation meets the requirements of this subsection and if the preferred stock of such corporation would meet such requirements but for the fact that it cannot be listed and registered as required because it is nonvoting stock, such preferred stock shall be treated as meeting the requirements of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nontaxability for deposits</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this title—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> taxable income (determined without regard to this section and chapter 535 of title 46, United States Code) for the taxable year shall be reduced by an amount equal to the amount deposited for the taxable year out of amounts referred to in subsection (a)(1)(A),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> gain from a transaction referred to in subsection (a)(1)(C) shall not be taken into account if an amount equal to the net proceeds (as defined in joint regulations) from such transaction is deposited in the fund,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the earnings (including gains and losses) from the investment and reinvestment of amounts held in the fund shall not be taken into account,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the earnings and profits (within the meaning of section 316) of any corporation shall be determined without regard to this section and chapter 535 of title 46, United States Code, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> in applying the tax imposed by section 531 (relating to the accumulated earnings tax), amounts while held in the fund shall not be taken into account.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Only qualified deposits eligible for treatment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Paragraph (1) shall apply with respect to any amount only if such amount is deposited in the fund pursuant to the agreement and not later than the time provided in joint regulations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of accounts</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Within a capital construction fund 3 accounts shall be maintained:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the capital account,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the capital gain account, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the ordinary income account.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Capital account</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The capital account shall consist of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> amounts referred to in subsection (a)(1)(B),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> amounts referred to in subsection (a)(1)(C) other than that portion thereof which represents gain not taken into account by reason of subsection (c)(1)(B),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the percentage applicable under section 243(a)(1) of any dividend received by the fund with respect to which the person maintaining the fund would (but for subsection (c)(1)(C)) be allowed a deduction under section 243, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> interest income exempt from taxation under section 103.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Capital gain account</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The capital gain account shall consist of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> amounts representing capital gains on assets held for more than 6 months and referred to in subsection (a)(1)(C) or (a)(1)(D), reduced by</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> amounts representing capital losses on assets held in the fund for more than 6 months.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ordinary income account</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The ordinary income account shall consist of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> amounts referred to in subsection (a)(1)(A),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> amounts representing capital gains on assets held for 6 months or less and referred to in subsection (a)(1)(C) or (a)(1)(D), reduced by</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> amounts representing capital losses on assets held in the fund for 6 months or less,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> interest (not including any tax-exempt interest referred to in paragraph (2)(D)) and other ordinary income (not including any dividend referred to in subparagraph (E)) received on assets held in the fund,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> ordinary income from a transaction described in subsection (a)(1)(C), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> the portion of any dividend referred to in paragraph (2)(C) not taken into account under such paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Capital losses only allowed to offset certain gains</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except on termination of a capital construction fund, capital losses referred to in paragraph (3)(B) or in paragraph (4)(B)(ii) shall be allowed only as an offset to gains referred to in paragraph (3)(A) or (4)(B)(i), respectively.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purposes of qualified withdrawals</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A qualified withdrawal from the fund is one made in accordance with the terms of the agreement but only if it is for:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the acquisition, construction, or reconstruction of a qualified vessel,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the acquisition, construction, or reconstruction of barges and containers which are part of the complement of a qualified vessel, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the payment of the principal on indebtedness incurred in connection with the acquisition, construction, or reconstruction of a qualified vessel or a barge or container which is part of the complement of a qualified vessel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">Except to the extent provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary, subparagraph (B), and so much of subparagraph (C) as relates only to barges and containers, shall apply only with respect to barges and containers constructed in the United States.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalty for failing to fulfill any substantial obligation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Under joint regulations, if the Secretary determines that any substantial obligation under any agreement is not being fulfilled, he may, after notice and opportunity for hearing to the person maintaining the fund, treat the entire fund or any portion thereof as an amount withdrawn from the fund in a nonqualified withdrawal.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax treatment of qualified withdrawals</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ordering rule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any qualified withdrawal from a fund shall be treated—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> first as made out of the capital account,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> second as made out of the capital gain account, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> third as made out of the ordinary income account.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment to basis of vessel, etc., where withdrawal from ordinary income account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If any portion of a qualified withdrawal for a vessel, barge, or container is made out of the ordinary income account, the basis of such vessel, barge, or container shall be reduced by an amount equal to such portion.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment to basis of vessel, etc., where withdrawal from capital gain account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If any portion of a qualified withdrawal for a vessel, barge, or container is made out of the capital gain account, the basis of such vessel, barge, or container shall be reduced by an amount equal to such portion.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment to basis of vessels, etc., where withdrawals pay principal on debt</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If any portion of a qualified withdrawal to pay the principal on any indebtedness is made out of the ordinary income account or the capital gain account, then an amount equal to the aggregate reduction which would be required by paragraphs (2) and (3) if this were a qualified withdrawal for a purpose described in such paragraphs shall be applied, in the order provided in joint regulations, to reduce the basis of vessels, barges, and containers owned by the person maintaining the fund. Any amount of a withdrawal remaining after the application of the preceding sentence shall be treated as a nonqualified withdrawal.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ordinary income recapture of basis reduction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If any property the basis of which was reduced under paragraph (2), (3), or (4) is disposed of, any gain realized on such disposition, to the extent it does not exceed the aggregate reduction in the basis of such property under such paragraphs, shall be treated as an amount referred to in subsection (g)(3)(A) which was withdrawn on the date of such disposition. Subject to such conditions and requirements as may be provided in joint regulations, the preceding sentence shall not apply to a disposition where there is a redeposit in an amount determined under joint regulations which will, insofar as practicable, restore the fund to the position it was in before the withdrawal.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax treatment of nonqualified withdrawals</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in subsection (h), any withdrawal from a capital construction fund which is not a qualified withdrawal shall be treated as a nonqualified withdrawal.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Ordering rule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any nonqualified withdrawal from a fund shall be treated—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> first as made out of the ordinary income account,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> second as made out of the capital gain account, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> third as made out of the capital account.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of this section, items withdrawn from any account shall be treated as withdrawn on a first-in-first-out basis; except that (i) any nonqualified withdrawal for research, development, and design expenses incident to new and advanced ship design, machinery and equipment, and (ii) any amount treated as a nonqualified withdrawal under the second sentence of subsection (f)(4), shall be treated as withdrawn on a last-in-first-out basis.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operating rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this title—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any amount referred to in paragraph (2)(A) shall be included in income as an item of ordinary income for the taxable year in which the withdrawal is made,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any amount referred to in paragraph (2)(B) shall be included in income for the taxable year in which the withdrawal is made as an item of gain realized during such year from the disposition of an asset held for more than 6 months, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> for the period on or before the last date prescribed for payment of tax for the taxable year in which this withdrawal is made—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> no interest shall be payable under section 6601 and no addition to the tax shall be payable under section 6651,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> interest on the amount of the additional tax attributable to any item referred to in subparagraph (A) or (B) shall be paid at the applicable rate (as defined in paragraph (4)) from the last date prescribed for payment of the tax for the taxable year for which such item was deposited in the fund, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> no interest shall be payable on amounts referred to in clauses (i) and (ii) of paragraph (2) or in the case of any nonqualified withdrawal arising from the application of the recapture provision of section 606(5) of the Merchant Marine Act, 1936, as in effect on <date date="1969-12-31">December 31, 1969</date>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest rate</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (3)(C)(ii), the applicable rate of interest for any nonqualified withdrawal shall be determined and published jointly by the Secretary of the Treasury or his delegate and the applicable Secretary and shall bear a relationship to 8 percent which the Secretaries determine under joint regulations to be comparable to the relationship which the money rates and investment yields for the calendar year immediately preceding the beginning of the taxable year bear to the money rates and investment yields for the calendar year 1970.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amount not withdrawn from fund after 25 years from deposit taxed as nonqualified withdrawal</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The applicable percentage of any amount which remains in a capital construction fund at the close of the 26th, 27th, 28th, 29th, or 30th taxable year following the taxable year for which such amount was deposited shall be treated as a nonqualified withdrawal in accordance with the following table:<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><th><p><b> If the amount remains in the fund</b></p><p><b>  at the close of the—</b></p></th><th><p><b>The applicable percentage is—</b></p></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>26th taxable year</span></p></td><td><p>20 percent  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>27th taxable year</span></p></td><td><p>40 percent  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>28th taxable year</span></p></td><td><p>60 percent  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>29th taxable year</span></p></td><td><p>80 percent  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>30th taxable year</span></p></td><td><p>100 percent.</p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Earnings treated as deposits</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The earnings of any capital construction fund for any taxable year (other than net gains) shall be treated for purposes of this paragraph as an amount deposited for such taxable year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amounts committed treated as withdrawn</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), an amount shall not be treated as remaining in a capital construction fund at the close of any taxable year to the extent there is a binding contract at the close of such year for a qualified withdrawal of such amount with respect to an identified item for which such withdrawal may be made.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authority to treat excess funds as withdrawn</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If the Secretary determines that the balance in any capital construction fund exceeds the amount which is appropriate to meet the vessel construction program objectives of the person who established such fund, the amount of such excess shall be treated as a nonqualified withdrawal under subparagraph (A) unless such person develops appropriate program objectives within 3 years to dissipate such excess.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(E)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amounts in fund on <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date></heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, all amounts in a capital construction fund on <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>, shall be treated as deposited in such fund on such date.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonqualified withdrawals taxed at highest marginal rate</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">In the case of any taxable year for which there is a nonqualified withdrawal (including any amount so treated under paragraph (5)), the tax imposed by chapter 1 shall be determined—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> by excluding such withdrawal from gross income, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> by increasing the tax imposed by chapter 1 by the product of the amount of such withdrawal and the highest rate of tax specified in section 1 (section 11 in the case of a corporation).</content>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent2 firstIndent0">In the case of a taxpayer other than a corporation, with respect to the portion of any nonqualified withdrawal made out of the capital gain account during a taxable year to which section 1(h) applies, the rate of tax taken into account under the preceding sentence shall not exceed 20 percent.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax benefit rule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">If any portion of a nonqualified withdrawal is properly attributable to deposits (other than earnings on deposits) made by the taxpayer in any taxable year which did not reduce the taxpayer’s liability for tax under chapter 1 for any taxable year preceding the taxable year in which such withdrawal occurs—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> such portion shall not be taken into account under subparagraph (A), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an amount equal to such portion shall be treated as allowed as a deduction under section 172 for the taxable year in which such withdrawal occurs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with deduction for net operating losses</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any nonqualified withdrawal excluded from gross income under subparagraph (A) shall be excluded in determining taxable income under section 172(b)(2).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain corporate reorganizations and changes in partnerships</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Under joint regulations—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a transfer of a fund from one person to another person in a transaction to which section 381 applies may be treated as if such transaction did not constitute a nonqualified withdrawal, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a similar rule shall be applied in the case of a continuation of a partnership.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, any term defined in chapter 535 of title 46, United States Code, which is also used in this section (including the definition of “Secretary”) shall have the meaning given such term by such chapter as in effect on the date of the enactment of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 99–514, title II, § 261(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref>100 Stat. 2208</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title I</ref>, §§ 1002(m)(1), 1018(u)(23), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3382</ref>, 3591; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11101(d)(7)(A)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–405</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–34, title III, § 311(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 835</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–27, title III, § 301(a)(2)(D)</ref>, <date date="2003-05-28">May 28, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 758</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 109–304, § 17(e)(6)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-06">Oct. 6, 2006</date>, <ref>120 Stat. 1708</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 112–240, title I, § 102(c)(1)(D)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref>126 Stat. 2319</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(117)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4054</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–97, title I, § 13001(b)(2)(Q)</ref>, (7), <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 2097</ref>, 2098; <ref>Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(352)</ref>, <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref>132 Stat. 1201</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7519.</num>
<heading> Required payments for entities electing not to have required taxable year</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This section applies to a partnership or S corporation for any taxable year, if—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> an election under section 444 is in effect for the taxable year, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the required payment determined under subsection (b) for such taxable year (or any preceding taxable year) exceeds $500.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required payment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “required payment” means, with respect to any applicable election year of a partnership or S corporation, an amount equal to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> the excess of the product of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the applicable percentage of the adjusted highest section 1 rate, multiplied by</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the net base year income of the entity, over</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the net required payment balance.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of paragraph (1)(A), the term “adjusted highest section 1 rate” means the highest rate of tax in effect under section 1 as of the end of the base year plus 1 percentage point (or, in the case of applicable election years beginning in 1987, 36 percent).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Refund of payments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If, for any applicable election year, the amount determined under subsection (b)(2) exceeds the amount determined under subsection (b)(1), the entity shall be entitled to a refund of such excess for such year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination of elections, etc.</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">If—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> an election under section 444 is terminated effective with respect to any year, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the entity is liquidated during any year, the entity shall be entitled to a refund of the net required payment balance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Date on which refund payable</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any refund under this subsection shall be payable on the later of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> April 15 of the calendar year following—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> in the case of the year referred to in paragraph (1), the calendar year in which it begins,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> in the case of the year referred to in paragraph (2), the calendar year in which it ends, or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the day 90 days after the day on which claim therefor is filed with the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Net base year income</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An entity’s net base year income shall be equal to the sum of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the deferral ratio multiplied by the entity’s net income for the base year, plus</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> the excess (if any) of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the deferral ratio multiplied by the aggregate amount of applicable payments made by the entity during the base year, over</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the aggregate amount of such applicable payments made during the deferral period of the base year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “deferral ratio” means the ratio which the number of months in the deferral period of the base year bears to the number of months in the partnership’s or S corporation’s taxable year.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Net income</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Net income is determined by taking into account the aggregate amount of the following items—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Partnerships</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of a partnership, net income shall be the amount (not below zero) determined by taking into account the aggregate amount of the partnership’s items described in section 702(a) (other than credits and tax-exempt income).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> S corporations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of an S corporation, net income shall be the amount (not below zero) determined by taking into account the aggregate amount of the S corporation’s items described in section 1366(a) (other than credits and tax-exempt income). If the S corporation was a C corporation for the base year, its taxable income for such year shall be treated as its net income for such year (and such corporation shall be treated as an S corporation for such taxable year for purposes of paragraph (3)).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain limitations disregarded</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A) or (B), any limitation on the amount of any item described in either such paragraph which may be taken into account for purposes of computing the taxable income of a partner or shareholder shall be disregarded.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable payments</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “applicable payment” means amounts paid by a partnership or S corporation which are includible in gross income of a partner or shareholder.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “applicable payment” shall not include any—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> gain from the sale or exchange of property between the partner or shareholder and the partnership or S corporation, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> dividend paid by the S corporation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable percentage</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The applicable percentage is the percentage determined in accordance with the following table:<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><th><p><b>If the applicable election year of</b></p><p><b> the partnership or S corporation</b></p><p><b> begins during:</b></p></th><th><p><b>The applicable percentage is:</b></p></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1987</span></p></td><td><p>25  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1988</span></p></td><td><p>50  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1989</span></p></td><td><p>75  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>1990 or thereafter</span></p></td><td><p>100.</p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</p>
<p class="indent1 firstIndent0">Notwithstanding the preceding provisions of this paragraph, the applicable percentage for any partnership or S corporation shall be 100 percent unless more than 50 percent of such entity’s net income for the short taxable year which would have resulted if the entity had not made an election under section 444 would have been allocated to partners or shareholders who would have been entitled to the benefits of section 806(e)(2)(C) of the Tax Reform Act of 1986 with respect to such income.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of guaranteed payments</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Any guaranteed payment by a partnership shall not be treated as an applicable payment, and the amount of the net income of the partnership shall be determined by not taking such guaranteed payment into account.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guaranteed payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “guaranteed payment” means any payment referred to in section 707(c).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other definitions and special rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Deferral period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “deferral period” has the meaning given to such term by section 444(b)(4).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Years</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Base year</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “base year” means, with respect to any applicable election year, the taxable year of the partnership or S corporation preceding such applicable election year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable election year</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “applicable election year” means any taxable year of a partnership or S corporation with respect to which an election is in effect under section 444.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement of reporting</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each partnership or S corporation which makes an election under section 444 shall include on any required return or statement such information as the Secretary shall prescribe as is necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Net required payment balance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “net required payment balance” means the excess (if any) of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the aggregate of the required payments under this section for all preceding applicable election years, over</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the aggregate amount allowable as a refund to the entity under subsection (c) for all preceding applicable election years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative provisions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection or in regulations prescribed by the Secretary, any payment required by this section shall be assessed and collected in the same manner as if it were a tax imposed by subtitle C.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Due date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amount of any payment required by this section shall be paid on or before April 15 of the calendar year following the calendar year in which the applicable election year begins (or such later date as may be prescribed by the Secretary).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interest</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of determining interest, any payment required by this section shall be treated as a tax; except that no interest shall be allowed with respect to any refund of a payment made under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of any failure by any person to pay on the date prescribed therefor any amount required by this section, there shall be imposed on such person a penalty of 10 percent of the underpayment. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term “underpayment” means the excess of the amount of the payment required under this section over the amount (if any) of such payment paid on or before the date prescribed therefor. No penalty shall be imposed under this subparagraph on any failure which is shown to be due to reasonable cause and not willful neglect.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Negligence and fraud penalties made applicable</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of part II of subchapter A of chapter 68, any payment required by this section shall be treated as a tax.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Willful failure</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">If any partnership or S corporation willfully fails to comply with the requirements of this section, section 444 shall cease to apply with respect to such partnership or S corporation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the provisions of this section and section 280H, including regulations providing for appropriate adjustments in the application of this section and sections 280H and 444 in cases where—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> 2 or more applicable election years begin in the same calendar year, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the base year is a taxable year of less than 12 months.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–203, title X, § 10206(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref>101 Stat. 1330–398</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title II, § 2004(e)(4)</ref>–(10), (14)(B), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3601</ref>, 3602; <ref>Pub. L. 101–239, title VII</ref>, §§ 7721(c)(12), 7821(b), <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2400</ref>, 2424; <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11704(a)(29)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–519</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 105–34, title XII, § 1281(d)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 1037</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7520.</num>
<heading> Valuation tables</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this title, the value of any annuity, any interest for life or a term of years, or any remainder or reversionary interest shall be determined—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> under tables prescribed by the Secretary, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> by using an interest rate (rounded to the nearest 2/10ths of 1 percent) equal to 120 percent of the Federal midterm rate in effect under section 1274(d)(1) for the month in which the valuation date falls.</content>
</paragraph>
<continuation class="indent0 firstIndent0">If an income, estate, or gift tax charitable contribution is allowable for any part of the property transferred, the taxpayer may elect to use such Federal midterm rate for either of the 2 months preceding the month in which the valuation date falls for purposes of paragraph (2). In the case of transfers of more than 1 interest in the same property with respect to which the taxpayer may use the same rate under paragraph (2), the taxpayer shall use the same rate with respect to each such interest.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Section not to apply for certain purposes</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply for purposes of part I of subchapter D of chapter 1 or any other provision specified in regulations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tables</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The tables prescribed by the Secretary for purposes of subsection (a) shall contain valuation factors for a series of interest rate categories.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Revision for recent mortality charges</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall revise the initial tables prescribed for purposes of subsection (a) to take into account the most recent mortality experience available as of the time of such revision. Such tables shall be revised not less frequently than once each 10 years to take into account the most recent mortality experience available as of the time of the revision.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Valuation date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “valuation date” means the date as of which the valuation is made.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tables to include formulas</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “tables” includes formulas.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title V, § 5031(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3668</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(118)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4054</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7521.</num>
<heading> Procedures involving taxpayer interviews</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recording of interviews</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recording by taxpayer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any officer or employee of the Internal Revenue Service in connection with any in-person interview with any taxpayer relating to the determination or collection of any tax shall, upon advance request of such taxpayer, allow the taxpayer to make an audio recording of such interview at the taxpayer’s own expense and with the taxpayer’s own equipment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Recording by IRS officer or employee</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An officer or employee of the Internal Revenue Service may record any interview described in paragraph (1) if such officer or employee—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> informs the taxpayer of such recording prior to the interview, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> upon request of the taxpayer, provides the taxpayer with a transcript or copy of such recording but only if the taxpayer provides reimbursement for the cost of the transcription and reproduction of such transcript or copy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Safeguards</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Explanations of processes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">An officer or employee of the Internal Revenue Service shall before or at an initial interview provide to the taxpayer—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of an in-person interview with the taxpayer relating to the determination of any tax, an explanation of the audit process and the taxpayer’s rights under such process, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of an in-person interview with the taxpayer relating to the collection of any tax, an explanation of the collection process and the taxpayer’s rights under such process.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Right of consultation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If the taxpayer clearly states to an officer or employee of the Internal Revenue Service at any time during any interview (other than an interview initiated by an administrative summons issued under subchapter A of chapter 78) that the taxpayer wishes to consult with an attorney, certified public accountant, enrolled agent, enrolled actuary, or any other person permitted to represent the taxpayer before the Internal Revenue Service, such officer or employee shall suspend such interview regardless of whether the taxpayer may have answered one or more questions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Representatives holding power of attorney</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any attorney, certified public accountant, enrolled agent, enrolled actuary, or any other person permitted to represent the taxpayer before the Internal Revenue Service who is not disbarred or suspended from practice before the Internal Revenue Service and who has a written power of attorney executed by the taxpayer may be authorized by such taxpayer to represent the taxpayer in any interview described in subsection (a). An officer or employee of the Internal Revenue Service may not require a taxpayer to accompany the representative in the absence of an administrative summons issued to the taxpayer under subchapter A of chapter 78. Such an officer or employee, with the consent of the immediate supervisor of such officer or employee, may notify the taxpayer directly that such officer or employee believes such representative is responsible for unreasonable delay or hindrance of an Internal Revenue Service examination or investigation of the taxpayer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Section not to apply to certain investigations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">This section shall not apply to criminal investigations or investigations relating to the integrity of any officer or employee of the Internal Revenue Service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VI, § 6228(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3731</ref>, § 7520; renumbered § 7521, <ref>Pub. L. 101–239, title VII, § 7816(u)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref>103 Stat. 2423</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7522.</num>
<heading> Content of tax due, deficiency, and other notices</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Any notice to which this section applies shall describe the basis for, and identify the amounts (if any) of, the tax due, interest, additional amounts, additions to the tax, and assessable penalties included in such notice. An inadequate description under the preceding sentence shall not invalidate such notice.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notices to which section applies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">This section shall apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any tax due notice or deficiency notice described in section 6155, 6212, or 6303,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any notice generated out of any information return matching program, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> the 1st letter of proposed deficiency which allows the taxpayer an opportunity for administrative review in the Internal Revenue Service Independent Office of Appeals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 100–647, title VI, § 6233(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref>102 Stat. 3735</ref>, § 7521; renumbered § 7522, <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11704(a)(30)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–519</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–25, title I, § 1001(b)(1)(I)</ref>, <date date="2019-07-01">July 1, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 985</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7523.</num>
<heading> Graphic presentation of major categories of Federal outlays and income</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of any booklet of instructions for Form 1040, 1040A, or 1040EZ prepared by the Secretary for filing individual income tax returns for taxable years beginning in any calendar year, the Secretary shall include in a prominent place—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> a pie-shaped graph showing the relative sizes of the major outlay categories, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> a pie-shaped graph showing the relative sizes of the major income categories.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions and special rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Major outlay categories</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “major outlay categories” means the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Defense, veterans, and foreign affairs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Social security, medicare, and other retirement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Physical, human, and community development.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Social programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Law enforcement and general government.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> Interest on the debt.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Major income categories</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “major income categories” means the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> Social security, medicare, and unemployment and other retirement taxes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> Personal income taxes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> Corporate income taxes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> Borrowing to cover the deficit.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> Excise, customs, estate, gift, and miscellaneous taxes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required footnotes</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The pie-shaped graph showing the major outlay categories shall include the following footnotes:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> A footnote to the category referred to in paragraph (1)(A) showing the percentage of the total outlays which is for defense, the percentage of total outlays which is for veterans, and the percentage of total outlays which is for foreign affairs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> A footnote to the category referred to in paragraph (1)(C) showing that such category consists of agriculture, natural resources, environment, transportation, education, job training, economic development, space, energy, and general science.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> A footnote to the category referred to in paragraph (1)(D) showing the percentage of the total outlays which is for medicaid, supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits, and assistance under a State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act and the percentage of total outlays which is for public health, unemployment, assisted housing, and social services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Data on which graphs are based</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The graphs required under subsection (a) shall be based on data for the most recent fiscal year for which complete data is available as of the completion of the preparation of the instructions by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11622(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref>104 Stat. 1388–504</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 104–193, title I, § 110</ref>(<i>l</i>)(4), formerly § 110(<i>l</i>)(8), <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 2173</ref>, renumbered <ref>Pub. L. 105–33, title V, § 5514(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref>111 Stat. 620</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–234, title IV, § 4002(b)(1)(E)</ref>, (2)(O), <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1096</ref>, 1097; <ref>Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title IV, § 4002(b)(1)(E), (2)(O), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref>122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1857, 1858.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7524.</num>
<heading> Annual notice of tax delinquency</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not less often than annually, the Secretary shall send a written notice to each taxpayer who has a tax delinquent account of the amount of the tax delinquency as of the date of the notice.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 104–168, title XII, § 1204(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-07-30">July 30, 1996</date>, <ref>110 Stat. 1471</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7525.</num>
<heading> Confidentiality privileges relating to taxpayer communications</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Uniform application to taxpayer communications with federally authorized practitioners</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">With respect to tax advice, the same common law protections of confidentiality which apply to a communication between a taxpayer and an attorney shall also apply to a communication between a taxpayer and any federally authorized tax practitioner to the extent the communication would be considered a privileged communication if it were between a taxpayer and an attorney.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Paragraph (1) may only be asserted in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any noncriminal tax matter before the Internal Revenue Service; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any noncriminal tax proceeding in Federal court brought by or against the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federally authorized tax practitioner</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “federally authorized tax practitioner” means any individual who is authorized under Federal law to practice before the Internal Revenue Service if such practice is subject to Federal regulation under <ref>section 330 of title 31</ref>, United States Code.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax advice</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “tax advice” means advice given by an individual with respect to a matter which is within the scope of the individual’s authority to practice described in subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Section not to apply to communications regarding tax shelters</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The privilege under subsection (a) shall not apply to any written communication which is—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> between a federally authorized tax practitioner and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> any person,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> any director, officer, employee, agent, or representative of the person, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> any other person holding a capital or profits interest in the person, and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> in connection with the promotion of the direct or indirect participation of the person in any tax shelter (as defined in section 6662(d)(2)(C)(ii)).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title III, § 3411(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 750</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–357, title VIII, § 813(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1581</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7526.</num>
<heading> Low-income taxpayer clinics</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may, subject to the availability of appropriated funds, make grants to provide matching funds for the development, expansion, or continuation of qualified low-income taxpayer clinics.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified low-income taxpayer clinic</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “qualified low-income taxpayer clinic” means a clinic that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> does not charge more than a nominal fee for its services (except for reimbursement of actual costs incurred); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> represents low-income taxpayers in controversies with the Internal Revenue Service; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> operates programs to inform individuals for whom English is a second language about their rights and responsibilities under this title.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Representation of low-income taxpayers</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A clinic meets the requirements of subparagraph (A)(ii)(I) if—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> at least 90 percent of the taxpayers represented by the clinic have incomes which do not exceed 250 percent of the poverty level, as determined in accordance with criteria established by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the amount in controversy for any taxable year generally does not exceed the amount specified in section 7463.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Clinic</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “clinic” includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a clinical program at an accredited law, business, or accounting school in which students represent low-income taxpayers in controversies arising under this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> an organization described in section 501(c) and exempt from tax under section 501(a) which satisfies the requirements of paragraph (1) through representation of taxpayers or referral of taxpayers to qualified representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified representative</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “qualified representative” means any individual (whether or not an attorney) who is authorized to practice before the Internal Revenue Service or the applicable court.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules and limitations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Aggregate limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Unless otherwise provided by specific appropriation, the Secretary shall not allocate more than $6,000,000 per year (exclusive of costs of administering the program) to grants under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on annual grants to a clinic</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The aggregate amount of grants which may be made under this section to a clinic for a year shall not exceed $100,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Multi-year grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon application of a qualified low-income taxpayer clinic, the Secretary is authorized to award a multi-year grant not to exceed 3 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criteria for awards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In determining whether to make a grant under this section, the Secretary shall consider—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the numbers of taxpayers who will be served by the clinic, including the number of taxpayers in the geographical area for whom English is a second language;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the existence of other low-income taxpayer clinics serving the same population;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the quality of the program offered by the low-income taxpayer clinic, including the qualifications of its administrators and qualified representatives, and its record, if any, in providing service to low-income taxpayers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> alternative funding sources available to the clinic, including amounts received from other grants and contributions, and the endowment and resources of the institution sponsoring the clinic.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement of matching funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A low-income taxpayer clinic must provide matching funds on a dollar-for-dollar basis for all grants provided under this section. Matching funds may include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the salary (including fringe benefits) of individuals performing services for the clinic; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the cost of equipment used in the clinic.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">Indirect expenses, including general overhead of the institution sponsoring the clinic, shall not be counted as matching funds.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision of information regarding qualified low-income taxpayer clinics</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, officers and employees of the Department of the Treasury may—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> advise taxpayers of the availability of, and eligibility requirements for receiving, advice and assistance from one or more specific qualified low-income taxpayer clinics receiving funding under this section, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide information regarding the location of, and contact information for, such clinics.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 105–206, title III, § 3601(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-22">July 22, 1998</date>, <ref>112 Stat. 774</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 116–25, title I, § 1402(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-07-01">July 1, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 997</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7526A.</num>
<heading> Return preparation programs for applicable taxpayers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment of Volunteer Income Tax Assistance Matching Grant Program</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a Community Volunteer Income Tax Assistance Matching Grant Program under which the Secretary may, subject to the availability of appropriated funds, make grants to provide matching funds for the development, expansion, or continuation of qualified return preparation programs assisting applicable taxpayers and members of underserved populations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Qualified return preparation programs may use grants received under this section for—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> ordinary and necessary costs associated with program operation in accordance with cost principles under the applicable Office of Management and Budget circular, including—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> wages or salaries of persons coordinating the activities of the program,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> developing training materials, conducting training, and performing quality reviews of the returns prepared under the program,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> equipment purchases, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> vehicle-related expenses associated with remote or rural tax preparation services,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> outreach and educational activities described in subsection (c)(2)(B), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> services related to financial education and capability, asset development, and the establishment of savings accounts in connection with tax return preparation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement of matching funds</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">A qualified return preparation program must provide matching funds on a dollar-for-dollar basis for all grants provided under this section. Matching funds may include—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the salary (including fringe benefits) of individuals performing services for the program,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the cost of equipment used in the program, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> other ordinary and necessary costs associated with the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">Indirect expenses, including general overhead of any entity administering the program, shall not be counted as matching funds.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Each applicant for a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to applications which demonstrate—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> assistance to applicable taxpayers, with emphasis on outreach to, and services for, such taxpayers,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> taxpayer outreach and educational activities relating to eligibility and availability of income supports available through this title, including the earned income tax credit, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> specific outreach and focus on one or more underserved populations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Amounts taken into account</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In determining matching grants under this section, the Secretary shall only take into account amounts provided by the qualified return preparation program for expenses described in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program adherence</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish procedures for, and shall conduct not less frequently than once every 5 calendar years during which a qualified return preparation program is operating under a grant under this section, periodic site visits—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to ensure the program is carrying out the purposes of this section, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to determine whether the program meets such program adherence standards as the Secretary shall by regulation or other guidance prescribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional requirements for grant recipients not meeting program adherence standards</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of any qualified return preparation program which—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is awarded a grant under this section, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> is subsequently determined—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> not to meet the program adherence standards described in paragraph (1)(B), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> not to be otherwise carrying out the purposes of this section,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">such program shall not be eligible for any additional grants under this section unless such program provides sufficient documentation of corrective measures established to address any such deficiencies determined.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified return preparation program</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “qualified return preparation program” means any program—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> which provides assistance to individuals, not less than 90 percent of whom are applicable taxpayers, in preparing and filing Federal income tax returns,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> which is administered by a qualified entity,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in which all volunteers who assist in the preparation of Federal income tax returns meet the training requirements prescribed by the Secretary, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> which uses a quality review process which reviews 100 percent of all returns.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified entity</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “qualified entity” means any entity which—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> is an eligible organization,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> is in compliance with Federal tax filing and payment requirements,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> is not debarred or suspended from Federal contracts, grants, or cooperative agreements, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> agrees to provide documentation to substantiate any matching funds provided pursuant to the grant program under this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible organization</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “eligible organization” means—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> an institution of higher education which is described in section 102 (other than subsection (a)(1)(C) thereof) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref>20 U.S.C. 1002</ref>), as in effect on the date of the enactment of this section, and which has not been disqualified from participating in a program under title IV of such Act,</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> an organization described in section 501(c) and exempt from tax under section 501(a),</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<chapeau> a local government agency, including—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a county or municipal government agency, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> an Indian tribe, as defined in section 4(13) of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<ref>25 U.S.C. 4103(13)</ref>), including any tribally designated housing entity (as defined in section 4(22) of such Act (<ref>25 U.S.C. 4103(22)</ref>)), tribal subsidiary, subdivision, or other wholly owned tribal entity,</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> a local, State, regional, or national coalition (with one lead organization which meets the eligibility requirements of clause (i), (ii), or (iii) acting as the applicant organization), or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of applicable taxpayers and members of underserved populations with respect to which no organizations described in the preceding clauses are available—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> a State government agency, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> an office providing Cooperative Extension services (as established at the land-grant colleges and universities under the Smith-Lever Act of <date date="1914-05-08">May 8, 1914</date>).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Applicable taxpayers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “applicable taxpayer” means a taxpayer whose income for the taxable year does not exceed an amount equal to the completed phaseout amount under section 32(b) for a married couple filing a joint return with three or more qualifying children, as determined in a revenue procedure or other published guidance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Underserved population</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “underserved population” includes populations of persons with disabilities, persons with limited English proficiency, Native Americans, individuals living in rural areas, members of the Armed Forces and their spouses, and the elderly.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules and limitations</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Duration of grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon application of a qualified return preparation program, the Secretary is authorized to award a multi-year grant not to exceed 3 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Aggregate limitation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Unless otherwise provided by specific appropriation, the Secretary shall not allocate more than $30 million per fiscal year (exclusive of costs of administering the program) to grants under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Promotion of programs</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall promote tax preparation through qualified return preparation programs through the use of mass communications and other means.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Provision of information regarding qualified return preparation programs</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary may provide taxpayers information regarding qualified return preparation programs receiving grants under this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Referrals to low-income taxpayer clinics</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Qualified return preparation programs receiving a grant under this section are encouraged, in appropriate cases, to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> advise taxpayers of the availability of, and eligibility requirements for receiving, advice and assistance from qualified low-income taxpayer clinics receiving funding under section 7526, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide information regarding the location of, and contact information for, such clinics.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–25, title I, § 1401(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-07-01">July 1, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 993</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7527.</num>
<heading> Advance payment of credit for health insurance costs of eligible individuals</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of the Trade Adjustment Assistance Reauthorization Act of 2015, the Secretary shall establish a program for making payments on behalf of certified individuals to providers of qualified health insurance (as defined in section 35(e)) for such individuals.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on advance payments during any taxable year</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary may make payments under subsection (a) only to the extent that the total amount of such payments made on behalf of any individual during the taxable year does not exceed 72.5 percent of the amount paid by the taxpayer for coverage of the taxpayer and qualifying family members under qualified health insurance for eligible coverage months beginning in the taxable year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certified individual</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “certified individual” means any individual for whom a qualified health insurance costs credit eligibility certificate is in effect.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Qualified health insurance costs eligibility certificate</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “qualified health insurance costs eligibility certificate” means any written statement that an individual is an eligible individual (as defined in section 35(c)) if such statement provides such information as the Secretary may require for purposes of this section and—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of an eligible TAA recipient (as defined in section 35(c)(2)) or an eligible alternative TAA recipient (as defined in section 35(c)(3)), is certified by the Secretary of Labor (or by any other person or entity designated by the Secretary), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of an eligible PBGC pension recipient (as defined in section 35(c)(4)), is certified by the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (or by any other person or entity designated by the Secretary).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inclusion of certain information</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of any statement described in paragraph (1), such statement shall not be treated as a qualified health insurance costs credit eligibility certificate unless such statement includes—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the name, address, and telephone number of the State office or offices responsible for providing the individual with assistance with enrollment in qualified health insurance (as defined in section 35(e)),</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a list of the coverage options that are treated as qualified health insurance (as so defined) by the State in which the individual resides, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of a TAA-eligible individual (as defined in section 4980B(f)(5)(C)(iv)(II)), a statement informing the individual that the individual has 63 days from the date that is 7 days after the date of the issuance of such certificate to enroll in such insurance without a lapse in creditable coverage (as defined in section 9801(c)).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment for premiums due prior to commencement of advance payments</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The program established under subsection (a) shall provide that the Secretary shall make 1 or more retroactive payments on behalf of a certified individual in an aggregate amount equal to 72.5 percent of the premiums for coverage of the taxpayer and qualifying family members under qualified health insurance for eligible coverage months (as defined in section 35(b)) occurring—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of the Trade Adjustment Assistance Reauthorization Act of 2015; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> prior to the first month for which an advance payment is made on behalf of such individual under subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reduction of payment for amounts received under national emergency grants</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amount of any payment determined under paragraph (1) shall be reduced by the amount of any payment made to the taxpayer for the purchase of qualified health insurance under a national emergency grant pursuant to section 173(f) of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act) for a taxable year including the eligible coverage months described in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 107–210, div. A, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-06">Aug. 6, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 960</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 111–5, div. B, title I</ref>, §§ 1899A(a)(2), 1899B(a), 1899H(a), <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref>123 Stat. 424</ref>, 430; <ref>Pub. L. 111–344, title I</ref>, §§ 111(b), 112(a), 118(a), <date date="2010-12-29">Dec. 29, 2010</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3615</ref>, 3616; <ref>Pub. L. 112–40, title II, § 241(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-10-21">Oct. 21, 2011</date>, <ref>125 Stat. 418</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–128, title V, § 512(r)</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 1712</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–27, title IV, § 407(c)</ref>, <date date="2015-06-29">June 29, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 382</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7527A.</num>
<heading> Advance payment of child tax credit</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a program for making periodic payments to taxpayers which, in the aggregate during any calendar year, equal the annual advance amount determined with respect to such taxpayer for such calendar year. Except as provided in subsection (b)(3)(B), the periodic payments made to any taxpayer for any calendar year shall be in equal amounts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual advance amount</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the term “annual advance amount” means, with respect to any taxpayer for any calendar year, the amount (if any) which is estimated by the Secretary as being equal to 50 percent of the amount which would be treated as allowed under subpart C of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 by reason of section 24(i)(1) for the taxpayer’s taxable year beginning in such calendar year if—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the status of the taxpayer as a taxpayer described in section 24(i)(1) is determined with respect to the reference taxable year,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the taxpayer’s modified adjusted gross income for such taxable year is equal to the taxpayer’s modified adjusted gross income for the reference taxable year,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the only children of such taxpayer for such taxable year are qualifying children properly claimed on the taxpayer’s return of tax for the reference taxable year, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the ages of such children (and the status of such children as qualifying children) are determined for such taxable year by taking into account the passage of time since the reference taxable year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reference taxable year</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (3)(A), the term “reference taxable year” means, with respect to any taxpayer for any calendar year, the taxpayer’s taxable year beginning in the preceding calendar year or, in the case of taxpayer who did not file a return of tax for such taxable year, the taxpayer’s taxable year beginning in the second preceding calendar year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Modifications during calendar year</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary may modify, during any calendar year, the annual advance amount with respect to any taxpayer for such calendar year to take into account—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> a return of tax filed by such taxpayer during such calendar year (and the taxable year to which such return relates may be taken into account as the reference taxable year), and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any other information provided by the taxpayer to the Secretary which allows the Secretary to determine payments under subsection (a) which, in the aggregate during any taxable year of the taxpayer, more closely total the Secretary’s estimate of the amount treated as allowed under subpart C of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 by reason of section 24(i)(1) for such taxable year of such taxpayer.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adjustment to reflect excess or deficit in prior payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of any modification of the annual advance amount under subparagraph (A), the Secretary may adjust the amount of any periodic payment made after the date of such modification to properly take into account the amount by which any periodic payment made before such date was greater than or less than the amount that such payment would have been on the basis of the annual advance amount as so modified.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of status</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">If information contained in the taxpayer’s return of tax for the reference taxable year does not establish the status of the taxpayer as being described in section 24(i)(1), the Secretary shall, for purposes of paragraph (1)(A), determine such status based on information known to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of certain deaths</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A child shall not be taken into account in determining the annual advance amount under paragraph (1) if the death of such child is known to the Secretary as of the beginning of the calendar year for which the estimate under such paragraph is made.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> On-line information portal</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish an on-line portal which allows taxpayers to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> elect not to receive payments under this section, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> provide information to the Secretary which would be relevant to a modification under subsection (b)(3)(B) of the annual advance amount, including information regarding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> a change in the number of the taxpayer’s qualifying children, including by reason of the birth of a child,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> a change in the taxpayer’s marital status,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> a significant change in the taxpayer’s income, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> any other factor which the Secretary may provide.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notice of payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than January 31 of the calendar year following any calendar year during which the Secretary makes one or more payments to any taxpayer under this section, the Secretary shall provide such taxpayer with a written notice which includes the taxpayer’s taxpayer identity (as defined in section 6103(b)(6)), the aggregate amount of such payments made to such taxpayer during such calendar year, and such other information as the Secretary determines appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative provisions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of electronic funds payment requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The payments made by the Secretary under subsection (a) shall be made by electronic funds transfer to the same extent and in the same manner as if such payments were Federal payments not made under this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of certain rules</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Rules similar to the rules of subparagraphs (B) and (C) of section 6428A(f)(3) shall apply for purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception from reduction or offset</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any payment made to any individual under this section shall not be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> subject to reduction or offset pursuant to subsection (c), (d), (e), or (f) of section 6402 or any similar authority permitting offset, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> reduced or offset by other assessed Federal taxes that would otherwise be subject to levy or collection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of advance payments in the possessions of the United States</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The advance payment amount determined under this section shall be determined—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> by applying section 24(i)(1) without regard to the phrase “or is a bona fide resident of Puerto Rico (within the meaning of section 937(a))”, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> without regard to section 24(k)(3)(C)(ii)(I).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mirror code possessions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">In the case of any possession of the United States with a mirror code tax system (as defined in section 24(k)), this section shall not be treated as part of the income tax laws of the United States for purposes of determining the income tax law of such possession unless such possession elects to have this section be so treated.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative expenses of advance payments</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Mirror code possessions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">In the case of any possession described in subparagraph (B) which makes the election described in such subparagraph, the amount otherwise paid by the Secretary to such possession under section 24(k)(1)(A) with respect to taxable years beginning in 2021 shall be increased by $300,000 if such possession has a plan, which has been approved by the Secretary, for making advance payments consistent with such election.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> American Samoa</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The amount otherwise paid by the Secretary to American Samoa under subparagraph (A) of section 24(k)(3) with respect to taxable years beginning in 2021 shall be increased by $300,000 if the plan described in subparagraph (B) of such section includes a program, which has been approved by the Secretary, for making advance payments under rules similar to the rules of this section.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing of payment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary may pay, upon the request of the possession of the United States to which the payment is to be made, the amount of the increase determined under clause (i) or (ii) immediately upon approval of the plan referred to in such clause, respectively.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">No payments shall be made under the program established under subsection (a) with respect to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any period before <date date="2021-07-01">July 1, 2021</date>, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any period after <date date="2021-12-31">December 31, 2021</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as the Secretary determines necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section and subsections (i)(1) and (j) of section 24, including regulations or other guidance which provides for the application of such provisions where the filing status of the taxpayer for a taxable year is different from the status used for determining the annual advance amount.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–2, title IX, § 9611(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 146</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7528.</num>
<heading> Internal Revenue Service user fees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> General rule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a program requiring the payment of user fees for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> requests to the Internal Revenue Service for ruling letters, opinion letters, and determination letters, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> other similar requests.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program criteria</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The fees charged under the program required by subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall vary according to categories (or subcategories) established by the Secretary,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall be determined after taking into account the average time for (and difficulty of) complying with requests in each category (and subcategory), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> shall be payable in advance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemptions, etc.</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary shall provide for such exemptions (and reduced fees) under such program as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption for certain requests regarding pension plans</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall not require payment of user fees under such program for requests for determination letters with respect to the qualified status of a pension benefit plan maintained solely by 1 or more eligible employers or any trust which is part of the plan. The preceding sentence shall not apply to any request—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> made after the later of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the fifth plan year the pension benefit plan is in existence, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the end of any remedial amendment period with respect to the plan beginning within the first 5 plan years, or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> made by the sponsor of any prototype or similar plan which the sponsor intends to market to participating employers.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions and special rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (B)—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Pension benefit plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The term “pension benefit plan” means a pension, profit-sharing, stock bonus, annuity, or employee stock ownership plan.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Eligible employer</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The term “eligible employer” means an eligible employer (as defined in section 408(p)(2)(C)(i)(I)) which has at least 1 employee who is not a highly compensated employee (as defined in section 414(q)) and is participating in the plan. The determination of whether an employer is an eligible employer under subparagraph (B) shall be made as of the date of the request described in such subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(iii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of average fees charged</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">For purposes of any determination of average fees charged, any request to which subparagraph (B) applies shall not be taken into account.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Average fee requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The average fee charged under the program required by subsection (a) shall not be less than the amount determined under the following table:<table width="50%" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><colgroup><col/><col/></colgroup><thead><tr class="header"><td/></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p> </p></td><td><p><b>Average</b></p></td></tr><tr><td><p><b>Category</b></p></td><td><p><b>Fee</b></p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Employee plan ruling and opinion</span></p></td><td><p>$250  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Exempt organization ruling</span></p></td><td><p>$350  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Employee plan determination</span></p></td><td><p>$300  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Exempt organization determination</span></p></td><td><p>$275  </p></td></tr><tr><td><p class="leaders"><span>Chief counsel ruling</span></p></td><td><p>$200.</p></td></tr></tbody></table>
</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certified professional employer organizations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The fee charged under the program in connection with the certification by the Secretary of a professional employer organization under section 7705 shall be an annual fee not to exceed $1,000 per year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–89, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-10-01">Oct. 1, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 1132</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 108–357, title VIII, § 891(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1644</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–28, title VIII, § 8244</ref>, <date date="2007-05-25">May 25, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 200</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–295, div. B, title II, § 206(f)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 4071</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7529.</num>
<heading> Notification of suspected identity theft</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">If the Secretary determines that there has been or may have been an unauthorized use of the identity of any individual, the Secretary shall, without jeopardizing an investigation relating to tax administration—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> as soon as practicable—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> notify the individual of such determination,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provide instructions on how to file a report with law enforcement regarding the unauthorized use,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> identify any steps to be taken by the individual to permit law enforcement to access personal information of the individual during the investigation,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> provide information regarding actions the individual may take in order to protect the individual from harm relating to the unauthorized use, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> offer identity protection measures to the individual, such as the use of an identity protection personal identification number, and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<chapeau> at the time the information described in paragraph (1) is provided (or, if not available at such time, as soon as practicable thereafter), issue additional notifications to such individual (or such individual’s designee) regarding—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> whether an investigation has been initiated in regards to such unauthorized use,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> whether the investigation substantiated an unauthorized use of the identity of the individual, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> whether—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any action has been taken against a person relating to such unauthorized use, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any referral has been made for criminal prosecution of such person and, to the extent such information is available, whether such person has been criminally charged by indictment or information.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Employment-related identity theft</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the unauthorized use of the identity of an individual includes the unauthorized use of the identity of the individual to obtain employment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of employment-related identity theft</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this section, in making a determination as to whether there has been or may have been an unauthorized use of the identity of an individual to obtain employment, the Secretary shall review any information—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> obtained from a statement described in section 6051 or an information return relating to compensation for services rendered other than as an employee, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> provided to the Internal Revenue Service by the Social Security Administration regarding any statement described in section 6051,</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">which indicates that the social security account number provided on such statement or information return does not correspond with the name provided on such statement or information return or the name on the tax return reporting the income which is included on such statement or information return.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 116–25, title II, § 2007(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-07-01">July 1, 2019</date>, <ref>133 Stat. 1005</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 7530.</num>
<heading> Application of earned income tax credit to possessions of the United States</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Puerto Rico</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">With respect to calendar year 2021 and each calendar year thereafter, the Secretary shall, except as otherwise provided in this subsection, make payments to Puerto Rico equal to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the specified matching amount for such calendar year, plus</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of calendar years 2021 through 2025, the lesser of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the expenditures made by Puerto Rico during such calendar year for education efforts with respect to individual taxpayers and tax return preparers relating to the earned income tax credit, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> $1,000,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement to reform earned income tax credit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall not make any payments under paragraph (1) with respect to any calendar year unless Puerto Rico has in effect an earned income tax credit for taxable years beginning in or with such calendar year which (relative to the earned income tax credit which was in effect for taxable years beginning in or with calendar year 2019) increases the percentage of earned income which is allowed as a credit for each group of individuals with respect to which such percentage is separately stated or determined in a manner designed to substantially increase workforce participation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specified matching amount</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">For purposes of this subsection—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The term “specified matching amount” means, with respect to any calendar year, the lesser of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<chapeau> the excess (if any) of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the cost to Puerto Rico of the earned income tax credit for taxable years beginning in or with such calendar year, over</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the base amount for such calendar year, or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the product of 3, multiplied by the base amount for such calendar year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Base amount</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Base amount for 2021</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">In the case of calendar year 2021, the term “base amount” means the greater of—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the cost to Puerto Rico of the earned income tax credit for taxable years beginning in or with calendar year 2019 (rounded to the nearest multiple of $1,000,000), or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> $200,000,000.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inflation adjustment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">In the case of any calendar year after 2021, the term “base amount” means the dollar amount determined under clause (i) increased by an amount equal to—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> such dollar amount, multiplied by—</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for such calendar year, determined by substituting “calendar year 2020” for “calendar year 2016” in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<continuation class="indent3 firstIndent-1"> Any amount determined under this clause shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $1,000,000.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Rules related to payments</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Timing of payments</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Secretary shall make payments under paragraph (1) for any calendar year—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> after receipt of such information as the Secretary may require to determine such payments, and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> except as provided in clause (i), within a reasonable period of time before the due date for individual income tax returns (as determined under the laws of Puerto Rico) for taxable years which began on the first day of such calendar year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary may require the reporting of such information as the Secretary may require to carry out this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determination of cost of earned income tax credit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">For purposes of this subsection, the cost to Puerto Rico of the earned income tax credit shall be determined by the Secretary on the basis of the laws of Puerto Rico and shall include reductions in revenues received by Puerto Rico by reason of such credit and refunds attributable to such credit, but shall not include any administrative costs with respect to such credit.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Possessions with mirror code tax systems</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">With respect to calendar year 2021 and each calendar year thereafter, the Secretary shall, except as otherwise provided in this subsection, make payments to the Virgin Islands, Guam, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands equal to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the cost to such possession of the earned income tax credit for taxable years beginning in or with such calendar year, plus</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of calendar years 2021 through 2025, the lesser of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the expenditures made by such possession during such calendar year for education efforts with respect to individual taxpayers and tax return preparers relating to such earned income tax credit, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> $50,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of certain rules</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Rules similar to the rules of subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of subsection (a)(4) shall apply for purposes of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> American Samoa</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">With respect to calendar year 2021 and each calendar year thereafter, the Secretary shall, except as otherwise provided in this subsection, make payments to American Samoa equal to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> the lesser of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the cost to American Samoa of the earned income tax credit for taxable years beginning in or with such calendar year, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> $16,000,000, plus</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> in the case of calendar years 2021 through 2025, the lesser of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the expenditures made by American Samoa during such calendar year for education efforts with respect to individual taxpayers and tax return preparers relating to such earned income tax credit, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> $50,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement to enact and maintain an earned income tax credit</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary shall not make any payments under paragraph (1) with respect to any calendar year unless American Samoa has in effect an earned income tax credit for taxable years beginning in or with such calendar year which allows a refundable tax credit to individuals on the basis of the taxpayer’s earned income which is designed to substantially increase workforce participation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Inflation adjustment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In the case of any calendar year after 2021, the $16,000,000 amount in paragraph (1)(A)(ii) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> such dollar amount, multiplied by—</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for such calendar year, determined by substituting “calendar year 2020” for “calendar year 2016” in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</content>
</subparagraph>
<continuation class="indent1 firstIndent0">Any increase determined under this clause shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $100,000.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Application of certain rules</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Rules similar to the rules of subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of subsection (a)(4) shall apply for purposes of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Treatment of payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of <ref>section 1324 of title 31</ref>, United States Code, the payments under this section shall be treated in the same manner as a refund due from a credit provision referred to in subsection (b)(2) of such section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 117–2, title IX, § 9625(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-03-11">Mar. 11, 2021</date>, <ref>135 Stat. 155</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>