<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 50—</num>
<heading>FOREIGN PROCUREMENT</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 5000C.</num>
<heading> Imposition of tax on certain foreign procurement</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Imposition of tax</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is hereby imposed on any foreign person that receives a specified Federal procurement payment a tax equal to 2 percent of the amount of such specified Federal procurement payment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specified Federal procurement payment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “specified Federal procurement payment” means any payment made pursuant to a contract with the Government of the United States for—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the provision of goods, if such goods are manufactured or produced in any country which is not a party to an international procurement agreement with the United States, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the provision of services, if such services are provided in any country which is not a party to an international procurement agreement with the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Foreign person</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “foreign person” means any person other than a United States person.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative provisions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Withholding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The amount deducted and withheld under chapter 3 shall be increased by the amount of tax imposed by this section on such payment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other administrative provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of subtitle F, any tax imposed by this section shall be treated as a tax imposed by subtitle A.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 111–347, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-02">Jan. 2, 2011</date>, <ref>124 Stat. 3666</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>