<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 45—</num>
<heading>PROVISIONS RELATING TO EXPATRIATED ENTITIES</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 4985.</num>
<heading> Stock compensation of insiders in expatriated corporations</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Imposition of tax</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In the case of an individual who is a disqualified individual with respect to any expatriated corporation, there is hereby imposed on such person a tax equal to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> the rate of tax specified in section 1(h)(1)(D), multiplied by</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> the value (determined under subsection (b)) of the specified stock compensation held (directly or indirectly) by or for the benefit of such individual or a member of such individual’s family (as defined in section 267) at any time during the 12-month period beginning on the date which is 6 months before the expatriation date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Value</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of subsection (a)—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The value of specified stock compensation shall be—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of a stock option (or other similar right) or a stock appreciation right, the fair value of such option or right, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in any other case, the fair market value of such compensation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Date for determining value</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The determination of value shall be made—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> in the case of specified stock compensation held on the expatriation date, on such date,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in the case of such compensation which is canceled during the 6 months before the expatriation date, on the day before such cancellation, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> in the case of such compensation which is granted after the expatriation date, on the date such compensation is granted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Tax to apply only if shareholder gain recognized</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall apply to any disqualified individual with respect to an expatriated corporation only if gain (if any) on any stock in such corporation is recognized in whole or part by any shareholder by reason of the acquisition referred to in section 7874(a)(2)(B)(i) with respect to such corporation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exception where gain recognized on compensation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Subsection (a) shall not apply to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> any stock option which is exercised on the expatriation date or during the 6-month period before such date and to the stock acquired in such exercise, if income is recognized under section 83 on or before the expatriation date with respect to the stock acquired pursuant to such exercise, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> any other specified stock compensation which is exercised, sold, exchanged, distributed, cashed-out, or otherwise paid during such period in a transaction in which income, gain, or loss is recognized in full.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Disqualified individual</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “disqualified individual” means, with respect to a corporation, any individual who, at any time during the 12-month period beginning on the date which is 6 months before the expatriation date—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> is subject to the requirements of section 16(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 with respect to such corporation or any member of the expanded affiliated group which includes such corporation, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> would be subject to such requirements if such corporation or member were an issuer of equity securities referred to in such section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expatriated corporation; expatriation date</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expatriated corporation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “expatriated corporation” means any corporation which is an expatriated entity (as defined in section 7874(a)(2)). Such term includes any predecessor or successor of such a corporation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expatriation date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “expatriation date” means, with respect to a corporation, the date on which the corporation first becomes an expatriated corporation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Specified stock compensation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The term “specified stock compensation” means payment (or right to payment) granted by the expatriated corporation (or by any member of the expanded affiliated group which includes such corporation) to any person in connection with the performance of services by a disqualified individual for such corporation or member if the value of such payment or right is based on (or determined by reference to) the value (or change in value) of stock in such corporation (or any such member).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Such term shall not include—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> any option to which part II of subchapter D of chapter 1 applies, or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> any payment or right to payment from a plan referred to in section 280G(b)(6).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expanded affiliated group</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “expanded affiliated group” means an affiliated group (as defined in section 1504(a) without regard to section 1504(b)(3)); except that section 1504(a) shall be applied by substituting “more than 50 percent” for “at least 80 percent” each place it appears.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Cancellation of restriction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The cancellation of a restriction which by its terms will never lapse shall be treated as a grant.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Payment or reimbursement of tax by corporation treated as specified stock compensation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Any payment of the tax imposed by this section directly or indirectly by the expatriated corporation or by any member of the expanded affiliated group which includes such corporation—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> shall be treated as specified stock compensation, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> shall not be allowed as a deduction under any provision of chapter 1.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Certain restrictions ignored</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Whether there is specified stock compensation, and the value thereof, shall be determined without regard to any restriction other than a restriction which by its terms will never lapse.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Property transfers</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any transfer of property shall be treated as a payment and any right to a transfer of property shall be treated as a right to a payment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Other administrative provisions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">For purposes of subtitle F, any tax imposed by this section shall be treated as a tax imposed by subtitle A.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(Added <ref>Pub. L. 108–357, title VIII, § 802(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1566</ref>; amended <ref>Pub. L. 115–97, title I, § 13604(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-22">Dec. 22, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 2165</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</chapter>