<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter>
<num>CHAPTER 15—</num>
<heading>ENHANCED BORDER SECURITY AND VISA ENTRY REFORM</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1701.</num>
<heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In this chapter:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Alien</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “alien” has the meaning given the term in <ref>section 1101(a)(3) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Appropriate committees of Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “appropriate committees of Congress” means the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The Committee on the Judiciary, the Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Committee on the Judiciary, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on International Relations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Chimera system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “Chimera system” means the interoperable electronic data system required to be developed and implemented by <ref>section 1722(a)(2) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Federal law enforcement agencies</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The term “Federal law enforcement agencies” means the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> The United States Secret Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> The Drug Enforcement Administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> The Federal Bureau of Investigation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> The Immigration and Naturalization Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> The United States Marshall Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> The Naval Criminal Investigative Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> The Coast Guard.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> The Diplomatic Security Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> The United States Postal Inspection Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> The Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, Department of Justice.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> The United States Customs Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(L)</num>
<content> The National Park Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Intelligence community</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “intelligence community” has the meaning given that term in <ref>section 3003(4) of title 50</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> President</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “President” means the President of the United States, acting through the Assistant to the President for Homeland Security, in coordination with the Secretary of State, the Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization, the Attorney General, the Director of Central Intelligence, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Secretary of Transportation, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, and the Secretary of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(7)</num>
<heading class="bold"> USA PATRIOT Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The term “USA PATRIOT Act” means the Uniting and Strengthening America by Providing Appropriate Tools Required to Intercept and Obstruct Terrorism (USA PATRIOT ACT) Act of 2001 (<ref>Public Law 107–56</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, § 2</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 544</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 107–296, title XI, § 1112(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 2276</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–293, title VI, § 619</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1062</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–125, title VIII, § 802(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>, <ref>130 Stat. 210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER I—</num>
<heading>FUNDING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1711.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations for hiring and training Government personnel</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional personnel</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> INS inspectors</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to the availability of appropriations, during each of the fiscal years 2003 through 2006, the Attorney General shall increase the number of inspectors and associated support staff in the Immigration and Naturalization Service by the equivalent of at least 200 full-time employees over the number of inspectors and associated support staff in the Immigration and Naturalization Service authorized by the USA PATRIOT Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> INS investigative personnel</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Subject to the availability of appropriations, during each of the fiscal years 2003 through 2006, the Attorney General shall increase the number of investigative and associated support staff of the Immigration and Naturalization Service by the equivalent of at least 200 full-time employees over the number of investigators and associated support staff in the Immigration and Naturalization Service authorized by the USA PATRIOT Act.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection, including such sums as may be necessary to provide facilities, attorney personnel and support staff, and other resources needed to support the increased number of inspectors, investigative staff, and associated support staff.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations for INS staffing</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002111">1</ref> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated for the Department of Justice such sums as may be necessary to provide an increase in the annual rate of basic pay effective <date date="2002-10-01">October 1, 2002</date>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> for all journeyman Border Patrol agents and inspectors who have completed at least one year’s service and are receiving an annual rate of basic pay for positions at GS–9 of the General Schedule under <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref> from the annual rate of basic pay payable for positions at GS–9 of the General Schedule under such section 5332, to an annual rate of basic pay payable for positions at GS–11 of the General Schedule under such section 5332;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> for inspections assistants, from the annual rate of basic pay payable for positions at GS–5 of the General Schedule under <ref>section 5332 of title 5</ref> to an annual rate of basic pay payable for positions at GS–7 of the General Schedule under such section 5332; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> for the support staff associated with the personnel described in subparagraphs (A) and (B), at the appropriate GS level of the General Schedule under such section 5332.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations for training</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<chapeau> to appropriately train Immigration and Naturalization Service personnel on an ongoing basis—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to ensure that their proficiency levels are acceptable to protect the borders of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> otherwise to enforce and administer the laws within their jurisdiction;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to provide adequate continuing cross-training to agencies staffing the United States border and ports of entry to effectively and correctly apply applicable United States laws;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to fully train immigration officers to use the appropriate lookout databases and to monitor passenger traffic patterns; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> to expand the Carrier Consultant Program described in <ref>section 1225a(b) of this title</ref>.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002112">2</ref></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations for consular functions</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Responsibilities</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of State shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> implement enhanced security measures for the review of visa applicants;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> staff the facilities and programs associated with the activities described in subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide ongoing training for consular officers and diplomatic security agents.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated for the Department of State such sums as may be necessary to carry out paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 545</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1712.</num>
<heading> Authorization of appropriations for improvements in technology and infrastructure</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Funding of technology</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">In addition to funds otherwise available for such purpose, there are authorized to be appropriated $150,000,000 to the Immigration and Naturalization Service for purposes of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> making improvements in technology (including infrastructure support, computer security, and information technology development) for improving border security;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> expanding, utilizing, and improving technology to improve border security; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> facilitating the flow of commerce and persons at ports of entry, including improving and expanding programs for preenrollment and preclearance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Waiver of fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Federal agencies involved in border security may waive all or part of enrollment fees for technology-based programs to encourage participation by United States citizens and aliens in such programs. Any agency that waives any part of any such fee may establish its fees for other services at a level that will ensure the recovery from other users of the amounts waived.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Offset of increases in fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Attorney General may, to the extent reasonable, increase land border fees for the issuance of arrival-departure documents to offset technology costs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Improvement and expansion of INS, State Department, and customs facilities</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Immigration and Naturalization Service and the Department of State such sums as may be necessary to improve and expand facilities for use by the personnel of those agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 546</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1713.</num>
<heading> Machine-readable visa fees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Fee amount</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The machine-readable visa fee charged by the Department of State shall be the higher of $65 or the cost of the machine-readable visa service, as determined by the Secretary of State after conducting a study of the cost of such service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Surcharge</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Department of State is authorized to charge a surcharge of $10, in addition to the machine-readable visa fee, for issuing a machine-readable visa in a nonmachine-readable passport.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Availability of collected fees</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, amounts collected as fees described in this section shall be deposited in the Consular and Border Security Programs account to recover costs of providing consular services. Amounts so credited shall be available, until expended, for the same purposes as the appropriation to which credited.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 547</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–31, div. J, title VII, § 7081(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-05-05">May 5, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 716</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1714.</num>
<heading> Surcharges related to consular services</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Beginning in fiscal year 2005 and thereafter, the Secretary of State is authorized to charge surcharges related to consular services in support of enhanced border security that are in addition to the passport and immigrant visa fees in effect on <date date="2004-01-01">January 1, 2004</date>: <i>Provided</i>, That funds collected pursuant to this authority shall be deposited in the Consular and Border Security Programs account, and shall be available until expended for the purposes of such account: <i>Provided further</i>, That such surcharges shall be $12 on passport fees, and $45 on immigrant visa fees.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–447, div. B, title IV</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 2896</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 115–31, div. J, title VII, § 7081(c)</ref>, <date date="2017-05-05">May 5, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 716</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1715.</num>
<heading> Consular and Border Security Programs</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Separate fund</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established in the Treasury a separate fund to be known as the “Consular and Border Security Programs” account into which the following fees shall be deposited for the purposes of the consular and border security programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> to (g) Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transfer of funds</heading>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The unobligated balances of amounts available from fees referenced under this section may be transferred to the Consular and Border Security Programs account.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Funds deposited in or transferred to the Consular and Border Security Programs account may be transferred between funds appropriated under the heading “Administration of Foreign Affairs”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent0">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The transfer authorities in this section shall be in addition to any other transfer authority available to the Department of State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The amendments made by this section shall take effect no later than <date date="2018-10-01">October 1, 2018</date>, and shall be implemented in a manner that ensures the fees collected, transferred, and used in fiscal year 2019 can be readily tracked.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 115–31, div. J, title VII, § 7081</ref>, <date date="2017-05-05">May 5, 2017</date>, <ref>131 Stat. 716</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER II—</num>
<heading>INTERAGENCY INFORMATION SHARING</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1721.</num>
<heading> Interim measures for access to and coordination of law enforcement and other information</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interim directive</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Until the plan required by subsection (c) is implemented, Federal law enforcement agencies and the intelligence community shall, to the maximum extent practicable, share any information with the Department of State and the Immigration and Naturalization Service relevant to the admissibility and deportability of aliens, consistent with the plan described in subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report identifying law enforcement and intelligence information</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 120 days after <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, the President shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report identifying Federal law enforcement and the intelligence community information needed by the Department of State to screen visa applicants, or by the Immigration and Naturalization Service to screen applicants for admission to the United States, and to identify those aliens inadmissible or deportable under the Immigration and Nationality Act [<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination plan</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement for plan</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than one year after <date date="2001-10-26">October 26, 2001</date>, the President shall develop and implement a plan based on the findings of the report under subsection (b) that requires Federal law enforcement agencies and the intelligence community to provide to the Department of State and the Immigration and Naturalization Service all information identified in that report as expeditiously as practicable.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the preparation and implementation of the plan under this subsection, the President shall consult with the appropriate committees of Congress.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Protections regarding information and uses thereof</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The plan under this subsection shall establish conditions for using the information described in subsection (b) received by the Department of State and Immigration and Naturalization Service—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to limit the redissemination of such information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to ensure that such information is used solely to determine whether to issue a visa to an alien or to determine the admissibility or deportability of an alien to the United States, except as otherwise authorized under Federal law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to ensure the accuracy, security, and confidentiality of such information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to protect any privacy rights of individuals who are subjects of such information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> to provide data integrity through the timely removal and destruction of obsolete or erroneous names and information; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> in a manner that protects the sources and methods used to acquire intelligence information as required by <ref>section 403–3(c)(7) of title 50</ref>.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002113">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Criminal penalties for misuse of information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Any person who obtains information under this subsection without authorization or exceeding authorized access (as defined in <ref>section 1030(e) of title 18</ref>), and who uses such information in the manner described in any of the paragraphs (1) through (7) of section 1030(a) of such title, or attempts to use such information in such manner, shall be subject to the same penalties as are applicable under section 1030(c) of such title for violation of that paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 547</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–177, title III, § 377(f)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-13">Dec. 13, 2003</date>, <ref>117 Stat. 2631</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1722.</num>
<heading> Interoperable law enforcement and intelligence data system with name-matching capacity and training</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interoperable law enforcement and intelligence electronic data system</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement for integrated immigration and naturalization data system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Immigration and Naturalization Service shall fully integrate all databases and data systems maintained by the Service that process or contain information on aliens. The fully integrated data system shall be an interoperable component of the electronic data system described in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement for interoperable data system</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Upon the date of commencement of implementation of the plan required by <ref>section 1721(c) of this title</ref>, the President shall develop and implement an interoperable electronic data system to provide current and immediate access to information in databases of Federal law enforcement agencies and the intelligence community that is relevant to determine whether to issue a visa or to determine the admissibility or deportability of an alien (also known as the “Chimera system”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Consultation requirement</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In the development and implementation of the data system under this subsection, the President shall consult with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) and any such other agency as may be deemed appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Technology standard</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The data system developed and implemented under this subsection, and the databases referred to in paragraph (2), shall utilize the technology standard established pursuant to <ref>section 1379 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Access to information in data system</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (6), information in the data system under this subsection shall be readily and easily accessible—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> to any consular officer responsible for the issuance of visas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> to any Federal official responsible for determining an alien’s admissibility to or deportability from the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> to any Federal law enforcement or intelligence officer determined by regulation to be responsible for the investigation or identification of aliens.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on access</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The President shall, in accordance with applicable Federal laws, establish procedures to restrict access to intelligence information in the data system under this subsection, and the databases referred to in paragraph (2), under circumstances in which such information is not to be disclosed directly to Government officials under paragraph (5).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Name-search capacity and support</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The interoperable electronic data system required by subsection (a) shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> have the capacity to compensate for disparate name formats among the different databases referred to in subsection (a);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> be searchable on a linguistically sensitive basis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> provide adequate user support;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> to the extent practicable, utilize commercially available technology; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> be adjusted and improved, based upon experience with the databases and improvements in the underlying technologies and sciences, on a continuing basis.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Linguistically sensitive searches</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">To satisfy the requirement of paragraph (1)(B), the interoperable electronic database shall be searchable based on linguistically sensitive algorithms that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> account for variations in name formats and transliterations, including varied spellings and varied separation or combination of name elements, within a particular language; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> incorporate advanced linguistic, mathematical, statistical, and anthropological research and methods.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Languages required</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Priority languages</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Linguistically sensitive algorithms shall be developed and implemented for no fewer than 4 languages designated as high priorities by the Secretary of State, after consultation with the Attorney General and the Director of Central Intelligence.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation schedule</heading>
<chapeau class="indent3">Of the 4 linguistically sensitive algorithms required to be developed and implemented under clause (i)—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the highest priority language algorithms shall be implemented within 18 months after <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent4">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> an additional language algorithm shall be implemented each succeeding year for the next three years.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Adequate user support</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Secretary of State and the Attorney General shall jointly prescribe procedures to ensure that consular and immigration officers can, as required, obtain assistance in resolving identity and other questions that may arise about the names of aliens seeking visas or admission to the United States that may be subject to variations in format, transliteration, or other similar phenomenon.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Interim reports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Six months after <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, the President shall submit a report to the appropriate committees of Congress on the progress in implementing each requirement of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Reports by intelligence agencies</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Current standards</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 60 days after <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, the Director of Central Intelligence shall complete the survey and issue the report previously required by section 309(a) of the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1998 (<ref>50 U.S.C. 403–3</ref> note).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002114">1</ref></p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Guidelines</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 120 days after <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, the Director of Central Intelligence shall issue the guidelines and submit the copy of those guidelines previously required by section 309(b) of the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1998.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(6)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 548</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1723.</num>
<heading> Commission on Interoperable Data Sharing</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than one year after <date date="2001-10-26">October 26, 2001</date>, the President shall establish a Commission on Interoperable Data Sharing (in this section referred to as the “Commission”). The purposes of the Commission shall be to—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> monitor the protections described in <ref>section 1721(c)(3) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> provide oversight of the interoperable electronic data system described in <ref>section 1722 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> report to Congress annually on the Commission’s findings and recommendations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall consist of nine members, who shall be appointed by the President, as follows:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> One member, who shall serve as Chair of the Commission.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Eight members, who shall be appointed from a list of nominees jointly provided by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, the Majority Leader of the Senate, and the Minority Leader of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Commission shall consider recommendations regarding the following issues:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> Adequate protection of privacy concerns inherent in the design, implementation, or operation of the interoperable electronic data system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> Timely adoption of security innovations, consistent with generally accepted security standards, to protect the integrity and confidentiality of information to prevent the risks of accidental or unauthorized loss, access, destruction, use modification, or disclosure of information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The adequacy of mechanisms to permit the timely correction of errors in data maintained by the interoperable data system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Other protections against unauthorized use of data to guard against the misuse of the interoperable data system or the data maintained by the system, including recommendations for modifications to existing laws and regulations to sanction misuse of the system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Commission such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 551</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1724.</num>
<heading> Personnel management authorities for positions involved in the development and implementation of the interoperable electronic data system (“Chimera system”)</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law relating to position classification or employee pay or performance, the Attorney General may hire and fix the compensation of necessary scientific, technical, engineering, and other analytical personnel for the purpose of the development and implementation of the interoperable electronic data system described in <ref>section 1722(a)(2) of this title</ref> (also known as the “Chimera system”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on rate of pay</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided by law, no employee compensated under subsection (a) may be paid at a rate in excess of the rate payable for a position at level III of the Executive Schedule.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Limitation on total calendar year payments</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Total payments to employees under any system established under this section shall be subject to the limitation on payments to employees under <ref>section 5307 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operating plan</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on International Relations of the House of Representatives an operating plan—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> describing the Attorney General’s intended use of the authority under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> identifying any provisions of title 5 being waived for purposes of the development and implementation of the Chimera system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Termination date</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The authority of this section shall terminate upon the implementation of the Chimera system.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 551</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER III—</num>
<heading>VISA ISSUANCE</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1731.</num>
<heading> Implementation of an integrated entry and exit data system</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Development of system</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In developing the integrated entry and exit data system for the ports of entry, as required by the Immigration and Naturalization Service Data Management Improvement Act of 2000 (<ref>Public Law 106–215</ref>), the Attorney General and the Secretary of State shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> implement, fund, and use a technology standard under <ref>section 1379 of this title</ref> at United States ports of entry and at consular posts abroad;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> establish a database containing the arrival and departure data from machine-readable visas, passports, and other travel and entry documents possessed by aliens; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> make interoperable all security databases relevant to making determinations of admissibility under <ref>section 1182 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In implementing the provisions of subsection (a), the Immigration and Naturalization Service and the Department of State shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> utilize technologies that facilitate the lawful and efficient cross-border movement of commerce and persons without compromising the safety and security of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> consider implementing the North American National Security Program described in <ref>section 1751 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 552</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1732.</num>
<heading> Machine-readable, tamper-resistant entry and exit documents</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, the Attorney General, the Secretary of State, and the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), acting jointly, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a comprehensive report assessing the actions that will be necessary, and the considerations to be taken into account, to achieve fully, not later than <date date="2004-10-26">October 26, 2004</date>—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> implementation of the requirements of subsections (b) and (c); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> deployment of the equipment and software to allow biometric comparison and authentication of the documents described in subsections (b) and (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Estimates</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In addition to the assessment required by paragraph (1), the report required by that paragraph shall include an estimate of the costs to be incurred, and the personnel, man-hours, and other support required, by the Department of Justice, the Department of State, and NIST to achieve the objectives of subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than <date date="2004-10-26">October 26, 2004</date>, the Attorney General and the Secretary of State shall issue to aliens only machine-readable, tamper-resistant visas and other travel and entry documents that use biometric identifiers. The Attorney General and the Secretary of State shall jointly establish document authentication standards and biometric identifiers standards to be employed on such visas and other travel and entry documents from among those biometric identifiers recognized by domestic and international standards organizations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Readers and scanners at ports of entry</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than <date date="2005-10-26">October 26, 2005</date>, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall install at all ports of entry of the United States equipment and software to allow biometric comparison and authentication of all United States visas and other travel and entry documents issued to aliens, and passports issued pursuant to subsection (c)(1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of readers and scanners</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall utilize biometric data readers and scanners that—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> domestic and international standards organizations determine to be highly accurate when used to verify identity;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> can read the biometric identifiers utilized under subsections (b)(1) and (c)(1); and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> can authenticate the document presented to verify identity.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of technology standard</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The systems employed to implement paragraphs (1) and (2) shall utilize the technology standard established pursuant to <ref>section 1379 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. O, title II, § 202(c)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2989</ref></heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section, including reimbursement to international and domestic standards organizations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 553</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–299, § 1</ref>, <date date="2004-08-09">Aug. 9, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 1100</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 114–113, div. O, title II, § 202(c)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref>129 Stat. 2989</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1733.</num>
<heading> Terrorist lookout committees</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall require a terrorist lookout committee to be maintained within each United States mission to a foreign country.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The purpose of each committee established under subsection (a) shall be—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> to utilize the cooperative resources of all elements of the United States mission in the country in which the consular post is located to identify known or potential terrorists and to develop information on those individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> to ensure that such information is routinely and consistently brought to the attention of appropriate United States officials for use in administering the immigration laws of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> to ensure that the names of known and suspected terrorists are entered into the appropriate lookout databases.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Composition; chair</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish rules governing the composition of such committees.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each committee established under subsection (a) shall meet at least monthly to share information pertaining to the committee’s purpose as described in subsection (b)(2).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Periodic reports to the Secretary of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Each committee established under subsection (a) shall submit monthly reports to the Secretary of State describing the committee’s activities, whether or not information on known or suspected terrorists was developed during the month.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. J, title VII, § 7034(i)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2624</ref></heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to implement this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 554</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 113–235, div. J, title VII, § 7034(i)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref>128 Stat. 2624</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1734.</num>
<heading> Improved training for consular officers</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Training</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall require that all consular officers responsible for adjudicating visa applications, before undertaking to perform consular responsibilities, receive specialized training in the effective screening of visa applicants who pose a potential threat to the safety or security of the United States. Such officers shall be specially and extensively trained in the identification of aliens inadmissible under section 1182(a)(3)(A) and (B) of this title, interagency and international intelligence sharing regarding terrorists and terrorism, and cultural-sensitivity toward visa applicants. In accordance with <ref>section 1776 of this title</ref>, and as part of the consular training provided to such officers by the Secretary of State, such officers shall also receive training in detecting fraudulent documents and general document forensics and shall be required as part of such training to work with immigration officers conducting inspections of applicants for admission into the United States at ports of entry.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Use of foreign intelligence information</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As an ongoing component of the training required in subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall coordinate with the Assistant to the President for Homeland Security, Federal law enforcement agencies, and the intelligence community to compile and disseminate to the Bureau of Consular Affairs reports, bulletins, updates, and other current unclassified information relevant to terrorists and terrorism and to screening visa applicants who pose a potential threat to the safety or security of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to implement this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 555</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title VII, § 7203(c)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1735.</num>
<heading> Restriction on issuance of visas to nonimmigrants from countries that are state sponsors of international terrorism</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">No nonimmigrant visa under <ref>section 1101(a)(15) of this title</ref> shall be issued to any alien from a country that is a state sponsor of international terrorism unless the Secretary of State determines, in consultation with the Attorney General and the heads of other appropriate United States agencies, that such alien does not pose a threat to the safety or national security of the United States. In making a determination under this subsection, the Secretary of State shall apply standards developed by the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Attorney General and the heads of other appropriate United States agencies, that are applicable to the nationals of such states.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> State sponsor of international terrorism defined</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In this section, the term “state sponsor of international terrorism” means any country the government of which has been determined by the Secretary of State under any of the laws specified in paragraph (2) to have repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Laws under which determinations were made</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The laws specified in this paragraph are the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content><ref>Section 4605(j)(1)(A) of title 50</ref> (or successor statute).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002115">1</ref></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content><ref>Section 2780(d) of title 22</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content><ref>Section 2371(a) of title 22</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 555</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1736.</num>
<heading> Check of lookout databases</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Prior to the admission of an alien under the visa waiver program established under <ref>section 1187 of this title</ref>, the Immigration and Naturalization Service shall determine that the applicant for admission does not appear in any of the appropriate lookout databases available to immigration inspectors at the time the alien seeks admission to the United States.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title III, § 307(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 556</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1737.</num>
<heading> Tracking system for stolen passports</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Entering stolen passport identification numbers in the interoperable data system</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Beginning with implementation under <ref>section 1722 of this title</ref> of the law enforcement and intelligence data system, not later than 72 hours after receiving notification of the loss or theft of a United States or foreign passport, the Attorney General and the Secretary of State, as appropriate, shall enter into such system the corresponding identification number for the lost or stolen passport.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Entry of information on previously lost or stolen passports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">To the extent practicable, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall enter into such system the corresponding identification numbers for the United States and foreign passports lost or stolen prior to the implementation of such system.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transition period</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Until such time as the law enforcement and intelligence data system described in <ref>section 1722 of this title</ref> is fully implemented, the Attorney General shall enter the data described in subsection (a) into an existing data system being used to determine the admissibility or deportability of aliens.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title III, § 308</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 556</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1738.</num>
<heading> Identification documents for certain newly admitted aliens</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, the Attorney General shall ensure that, immediately upon the arrival in the United States of an individual admitted under <ref>section 1157 of this title</ref>, or immediately upon an alien being granted asylum under <ref>section 1158 of this title</ref>, the alien will be issued an employment authorization document. Such document shall, at a minimum, contain the fingerprint and photograph of such alien.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title III, § 309</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 556</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER IV—</num>
<heading>INSPECTION AND ADMISSION OF ALIENS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1751.</num>
<heading> Study of the feasibility of a North American National Security Program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The President shall conduct a study of the feasibility of establishing a North American National Security Program to enhance the mutual security and safety of the United States, Canada, and Mexico.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In conducting the study required by subsection (a), the President shall consider the following:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preclearance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The feasibility of establishing a program enabling foreign national travelers to the United States to submit voluntarily to a preclearance procedure established by the Department of State and the Immigration and Naturalization Service to determine whether such travelers are admissible to the United States under <ref>section 1182 of this title</ref>. Consideration shall be given to the feasibility of expanding the preclearance program to include the preclearance both of foreign nationals traveling to Canada and foreign nationals traveling to Mexico.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Preinspection</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The feasibility of expanding preinspection facilities at foreign airports as described in <ref>section 1225a of this title</ref>. Consideration shall be given to the feasibility of expanding preinspections to foreign nationals on air flights destined for Canada and Mexico, and the cross training and funding of inspectors from Canada and Mexico.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Conditions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">A determination of the measures necessary to ensure that the conditions required by <ref>section 1225a(a)(5) of this title</ref> are satisfied, including consultation with experts recognized for their expertise regarding the conditions required by that section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, the President shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report setting forth the findings of the study conducted under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 557</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1752.</num>
<heading> Staffing levels at ports of entry</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Immigration and Naturalization Service shall staff ports of entry at such levels that would be adequate to meet traffic flow and inspection time objectives efficiently without compromising the safety and security of the United States. Estimated staffing levels under workforce models for the Immigration and Naturalization Service shall be based on the goal of providing immigration services described in <ref>section 1356(g) of this title</ref> within 45 minutes of a passenger’s presentation for inspection.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title IV, § 403(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 559</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1752a.</num>
<heading> Model ports-of-entry</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> establish a model ports-of-entry program for the purpose of providing a more efficient and welcoming international arrival process in order to facilitate and promote business and tourist travel to the United States, while also improving security; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> implement the program initially at the 20 United States international airports that have the highest number of foreign visitors arriving annually as of <date date="2007-08-03">August 3, 2007</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Program elements</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The program shall include—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> enhanced queue management in the Federal Inspection Services area leading up to primary inspection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> assistance for foreign travelers once they have been admitted to the United States, in consultation, as appropriate, with relevant governmental and nongovernmental entities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> instructional videos, in English and such other languages as the Secretary determines appropriate, in the Federal Inspection Services area that explain the United States inspection process and feature national, regional, or local welcome videos.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Additional Customs and Border Protection officers for high-volume ports</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subject to the availability of appropriations, not later than the end of fiscal year 2008 the Secretary of Homeland Security shall employ not fewer than an additional 200 Customs and Border Protection officers over the number of such positions for which funds were appropriated for the proceeding fiscal year to address staff shortages at the 20 United States international airports that have the highest number of foreign visitors arriving annually as of <date date="2007-08-03">August 3, 2007</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 110–53, title VII, § 725</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 350</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1753.</num>
<heading> Joint United States-Canada projects for alternative inspections services</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">United States border inspections agencies, including the Immigration and Naturalization Service, acting jointly and under an agreement of cooperation with the Government of Canada, may conduct joint United States-Canada inspections projects on the international border between the two countries. Each such project may provide alternative inspections services and shall undertake to harmonize the criteria for inspections applied by the two countries in implementing those projects.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Attorney General and the Secretary of the Treasury shall prepare and submit annually to Congress a report on the joint United States-Canada inspections projects conducted under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Exemption from Administrative Procedure Act and Paperwork Reduction Act</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5 (commonly referred to as the “Administrative Procedure Act”) and chapter 35 of title 44 (commonly referred to as the “Paperwork Reduction Act”) shall not apply to fee setting for services and other administrative requirements relating to projects described in subsection (a), except that fees and forms established for such projects shall be published as a notice in the Federal Register.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 560</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER V—</num>
<heading>FOREIGN STUDENTS AND EXCHANGE VISITORS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1761.</num>
<heading> Foreign student monitoring program</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading>
<content/>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Information required of the visa applicant</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Prior to the issuance of a visa under subparagraph (F), subparagraph (M), or, with respect to an alien seeking to attend an approved institution of higher education, subparagraph (J) of <ref>section 1101(a)(15) of this title</ref>, each alien applying for such visa shall provide to a consular officer the following information:</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> The alien’s address in the country of origin.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> The names and addresses of the alien’s spouse, children, parents, and siblings.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> The names of contacts of the alien in the alien’s country of residence who could verify information about the alien.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> Previous work history, if any, including the names and addresses of employers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Transitional program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 120 days after <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, and until such time as the system described in <ref>section 1372 of this title</ref> is fully implemented, the following requirements shall apply:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Restrictions on issuance of visas</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">A visa may not be issued to an alien under subparagraph (F), subparagraph (M), or, with respect to an alien seeking to attend an approved institution of higher education, subparagraph (J) of <ref>section 1101(a)(15) of this title</ref>, unless—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> the Department of State has received from an approved institution of higher education or other approved educational institution electronic evidence of documentation of the alien’s acceptance at that institution; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> the consular officer has adequately reviewed the applicant’s visa record.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification upon visa issuance</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Upon the issuance of a visa under section 1101(a)(15)(F) or (M) of this title to an alien, the Secretary of State shall transmit to the Immigration and Naturalization Service a notification of the issuance of that visa.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(C)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification upon admission of alien</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Immigration and Naturalization Service shall notify the approved institution of higher education or other approved educational institution that an alien accepted for such institution or program has been admitted to the United States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(D)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Notification of failure of enrollment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Not later than 30 days after the deadline for registering for classes for an academic term, the approved institution of higher education or other approved educational institution shall inform the Immigration and Naturalization Service through data-sharing arrangements of any failure of any alien described in subparagraph (C) to enroll or to commence participation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement to submit list of approved institutions</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 30 days after <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, the Attorney General shall provide the Secretary of State with a list of all approved institutions of higher education and other approved educational institutions that are authorized to receive nonimmigrants under section 1101(a)(15)(F) or (M) of this title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 560</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1762.</num>
<heading> Review of institutions and other entities authorized to enroll or sponsor certain nonimmigrants</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Periodic review of compliance</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">Not later than two years after <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, and every two years thereafter, the Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, shall conduct a review of the institutions certified to receive nonimmigrants under section 1101(a)(15)(F), (M), or (J) of this title. Each review shall determine whether the institutions are in compliance with—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> recordkeeping and reporting requirements to receive nonimmigrants under section 1101(a)(15)(F), (M), or (J) of this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> recordkeeping and reporting requirements under <ref>section 1372 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Periodic review of sponsors of exchange visitors</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement for reviews</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than two years after <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, and every two years thereafter, the Secretary of State shall conduct a review of the entities designated to sponsor exchange visitor program participants under <ref>section 1101(a)(15)(J) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Determinations</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">On the basis of reviews of entities under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall determine whether the entities are in compliance with—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> recordkeeping and reporting requirements to receive nonimmigrant exchange visitor program participants under <ref>section 1101(a)(15)(J) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> recordkeeping and reporting requirements under <ref>section 1372 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Effect of material failure to comply</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Material failure of an institution or other entity to comply with the recordkeeping and reporting requirements to receive nonimmigrant students or exchange visitor program participants under section 1101(a)(15)(F), (M), or (J) of this title, or <ref>section 1372 of this title</ref>, shall result in the suspension for at least one year or termination, at the election of the Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization, of the institution’s approval to receive such students, or result in the suspension for at least one year or termination, at the election of the Secretary of State, of the other entity’s designation to sponsor exchange visitor program participants, as the case may be.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 563</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
<subchapter>
<num>SUBCHAPTER VI—</num>
<heading>MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS</heading>
<section>
<num>§ 1771.</num>
<heading> General Accounting Office study</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement for study</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study to determine the feasibility and utility of implementing a requirement that each nonimmigrant alien in the United States submit to the Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization each year a current address and, where applicable, the name and address of an employer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Nonimmigrant alien defined</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">In paragraph (1), the term “nonimmigrant alien” means an alien described in <ref>section 1101(a)(15) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the study under subsection (a). The report shall include the Comptroller General’s findings, together with any recommendations that the Comptroller General considers appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 564</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1772.</num>
<heading> International cooperation</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> International electronic data system</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of State and the Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization, in consultation with the Assistant to the President for Homeland Security, shall jointly conduct a study of the alternative approaches (including the costs of, and procedures necessary for, each alternative approach) for encouraging or requiring Canada, Mexico, and countries treated as visa waiver program countries under section 217 of the Immigration and Nationality Act [<ref>8 U.S.C. 1187</ref>] to develop an intergovernmental network of interoperable electronic data systems that—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> facilitates real-time access to that country’s law enforcement and intelligence information that is needed by the Department of State and the Immigration and Naturalization Service to screen visa applicants and applicants for admission into the United States to identify aliens who are inadmissible or deportable under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101</ref> et seq.);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> is interoperable with the electronic data system implemented under <ref>section 1722 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> performs in accordance with implementation of the technology standard referred to in <ref>section 1722(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, the Secretary of State and the Attorney General shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report setting forth the findings of the study conducted under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 564</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1773.</num>
<heading> Statutory construction</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to impose requirements that are inconsistent with the USMCA (as defined in <ref>section 4502 of title 19</ref>) or to require additional documents for aliens for whom documentary requirements are waived under <ref>section 1182(d)(4)(B) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title VI, § 604</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 565</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 116–113, title V, § 503(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2020-01-29">Jan. 29, 2020</date>, <ref>134 Stat. 72</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1774.</num>
<heading> Annual report on aliens who fail to appear after release on own recognizance</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Requirement for report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Not later than January 15 of each year, the Attorney General shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the total number of aliens who, during the preceding year, failed to attend a removal proceeding after having been arrested outside a port of entry, served a notice to appear under <ref>section 1229(a)(1) of this title</ref>, and released on the alien’s own recognizance. The report shall also take into account the number of cases in which there were defects in notices of hearing or the service of notices of hearing, together with a description and analysis of the effects, if any, that the defects had on the attendance of aliens at the proceedings.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">Notwithstanding the time for submission of the annual report provided in subsection (a), the report for 2001 shall be submitted not later than 6 months after <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title VI, § 605</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 565</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1775.</num>
<heading> Retention of nonimmigrant visa applications by the Department of State</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Department of State shall retain, for a period of seven years from the date of application, every application for a nonimmigrant visa under section 101(a)(15) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)</ref>) in a form that will be admissible in the courts of the United States or in administrative proceedings, including removal proceedings under such Act [<ref>8 U.S.C. 1101</ref> et seq.], without regard to whether the application was approved or denied.</p>
</content>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 107–173, title VI, § 606</ref>, <date date="2002-05-14">May 14, 2002</date>, <ref>116 Stat. 565</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1776.</num>
<heading> Training program</heading>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Review, evaluation, and revision of existing training programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> review and evaluate the training regarding travel and identity documents, and techniques, patterns, and trends associated with terrorist travel that is provided to personnel of the Department of Homeland Security;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> in coordination with the Secretary of State, review and evaluate the training described in subparagraph (A) that is provided to relevant personnel of the Department of State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<chapeau> in coordination with the Secretary of State, develop and implement an initial training and periodic retraining program—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> to teach border, immigration, and consular officials (who inspect or review travel or identity documents as part of their official duties) how to effectively detect, intercept, and disrupt terrorist travel; and</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent2">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> to ensure that the officials described in clause (i) regularly receive the most current information on such matters and are periodically retrained on the matters described in paragraph (2).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Required topics of revised programs</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">The training program developed under paragraph (1)(C) shall include training in—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> methods for identifying fraudulent and genuine travel documents;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> methods for detecting terrorist indicators on travel documents and other relevant identity documents;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> recognition of travel patterns, tactics, and behaviors exhibited by terrorists;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> effective utilization of information contained in databases and data systems available to the Department of Homeland Security; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent1">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> other topics determined to be appropriate by the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of State or the Director of National Intelligence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department of Homeland Security</heading>
<clause class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide all border and immigration officials who inspect or review travel or identity documents as part of their official duties with the training described in paragraph (1)(C).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not later than 12 months after <date date="2004-12-17">December 17, 2004</date>, and annually thereafter for a period of 3 years, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit a report to Congress that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> describes the number of border and immigration officials who inspect or review identity documents as part of their official duties, and the proportion of whom have received the revised training program described in paragraph (1)(C)(i);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> explains the reasons, if any, for not completing the requisite training described in paragraph (1)(C)(i);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> provides a timetable for completion of the training described in paragraph (1)(C)(i) for those who have not received such training; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> describes the status of periodic retraining of appropriate personnel described in paragraph (1)(C)(ii).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Department of State</heading>
<clause class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">The Secretary of State shall provide all consular officers who inspect or review travel or identity documents as part of their official duties with the training described in paragraph (1)(C).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<chapeau class="indent2">Not later than 12 months after <date date="2004-12-17">December 17, 2004</date>, and annually thereafter for a period of 3 years, the Secretary of State shall submit a report to Congress that—</chapeau>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> describes the number of consular officers who inspect or review travel or identity documents as part of their official duties, and the proportion of whom have received the revised training program described in paragraph (1)(C)(i);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(II)</num>
<content> explains the reasons, if any, for not completing the requisite training described in paragraph (1)(C)(i);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(III)</num>
<content> provides a timetable for completion of the training described in paragraph (1)(C)(i) for those who have not received such training; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause class="indent3">
<num>(IV)</num>
<content> describes the status of periodic retraining of appropriate personnel described in paragraph (1)(C)(ii).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(4)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Assistance to others</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Homeland Security may assist States, Indian tribes, local governments, and private organizations to establish training programs related to terrorist travel intelligence.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(5)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2005 through 2009 to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title VII, § 7201(d)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3811</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1777.</num>
<heading> Establishment of Human Smuggling and Trafficking Center</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There is established a Human Smuggling and Trafficking Center (referred to in this section as the “Center”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Operation</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of State, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Attorney General shall operate the Center in accordance with the Memorandum of Understanding entitled, “Human Smuggling and Trafficking Center (HSTC), Charter”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Functions</heading>
<chapeau class="indent0">In addition to such other responsibilities as the President may assign, the Center shall—</chapeau>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(1)</num>
<content> serve as the focal point for interagency efforts to integrate and disseminate intelligence and information related to terrorist travel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(2)</num>
<content> serve as a clearinghouse with respect to all relevant information from all Federal Government agencies in support of the United States strategy to prevent separate, but related, issues of clandestine terrorist travel and facilitation of migrant smuggling and trafficking of persons;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(3)</num>
<content> ensure cooperation among all relevant policy, law enforcement, diplomatic, and intelligence agencies of the Federal Government to improve effectiveness and to convert all information available to the Federal Government relating to clandestine terrorist travel and facilitation, migrant smuggling, and trafficking of persons into tactical, operational, and strategic intelligence that can be used to combat such illegal activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent1">
<num>(4)</num>
<content> prepare and submit to Congress, on an annual basis, a strategic assessment regarding vulnerabilities in the United States and foreign travel system that may be exploited by international terrorists, human smugglers and traffickers, and their facilitators.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(d)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Director</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall nominate an official of the Government of the United States to serve as the Director of the Center, in accordance with the requirements of the memorandum of understanding entitled the “Human Smuggling and Trafficking Center (HSTC) Charter”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(e)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Staffing of the Center</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of Homeland Security, in cooperation with heads of other relevant agencies and departments, shall ensure that the Center is staffed with not fewer than 40 full-time equivalent positions, including, as appropriate, detailees from the following:</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<chapeau> Agencies and offices within the Department of Homeland Security, including the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Office of Intelligence and Analysis.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The Transportation Security Administration.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> United States Citizenship and Immigration Services.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> United States Customs and Border Protection.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> The United States Coast Guard.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> Other departments, agencies, or entities, including the following:</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> The Central Intelligence Agency.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> The Department of Defense.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> The Department of the Treasury.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> The National Counterterrorism Center.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> The National Security Agency.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> The Department of Justice.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> The Department of State.</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> Any other relevant agency or department.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Expertise of detailees</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">The Secretary of Homeland Security, in cooperation with the head of each agency, department, or other entity referred to in paragraph (1), shall ensure that the detailees provided to the Center under such paragraph include an adequate number of personnel who are—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> intelligence analysts or special agents with demonstrated experience related to human smuggling, trafficking in persons, or terrorist travel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<chapeau> personnel with experience in the areas of—</chapeau>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(i)</num>
<content> consular affairs;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(ii)</num>
<content> counterterrorism;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iii)</num>
<content> criminal law enforcement;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(iv)</num>
<content> intelligence analysis;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(v)</num>
<content> prevention and detection of document fraud;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vi)</num>
<content> border inspection;</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(vii)</num>
<content> immigration enforcement; or</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent3">
<num>(viii)</num>
<content> human trafficking and combating severe forms of trafficking in persons.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(3)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enhanced personnel management</heading>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(A)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Incentives for service in certain positions</heading>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> In general</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">The Secretary of Homeland Security, and the heads of other relevant agencies, shall prescribe regulations or promulgate personnel policies to provide incentives for service on the staff of the Center, particularly for serving terms of at least two years duration.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause class="indent5 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(ii)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Forms of incentives</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent3">Incentives under clause (i) may include financial incentives, bonuses, and such other awards and incentives as the Secretary and the heads of other relevant agencies,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002116">1</ref> consider appropriate.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent4 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(B)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Enhanced promotion for service at the Center</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the heads of other relevant agencies, shall ensure that personnel who are assigned or detailed to service at the Center shall be considered for promotion at rates equivalent to or better than similarly situated personnel of such agencies who are not so assigned or detailed, except that this subparagraph shall not apply in the case of personnel who are subject to the provisions of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 [<ref>22 U.S.C. 3901</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(f)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Administrative support and funding</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide to the Center the administrative support and funding required for its maintenance, including funding for personnel, leasing of office space, supplies, equipment, technology, training, and travel expenses necessary for the Center to carry out its functions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(g)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report</heading>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(1)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Initial report</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2004-12-17">December 17, 2004</date>, the President shall transmit to Congress a report regarding the implementation of this section, including a description of the staffing and resource needs of the Center.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph class="indent3 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(2)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Follow-up report</heading>
<chapeau class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2007-08-03">August 3, 2007</date>, the President shall transmit to Congress a report regarding the operation of the Center and the activities carried out by the Center, including a description of—</chapeau>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(A)</num>
<content> the roles and responsibilities of each agency or department that is participating in the Center;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(B)</num>
<content> the mechanisms used to share information among each such agency or department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(C)</num>
<content> the personnel provided to the Center by each such agency or department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(D)</num>
<content> the type of information and reports being disseminated by the Center;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(E)</num>
<content> any efforts by the Center to create a centralized Federal Government database to store information related to unlawful travel of foreign nationals, including a description of any such database and of the manner in which information utilized in such a database would be collected, stored, and shared;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(F)</num>
<content> how each agency and department shall utilize its resources to ensure that the Center uses intelligence to focus and drive its efforts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(G)</num>
<content> efforts to consolidate networked systems for the Center;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(H)</num>
<content> the mechanisms for the sharing of homeland security information from the Center to the Office of Intelligence and Analysis, including how such sharing shall be consistent with <ref>section 485(b) of title 6</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(I)</num>
<content> the ability of participating personnel in the Center to freely access necessary databases and share information regarding issues related to human smuggling, trafficking in persons, and terrorist travel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(J)</num>
<content> how the assignment of personnel to the Center is incorporated into the civil service career path of such personnel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph class="indent2">
<num>(K)</num>
<content> cooperation and coordination efforts, including any memorandums of understanding, among participating agencies and departments regarding issues related to human smuggling, trafficking in persons, and terrorist travel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(h)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Relationship to the NCTC</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">As part of its mission to combat terrorist travel, the Center shall work to support the efforts of the National Counterterrorism Center.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(i)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Coordination with the Office of Intelligence and Analysis</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Office of Intelligence and Analysis, in coordination with the Center, shall submit to relevant State, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies periodic reports regarding terrorist threats related to human smuggling, human trafficking, and terrorist travel.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 108–458, title VII, § 7202</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref>118 Stat. 3813</ref>; <ref>Pub. L. 110–53, title VII, § 721(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref>121 Stat. 346–348</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
<section>
<num>§ 1778.</num>
<heading> Vulnerability and threat assessment</heading>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(a)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Study</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Under Secretary of Homeland Security for Border and Transportation Security, in consultation with the Under Secretary of Homeland Security for Science and Technology and the Under Secretary of Homeland Security for Information Analysis and Infrastructure Protection, shall study the technology, equipment, and personnel needed to address security vulnerabilities within the United States for each field office of the Bureau of Customs and Border Protection that has responsibility for any portion of the United States borders with Canada and Mexico. The Under Secretary shall conduct follow-up studies at least once every 5 years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(b)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">The Under Secretary shall submit a report to Congress on the Under Secretary’s findings and conclusions from each study conducted under subsection (a) together with legislative recommendations, as appropriate, for addressing any security vulnerabilities found by the study.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection class="indent2 firstIndent-2">
<num class="bold">(c)</num>
<heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading>
<content>
<p class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Homeland Security Directorate of Border and Transportation Security such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 2006 through 2011 to carry out any such recommendations from the first study conducted under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit>(<ref>Pub. L. 109–13, div. B, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2005-05-11">May 11, 2005</date>, <ref>119 Stat. 316</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
</subchapter>
</chapter>